<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="007829">
  <docid>007829</docid>
  <title>A Boy and His Blob</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>VideoGame</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">E</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">20 October 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
<plot>The boy from the original NES game is now sixteen years old and jellybeans are still very much his thing. He remembers his alien pal Blobert from six years ago but no one ever believed him about their adventure and eventually gave up on trying to convince people of. That is until Blobert returns, crash-landing on Earth, to tell him that the evil Emperor of Blobonia, who they defeated in the original, is hiding out on Earth and plans to enslave all Earthlings. Now they must once again defeat the evil Emperor. This time around you'll have more than 15 kinds of jellybeans you can feed to Blobert to transform him into all kinds of crazy items. Items he can transform into include a bomb, a blowtorch, a trampoline or even a suit of armor for the boy. The 3D side scrolling adventure takes place in more than 15 levels, 5 environments and on 2 planets. You'll have to fight thugs and evil blobs along the way while solving puzzles using your blob's multiple abilities. The touch screen is used for an overhead map and for jellybean management. You can visit a candy shop between levels in order to buy more beans that you think you might need in the next level. You can also practice in a tutorial mode to get used to all the things your blob can do.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?007829</url></doc>
