<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="007619">
  <docid>007619</docid>
  <title>A Bicicleta e O Escuro</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Rassi, Erico</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Biography</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>popular-art</keyword>
    <keyword>art-and-environment</keyword>
    <keyword>culture</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Portuguese</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Brazil</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Brazil">12</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Portugal">10 March 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Bolivia">20 August 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Chile">18 November 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Brazil">63</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Nunes, Claudia</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Nunes, Claudia</producer>
    <producer>Ramos, Ursula</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Nunes, Claudia</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Damaso, Kleber</actor>
      <role>Mauricinho Hippie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Martins, Girie</actor>
      <role>Escurinho</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Documentary about two popular Brazilian artists, Mauricinho Hippie and Escurinho from Campininha, and their irreverent cultural activism to stand for the art and the environment. Statement: In the last years of the decade of 70 and first years of the 80 decade, there was a Hippie Market in Goiania: an art and handcraft market that was held at Civic Square(the main square of Goiania Historical Center). The Hippie Market was a place for shopping and a meeting point of all society, mainly of intellectuals, artists, craftsmen, some thinkers and politic militants. Among all, two characters were remarkable and were always present at Hippie Market: Mauricinho Hippie and the percussionist Mr. Dark. Mauricinho was, perhaps, the first, clear and deprived of diversity, expression in Goiania. He was a young man, also a musician, that used to ride his ornamented bike, with his half naked body all painted and covered with feathers and indigenous ornaments. People from the city called him gay and homosexual. He threw kisses for everybody. He used to pass and arrive absolute, because somehow he had acquired respect from the city. And even those who didn't get close to him, enjoyed seeing Mauricinho pass by in his bike, coloring the air and our soul. In the Independence Parades he was always there occupying his extra-official position of expression. It wasn't difficult to imagine following him a huge and varied stroll of 'Carajas' and Caiapos' (indians), warriors, gays, transvestites, lesbians, urban and rural workers, men, women, children, youths, seniors, nuns, priests, pastors, police. Mr. Dark was also a musician(percussionist) that lived in Campinas, a small town founded before Goiania's construction and that was later on joined to the capital city. He, along with his tambourine and other percussion instruments, was a constant presence in the 'capoeira's' (african fight) circles held in Civic Square. Mr. Dark used to say that Goiania was originated from Campininha and not the opposite as the official thought wanted it to be. Mr. Dark was a straight black man who went to jail many times for various reasons and also suffered the tyranny's repression, perhaps not because of his politician militancy, in which he was not that engaged, but because of his mischievous and "dark" way of situating himself in society and in the limits of his artistic expression. Mr. Dark from Campininha was and is, like many others in Brazil, the clear expression of the word in its anthropological meaning and immortalized by the samba of Geraldo Pereira, a brazilian musician.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?007619</url></doc>
