<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="008077">
  <docid>008077</docid>
  <title>A Cabin in Time</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bannon, Edward</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>time</keyword>
    <keyword>love</keyword>
    <keyword>ghost</keyword>
    <keyword>past</keyword>
    <keyword>tragedy</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">85</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Larson, Linda (III)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bannon, Edward</producer>
    <producer>Larson, Linda (III)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Larson, Linda (III)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Boll, Arlan H.</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bennett, Nick (II)</actor>
      <role>Thomas</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kerry, John (I)</actor>
      <role>Angus</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lafollette, Dennis</actor>
      <role>Judge</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Larson, Linda (III)</actor>
      <role>Samantha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lincors, Nancy</actor>
      <role>Rachel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moran, Marcia</actor>
      <role>Mary</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rolfes, Andrew A.</actor>
      <role>Sheriff</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"A Cabin in Time" tells the dramatic story of tragic love and loss that reach across time and haunt the present. After the death of her husband, Samantha moves into a cabin in the west. An old friend, Rachel, visits. Their reunion is haunted by the ghost of a young woman, Prudence. A century ago, Prudence lived. She is tormented by her past. Her betroth, Thomas, lived in the cabin and was critically injured. He pleads through excruciating pain for assistance in ending his life. Prudence tearfully relents and helps him to die. This deed unleashes unbearable guilt in Prudence, and the town, inflamed by religious-fueled rage, rushes to punish. Terrified, Prudence points at Thomas's mother, Mary, as the murderer, and Mary is hung for the crime. Visions of this past, once blissfully happy and suddenly tragically sad, are unveiled. As Samantha tries to understand, confrontations with the angry and confused Ghost Prudence threaten. The lives of Samantha and Prudence forever change as a mysterious intervention turns back time. The past and the present are altered forever.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?008077</url></doc>
