<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="008305">
  <docid>008305</docid>
  <title>A Certain Circumvention</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Babbitt, Grant</editor>
    <editor>Schaack, Taylor Messner</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">21 August 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">8</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Babbitt, Grant</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Seaton, Brittani</producer>
    <producer>Babbitt, Grant</producer>
    <producer>Pullium, Bobby</producer>
    <producer>Schaack, Taylor Messner</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Babbitt, Grant</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Babbitt, Grant</actor>
      <role>Calvin's Friend #2</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Babbitt, Kasey</actor>
      <role>Calvin's Friend #1</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bruschi, Emily</actor>
      <role>Calvin's Friend #3</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hamilton, Ryan (II)</actor>
      <role>Calvin</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This is a short film about the struggle that we all face when we begin to questions ourselves. The thought of God and his existence troubles many people across all ages, races, and genders - relate-able to the many viewers who have death with an illness or death of a loved one, and asked... 'why?' A young (and very religious) couple deals with Maggie's terminal illness. Calvin and Maggie try to cope with the thought of her death, and the after effects that may occur. At first, Maggie tries to find safety and protection in her faith and Calvin, but she eventually becomes bitter when the realization of her illness emerges. Maggie wants to distance herself from Calvin to protect him as much as she can. Calvin on the other hand is strong in his faith, and he tries to convince Maggie that all will be well with her illness. The couple finds that the once strong faith they both held is now in question. After Maggie passes, Calvin is left in the rubble of depression and death. As he tries to maintain his faith, he questions if God is really out there. The film is Calvin's life now, one year later after Maggie's death. He has many flashbacks of good times and bad as he leaves her graveside to return to the bed they both once shared.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?008305</url></doc>
