<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="009225">
  <docid>009225</docid>
  <title>A Darker Shade of Gray</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Goh, Andrew</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>gray</keyword>
    <keyword>film-student</keyword>
    <keyword>neo-noir</keyword>
    <keyword>detective</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Etheridge, Daniel</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Cansler, Rachael</producer>
    <producer>Ettlinger, Zak</producer>
    <producer>Etheridge, Daniel</producer>
    <producer>Gruver, Megan</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Funderburk, Mannly</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arndt, Jack (II)</actor>
      <role>Detective Carl Kincaid</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barker, Kristin</actor>
      <role>Mary</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hammil, Nicodemus</actor>
      <role>Detective Milton Gray</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wonderley, Kenneth</actor>
      <role>Captain O'Hara</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Detective Milton Gray is tormented by his past and has no faith in his future. Once a respected officer of the law, he is now a guilt-ridden, pill-popping addict; a fallen sentinel. He is a man who wants desperately to do the right thing, but has no idea what that is. He can tell right from wrong but doesn't know where he lies on the spectrum. He views his job as not only to protect the innocent but to punish the guilty, so when he finds himself in the wrong he reacts in a self-destructive fashion. He reaches the breaking point, after a startling revelation regarding a previous case with an executed young man. Gray is suspended by his superior and forced to take some time off. Despite attempts of comfort by his partner, Carl Kincaid, Gray ostracizes himself. Unknown to Gray, a mysterious figure connected to his past is watching him. His lost faith and overwhelming guilt drive Milton to systematically destroy himself. Spurned by his Captain and looked down on by his partner, Gray, returns home and resigns to take his own life. Before he can complete the task, a scream distracts him. Taking this as a chance for redemption, Gray goes to investigate. What he does not know is that his mysterious stalker and his old case are dangerously related, and that the world can't be divided into black and white. It's all just a darker shade of Gray.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?009225</url></doc>
