<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="010570">
  <docid>010570</docid>
  <title>A Forked World</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Burtt, Carey</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>downsizing</keyword>
    <keyword>bass-player</keyword>
    <keyword>new-age</keyword>
    <keyword>urination</keyword>
    <keyword>misanthrope</keyword>
    <keyword>sex-with-priest</keyword>
    <keyword>toilet</keyword>
    <keyword>private-investigator</keyword>
    <keyword>tampon</keyword>
    <keyword>misanthropy</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">3 December 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">82</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Burtt, Carey</director>
    <director>DiGiovanna, James</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Burtt, Carey</producer>
    <producer>DiGiovanna, James</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Burtt, Carey</writer>
    <writer>DiGiovanna, James</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Burtt, Carey</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bennett, Bruce (V)</actor>
      <role>Barry</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Den Dekker, Michael</actor>
      <role>Police Officer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Diana, Mike</actor>
      <role>Dan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fere, Christine</actor>
      <role>Angela</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ratner, Nic</actor>
      <role>The Preacher</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A Forked World is the story of two mean people who struggle to remain mean in a world that wants them to be nice. Barry is a self-destructive, verbally abusive bass player who works a soul-deadening job for the sole reason of deadening his soul. At a party he meets Angela, a woman whose hatred for humanity is expressed in her tendency to leave insulting hand-made dolls as gifts for unsuspecting New Yorkers. The two form a loving hate-hate relationship based on mutual disrespect and violence. However, paradise cannot last, as Angela gets an exciting job as a private investigator whose assignment is to humiliate horny losers just as Barry's company downsizes him, forcing him to stay home and shop for tampons. Soon he is seduced by the New Age philosophy of Spoon Consciousness, and he melts into the wimpy antithesis of his previous self. When his passivity becomes more than Angela can bear, she tries to fork him out of his spoony cocoon by peeing on toilets, hitting him with dead mice, and having sex with a deranged priest. If it works, she'll have the unstable, hate-filled misanthrope she loves back in her arms and other places. If it fails, Barry could be lost to a world where utensils are the universal metaphor and flowers are feasted on by hungry cultists and their sex-deprived spouses.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?010570</url></doc>
