<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="010851">
  <docid>010851</docid>
  <title>A Gentleman from Malta</title>
  <year>1997</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Scerri-Ferrante, Malcolm</editor>
  </editors>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Malta</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Germany">19 December 1997</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">50</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="Austria">40</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Scerri-Ferrante, Malcolm</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kattner, Dr. Brita</producer>
    <producer>Scerri-Ferrante, Malcolm</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Scerri-Ferrante, Malcolm</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kaizar, Peter</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>A Maltese and Austrian co-production, this documentary takes a deep insight into the personal life and works of the late Francis Ebejer. In 1996 rare and exclusive footage of Ebejer was discovered in Vienna. The tapes, containing unused scenes, had been relegated to the basement of a producer's weekend log-house in the outskirts of the city. The recordings, filmed shortly before his death, showed Ebejer playing himself in a rare attempt to reveal his private life. It was the discovery of this footage that led Malcolm Scerri-Ferrante to produce this documentary. Over the span of his career, Ebejer wrote more than 50 plays for theatre and television, and his novels have been translated into nine languages including Japanese. He received many awards, both locally and abroad, amongst them France's Medaille d'Honeur de la Ville d'Avignon. Ebejer explored novel means of expression in dramatic literature. In his works one can trace a fascinating and intriguing development which is to this day debated in various universities across Europe. Despite his achievements Ebejer never postured as the international figure he was, though this lack of self-confidence was thought to actually spur his success. He was known to be an unhappy man with a complex and reserved personality, and his life was marred by tragedy that included the break-up of his marriage and tragic deaths in his family Like many writers, Ebejer used these downfalls as a form of inspiration for his work, but he was to remain an extremely private and introverted character. Besides his works, this documentary also explores, for the first time in any documented manner, the personal life of Francis Ebejer.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?010851</url></doc>
