<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="013085">
  <docid>013085</docid>
  <title>A Matter of Time</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <producers>
    <producer>Heffner, Daniel J.</producer>
    <producer>Roe, Philip</producer>
    <producer>Sheldrick, Peter</producer>
    <producer>Rappaport, Derek</producer>
    <producer>Heffner, Daniel J.</producer>
    <producer>Roe, Philip</producer>
    <producer>Sheldrick, Peter</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Sheldrick, Peter</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>What happens when the past you can't remember comes back with a vengeance? Jane Doe is young and beautiful. She's also an amnesiac. Stuck in an institution for the past year, she's unable to remember who, or what, she is. Jane's not only a stranger to Dr. Weismann, the man assigned to help her, but she's a stranger to the woman who peers back at her from the reflection in the mirror everyday: herself. And now, on the day she's to be shipped out of the closing institution, a highly skilled gang of killers turn up. They take over the hospital. Shut it down, trapping a skeletal crew of hospital workers inside. And they want Jane. Dead - or alive. A Matter of Time finds the woman with no real name and no real past having to out wit and survive her executioners as she tries to piece together the jigsaw that is her life. While the killers pursue her in this deadly game of cat and mouse, Jane Doe is not only traveling through the hallways of this decrepit building, but through the poorly lit passages and corridors of her mind. With the help of the trapped skeletal crew, including Weismann - whose feelings for his patient have bubbled to the surface - Jane discovers she also has a particular gift herself: she can kill. Racing against time, Jane searches for the key to who she really is. The question remains: will she like what she finds?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?013085</url></doc>
