<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="013558">
  <docid>013558</docid>
  <title>A Morning in Venice</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Jacobs, Wayne</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Reality-TV</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>venice</keyword>
    <keyword>virtual-reality</keyword>
    <keyword>walk</keyword>
    <keyword>reality</keyword>
    <keyword>italy</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">G</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">15 July 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">38</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Jacobs, Wayne</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Jacobs, Kathryn</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Jacobs, Kathryn</writer>
    <writer>Jacobs, Wayne</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>The first half of the 30 minute walk begins as Venice comes to life in the early morning. The streets are virtually empty aside from the occasional delivery cart wheeling by. As you walk the narrow twisting passageways, you can almost smell the cappuccino and taste the freshly-baked pastries as vendors open their shops. The blue haze slowly gives way to a bright morning sun as you travel with people on their way to work. The first half of your early April morning walk ends as you arrive in historic St. Mark's Square, called by Napoleon, "The finest drawing room in Europe." The second half of your 30 minute walk lets you experience a late morning stroll to the beautiful Ponte Storto and on to the Castello district of Venice. Along the way, you will pass gondoliers in their traditional garb awaiting passengers, sidewalk cafes preparing for luncheon, people chatting and visiting in open squares, fruit and vegetable street markets, and sun-dappled canals. You will follow an elderly Italian gentleman out for a hand-in-hand stroll with his little grandson. You'll also enjoy watching fashionably-dressed Venetian women strolling past upscale shops along the way. Your walk ends as a church bell tolls noontime. An 8 minute mini-documentary on Venice is also included as a separate chapter.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?013558</url></doc>
