<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="014110">
  <docid>014110</docid>
  <title>A Non-Issue?</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>punctuation-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>question-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>same-sex-marriage</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Mishory, Matthew</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Singletary, Edward</producer>
    <producer>Einheuser, Michael</producer>
    <producer>Mishory, Matthew</producer>
    <producer>Zimmer Jr., Robert</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Corvino, John</writer>
    <writer>Mishory, Matthew</writer>
    <writer>Zimmer Jr., Robert</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Corvino, John</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The rebirth of the gay rights movement and the battle over legalizing same-sex marriage will be the focus of this compelling new documentary. In November 2008, philosopher, lecturer, and columnist Dr. John Corvino watched as American voters overwhelmingly elected their first African-American president - while simultaneously denying basic civil rights to same-sex couples in three states, including normally progressive California, via the now-infamous Proposition 8, which revoked marriage equality rights awarded by the state Supreme Court. Existing illusions that 2008 America is a "post-gay" society, that sexual orientation is a "non-issue," that the culture war is over - were immediately vanquished. This documentary will follow Dr. John Corvino, a philosopher, lecturer and author of "The Gay Moralist," as he crisscrosses the nation engaging and debating those who believe gays should be denied basic civil liberties, illustrating his viewpoints with compelling personal stories of ordinary gay Americans. Since the early 1990s, Corvino has educated and entertained professional organizations, government contractors, churches, and hundreds of college and university audiences and been a guest on MSNBC's "Scarborough Country" and on numerous radio programs.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?014110</url></doc>
