<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="016264">
  <docid>016264</docid>
  <title>A Soldier's Winnings</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Daniels, Brandon</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">30 March 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Joy, Anthony</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Dolan, John (X)</producer>
    <producer>Joy, Anthony</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Joy, Anthony</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Treece, Steve</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bebber, Michelle</actor>
      <role>Heather</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kristy, Beverly</actor>
      <role>Steve's Mother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Passmore, Aaron</actor>
      <role>Marty</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Slivka, Adam</actor>
      <role>Jeff</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tatalovich, Nick</actor>
      <role>Steve</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Two young friends, Marty and Jeff, are playing a game when Heather (Marty's girlfriend) enters and informs them that their friend Steve, serving in a war, was recently killed. The friends, distraught and saddened, and searching for solitude, soon find Steve very much alive - knocking at the door explaining how he had not been killed. In addition, Steve tells his friends that he has a multi-million dollar winning lottery ticket which he received in a care package from Marty. After an attempt to persuade Steve for a "finder's fee," his friends plot a scheme to kill him and take the winning ticket. A botched attempt soon finds Marty and his best friend Jeff arguing over the best way to hide the body. Soon, the friends have to go to Steve's funeral in an attempt to make everything appear normal. After several unsuccessful attempts at hiding the body, the friends find themselves in more trouble than they predicted. As Steve's family is getting closer to the secret that he had not died in the war, Marty and his girlfriend Heather find themselves in a situation that is beyond their control.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?016264</url></doc>
