<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="017204">
  <docid>017204</docid>
  <title>A Tight Spot</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Muhammad, Ray</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">20 June 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">12</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Muhammad, Ray</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Cooper, Owen</producer>
    <producer>Muhammad, Ray</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Muhammad, Ray</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jones, Erickka</actor>
      <role>Tanya</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maasi, Khalil</actor>
      <role>Tony</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Robinson, Jared (I)</actor>
      <role>Todd</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Ten Minutes. One Room. A Husband. His Wife. Her Lover. A Gun. The films opens with quick flashes of a young couple making love intercut with the photos of a young husband and wife. Neither participant can be seen clearly, but we see enough of the woman to realize that she is the same woman in the pictures. When they are done, the woman, Tanya, collapses contentedly on the chest of her lover who we can plainly see is not the groom in the photos. Basking in the afterglow of intense love making and wanting the afternoon to last, Tanya offers to make lunch for her companion who declines; He says that he has some business to take care of. This upsets Tanya whose elated attitude changes from enthusiasm to dissapointment. The young man, Tony, quickly allays her fears by reassuring her that she is not "just a piece of ass" for him and that he really does love her. He asks her to be "a little more patient" until he can take her away. Once she is placated, he abruptly excuses himself to go to the bathroom. As he exits, Tanya calls after him telling him that she loves him as well. He leaves. Tanya waits, happily dressing herself in his shirt as she reminices about their union before. We hear the sound of a car driving up and the jingle jangle of house keys entering and disturbing a door. As Tony returns to the bedroom he is greeted by a frightened Tanya and a new arrival. Her husband Todd who is brandishing a gun. Todd politely invites Tony in the room and even offers him a drink from the small flask he was carrying. He taunts the terrified pair who have no idea what his intentions are...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?017204</url></doc>
