<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="017479">
  <docid>017479</docid>
  <title>A Tribute to the Wizard of Oz</title>
  <year>1999</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Hooke, William</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>caribbean</keyword>
    <keyword>scarecrow</keyword>
    <keyword>prosthetic-body-part</keyword>
    <keyword>oz</keyword>
    <keyword>makeup</keyword>
    <keyword>garland</keyword>
    <keyword>pirate</keyword>
    <keyword>tin-man</keyword>
    <keyword>special-effects</keyword>
    <keyword>wizard</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">27 May 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Essman, Scott</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Essman, Scott</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Essman, Scott</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>O'Halloran, Brian (II)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ashe Jr., Robert</actor>
      <role>Winkie Guard</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ashe, Rob</actor>
      <role>Winkie Guard</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Baker, Rick (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Castagnaro, Jeanne</actor>
      <role>Dorothy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>DeShan, Ken</actor>
      <role>Scarecrow</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Griffo, Joseph S.</actor>
      <role>Flying Monkey</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harnell, Jess</actor>
      <role>Lion</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maren, Jerry</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stilwell, Robert (I)</actor>
      <role>Tin Man</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Underwood, Ron (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A tribute to the characters and makeup artists from the Wizard of Oz, as performed and created by some of the top makeup people in Hollywood. On September 12, 1998, a group of top makeup artists gathered in Studio City, CA, to pay tribute to Jack Dawn and his team from the seminal 1939 classic, The Wizard of Oz. In addition to appearances by makeup stalwart Rick Baker and feature film director Ron Underwood, the celebration was enhanced with an impromptu performance by "lollipop guild" Munchkin Jerry Maren, who was only 18 when he acted in the original Oz. Howard Smit, who was a Munchkin and Winkie Guard makeup artist on the film, spoke eloquently about Charlie Schram, a key makeup artist on Dawn's team, responsible for many makeups on the film, including the Cowardly Lion. Undoubtedly, the biggest treat of the tribute was the recreation of seven characters from the film, realized in stunning detail by a ?dream team? of artists led by makeup department head Bill Corso. In fact, Corso's friend and voice-over actor Jess Harnell initiated the tribute with his enthusiasm for a local stage performance as the Cowardly Lion earlier in the summer of 1998. Corso had created his costume and makeup for the stage performance, further enhanced for the tribute. Additionally, Corso oversaw the new fabrication of makeups for the Scarecrow, played by Ken DeShan, the Tin Man, Bob Stilwell, and Dorothy, Jeanne Castagnaro, with their makeup applied by Kenny Myers, Kevin Haney, and Deborah Patino, respectively. Matthew Mungle donated prosthetics for the Wicked Witch, Denise Moses, applied by Ve Neill, and for the Flying Monkey, Joe Griffo, applied by Richard Snell. Todd Tucker created a Winkie Guard on actor Rob Ashe, whose elaborate costume was built from scratch by Jennifer McManus. Myers' wife, Karen, provided the detailed wigs and hairpieces for all. Though the tribute was only performed once, Warner Bros. Pictures hired the five primary characters to appear at historic Mann?s Chinese Theater on Hollywood Boulevard for an appearance commemorating the 60th anniversary re-release of the film for a new generation of audiences. 3,000 people lined the street for a glimpse of the recreations, again created by Corso and five of his team, all of whom next worked on the feature film, "Dr. Seuss's How the Grinch Stole Christmas."</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?017479</url></doc>
