<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="018266">
  <docid>018266</docid>
  <title>A Wild Beetle Chase</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Jackson, Sarah Anne</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>montana</keyword>
    <keyword>science</keyword>
    <keyword>research</keyword>
    <keyword>italy</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">6 October 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">13</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Jackson, Sarah Anne</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Jackson, Sarah Anne</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Jackson, Sarah Anne</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Even if everything seems impossible, if you do a good job trying, you're bound to find something. The National Science Foundation is currently trying to make the most complete family tree for all life on earth. Since beetles make up at least a fourth of all described animal species, the Beetle Tree of Life Project is extremely important to the overall effort. Dr. Micheal A. Ivie takes a collecting trip to Italy to look for one beetle that could explain a great deal about early beetle evolution. Unfortunately, there's a catch: this beetle has only ever been collected once by one person in one hole about thirty years ago, and to make matters worse, the beetle is only about one millimeter long. Scientific research, always presented as striving to solve huge problems using only the most logical and technical methods, is turned on its head to reveal the reality where methods are bizarre and failure is not only common, but just another step in the process.. Bucket after bucket of soil is dug out of the Italian countryside to be painstakingly sifted, all in effort to find something about the same size as each grain of sand. Dream sequences, animation, and stock footage help to delve deeper into the passion and obsession that drives this impossible task of science. What if he doesn't find it? Was it still worth trying?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?018266</url></doc>
