<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="019704">
  <docid>019704</docid>
  <title>A.S.K.</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Dekker, Stacie</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Mystery</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">16</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Rajan, Sriram</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Sriram, Anusha</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Rajan, Sriram</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Smiley, Jayson</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Coleman, Joher</actor>
      <role>Gopal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Guerrero, Doris L.</actor>
      <role>Catalina</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jimenez, Jesse</actor>
      <role>Miguel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kinsly, Kelsa</actor>
      <role>Amy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>LaTitia-DeLaine</actor>
      <role>Martha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maloney, Tim (III)</actor>
      <role>Chester</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tobin, Randy</actor>
      <role>Rick</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zderko, John</actor>
      <role>Shane</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A.S.K. is the story of four individuals from different strata of society, all leading their own versions of everyday lives, each with problems that are common among normal people. Rick is a pencil sketch artist who feels his creativity stymied in a relationship with his girlfriend, Martha. Catalina is a frustrated single mother to Miguel, who blames men in general for the misery in her life, and all around. Kavita is married to a successful man, with everything at her disposal, except the pleasure of bearing a child. And lastly, Shane is a former finance executive, who finds himself homeless and on the street because of a series of wrong choices. One thing is common to all four - each has decided to vent out their life's anger and frustrations in their own unique, creative ways, and that's why they have been selected from a number of nationwide applicants to take part in an elite, secret competition. They are oriented to the rules of the competition at an unlikely location by the mysterious Chester, with a preacher's passion but a conman's guile. Who is Chester? What is this secretive competition? And what is the common passion that ties these four disparate people together?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?019704</url></doc>
