<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="019901">
  <docid>019901</docid>
  <title>ADAM &amp; the Allegory of the Forest</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Charles, David (XIV)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">10</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Halsey, Ryan Alan</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Endler, Sebastian</producer>
    <producer>Marin, Alejandro Montoya</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Halsey, Ryan Alan</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Doty Jr., John</actor>
      <role>German Soldier</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Enberg, Kirsi</actor>
      <role>Aniela</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Martel, Simon</actor>
      <role>Adam</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Adam Traugott is a German officer, who in 1945 chooses to desert the German military and the 2nd World War. After weeks of journeying through a foreign wilderness, Adam finds he must revert to a more primal existence in order to survive. He tries to catch a small animal by making a primitive trap. He baits the trap with the last of his rations (rations that he scavenged off another dead soldier), but fails to catch anything. He tries to make a fire using anything he can, but again fails in his attempts. All Adam has to comfort him is a damaged field radio, which he also scavenged. Despite numerous attempts to reach anyone for help, his desperate pleas go unanswered. However, one night Adam is awoken by the radio and upon turning it off he hears voices emanating from a distance. He recognizes them as German soldiers and flees for his life. Adam comes across an old decrepit barn, and in desperation seeks shelter from the approaching soldiers. There he unexpectedly encounters Aniela, a farm wife left to tend the household while her husband and sons are off fighting the in war. Both dare not make a sound as they hear the rogue soldiers scouting around outside....</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?019901</url></doc>
