<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="019945">
  <docid>019945</docid>
  <title>AIDS Inc.</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Calhoun, Rodney</editor>
    <editor>Marconi, Roland</editor>
    <editor>Perla, Susan</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>western-blot-test</keyword>
    <keyword>doctor</keyword>
    <keyword>acronym-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>hiv-test</keyword>
    <keyword>syphilis</keyword>
    <keyword>kary-mullis</keyword>
    <keyword>gay</keyword>
    <keyword>immune-disorder</keyword>
    <keyword>period-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>transfusion</keyword>
    <keyword>group-sex</keyword>
    <keyword>azt</keyword>
    <keyword>homosexual</keyword>
    <keyword>aids</keyword>
    <keyword>robert-gallo</keyword>
    <keyword>hiv-positive</keyword>
    <keyword>richard-polonetsky</keyword>
    <keyword>medication</keyword>
    <keyword>hiv</keyword>
    <keyword>hiv-aids</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">5 April 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">120</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Null, Gary</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Calhoun, Rodney</producer>
    <producer>Goldman, Melissa</producer>
    <producer>Polonetsky, Richard</producer>
    <producer>Shagawat, Jennifer</producer>
    <producer>Spratt, Rachel (II)</producer>
    <producer>Null, Gary</producer>
    <producer>Barbosa, Jenny</producer>
    <producer>Castaneda, Maria</producer>
    <producer>Enstorm, Lynn</producer>
    <producer>Lewis, Petrena</producer>
    <producer>Marconi, Roland</producer>
    <producer>Van Cleve, Valerie (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Null, Gary</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Duesberg, Peter</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gallo, Dr. Robert</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mullis, Kary B.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Null, Gary</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rasnick, David</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>AIDS, Inc. is a film about the multi-billion dollar AIDS industry, and how it profits from continuing fears and misconceptions about the disease. While AIDS grabs the headlines and raises billions of dollars with celebrity endorsements and billionaire endowments, we are no closer to finding a cure than when the scourge first appeared 30 years ago. Could it be that after so many years of research, and so much money being spent, that the entire orthodox medical establishment has been wrong about AIDS, or even worse, has sought to profit on a system that it knew was flawed from the beginning? Doctor Robert Gallo who discovered the HIV virus said that there is no legitimate dissent when it comes to AIDS. But there are more than 5,000 physicians, microbiologists, journalists and activists who disagree and say that we have been misled about the real causes of AIDS and the nature of its treatment. The mainstream media has chosen not to provide an outlet for their opinions. In this important film, documentary filmmaker and health expert Gary Null, traveled to more than 30 countries over an eight year period to seek them out and get their interviews. This is the first film on AIDS that brings the most compelling of their arguments together in one place. Dr. Null blows the lid off the wealthy AIDS industry and shows how greed and corruption have prevented any real progress in fighting the epidemic or its underlying causes. The film challenges the entrenched notion that AIDS or HIV is an African monkey virus that is spread sexually and can be "treated" with harmful drugs. Instead, the film considers the common underlying conditions of the epidemic, such as malnutrition, unclean water, poverty, illness, and poor lifestyle choices. The evidence is damning, and a clarion call to the public that the AIDS Industrial Complex is on the wrong track and has become a spending juggernaut completely out of control.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?019945</url></doc>
