<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="020019">
  <docid>020019</docid>
  <title>AMC Live: The Hollywood Auction</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <producers>
    <producer>Auerbach, Rolfe</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bruneau, Sharon</actor>
      <role>Herself - Presenter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Burke, John (X)</actor>
      <role>Host</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>AMC Classic Movie Cable Network And Internet Auction To Host Online/TV Combo Auction Featuring Hollywood's Leading Men AMC and AMCtv.com will host its first-ever, interactive on-air, online auction honoring America's favorite sport. The auction features exciting and authentic memorabilia, including signed baseballs from early Hall of Famers Babe Ruth, Lou Gehrig and Mickey Mantle to more contemporary icons Cal Ripken and Derek Jeter. Several rare signed photographs from baseball legends Ted Williams, Mickey Mantle, THE NATURAL star Robert Redford, an original wire photograph of Marilyn Monroe and Joe DiMaggio, The Cowardly Lion costume worn by Bert Lahr in "The Wizard of Oz.", Charlie Chaplin's cane from the 1914 film "The Masquerader.", Lunch for 10 on the yacht "Wild Goose," once owned by John Wayne and Elvis Presley's suit from "It Happened at the World's Fair" (1963). On Friday, November 30, during breaks in AMC's 8:00 PM (ET) airing of THE NATURAL (1984), host John Burke and presenter Sharon Bruneau will share some of the excitement generated by a live auction featuring auctioneer, Tere Morris, of hot collectibles while tempting baseball enthusiasts with close-ups on some of the most high-profile auction items. Knowledgeable guests, including memorabilia expert Elyse Luray Marx, appraiser Simeon Lipman of Mastro Fine Sports Auctions, and sports personalities will offer insight and context on the auction items. Included in the auction is memorabilia from THE NATURAL. An original one-sheet movie poster from the film and autographed photos from stars Robert Redford, Glenn Close and Kim Basinger are accompanied with a letter of authenticity from Gotta Have It!, one of the leading baseball memorabilia companies, as do all of the auction items. This event is AMC's first-ever multi-platform interstitial auction. A special link will be available on amctv.com on November 30 for direct access to the live bidding. Users can view a complete catalog of auction lots on the site beginning Saturday, November 17. Amctv.com is AMC's complementary interactive destination website, powered by the exclusive AMC Web surfers bidding online for the belongings and memorabilia of Hollywood's leading men will have their choice of objects owned by Charlie Chaplin, John Wayne and Elvis. Free White Paper: A New Approach to Payment Security (PCI) Based on his work with Internet 500 and Fortune 1000 companies, e-payment expert Dave Glaser reveals a totally new approach to payment security and centralized payment management. Includes a blueprint for centralizing payment management. It is not likely that the founders of the Internet ever imagined all their hard work would lead to an online bidding war for bullet casings from the set of "Mission Impossible 2." However, thanks to a live TV and Internet auction being put on by cable channel American Movie Classics (AMC) and Ibidlive on July 12th, that is exactly what's happening. The auction will carry a wide range of movie memorabilia from some of Hollywood's leading men and will be broadcast live from Los Angeles on AMC. Web surfers will be able to bid in real time via the Net. When a bid is entered online, it is picked up almost instantly by an "auction attendant" who is live at the event and sends up the bid, just as is traditionally done with phone auctions, Ibidlive said. Mixed Results For instance, an auction of Marilyn Monroe memorabilia at eBay (Nasdaq: EBAY) in March ended with mixed results. A silk-and-chiffon gown worn in the movie "The Prince and the Showgirl" and a handwritten note on Monroe's reasons for seeking a divorce from her first husband, Jim Dougherty, went for US$23,375 and nearly $3,000, respectively. However, a set of nude photographs of the movie star failed to sell, reportedly because none of the five bids received met the undisclosed minimum price set by the seller, Tom Kelley, Jr. In September 2000, however, William Doyle Galleries broadcast its sale of late actor James Cagney's collection on Ibidlive and Pax TV. That sale brought in $480,671, with a quarter of the lots selling to online bidders.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?020019</url></doc>
