<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="020351">
  <docid>020351</docid>
  <title>Aaj Ka Laawaris</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Suresh, Sai</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Telugu</language>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Arjun (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Qureshi, Mohammed Imran</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Iman (III)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arjun (II)</actor>
      <role>Kashi 'Madrasi'</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Babu, Jagapathi</actor>
      <role>Shiva</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gajala</actor>
      <role>Meena</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Vija</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vivekanathan</actor>
      <role>Pandey</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Kashi lives a middle-class lifestyle with his mom and dad. When his honest father refuses to change his testimony in order to accommodate some gangsters, they kill him and then his mother. A traumatized Kashi grows up and takes up crime as a career, is arrested and lands in Allahabad Jail. This is where he meets and befriends another convict, Shiva. The second time both men meet is at a restaurant in Mumbai where Shiva is in the company of his wife, Meena, and Kashi is with his fiancée, Anjali. Kashi has never forgotten his parents' assailants, and has already found and killed two of them. He does locate the third killer and guns him down. Quite unknown to both men, they work for rival underworld dons and estranged brothers, Mani and Ravi Verma. And the third time the two men will meet will be at the behest of Shiva - who has an unusual mission for Kashi. The question remains will Kashi meet with Shiva, and even he if dares, will he commit himself to this mission - knowing fully well that it may be a devious plot to ensnare and then kill him.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?020351</url></doc>
