<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="020469">
  <docid>020469</docid>
  <title>Aan</title>
  <year>1952</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kadri, Shamsudin</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Musical</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Sweden">15</certificate>
    <certificate country="India">U</certificate>
    <certificate country="Finland">K-16</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Sweden">30 January 1954</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Japan">January 1954</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Spain">9 November 1953</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Finland">23 April 1954</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">1956</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="France">26 March 1954</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Denmark">11 October 1954</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Japan">88</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="default">161</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="USA">101</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="France">105</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Khan, Mehboob (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Khan, Mehboob (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Choudhury, R.S.</writer>
    <writer>Raza, S. Ali</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Naushad (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Abdul (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Banu, Amir</actor>
      <role>Jai's mom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cuckoo</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Dilip (I)</actor>
      <role>Jai Tilak</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maya (III)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Miraz, Agha</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mukri</actor>
      <role>Chandan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Murad</actor>
      <role>Emperor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nath, Prem (I)</actor>
      <role>Prince Shamsher Singh</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A Royal Indian family consists of the Emperor Maharaj (Murad, his brother Shamsher Singh (Premnath) and sister Rajshree (Nadira). A poor villager named Jai Tilak (Dilip Kumar) enters a contest to tame Princess Rajshree's horse and after he is successful Shamsher challenges him to a game of fencing. Jai is declared the winner of the fight after much dispute and Shamsher is enraged at losing to a poor villager. Jai then falls in love with Rajshree and tries numurous times to woo her but the princess's arrogance prevents her from revealing her true feelings. Shamsher becomes even more enraged when the Emperor Maharaj reveals that Shamsher is not the heir to his throne after his death and that he plans to free India from dictation and turn to democracy. Shamsher then plans to gain control of the kingdom by killing the Maharajah on the night before he is due to travel to England for a medical procedure. However he is unsuccessful after the Maharajah escapes an attempt on his life by Shamsher's henchmen and disguises himself as a servant in his own palace. Shamsher then sets his eyes on Mangala (Nimmi) who is a village girl and childhood friend of Jai but her love is not reciprocated as he is only in love with princess Rajshree. After Mangala is kidnapped by Shamsher Singh who plans to keep her prisoner in his palace and molest her, Mangala takes a bottle of poison and dies. Jai kills Shamsher in revenge and provokes Princess Rajshree to launch an attack on his village to avenge her brother's death. Jai manages to kidnap Rajshree and sets out to gain her love by taking her into his village and forcing her to live as a peasant girl. Just when Rajshree begins to realise her feelings for Jai, Shamsher Singh who was presumed dead returns to get his revenge against Jai. What will happen to Jai and Rajshree? and Will Shamsher gain control of the Kingdom?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?020469</url></doc>
