<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="020577">
  <docid>020577</docid>
  <title>Aar Paar</title>
  <year>1985</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
    <language>Bengali</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Samanta, Shakti</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Samanta, Shakti</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Burman, Rahul Dev</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chakraborty, Mithun</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dutt, Manik</actor>
      <role>Jatin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dutt, Utpal</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ghosh, Maya</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ghosh, Tarun</actor>
      <role>Padla</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sen, Asit (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Ghanshyam alias Gania lives with his mom, and dad, Bhuvan, in a small fishing town of Raipur. He uses a ferry boat that he has leased from Mahesh Manna, to fish, sell fish to Mahesh, and use his earnings to buy the ferry in installments. Mahesh is greedy, lecherous, and crooked and when Ghanshyam finds out that he has been swindled, he takes his business elsewhere to another businessman named Mohammad Bassiruddin. Ghanshyam is in love with Kamli, the daughter of alcoholic, Basan, and would like to marry her. Mahesh also has his eyes on Kamli. Then one day both men are with an unconscious Kamli when the Daroga enters the room. Mahesh swears that he saw Ghanshyam molest Kamli, as a result Ghanshyam is arrested and held in a cell. It is in jail he is told that his father has been killed. When Kamli regains her senses, she goes to the police station and gives a statement that Ghanshyam did indeed molest her. A shocked Ghanshyam escapes from jail in order to find out why Kamli gave a statement against him, as well as find out who killed his father.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?020577</url></doc>
