<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="020692">
  <docid>020692</docid>
  <title>Aashique Mastane</title>
  <year>1995</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Kashyap, Ajay</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bokadia, M.C.</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Sen, Dilip</composer>
    <composer>Sen, Sameer</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Alagh, Maya</actor>
      <role>Kajal's mom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anand, Vikas</actor>
      <role>Police Inspector</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bahl, Mohnish</actor>
      <role>Sunny</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Banerjee, Beena</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Hari Prasad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bedi, Monica</actor>
      <role>Kajal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chopra, Prem</actor>
      <role>Retd. Major Prem Singh Ahluwalia/Police Commissioner Jodha Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harish (I)</actor>
      <role>Sohan/Rohan (dual role)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jhulka, Ayesha</actor>
      <role>Malti</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Abhishek</actor>
      <role>Mohan H Prasad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khote, Viju</actor>
      <role>Thele</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Murad, Raza</actor>
      <role>Hari Prasad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Packard, Gavin</actor>
      <role>Gavin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Talsania, Tiku</actor>
      <role>Achanak Singh</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Hari Prasad is a businessman and lives a wealthy lifestyle with his wife and son, Mohan. He finds out that Mohan has been a slacker, not interested in studies, nor in their business, so he decides to send him to retired Major Prem Singh Ahluwalia in scenic Kulu Manali to learn some discipline and get some work experience. Mohan reluctantly agrees to do so, and without asking his parents asks his friend, Sohan, to not only accompany him, but also impersonate him so that he can have some fun. Sohan agrees to become Mohan, meets with Prem and his attractive daughter, Malti, and both fall in love with each other. Prem is a very stern man who has hired look-alikes of Mithun Chakraborty, Rajnikanth, and Amitabh Bachchan on his farm. Sohan meets with Kajal, who lives with her widowed mother, and believing him to be of a poor family, hires him as her chauffeur, eventually both fall in love with each other. Then their lives are turned upside down when a woman named Esha is killed, and the police arrest the real Mohan for this crime, and hold him in a cell. When Sohan finds out, he goes to the police and admits killing Esha. The question remains, why was Mohan arrested, and why does Sohan have also to admit in this killing, or where both the impersonators involved in her killing?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?020692</url></doc>
