<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="020705">
  <docid>020705</docid>
  <title>Aasoo Bane Angaarey</title>
  <year>1993</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <genres>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Kumar, Mehul</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kudalkar, Laxmikant Shantaram</composer>
    <composer>Roshan, Rajesh</composer>
    <composer>Sharma, Pyarelal Ramprasad</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bindu (I)</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Durgadevi Verma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chopra, Prem</actor>
      <role>Sewakram</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dixit, Madhuri</actor>
      <role>Usha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Helen (I)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Irani, Aruna</actor>
      <role>Radha Verma/Mrs. Shyamsunder</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jeetendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Ravi Verma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kher, Anupam</actor>
      <role>Shyamsunder (Radha's husband)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Anoop</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Ashok (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lever, Johnny</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maruti, Guddi</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mehra, Raj</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mukherjee, Deb</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Oberoi, Suresh</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tijori, Deepak</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>After the death of his wife, wealthy Mr. Verma re-marries Durgadevi, so that she can look after his son, Ravi. Subsequently, Durga also gets pregnant and gives birth a Kiran. After a few years, Mr. Verma passes away, Durga decides to enter into politics with the Janata Sangruti Party and soon becomes the party president with the help of Sewakram. Years later both Ravi and Kiran have grown up. Ravi, who is the Managing Director of his firm, wants to marry a typist by the name of Usha, but this does not auger well with Durga, who wants him to marry someone who is equally wealthy. Then Ravi gets a surprise when Durga changes her mind and agrees to Ravi and Usha's marriage, which is performed with great pomp and ceremony. After the marriage, Durga stands for election and wins, and is elected the state's Chief Minister. Kiran tells his mother that he has had an affair with Usha before she married Ravi. A shocked Durga decides that Usha is not who she claims to be, and asks Ravi to travel abroad so she can deal with this situation. When Ravi comes to bid a pregnant Usha good-bye, he does not know that this may the last time he may see her alive, and Usha does not know what fate awaits her at the hands of Durgadevi, Kiran, and Sewakram.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?020705</url></doc>
