<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="020784">
  <docid>020784</docid>
  <title>Ab Insaf Hoga</title>
  <year>1995</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Shah, Harish</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Shah, Vinod (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Chitragupth, Anand</composer>
    <composer>Chitragupth, Milind</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anand, Vikas</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chaddha, Sahila</actor>
      <role>Sabina B. Khan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chakraborty, Mithun</actor>
      <role>Gaurishankar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chopra, Prem</actor>
      <role>Girdharilal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deshpande, Deepika</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deshpande, Sulabha</actor>
      <role>Kashibai</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hattangadi, Rohini</actor>
      <role>Judge</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Inamdar, Shafi</actor>
      <role>Ashok Mishra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jain, T.P.</actor>
      <role>Sabina's dad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kaushal, Ashwini</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Javed (I)</actor>
      <role>Ashok's friend</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mohan, Ram (I)</actor>
      <role>Bhervi Prasad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Murad, Raza</actor>
      <role>Kalicharan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Parvez, Yunus</actor>
      <role>Bashir Khan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Patel, Harish (I)</actor>
      <role>Bansi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rohera, Ghanshyam</actor>
      <role>Manglu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sahni, Parikshat</actor>
      <role>Inspector Khan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shaikh, Farooq (I)</actor>
      <role>Ramcharan</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Janki lives a poor lifestyle in a small village consisting of her dad, Bhervi Prasad and her mom. She meets and falls in love with her school-teacher, Ramcharan, and both want to get married. Ramcharan's brother is opposed to this marriage as Bhervi is unable to pay any dowry, nevertheless the marriage does take place, but the couple are turned out of Kalicharan's house, and instead go to live with Ramcharan's friend, Ashok Mishra. Ashok attempts to molest Janki, and a fight breaks out between Ramsharan and Ashok, and they move back to Janki's village where she finds that her parents have killed themselves. They decide to live in the village where Janki gives birth to a baby, Khusboo. Ramcharan is then assaulted by Ashok and receives a head injury that leaves him paralyzed. Janki takes him to Bombay, finds a job as a laborer, and takes Ramcharan to see a doctor. The doctor informs her that he must be treated immediately, however, it will cost her a lot of money. She approaches her employer, Girdharilal, who is willing to pay the entire cost of her husband's treatment provided she sleeps with him, when she refuses, she does not get any money and is instead molested. Ramcharan does recover a little, and goes to confront Girdharilal, but gets killed. The police refuse to register any complaint against Girdharilal. Alone, traumatized, and devastated Janki and Khusboo wander aimlessly. She gets into an accident with a car that belongs to Gaurishankar, a local gangster with a good heart, who wants to be a Muncipal Councillor. With Janki's help he does become a Councillor and both entrap Girdharilal, and then subsequently Ashok and Kalicharan, get them arrested on a variety of criminal charges and jailed. What Janki and Gaurishankar do not know is that the trio have gotten together in prison and have planned a devious scheme that will ensure that Janki gets killed - without implicating any one of them.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?020784</url></doc>
