<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="020759">
  <docid>020759</docid>
  <title>Aaya Toofan</title>
  <year>1964</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Hussain, Mohammed (I)</director>
    <director>Kapoor, Kedar</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kudalkar, Laxmikant Shantaram</composer>
    <composer>Sharma, Pyarelal Ramprasad</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Helen (I)</actor>
      <role>Rajkumari Chanda</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hussain, Anwar (I)</actor>
      <role>Raja Naagsen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rao, Maruti (II)</actor>
      <role>Mallu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Singh, Dara (I)</actor>
      <role>Deepu</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>After his father is killed by a bandit by the name of Bharat of Chandravan, Naagsen is crowned King, and he rules his kingdom along with his wife, Rani Kundala, and sister, Rajkumari Chanda. Naagsen is not satiated with Kundala, and has an affair with Dancer, Kala, who he houses in a palace of her own. When the King of Kamroo, who is also a magician, abducts Chanda, she is rescued by a brave warrior, Deepu, who asks Naagsen for her hand in marriage. Naagsen is displeased and asks for the bloodline of Deepu, and when he finds out that Deepu is the son of Bharat, he has him arrested and placed in the dungeon. But Chanda helps him escape as both have fallen in love with each other. Naagsen hatches a scheme with Kala, and as a result, Deepu is lured back into the palace, arrested, and jailed. Deepu's friend, Mallu, a snake charmer, manages to free Deepu, only to have him re-captured, jailed, blinded, and he, along with Chanda, banished from the kingdom. A Princess with no livelihood skills, and a blind man are not likely to survive very long - especially with the odds stacked very high against them.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?020759</url></doc>
