<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="020726">
  <docid>020726</docid>
  <title>Aatish</title>
  <year>1979</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">23 February 1979</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Sangal, Ambrish</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kumar, Mohan (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Jain, Ravindra</composer>
    <composer>Verma, Jaidev</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Begum, Mumtaz</actor>
      <role>Shanno's mom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhardwaj, Brahm</actor>
      <role>Rai's lawyer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Birbal</actor>
      <role>Gambler</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Das, Leena</actor>
      <role>Dancer/Singer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jeetendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Anand</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Dheeraj (I)</actor>
      <role>Rakesh Rai</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Sujit (I)</actor>
      <role>Khan (Bank Manager)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mukri</actor>
      <role>Diwan Chotelal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, Madan (I)</actor>
      <role>Girdhari</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rinku (I)</actor>
      <role>Ashu Rai</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shivpuri, Om</actor>
      <role>Rai</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shrestha, Raju</actor>
      <role>Raju Rai</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Mr. Rai is a wealthy businessman in Jammu, India, and lives in a palatial house with his wife, Shobha, a wheelchair-bound daughter, Ashu, a grown son, Rakesh, and a school-going son, Raju. His son despises him and is waiting him for to die, so that he can inherit all the wealth and spend it on dancing girls, alcohol, and gamblers. One day while Rai was returning from the Jammu &amp; Kashmir Bank with a suitcase full of cash, he is attacked by bandits, but is rescued by a young man named Anand. Anand is injured in this attack and is nursed by Shobha and the rest of the Rai family. Rai himself trusts Anand and initially appoints him as a Chief Supervisor, very much to the chagrin of Rakesh, who attempts, in vain, to implicate Anand in the theft of 2 Lakh Rupees. Anand uses fisticuffs to convince a hoodlum named Girdhari to let go of Rai's property. These incidents provoke Rai to ask Rakesh to leave the house, and promote Anand as the Manager. What the Rai family do not know is that Anand actually works for Girdhari and enacted this charade just to get in the good books of the Rai family - his motive to steal a golden statue of a Hindu Deity. The question that still remains unanswered is will Anand succeed in his nefarious mission?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?020726</url></doc>
