<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="021360">
  <docid>021360</docid>
  <title>Abodh</title>
  <year>1984</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">10 August 1984</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Nag, Hiren</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Barjatya, Tarachand</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Jain, Ravindra</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Choti, Mohan</actor>
      <role>Photographer at Fair</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>David, Sheela</actor>
      <role>Ratna G. Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dixit, Madhuri</actor>
      <role>Gauri Girdhari Singh/Gauri Shankar Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hingoo, Dinesh</actor>
      <role>Wedding Photographer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mishra, Leela</actor>
      <role>Gajanan's mom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pal, Tapas</actor>
      <role>Shankar Gajanan Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Purohit, Sunder</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Saraf, Ashok</actor>
      <role>Hanuman (Shankar's friend)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sharma, Vinod (I)</actor>
      <role>Gajanan Singh</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Naive, childish and precocious, Gauri lives a wealthy lifestyle in a small town called Rajanpur in India, along with her sister, Ratna; her mom; and dad, Girdhari Singh. While at the fair, she gets into an argument with a young man named Shankar. Shortly thereafter, Gauri is told that her marriage has been arranged. At first Gauri is thrilled at getting married, but changes her mind when she finds out that her groom is Shankar, but reconciles herself to this marriage. After she re-locates to Shankar's residence, she prefers to spend more time with Shankar's young brother, rather than her husband. Shankar starts to realize that Gauri has not matured yet and does not understand the real meaning of being married. As a result he is unable to get intimate with her. Gauri soon becomes bored, and re-locates to her parents' house, where she resides for several months. It is here that Gauri matures and realizes the importance of marriage and intimacy. She then returns to Shankar's house, where she is welcomed back - though not quite as warmly enough. Gauri starts to realize that her childishness has resulted in getting the cold shoulder from Shankar - who has decided to stay away from Gauri, and leaves to study in another town. For several months, the family does not get any news about Shankar, prompting Gajanan to take a trip to talk to Shankar. When Gajanan reaches the hostel where Shankar is supposed to live, he is told that Shankar has moved out. The question remains: Where has Shankar moved to, and why did he take this step without informing his family?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?021360</url></doc>
