<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="021729">
  <docid>021729</docid>
  <title>Absolute Evel: The Evel Knievel Story</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>McAllister, Andrew (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>History</genre>
    <genre>Biography</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>motorcycle-daredevil</keyword>
    <keyword>motorcycle-stunt</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">13 June 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">95</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Chan, Matt</producer>
    <producer>Severson, Dave</producer>
    <producer>Dang, Sandy</producer>
    <producer>Ikeda, Alice</producer>
    <producer>Butts, George</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Butts, George</writer>
    <writer>Dang, Sandy</writer>
    <writer>Ikeda, Alice</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fontaine, Ralph</actor>
      <role>Evel Knievel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Golon, Nate</actor>
      <role>Evel Knievel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McConaughey, Matthew</actor>
      <role>Himself - Host</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The definite biography told by the man who lived it himself, Evel Knievel. The undisputed King of the Daredevils. The Last Gladiator. His exploits are legendary and it's unlikely his accomplishments or notoriety will ever be duplicated. He was a self-made sports superstar whose only competitor was Death. And it was a foe he faced regularly throughout his life. No one, including Evel, ever believed he would live to old age. But Knievel has never been a man who did what was expected. Today, as he enters the twilight of his life, he is paying a high price for the life he led. Blood transfusions from his many near death injuries left him with Hepatitis C. In 1999 he had a liver transplant to ward off death once again. While still outspoken and controversial, his health has been fragile since this surgery. Although he is only 66 years old, today he lives in pain from the incredible abuse his body suffered during his days as a daredevil. No one can say for certain just how much longer he can keep death at bay. This interview and documentary may very well be his last chance at a public forum, a final opportunity to set the record straight and share the philosophies that have guided his life. The documentary takes a non-traditional approach as the producers let Evel tell his story himself. With the exception of his son, Robby Knievel, this is a very rare and candid first hand account coming from the man who lived the legend. Evel is extremely candid about his exploits, his loves, his legend and the philosophies that have guided his life. The documentary is also a showcase for never before seen footage of his life and exploits making it, perhaps one of the best documentaries on Evel Knievel.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?021729</url></doc>
