<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="024296">
  <docid>024296</docid>
  <title>Adventures of Texas Jack</title>
  <year>1934</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Western</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">3 March 1934</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">28</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Adamson, Victor</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bare, Richard L.</producer>
    <producer>Adamson, Victor</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Adamson, Victor</writer>
    <writer>Cohen, Bennett (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Adamson, Victor</actor>
      <role>Blister Sanderson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carre, Bartlett A.</actor>
      <role>Sheriff</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Evans, Jack (I)</actor>
      <role>Hank</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lee, Duke R.</actor>
      <role>Colonel Bodie / Steve Parsons</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Taliaferro, Hal</actor>
      <role>Texas Jack</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wilsey, Jay</actor>
      <role>Bill Mayberry</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This is one of 'Victor Adamson' (qv)'s cheap-jack productions that started out to be a 10-episode serial (the second of three instances an Adamson-serial project ended up as a feature) and is filled with stock footage from Adamson silent films, accounting for players here being seen in dual roles. Adamson produced it as Victor Adamson, wrote and directed it as Denver Dixon, and appeared in it as Al Mix, as this was made during the time he and 'Art Mix' (qv) were wrangling over who had the right to the Art Mix screen name (Tom Mix had yet another point of view), even though Victor Adamson was the one who first billed Kesterson as Art Mix, a billing name first used in silents by Adamson. Yes, it is confusing and there are certain research institutes in Hollywood that still haven't figured it out, and are most likely the culprits that dubbed this 1933-filmed,1934-released sound film as a 1925 silent. The story, a misnomer, begins with assuming the audience knows all about Texas Jack ('Wally Wales' (qv)), which they might have if earlier intended scenes had ever been filmed, and his sidekick Blister Sanderson (Victor Adamson as Al Mix), and the plot rambles around in about three directions, none of which make a lot of continuity sense. Richard L. Bare is shown as the Presenter on videos made from 16mm prints sold to television. Ranks as one of the cheapest feature films ever produced, itself quite an accomplishment given the prevailing standards of Gower Gulch.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?024296</url></doc>
