<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="024354">
  <docid>024354</docid>
  <title>Adventuress Wanted</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Sweden</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Unrated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">85</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>McAlevey, Thomas</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Mahar, Molly</producer>
    <producer>McAlevey, Thomas</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>McAlevey, Thomas</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Almkvist, Thomas</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kino, Yoshiko</actor>
      <role>Yoshko</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McAlevey, Thomas</actor>
      <role>Tom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nawale, Mercy</actor>
      <role>Pretty Native Girl</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>An American man and a Japanese woman leave from Sweden in a tiny beach-buggy headed for South Africa. The audience participates vicariously in the practical challenges of the trip and the personal growth and realizations of the couple. We begin in Stockholm following the life of Tom - a successful Western businessman - who decides to recruit a female companion for the ultimate adventure. In the brutal Sahara desert the Buggy literally falls to pieces paralleling graphically the tribulations of Yoshiko and Tom's relationship. In Cairo Tom gets sick and has his appendix removed. While recovering from surgery he and Yoshiko argue and decide to give up the trip; but this is not the end of the adventure... Yoshiko and Tom weather the elements and meet the people. With only one-another to rely on they brave everything from close encounters with lions and elephants to a death-defying illegal entry into Sudan. Yet through the joy and the tears and the mind-boggling physical challenges, Yoshiko and Tom keep the camera rolling. This film is about love and life. It is about heroic efforts in the face of adversity, and noble intentions sometimes gone awry. And it is all set against the majestic and dramatic background that is Africa.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?024354</url></doc>
