<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="025081">
  <docid>025081</docid>
  <title>After Dark; or, the Policeman and His Lantern</title>
  <year>1903</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">18 July 1903</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Smith, George Albert (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Green, Tom (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This is a mixture of fun and pathos. When the picture first bursts into view, the exterior of an English Police Station is seen, from which the squad emerges. A change and then one of the "finest" is seen posing before a great building as though proud of his uniform. Again a change and we see a table on which was placed a dark lantern. Bobby's hand reaches forth and grasps the lantern and we follow him through the famous "White Chapel" district of which we have heard so much. All that is seen are the rays of light from the lantern and the object at which they are pointed. We see a high board fence on which a number of advertisements appear and the rays move along until "Bobby's" best girl is seen on the top of the steps leading into the basement of the house where she is employed. In her hand she holds dainty viands, which she knows Bobby delights in, and she beckons to him to follow. In this case you can draw your own conclusions. We follow the light through all the dark passages of the district until it enters a bank building and surprises a burglar at work on a safe. Suddenly Bobby appears behind the lantern, a scuffle ensues and the burglar is captured. This is undoubtedly one of the most novel moving pictures ever made.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?025081</url></doc>
