<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="025862">
  <docid>025862</docid>
  <title>Agents: Live the Mission</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Mupas, Ray</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>christian</keyword>
    <keyword>spy</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">21 October 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">44</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Romero, Jared</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Go, Kathryn</producer>
    <producer>Cunningham, Maureen (III)</producer>
    <producer>Murphy, Kris (II)</producer>
    <producer>Romero, Nicole</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Romero, Jared</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Darren, Michael</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chute, Anthony</actor>
      <role>Doc</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Colon, Hannah</actor>
      <role>Bruiser Bronson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cooper, Abbie</actor>
      <role>Alex</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Go, Joel</actor>
      <role>JD</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Godshall, Shiloh</actor>
      <role>Agent Shiloh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Selby, Craig (I)</actor>
      <role>Agent Craig</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Welcome, Junior Agent, to your first day on the job here at AGENTS - a special ops group working for the Big Man above. An anonymous lead has turned out to be a trap and two of God's top field Agents - JD and Doc - have been kidnapped by the evil rival organization, M.E.N.A.C.E. Only you can figure out how to help free our captured Agents and thwart M.E.N.A.C.E.'s wicked plans. Feeling intimidated? No worries. Search the Mission File Database and access the logs detailing superstar Agent JD's first day as an Agent for God. A mild-mannered, goofball pizza delivery boy, JD soon finds himself caught in the middle of a nefarious M.E.N.A.C.E. plot to lace all of the school cafeteria's powdered donuts with sneezing powder. JD must put aside his insecurities and get involved, become an Agent and do battle with a menacing ninja, all in order to save the school from a horribly malicious prank. Through JD's story, you'll discover that God has created and set apart every person - each with his or her own specific strengths and weaknesses - to be an awesome and unique Special Agent today. With that knowledge, don't waste another minute. Help save the day, step up, and LIVE THE MISSION!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?025862</url></doc>
