<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="026034">
  <docid>026034</docid>
  <title>Agni Pareeksha</title>
  <year>1981</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">21 March 1981</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Majumdar, Kamal</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Chopra, B.R.</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Choudhury, Salil</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Banerjee, S.N. (I)</actor>
      <role>Jailer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dutt, Utpal</actor>
      <role>Ex-Manager Gupta</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Iftekhar</actor>
      <role>Psychiatrist Dr. Sen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jankidas</actor>
      <role>Ramu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapur, Shekhar</actor>
      <role>Karona's brother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lagoo, Shreeram</actor>
      <role>Advocate Anupam</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Palekar, Amol</actor>
      <role>Alok Choudhary/Ramesh Khanna</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Palsikar, Nana</actor>
      <role>Dinanath Sharma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Raj, Jagdish</actor>
      <role>Police Inspector</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sahni, Parikshat</actor>
      <role>Siddarth Sharma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Thakur, Dinesh</actor>
      <role>Dilip Thakur (Karuna's brother)</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>When her former lover, Anupam, returns to her life, her husband kills himself, and after this sudden suicide, Karuna Choudhary must not only look after the household; their family business, but must also admit her only child a son, Alok, in a mental hospital. Now she has met with an accident and has been confined to bed and any movement is by wheelchair. Things change for her when she hires a Secretary/Nurse/Governess in Meeta. She is so pleased with Meeta that she like her to be her daughter-in-law when her now grown-up and cured son, returns home. But Alok does not return, instead runs away to Bombay. An anxious Karuna asks her Manager, Siddharth Sharma, to locate him and bring him back home, which he does. Alok is unhappy at home, but when he meets Meeta he falls head over heels in love with her and wants to marry her. The only problem is Meeta is in love with Siddharth, and wants to marry him. Then everyone's lives are turned upside down when Alok is shot dead with a gun that has Siddharth's fingerprints on them. Siddharth is arrested by the police on the day he weds Meeta, charged with Alok's murder and theft of valuables from the Choudhary household, tried in court, found guilty, and sentenced to be hanged, and only a miracle can now save Siddharth from the gallows.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?026034</url></doc>
