<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="026488">
  <docid>026488</docid>
  <title>Ahmad's Xmas Carol</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Farahat, Fahmi Farouk</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 January 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">12</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Farahat, Fahmi Farouk</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Malas, Amer</producer>
    <producer>Zahra, Ahmad</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Farahat, Fahmi Farouk</writer>
    <writer>Hernandez, Rene H.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Abad, Javier (II)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Boucher, Eric (IV)</actor>
      <role>Dave's Dad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bryant, Evan</actor>
      <role>Dave</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kasumyan, Armen</actor>
      <role>Ahmad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Klein, Tammy</actor>
      <role>Dave's Mom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Montana, Sammy</actor>
      <role>Ahmad's Dad</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Christmas fills the air and Ahmad, an 8 year old mischievous Muslim-American boy, sneaks out of the house to visit his best friend across the street. Of course, he gets caught by his overly loving mother, who tries to stuff him with a banana - the thing Ahmad hates the most. He arrives at his friend's house to find a jolly father drinking eggnog and a mother baking cookies. Most importantly, he finds a house full of decorations and a pile of boxes wrapped with shiny paper of all colors and neatly placed under the overly decorated and lit tree... Presents!! Ahmad is perplexed as to why his friend would get presents. His friend explains, "It's Christmas!" Later that evening Ahmad confronts his family and demands that he gets presents because of Christmas. His father objects because they are Muslim and that he got presents during Eid, their Muslim holiday. Of course Ahmad being spoiled doesn't buy that excuse and throws a tantrum. His mom though convinces the dad to play along with her and promises Ahmad presents... Wow!! Ahmad, dream all night... Christmas morning Ahmad wakes up and rushes to the pillow cases he had placed - instead of stockings - and looks inside and what a sight... presents!! However, when it was time to open them, Ahmad was in for a surprise.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?026488</url></doc>
