<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="026936">
  <docid>026936</docid>
  <title>Ainhoa y el mar</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>death</keyword>
    <keyword>teenager</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Turkey">20 March 2005</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Spain">27 November 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Spain">22</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Alastruey, Karlos</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Marchena, Marla</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Alastruey, Karlos</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Evoghli, Arsham</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Aguirre, Alejandro (III)</actor>
      <role>Father</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Baigorri, Javier</actor>
      <role>Fisherman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carramiñana, Amaya</actor>
      <role>Leire</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"Ainhoa and the Sea" is a Short Fiction movie aimed to reflect upon how the human beings face the death of a loved one. Instead of a movie about the death, we want to explore the capacity of the human being to overcome the death of a very close person. In this movie, Ainhoa, a teenage girl, loses her two parents. The movie tries to express what resources can Ainhoa have in order to face that situation. We have chosen the death of a loved one as a subject because in our opinion death is the main taboo in western societies at the beginning of the century. There are few physical or social spaces where you can talk freely and sincerely about death. The materialistic ideology is put under question by the simple fact that everyone is going to pass away in some years. We live our lives without thinking that death is not so far away from each one of us. Death has become a taboo because of our own fear. Ainhoa is a 17 years old girl who lives alone with her father. She depends economically and emotionally upon him. Suddenly her father dies, and Ainhoa gets depressed not only because of the death itself, but also because of her doubts about her immediate future.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?026936</url></doc>
