<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="027191">
  <docid>027191</docid>
  <title>Aisaa Kyon</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Khan, Yakub (I)</editor>
    <editor>Sharma, Shiv Kumar (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Singh, B.B.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Sharma, K.C.</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Patil, Vijay (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dhawan, Sunil</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gill, Avtar</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Joshi, Mohan</actor>
      <role>Dharamdas</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Razak</actor>
      <role>Kaalu Khuta</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lever, Johnny</actor>
      <role>Janardhan Johnny</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mahadevan, Anant</actor>
      <role>Mahadevan (Interviewer)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mohan, Ram (I)</actor>
      <role>College Principal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Murad, Raza</actor>
      <role>Sharad Chander</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rajeshh</actor>
      <role>Rajesh Pandit/Rajesh Paswan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rindani, Shiva</actor>
      <role>Police Inspector</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Rajesh Pandit comes from a middle-class family, living with his widowed dad, and an unmarried sister. He studies in College, and is in love with fellow- collegian, Kaajal, who comes from a wealthy family and wants to be a Journalist. Unhappy with the College atmosphere, especially about reservations of scheduled caste, tribes, dalits, and other backward classes, who were shunned and despised in India, Rajesh contests the election for College Students President, and wins it against long-time President, Kranti Thakur. Rajesh's dream is now to pass his college examinations, study the Indian Police Service (IPS) and become a police officer, marry Kaajal and settle down. He does well in his exams as well in his interview and is told that he is likely to be selected. However, this does not happen and the fortunate candidate happens to be one from a backward class. His dreams shattered, now must come to terms that he must now resort to some other means to get an IPS posting, arrange for enough dowry to get his sister married. He is fully aware that the path is must now adopt will mean changing his name to Rajesh Paswan, and working for a shady politician named Dharamdas, a move that will change his life forever.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?027191</url></doc>
