<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="027650">
  <docid>027650</docid>
  <title>Akher kedba</title>
  <year>1950</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Musical</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Arabic</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Egypt">1950</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Badrakhan, Ahmed</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Al Atrache, Fouad</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>El-Ibiary, Abu Seoud</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Al Atrache, Farid</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Al Atrache, Farid</actor>
      <role>Samir</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Al Nabulsy, Abdel Salam (I)</actor>
      <role>Amin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Al-Kassar, Ali</actor>
      <role>Roz</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bakr, Said Abu</actor>
      <role>Satoor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Camelia (I)</actor>
      <role>Kiki</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gamal, Samia</actor>
      <role>Samira</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rosti, Stephan</actor>
      <role>The Doctor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Yasseen, Ismail</actor>
      <role>Arnab/The Aunt</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Samir is a singer living happily with his jealous wife Samira. However, His ex-girlfriend Kiki wants to relive their relationship again, but he refuses because he is afraid of Samira's violent reaction. Kiki seeks the help of an Indian Maharaja and asks him to force Samir to attend her birthday party, he then sends his men to do the job. Samir feels intimidated during the celebration and accidently breaks Kiki's pearl necklace which she borrowed from the Maharaja. He promises her to fix it and puts it in his pocket, but becomes drunk and loses consciousness. When Samira returns home after visiting her mother in Alexandria and discovers that her husband is missing, she searches for him frantically. Samir arrives during her absence, that is when his wife finds the neckace in his jacket, she qiuckly becomes suspicious. When Samira confronts her husband, he lies to her about everything and indulges his friend Arnab to tell her that they were together last night, so he can avoid her anger, but his lies soon cause a lot of chaos in a humorous manner.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?027650</url></doc>
