<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="029154">
  <docid>029154</docid>
  <title>Alejandra</title>
  <year>1942</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Gómez Muriel, Emilio</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Mexico</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Mexico">2 July 1942</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">3 September 1943</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Benavides hijo, José</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Benavides hijo, José</writer>
    <writer>Castera, Pedro</writer>
    <writer>D'Erzell, Catalina</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Esperón, Manuel</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Baledón, Rafael (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Blanch, Anita</actor>
      <role>Irene</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Camarillo, Dolores</actor>
      <role>Nana</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Frausto, Antonio R.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>García, Sara (I)</actor>
      <role>Elena</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Guízar, Susana</actor>
      <role>Alejandra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lozano, Salvador (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Morcillo, José</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Noriega, Manuel (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Quiroz, Salvador</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Velázquez, Víctor</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vera, Hernán (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Villarreal, Julio</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>de Córdova, Arturo</actor>
      <role>Ricardo</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Ricardo (Arturo de Córdova) is a young man that spent all his time in parties. Is 1879 and during New Year's Night Ricardo spent the night with his girlfriend, Irene (Anita Blanch), a pried woman who doesn't love to much Ricardo. Ricardo's mother, Elena (Sara García) spent the night alone with the housekeeper, and both are worried about Ricardo, remembering his childhood, when he use to be a good boy. One night, Ricardo finds a baby girl in front of the house, and without reading the note inside of the basket, he gives the baby to the housekeeper, asking her to feed the baby. Elena finds the note and reads that actually the baby is Ricardo's daughter, left there by Irene, her mother. In the note, Irene says that she can't take care for the baby and asks Ricardo to take care for her. The baby makes possible that Ricardo becomes a good man, and he will be like a father for the girl, named Alejandra, without knowing that she's his daughter. Elena will keep the secret for all these years. Now 18-years-old, Alejandra (Susana Guízar), after spent most of her childhood in Paris, returns to Mexico with a serious heart condition. His doctor and friend recommends not to much excitement for Alejandra. He's deeply in love with the girl. But Alejandra loves another man, Ricardo, and he feels in the same way about her. When Elena finds out that they're engaged, she'll must to tell all the truth to her son.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?029154</url></doc>
