<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="029989">
  <docid>029989</docid>
  <title>Alice's Balloon Race</title>
  <year>1926</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>hippopotamus</keyword>
    <keyword>pepper</keyword>
    <keyword>balloon-race</keyword>
    <keyword>elephant</keyword>
    <keyword>sneeze</keyword>
    <keyword>hot-air-balloon</keyword>
    <keyword>rope-ladder</keyword>
    <keyword>fall-from-height</keyword>
    <keyword>villain</keyword>
    <keyword>kids-and-family</keyword>
    <keyword>lightning</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">15 December 1929</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">8</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Disney, Walt</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Disney, Walt</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gay, Margie</actor>
      <role>Alice</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Alice and Julius, as a team, are one of four entrants in a $10,000 balloon race. The bad guy takes out one balloon quickly. It's not clear what kind of balloons these are, since they are sealed like hydrogen/helium balloons, but a good thwack on the top by the bad guy sends Alice and Julius plummeting to the ground, balloon still intact. Julius makes some attempts to re-launch, but they fail. He spots a hippo, smoking nearby, and has an idea: using some pepper, he creates a massive sneeze that re-launches them. But he wasn't onboard. Alice throws down a rope ladder, but it isn't anchored; Julius eventually pulls himself up with a rope. They are then immediately under attack by a lightning storm, which deflates the balloon. Julius makes substitutes from, first, a weiner dog and a couple of empty thought balloons, then, an elephant with extra air pumped in. He grabs a passing bird and catches up to the bad guy, then finds himself in another battle with lightning. He throws a bolt at the bad guy's balloon, then has his own elephant get pierced by another. They land on top of each other, and on Alice, who was pacing back and forth on the ground, then run away from the bad guy.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?029989</url></doc>
