<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="030497">
  <docid>030497</docid>
  <title>All About Us</title>
  <year>1993</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">55</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Coulson, Michael</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Gabriel, Peter</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gabriel, Peter</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Levin, Tony</actor>
      <role>Himself - Bass (segment "Live at the Brit Awards")</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>All About US is an interesting foray into the thinking and the technology that lies behind the most popular tracks from Peter Gabriel's US album. It contains documentary coverage of the thinking behind the most popular music videos together with the actual music videos themselves. Music videos include:1. Digging In the Dirt 2. Steam 3. Blood of Eden 4. Solsbury Hill 5. Zaar 6. Come Talk to Me 7. Kiss That Frog. Directed by Michael Coulson, All About Us includes rare interviews and behind the scenes footage of Gabriel as he finishes his album and gets his haircut ready to go out on tour. It also features some of the 11 contemporary artists who were commissioned by Gabriel, in an innovative approach to marketing, to create works inspired by the songs. Each of the artists - Andy Goldsworthy, Yayoi Kusama, David Mach, Helen Chadwick, Zadok Ben-David, Zush, Rebecca Horn, Mickael Beth- Selassie , Ian Hughes, Jordan Baseman, Finbar Kelly and Bili Bidjocka were given a track as inspiration. Coulson recorded their creative process. Seeing the way that Gabriel has merged the artistic concepts of both his music, lyric, and the artistic interpretations into the completed music videos demonstrates the multi-layered meaning and message of his works.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?030497</url></doc>
