<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="031423">
  <docid>031423</docid>
  <title>All's Swell That Ends Swell!</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <editors>
    <editor>Mylrea, Chris (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>medical-profession</keyword>
    <keyword>satire</keyword>
    <keyword>marriage</keyword>
    <keyword>husband-wife-relationship</keyword>
    <keyword>love</keyword>
    <keyword>extramarital-affair</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Australia">5 May 2006</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">10 September 2006</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="France">23 May 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Australia">11</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Ball, Nick (VI)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Wright, Dennis (I)</producer>
    <producer>Wright, Pattie (II)</producer>
    <producer>Ball, Nick (VI)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Ball, Nick (VI)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Askin, Richard</actor>
      <role>The Milkman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Coonan, Allison</actor>
      <role>Naughty Nurse</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cotter, David (I)</actor>
      <role>Dr. Henderson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Danaher, Clare</actor>
      <role>Macy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Davis, Tiffany</actor>
      <role>TV Pregnant Lady</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hateley, Katie</actor>
      <role>Straight Nurse</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lang, Lana</actor>
      <role>Betty</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Powell, Leigh (II)</actor>
      <role>Indian</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Powell, Ryan (II)</actor>
      <role>Cowboy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rive, Tony</actor>
      <role>Frank</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Swain, Brett</actor>
      <role>Gerry</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>1950's American Technicolor suburbia, complete with white picket fences and chirping birds. Perfect. Just Swell. Josephine is a young housewife who despite her best efforts is unable to please her ever dominant and ignorant husband Frank. While enjoying a Tupperware party with her friends, Josie discovers that the solution to her unhappiness is to start a family. Frank could think of nothing worse. Whilst watching television, Josie stumbles across an infomercial advertising a new technology developed by Dr. Henderson - "The Contraction Contraption": a machine that transfers the pain of childbirth to the father through "micro-waves". There should be no lasting effects for the husband, just a "wake up call" for bad ones. Josie cannot sign up quick enough! Nine months later, and Josie, Frank and their friends Macy and Gerry are enjoying a summer BBQ. Without warning, Josephine goes into labour. Upon arrival at the hospital, she is rigged up to the clunky machine. Frank sits in the waiting room, uncaring, unknowing. Throughout the birth, Dr. Henderson turns the percentage of pain to be transferred to Frank in steady upward increments. After a long labour, Josie is smiling. However, despite the machine indicating 100% pain transfer Frank feels nothing. Josie and Frank return home. Josephine is totally involved with their new bouncing baby girl. Frank is still ignorant and sour. Josephine and Frank make their way up to their front porch. Suddenly they both stop in their tracks. Lying before them is milk, spilt everywhere.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?031423</url></doc>
