<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="033467">
  <docid>033467</docid>
  <title>Am3r1c4, Am3r1c4, Am3r1c4, America irl</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Patrick, Mitch</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>art-house</keyword>
    <keyword>transgression</keyword>
    <keyword>experimental</keyword>
    <keyword>art</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">27 September 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">19</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Patrick, Mitch</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Patrick, Mitch</actor>
      <role>Mitch</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>AM3R1C4, AM3R1C4, AM3R1C4, AMERICAL IRL (in real life) is a transgressive short film that presents three digital American flag dissolutions amongst murky lascivious videos found on the Internet. In the latter part of the film the dissolution is then executed physically via performance. The film abstractly examines how physical interaction between person and person, and/or person and object in our digital age is now a much dislodged scenario. The interaction between person and the vaporous digital image and audio is now a ubiquitous paragon of interaction. The film is specifically referential to the Internet, which is utilized as a sublimated tool to host provocative content to suite specific socially unacceptable desires; therefore myriads of taboos have been displaced within the digital global village. The act of viewing provocative media that is usually censored from the public can be scrutinized as an inadvertent way of transgressing and dissolving established societal ethics. What is missing is the tactility of interaction and the physicality of the content presented in hard edged visual media. The video can be seen as a play between what viewers perpetually do intangibly (via cybernetics) and then performed "in real life". Conclusively, the video questions the legitimacy of transgression through the use of technology and how the same scenarios are deemed as absurd when performed in a physical space.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?033467</url></doc>
