<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="034543">
  <docid>034543</docid>
  <title>America's Next Top Superhero</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Baldwin, Allyson (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">6 April 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">10</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Stuart, Steve</director>
    <director>Stuart, Steven</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Stuart, Steve</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Adams, Bernadette</actor>
      <role>The Compactor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Burke, Kristine</actor>
      <role>The Gobbler</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deacon, Leigh</actor>
      <role>The Dominator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Engelmayer, Victoria</actor>
      <role>Narcolepsia</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Faith, Laura</actor>
      <role>The Ladybug</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Flanagan, Lucas</actor>
      <role>Greesed Lightnin'</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rodenhiser, Erik</actor>
      <role>The Creamator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stirling, David (II)</actor>
      <role>Brainiac</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"So, what's the plan this time, Brainiac?" After losing three superheroes to sinister accidents, Super Sidekick Brainiac is in search of a new superhero companion, so naturally he placed a newspaper ad. He's finally down to eight applicants, but there can only be one Next Top Superhero. Let the competition begin and may the best superhero win! Made as part of the 2004 Boston 48 Hour Film Project, America's Next Top Superhero represents what results when Playomatic Media Group only has 48 hours to conceive, script, produce, shoot, edit, score and master a short film. On the evening of Friday, April 2nd, Team Playomatic randomly drew the "Superhero" genre out of a hat and was informed the following items must be included in the film: Prop: Garden Hose Character: Spudgy McGonnagle, a Pastry Chief Line of Dialogue: "So, what's the plan this time, Brainiac?" This award-winning short was shot on Saturday, April 3rd and edited on Sunday, April 4th in Beverly, Massachusetts. It was first screened as an audience favorite at the Brattle Theatre in Cambridge on Tuesday, April 6th and later included in the Best of Boston screening on May 9th at the Regent Theatre in Arlington, Massachusetts. Winner of an unprecedented three awards at the Best of Boston screening: Best Costumes Best Use of Character Best Use of Line of Dialogue.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?034543</url></doc>
