<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="034729">
  <docid>034729</docid>
  <title>American Centurion</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Sugarman, Josh</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Sugarman, Josh</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Greenhill, Duke</producer>
    <producer>Yankowitz, Brandon</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Ain, Morty</writer>
    <writer>Sugarman, Josh</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Casaubon, Josh</actor>
      <role>Sergeant Milinger</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>For Sergeant Milinger, things look grim. Wounded, he's been peeled off his United States Army unit and forced to the dubious safety of a nearby rubble pile. Growing weak, it seems the Iraqi desert may be home to the soldier's last moments. Struggling to make one last stand, he readies his weapon and surveys the horizon. Suddenly, having spotted something odd in the distance, he stops. "Konichiwa," he hears behind him. Abruptly, he turns. Now before him, just inches from the barrel of his gun, stands a young, pajama-clad Japanese girl. Notebook in hand, she asks in her own tongue, "What is your name?" Bullets ricochet nearby, but the girl stands unphased. Is she real, an apparition, a heavenly intermediary, he asks himself? Before he can inquire, she's moved again - now inexplicably seated to his side. "Why are you here," she asks. Eventually, he begins to respond. A voice from above calls, and the girl looks upwards. Thousands of miles away, in a Japanese bedroom, we see that same girl. Wearing the latest technology, a pair of "interporting" glasses, she's in fact been in the quiet safety of her 22nd century bedroom all along, having been charged by her schoolteacher to visit Milinger as part of her nightly homework. As Chiyoko takes to the comfort of her bed and, as his enemies close in, Milinger scurries ineffectively for cover, "American Centurion" forces us to reflect on the possibility of a 100-year Iraq War and its impact on America's future.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?034729</url></doc>
