<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="035298">
  <docid>035298</docid>
  <title>American as Cherry Pie: The Life of H. Rap Brown</title>
  <year>2010</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">June 2010</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Edwards, Jamar</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Coffey, Terry</producer>
    <producer>Edwards, Jamar</producer>
    <producer>Pemberton, Warren</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Edwards, Jamar</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Al-Amin, Karima</actor>
      <role>Himself - Commentary Interviews</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brown, Ed (XIV)</actor>
      <role>Himself - Commentary Interviews</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brown, H. Rap</actor>
      <role>H. Rap Brown</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brown, Mayor Johnny</actor>
      <role>Himself - Commentary Interviews</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cleaver, Kathleen</actor>
      <role>Herself - Commentary Interviews</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dailey, Maceo</actor>
      <role>Himself - Commentary Interviews</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harvey, Attorney Bruce</actor>
      <role>Himself - Commentary Interviews</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mantz, Bob (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself - Commentary Interviews</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Martin, Bob (XV)</actor>
      <role>Himself - Commentary Interviews</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McBurney, Robert</actor>
      <role>Himself - Commentary Interviews</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McDew, Charles</actor>
      <role>Himself - Commentary Interviews</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>O'Neil, John (IX)</actor>
      <role>Himself - Commentary Interviews</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Professor Griff</actor>
      <role>Himself - Commentary Interview</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Residents of Atlanta's West End Community</actor>
      <role>Themselves-Commentary Interviews</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Saalakhan, El-Hajj Mauri</actor>
      <role>Himself - Commentary Interviews</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Seale, Bobby</actor>
      <role>Himself - Commentary Interviews</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"American As Cherry Pie: The Life of H. Rap Brown" is about the life of Imam Jamil (H. Rap Brown), known as the prolific civil rights militant during the troubling sixties, Brown was known for his fiery speeches and aggressive demonstrations against racism and poverty that surrounded the African-American communities during the civil rights era. Brown is often quoted from a speech that he delivered in the sixties when he said, "violence is American as cherry pie," Brown gave this speech when he believed that violent acts of racism must also be met with violence itself. Because of his original style of poetry and rhythmic delivery, Brown is often credited by Hip Hop musicians as being one of the pioneers of the genre of Hip Hop music. While serving a prison sentence in the seventies, Brown made the conversion to the Muslim faith and leads one of the largest Muslim organizations in the world. Now known as Imam Jamil Abdullah Al-Amin, Imam Jamil is currently serving a life sentence in Reidsville, Georgia, for allegedly murdering a Fulton County, Georgia, sheriff's deputy in March of 2000. The documentary will be giving a detailed look into Imam Jamil's life from various commentary interviews from the people who knew him best, both professionally and personally: Sister Karima (wife), Ed Brown (brother), John O'Neal (SNCC), Charles McDew (SNCC), Bob Mantz (SNCC), Bobby Seale (co-founder of the Black Panther Party), Kathleen Cleaver (Black Panther Party), Mayor Johnny Jackson (Whitehall, Alabama), Professor Maceo Dailey of the University of Texas at El Paso, Robert McBurney (Assistant United States Attorney), previous and current attorneys of Imam Jamil, and residents of Atlanta's West End community.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?035298</url></doc>
