<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="035698">
  <docid>035698</docid>
  <title>Among Duality</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Wells, Anthony</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>spirituality</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">3 July 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">13</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Wells, Scott (XI)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Wells, Scott (XI)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Wells, Scott (XI)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kerosene Kondors</composer>
    <composer>Randall, Elliot</composer>
    <composer>Wells, Anthony</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cullifordfikaris, Amber</actor>
      <role>Tramp</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lambert, Alex (III)</actor>
      <role>Rebel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wells, Scott (XI)</actor>
      <role>Surfer</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A young man walks upon a white fence as a meditation between the known safe world we call the sidewalk and the fearful unknown world represented by the potentially dangerous blackberry bushes. He falls into the 'unknown' and returns unscathed yet is teased by a girl who is soon blown away by the breeze that guides her south. A surfer driving an old Mercedes picks her up hitchhiking. She is on her way to Mexico for more of their "homemade desert agave tequila." The young man who has been following them in his truck jogs to the beach yet finds only the surfer. So he races back to catch the girl but suddenly the Mercedes is gone! He offers to help the surfer get his Mercedes back. If they hurry they can catch her. But for some strange reason the surfer doesn't seem to mind. He insists on remaining in a state of love rather than allowing fear to ruin his natural high. He simply chooses love and defines its counterpoint fear as illusion. In what seems like another competition to see who gets the girl, the young man learns that love need not conquers all, for love is all there is.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?035698</url></doc>
