<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="036261">
  <docid>036261</docid>
  <title>Amped</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Poche, Richard</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Mystery</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>bay-area</keyword>
    <keyword>drug-overdose</keyword>
    <keyword>rock-band</keyword>
    <keyword>suspense</keyword>
    <keyword>neo-noir</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 December 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">70</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Poche, Richard</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Poche, Richard</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bachman, Ray</actor>
      <role>Jimmy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barendrick, Shelby</actor>
      <role>Cassandra Reed</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brazell, Stuart</actor>
      <role>Lynn Straw</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Christensen, Trish</actor>
      <role>Veronica Low</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Di Prinzio, Elizabeth</actor>
      <role>Magnolia Leonard</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Poche, Cliff</actor>
      <role>Officer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Poche, Richard</actor>
      <role>Detective Robert Holden</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Amped 'TILL MY DYING DAY Homicide detective Robert Holden (Richard Poche) is rapidly becoming the stereotypical world weary detective by working in the crap city called Oakland. One morning he is called to investigate the death of Lynn Straw (Stuart Brazell), the new lead singer of the Bay Area female fronted rock band, "The Danger Dolls". Performers of the smash hit, "'Till My Dying Day", Holden quickly wants to put closure on the case and avoid scrutiny by the media. However, in what appears to be an open and shut case of a cocaine overdose, Holden soon finds out that each of the band members has something to hide. WHO KILLED LYNN STRAW? The irony of the band's most popular song is apparent as Lynn's body is found dead on the couch. Magnolia "Maggie" Leonard (Liz DiPrinzio) is the first to discover the body. Maggie is a fiery tempered lead guitarist, prone to outbursts which are held in check only by her music, a classic example of how "music calms the savage bitch." Then there is the sensual Cassandra Reed (Shelby Barendrick). A sultry bass player, Cassandra has the uncanny ability to enter a room full of people and soon become the ONLY woman in the room the men are paying attention to. With the arrival of Lynn, however, Cassandra soon became bitter at someone else getting the attention. Finally, there is Veronica Low (Trish Christensen), the superb rubber wristed drummer of the band and her boyfriend Jimmy (Ray Bachman). Veronica inexplicably goes into hiding immediately after Lynn's death. Songwriter Jimmy, on the other hand, seems to be running interference for her. HERE COMES DANGER With images of the achingly beautiful Lynn Straw on his mind, Detective Holden soon finds himself in a vortex of lies and deceit that threatens to capture everyone in its grasp.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?036261</url></doc>
