<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="038554">
  <docid>038554</docid>
  <title>Anam</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Schweizer, Ann-Sophie</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>German</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Germany">12</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Japan">27 October 2001</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Norway">29 November 2002</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Germany">25 April 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">86</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Alakus, Buket</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Emons, Hejo</producer>
    <producer>Schubert, Stefan</producer>
    <producer>Schwingel, Ralph</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Alakus, Buket</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Ergin, Mehmet</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Akhavan, Navíd</actor>
      <role>Deniz</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bademsoy, Tayfun</actor>
      <role>Mehmet</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Girisken, Jülide</actor>
      <role>Lelâ</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Köse, Nursel</actor>
      <role>Anam</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lansink, Leonard</actor>
      <role>Bernd</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ünel, Birol</actor>
      <role>Hasan</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Anam is about 40 years old and a traditionalistic Turkish wife and mother who lives with her family in a German city. Anam works as a cleaner and has made two friends there: Rita a man-crazy German and Didi a superstitious African. When Anam finds out that her twenty-year old son Deniz has drifted into the drug scene and that her husband Mehmet is having an affair with a colleague her whole world collapses around her. Although desperate she is determined to fight and goes looking for Deniz. Instead she finds his girlfriend Mandy who is also a drug addict. She decides to take care of the girl who is a stranger to her and finds herself confronted with an entirely unknown world. When she finally manages to track Deniz down to the cold-blooded dealer Hassain, she is rejected by him. Anam is forced to realize that painful as it is she can only help Deniz if he is prepared to accept her help. When Mandy dies trying to reconcile mother and son, Anam is determined to do everything she can to get her son out of the clutches of the dealer. However now it really is a matter of life or death.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?038554</url></doc>
