<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="039130">
  <docid>039130</docid>
  <title>And the Colours Are Like Summer</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Antranikian, Armen</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Brazil</country>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="France">20 May 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">4</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Tupinamb치, Gabriel</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Tupinamb치, Gabriel</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Tupinamb치, Gabriel</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Tupinamb치, Gabriel</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bransford, Darren</actor>
      <role>Ken</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>And the Colors Are Like Summer is a short film that deals with the passage from hate to love and with the place that violence and aggression have in the sexual and love discourse, specially when taken to its limits. Ken and Barbie are a couple that fights over everything. They cannot get enough of arguing and humiliating one another. At a first glance, there is no reason why they should stay together. Ken is constantly humiliated by Barbie, that calls him a loser everyday. Ken, on the other hand, treats Barbie in the most degrading manner possible, always jealous of her professional achievements. By exploring the tension that builds up in Ken and Barbie's relationship and the imagery that sustains this hateful discourse, the film shows that the transition between the apparently opposite pair hate/love might be smoother and more linear than it seems. The film is an hectic paced visual montage from different fights and arguments of the couple, inter-cut with images that produce and are produced by the action, forcing the tension between them to escalate and, finally, overflow into passionate love.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?039130</url></doc>
