<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="039958">
  <docid>039958</docid>
  <title>Angaara</title>
  <year>1996</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Ganguly, Anil</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ganguly, Rajani</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Sen, Dilip</composer>
    <composer>Sen, Sameer</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Amrapurkar, Sadashiv</actor>
      <role>Police Inspector</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhagwat, Suresh</actor>
      <role>Gulabi's maternal uncle</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Birje, Hemant</actor>
      <role>Chotu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chakraborty, Mithun</actor>
      <role>Sagar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chatwal, Suresh</actor>
      <role>Gulabi's maternal uncle</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dalvi, Sudhir</actor>
      <role>Sagar's dad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ghosh, Tarun</actor>
      <role>Vidyacharan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jalal, Farida</actor>
      <role>Saraswati</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Joshi, Mohan</actor>
      <role>Om Prakash</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Goga</actor>
      <role>Pascal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Packard, Gavin</actor>
      <role>Jackie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Patel, Harish (I)</actor>
      <role>Dhaniram Koilewala</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rami Reddy</actor>
      <role>Honda Dada</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sadanah, Kamal</actor>
      <role>Vishal</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Sagar is a young man who lives with his mom, Saraswati, a college-going brother, Vishal, and a school-going sister, Chutki, in a town in India. His father had abandoned them years ago and his whereabouts are unknown. Also unknown to his family, Sagar uses different disguises to steal money and jewelery from Dhaniram Koilewala, and a illicit liquor supplier, Pascal. A perplexed Dhaniram and irritated Pascal asks a gangster, Honda Dada, for help. Honda assigns two men for this job, Chotu and Jackie, and they find out that the person who has been pulling these tricks is an older male with a mustache, who continues to elude them at will. Then Sagar comes across a man named Om Prakash who tells him that his father is still alive, and he would be willing to take him along to meet him. Sagar dislikes his father, but decides to accompany Om Prakash. Sagar will soon find out that Om has an ulterior motive, but by that time it will be too late, and he will find that not only his life. but the life of his family, will be at stake - especially when Honda and his men find out who Sagar really is.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?039958</url></doc>
