<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="041251">
  <docid>041251</docid>
  <title>Ankush</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Ghosh, Atanu</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Bengali</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">31 December 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Ghosh, Atanu</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chatterjee, Parambrata</actor>
      <role>Rahul</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chatterjee, Soumitra</actor>
      <role>Somshankar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Haldar, Indrani</actor>
      <role>Aatrayee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maitra, Badshah</actor>
      <role>Pradipto</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Ankush and Aatrayee got married in 2002. It was an arranged marriage. Ankush was settled in New Jersey, USA. He left three days after marriage presumably because he had lots of pending work in his office. After four months, Aatrayee got her visa and left for New Jersey. But strangely, her husband did not come to receive her at the airport. She waited for hours and then, out of panic, rang up her parents in Calcutta, who in turn, enquired about it at her in-law's place. But no one had any clue as to why Ankush did not turn up at the airport or send somebody to receive Aatrayee. Meantime, Aatryee hired a cab and went searching for him in his house and office. It was now discovered that Ankush was last seen two days back. As it was getting dark, Aatrayee had no option but to ring up an acquaintance staying in Atlanta to help her out of the mess that she was in. Four years have passed. Ankush is still missing. No information could be retrieved about him in USA. Aatrayee did not return to Calcutta. She stayed on in Atlanta and got herself a job. Suddenly, out of a strange impulse, Aatrayee now embarks on a rather strange mission. She comes over to Calcutta secretly without even informing her parents and puts up in a guests. Prior to coming, she had published an advertisement in some Calcutta-based newspapers seeking information about Ankush. Out of the few responses she received, Aatrayee chose to meet three respondents - Somshankar, Prodipto and Rahul - all of whom claim to have clues regarding Ankush's mysterious disappearance and his present state of existence. But the question is - Will Aatrayee ultimately come face to face with the greatest enigma of her life, that is, Ankush ?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?041251</url></doc>
