<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="042536">
  <docid>042536</docid>
  <title>Antim Nyay</title>
  <year>1993</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Sehgal, Subhash</editor>
  </editors>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Dhadda, Sukhwant</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Sagoo, G.S.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Joshi, Madan</writer>
    <writer>Majumdar, Phani</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Patil, Vijay (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bakshi, Arun</actor>
      <role>Arjun Bakshi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chatwal, Suresh</actor>
      <role>Man at police news' briefing</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dubey, C.S.</actor>
      <role>Lawyer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Bharat</actor>
      <role>Deputy Minister</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kashyap, Sundeep</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kharbanda, Kulbhushan</actor>
      <role>Lala Ranjan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kiran, Shashi (I)</actor>
      <role>Aadesh Varma's employee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nair, Vishwanath</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nath, Alok</actor>
      <role>Aadesh Varma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nayak, Mohan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Parvez, Yunus</actor>
      <role>Lawyer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rege, Sunil</actor>
      <role>Police Commissioner</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shah, Mahavir</actor>
      <role>Munna</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shroff, Jackie</actor>
      <role>ACP Jay R. Singh</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Jay Singh lives a middle-classed lifestyle along with his dad, Raghunath, and mom, in Bombay. His dad is killed, and both he and his mother attempt to get justice, but their efforts prove to be all in vain. Then he meets with Seema, the only daughter of Editor Aadesh Varma, both fall in love and get engaged. Jay takes a course in Indian Police Services and hopes to become a police officer. He does well in his exams and is all set to secure his job, but before that could happen Aadesh gets killed, and Jay gets arrested and lodged in a cell. When his mother finds out, she goes to the Police Station, but is abused and not permitted to meet with him. Subsequently Jay is released, but re-arrested after he assaults Inspector Kelkar, and is tortured and beaten. The Police Commissioner subsequently arranges his release, and Jay returns home, gets married to Seema, and both find to their shock and surprise that Seema's house has been taken over by a criminal don, Lala Ranjan, who wants to demolish it and construct a hotel, while Aadesh's death has been written off as an accident. Jay, his mom, and Seema attempt to secure justice - only to find that the entire system is corrupt. Jay then is appointed as the Assistant Commissioner of Police and gets his first attempt at arresting Lala Ranjan when he gets a complaint from Arjun Bakshi that Lala has allegedly killed his brother-in-law. This arrest will lead to a chain of events that will shatter not only Jay's life but jeopardize the well being of a pregnant Seema, his mother, throw him into confrontation with fellow-officers - while Lala himself will be declared innocent - leaving him free to exact his vengeance from Jay.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?042536</url></doc>
