<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="042805">
  <docid>042805</docid>
  <title>Anubhav: An Experience</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Darak, Dilip</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Kumar, Sandeep (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Shah, Piyush</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Ali, Ghulam</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Afrin</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Amit (IV)</actor>
      <role>Vishal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arvind, Neel</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kanchan (VI)</actor>
      <role>Reema</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Shakti (I)</actor>
      <role>Public Prosecutor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kaushal, Priya</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Sohail</actor>
      <role>Jaikishan 'Jackie'</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rawal, Paresh (I)</actor>
      <role>Advocate Rana Vikram</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Jaikishan and Reema are in love with each other but live a poor lifestyle in India and are unable to marry. Jaikishan decides to seduce and marry a wealthy heiress, Monica, who he can subsequently divorce, take possession of her wealth, and then re-marry Reema. Everything goes according to plan, Jaikishan even accumulates enough money to buy Reema a bungalow, and re-unites with his college friend, Vishal and his wife, Manisha, who has a brain-tumor which must be surgically removed soon or she will die. Then Jaikishan's world crashes around him as Monica finds out that he has been two-timing her, so she seizes his bank accounts, leaving him in financial jeopardy and in debt with a goon named Gulshan. Jaikishan decides to avenge this humiliation by asking Vishal to seduce Monica, give him the money for Manisha's surgery, divorce Monica, take her wealth and re-marry Reema. Vishal reluctantly agrees to be part of this plan, has an affair, and even gets intimate with Monica. Jaikishan is now all set to accuse Monica of infidelity, take her wealth and re-marry Reema - but Murphy's law prevails - turning everyone's lives upside down.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?042805</url></doc>
