<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="042853">
  <docid>042853</docid>
  <title>Anuranan</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Shi, Mahadeb</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
    <language>Bengali</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital EX</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">28 November 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="India">113</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Chowdhury, Aniruddha Roy</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Chowdhury, Aniruddha Roy</producer>
    <producer>Gopal, Gagan</producer>
    <producer>Banerjee, Jeet</producer>
    <producer>Mukerjee, Indrani</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Chowdhury, Aniruddha Roy</writer>
    <writer>Pandey, Gaurav</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Bose, Tanmoy</composer>
    <composer>Rego, Aashish</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bandopadhaya, Haradhan</actor>
      <role>Mr. Sen 'Colonel'</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Basu, Dolly</actor>
      <role>Preeti's mother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bose, Rahul</actor>
      <role>Rahul Chatterjee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chanda, Barun</actor>
      <role>Mr. Guha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dawson, Jacqui</actor>
      <role>Roda</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Rajat</actor>
      <role>Amit Bannerjee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wear, Peter</actor>
      <role>Arther - Rahul's boss in London</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Rahul Chatterjee is a second-generation East Indian who lives in Birmingham, England, along with his wife, Nandita, and works as a Designer. Rahul's late father used to work in England, then re-located to Calcutta, where Rahul met Nandita, got married to her, and when she gave birth to a still-born baby, the devastated couple re-located to Bombay, and thereafter to Birmingham. Now his employer has negotiated a contract to re-develop Kanchenjunga in the Himalayas in India, and as a result Rahul gets transferred to Calcutta, which has now been re-named to Kolkata. He gets to meet with the Agent, Amit Bannerjee, who negotiated this project as well as his wife, Preeti. The two couples meet become friends and continue to meet often. Nandita gets a job as a Montessori school-teacher, while Amit takes a trip to London amidst protests from the Himalayan Gurkha community who are against any pollution-related development in this region. This is where he will get the devastating news of Rahul's sudden death near the Himalayas, and the even more shocking news of Rahul's affair with Preeti. Watch what impact this news has on Nandita, her sister, Mitha, as well as on Preeti's mother and the rest of the community.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?042853</url></doc>
