<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="043452">
  <docid>043452</docid>
  <title>Apne Huye Paraye</title>
  <year>1964</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Chakraborty, Ajit</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Chakraborty, Ajit</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Pankal, Jaikishan Dayabhai</composer>
    <composer>Raghuwanshi, Shankarsinh</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Agha</actor>
      <role>Fohkat</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Burke, Chand</actor>
      <role>Rampyari</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dulari (I)</actor>
      <role>Rekha's mom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Iftekhar</actor>
      <role>Public Prosecutor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Manoj (I)</actor>
      <role>Dr.Shankar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumari, Padma</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sunder (I)</actor>
      <role>Makhan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tiwari, Ramayan</actor>
      <role>Judge</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Rekha lives a middle-class lifestyle with her widowed mom. When she is five, her mom's friend, Nalini, passes away, compelling 5 year old Lata and her maid, Rampyari, to move in with them. Rekha is friendly with Shankar, and is sad when his family re-locates to Kanpur. Years later Rekha has matured, Shankar has returned as a qualified doctor, and asks her mom for Rekha's hand in marriage, to which she agrees. Before the engagement could take place, Rampyari finds that Shankar is having an affair with Lata, compelling both of them to get married, leaving Rekha heart-broken. After the marriage, Lata moves out to live with Shankar, and Rekha's mom passes, leaving her a heavily mortgaged house and many debts. Rekha's re-pays the debts and moves out to live her family servant, Fohkat, his son, Makhan, and Makhan's wife, Misri. Rekha finds employment and falls seriously ill. Shankar comes to treat her and asks her to come and live with them. When Rekha refuses, Lata comes over and makes her change her mind, and as a result both Fohkat and Rekha move in Shankar's house - not realizing that their entry will result in a murder in the household - which will not only turn everyone's lives upside down but also throw open their individual lives to a public scandal.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?043452</url></doc>
