<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="043439">
  <docid>043439</docid>
  <title>Apna Jahan</title>
  <year>1985</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Shetye, Shailesh</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">1985</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Bose, Subroto</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bose, Subroto</producer>
    <producer>Katrolia, Kailash</producer>
    <producer>Sahani, Joginder</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bose, Subroto</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Malik, Anu</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Desai, Kruttika</actor>
      <role>Rita</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gilani, Benjamin</actor>
      <role>Dr. Mukesh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gupta, Arti</actor>
      <role>Komal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kashyap, Vijay</actor>
      <role>Manohar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nath, Alok</actor>
      <role>D'Souza</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shah, Naseeruddin</actor>
      <role>Anil Sahani</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Anil Sahani works as an Electrician with Saini Electricals in a city in India. He is being forced out of his lodge as it is being demolished to make way for a multi-storied building. In desperate need of a room, he asks one of his customers, Shanti, if she will accept him as a paying guest. After some hesitation, she does provide him accommodation. Anil moves with her and her wheel-chair bound son, Ajay. Shanti's husband, Manohar, had abandoned her shortly after the birth of Ajay and she makes a living selling herbs and vegetables from her garden. Anil decides to marry her, and Shanti, after conferring with Dr. Mukesh and Komal, her friends, accepts, on the condition that she will not give birth to any more children, to which Anil agrees. After the marriage, whenever Anil attempts to get intimate, Shanti rejects him. Anil then attempts to kill Ajay, but Shanti prevents him and asks him to leave. A repentant Anil apologizes, the two get intimate, with Shanti then approaching Dr. Mukesh in an attempt to abort this child. She does give birth after being counseled by both Komal and Dr. Mukesh. As a result a healthy and normal son, Amar, is born. The family lives in harmony for the next 8 years, it is then that they decide to go for a holiday to Matheran, leaving Ajay in Komal's care. After their trip the family returns home to find out that Manohar has returned, and wants to see Ajay. Watch what impact this visit has on Ajay and the rest of the Sahani family.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?043439</url></doc>
