<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="043427">
  <docid>043427</docid>
  <title>Apna Bana Lo</title>
  <year>1982</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">12 March 1982</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Prakash, J. Om</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kumar, Jagdish</producer>
    <producer>Soorma, Vijay</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kudalkar, Laxmikant Shantaram</composer>
    <composer>Sharma, Pyarelal Ramprasad</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anand, Vikas</actor>
      <role>Juman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bedi, Rakesh</actor>
      <role>Hindle</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Choti, Mohan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dhawan, Sunil</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dubey, C.S.</actor>
      <role>Drunk</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Iyer, Kalpana</actor>
      <role>Paul's girlfriend</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jeetendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Master</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Shakti (I)</actor>
      <role>Paul</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Javed (I)</actor>
      <role>Tamasha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mehmood Jr.</actor>
      <role>Gutku</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Parashar, Deepak</actor>
      <role>Deepak</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, Amrish</actor>
      <role>Mr. Joshi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shivraj (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sunder (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Orphaned at a very young age, not aware of his religion nor his background, a young man is taken-in by a gangster and trained to accept crime as his career. This young man grows up to be a dreaded gangster himself by the name of Master. He works for another rich and powerful gangster by the name of Paul, who assigns him work for hefty fees. One day Master comes across an abandoned child, and decides to adopt the child. This changes his life, and he decides to go straight and give up on all criminal activities. That's when he finds out that getting honest employment is a lot more difficult that living a life of crime. Just when he is about to give up, he witnesses some men attempting to molest a woman, and he comes to her rescue. This woman is a well-known artiste by the name of Roopadevi, who decides to help Master out, and gives him a loan to open his own garage. When Paul attempts to bring Master back to his criminal world, Master turns him down. A few days later, the police raid Master's house and confiscate illicit drugs, and Master is arrested and held for trial. Roopa again helps Master out, but this time Master has made a new enemy - in the shape and form of Mr. Joshi, Roopa's mentor, who wants Roopa and her wealth for himself, and will do anything to get Master out of the way.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?043427</url></doc>
