<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="043997">
  <docid>043997</docid>
  <title>Aprilwetter</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Mona, Caterina</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Swiss German</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Switzerland</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Switzerland">2 July 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Germany">25 April 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Switzerland">14</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Hegelbach, Jeannine</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Imboden, Michael</producer>
    <producer>Gloor, Verena</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Hegelbach, Jeannine</writer>
    <writer>Teuwissen, Stephan</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Good, Alex</composer>
    <composer>Zeller, Patrik</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Born, Rouven</actor>
      <role>Lover 1</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maag, This</actor>
      <role>Ralph</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The slightly shy meteorologist Ralph, is secretly in love with his flatmate Annette. She only sees him as a good friend and leads a carefree lifestyle, having one affair after the other. While folding the laundry, Annette asks Ralph for the umpteenth time to leave her the apartment for the evening. He duly obliges and spends the evening traveling around the city by tram without destination, imagining fantasies of Annette and her lover that make him suffer. Suddenly, an attractive young woman sits down opposite him. She gives him the opportunity to break from his downward spiral. However, when he receives a text message from Annette, who asks him to come home, he lets this opportunity slip through his fingers. Annette is sitting at the kitchen table in a state of despair, as her lover did not show up. When Ralph appears, she asks him about the rain as a means of distraction. Ralph, quite the me-meteorologist, predicts the start of springtime and a real friend for her. They get closer and closer to each other and almost kiss. But as soon as her cell phone rings, everything seems to be lost. Later on, Annette and Ralph are lying in their respective beds. Annette receives a text message: the lover who stood her up apologizes and her world turns back to normal. Ralph, on the other hand, finds a pair of her panties in the pile of laundry on his bed. He looks at them briefly before throwing them into the laundry basket with a self-mocking smile on his face. Outside it starts snowing gently.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?043997</url></doc>
