<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="044734">
  <docid>044734</docid>
  <title>Archangel Thunderbird</title>
  <year>1998</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Davies, Kevin (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Leach, Chris (III)</producer>
    <producer>Luke, Tony</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Grant, Alan (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bradley, Doug (I)</actor>
      <role>Dr. Churchill</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bunting, Adrian</actor>
      <role>Rob Cainer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Daly, Eileen (I)</actor>
      <role>Miki Manson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deering, Jules</actor>
      <role>Wild haired technician</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fish, Martin</actor>
      <role>Heavy 1</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gaiman, Neil</actor>
      <role>Baal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McGhee, M.M.</actor>
      <role>Heavy 2</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This live-action/stop motion and CGI animated rarity was influenced by equal parts British B-horror films, television action adventure and Japanese anime. Dr. Churchill, a respected but reclusive scientist, uncovers evidence that the pre-Christian demons of ancient mythologies are real, and that they will return soon to reclaim the Earth as their own. He tries to warn the governments of the world, but is met with ridicule. His professional standing and credibility destroyed, he disappears. Later, his prediction comes true, as the gigantic extraterrestrials Baal and his consort Dygon descend on the world's capitols and begin the enslavement of humanity. Conventional militaries are unable to defend against the onslaught. All that stands between "The Anti-God" and the end of the world is Dr. Churchill and his covert resistance force of scientists and high-tech soldiers, DOOMSHIELD, aided by their secret weapon, an ancient magical semi-sentient mechanoid known as the Archangel Thunderbird. The vehicle requires a human pilot, but only someone with an incredibly rare psychological makeup can operate it. Enter Miki Manson, an extremely disturbed woman suffering from multiple personality disorder. The powers and abilities of the Archangel Thunderbird vary depending on which of Miki's personalities is in control when she enters the cockpit. Churchill and his assistants are challenged not just by the forces of Baal and Dygon, but also by the need to keep Miki under control so that she can continue to pilot the mechanoid.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?044734</url></doc>
