<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="045473">
  <docid>045473</docid>
  <title>Arkadius: Wild Orchid Dreams</title>
  <year>2000</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Poland">20 March 2000</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Magierski, Tomasz</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Allwood, Lucy (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Slesicki, Zbyszek</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>A 55 minute documentary telling the story of Arkadius, a boy who grew up under Communism in small-town Poland with the dream of becoming an artist. Combining stylish cinematography with content both humorous and moving, this fast-paced documentary traces his rise from seemingly hopeless beginnings to international celebrity and stardom in the West, as it follows the preparations for his first show at London Fashion Week, inspired by the erotic paintings of major British artist Allen Jones. Arkadius Weremczuk was born in Parczew, Poland, to strict parents who rejected his unorthodox longings for art and beauty. He was forced to study pedagogy, but finally rebelled, desperate to follow his dreams. He sold his few belongings to buy a one-way ticket to Italy, where he found work as a dishwasher in a beach hotel, working 80-hour weeks and sketching designs after midnight on kitchen napkins. At last he saved the money to buy a ticket to London, and gained acceptance to the prestigious St Martin's College. Supporting himself by sewing at night, he finally graduated top of his class, gained prestigious sponsorship from Swiss watch company Ebel, and acquired a clientele of British aristocrats and international catwalk fame for his outrageous original creations. WILD ORCHID DREAMS reveals Arkadius's roots in Parczew - his family recall how he was branded a weirdo in the town, and bullied for his crazy ideas. In Italy, the owners of the Alle Dune Hotel praise his hard work as a dishwasher. In striking contrast, we see Arkadius preparing the exotic creations for his first international catwalk show - selecting models, choosing make-up and luxury fabrics, and finally, starring dramatically in the show itself! He discusses art, seeing himself more as an artist than simply as a fashion designer, and arguing heatedly with his creative assistants about pricing and value. Interviews with British aristocrat and socialite Olga Polizzi, with the CEO of Ebel watches Sandro Arabian, and with his top London PR firm underline the contrast between the world he has left behind and the reality of his glittering future. Stunning footage of the clothes - ranging from the charming, to the sculptural, to the startlingly erotic - provides visual highlights to the narrative.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?045473</url></doc>
