<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="045543">
  <docid>045543</docid>
  <title>Armadillo</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Ruff, Jennifer</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Argentina</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Argentina">Unrated</certificate>
    <certificate country="USA">R</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">22 January 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Argentina">21</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Vidal, Cayetana</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Fantini Ortiz, Mercedes</producer>
    <producer>Perez Brancatto, Nazareno</producer>
    <producer>Walsh, Adam (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Vidal, Cayetana</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Cacivio, Diego</composer>
    <composer>Lopez, Juan Ignacio</composer>
    <composer>Tedesco, Jorge</composer>
    <composer>Zambrana, Sebastian</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Benegas, Ezequiel</actor>
      <role>Armadillo Boy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Calandrelo, Maria Fernanda</actor>
      <role>Verde</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Monteverde, Lucas</actor>
      <role>Antonio</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rivkin, Carlos</actor>
      <role>Don Tulio</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Verde is a fifteen years old virgin who lives in the flattest land in the world, in the middle of nowhere. She milks the cows, cooks for the workers and shoots morphine on her dying father. One morning the North wind arrives. Antonio, the main worker of the farm, finds an armadillo digging on a grave and knows that it is a bad sign. Verde just knows that it blows really hard and takes refuge on the chicken house, where she finds a mysterious wild boy. He does not talk, his hairy and has long nails. He seems harmless and Verde ends up trusting him. They get close to each other. The wind sneaks through a window awakens the instintcs of the boy: he jumps on her. She tries to escapes but the boy pulls the back of her poncho to make her stay and hurts the sides of her neck. Don Tulio notices the scratches and also, that there is no fresh milk as everyday. The only mention of the North wind makes him lock his daughter on the library. But no one can stop the forces of nature. Again Verde escapes and goes back to the chicken house, to tell the boy he is in danger. He does not listen, he just wants to play. Following an uncontrollable impulse, Verde kisses him. And they keep going until Antonio arrives looking for her. Behind the girl he sees an armadillo digging the ground, he tries to kick it but knocks the girl unconscious instead. Night falls. A creature advances in the night. Inside the house, the ritual has started. Men file its knives. Father wipes the forehead of the girl with a bloody handkerchief. She is tied up to a bed. "This is a hunt. You are the bait", says Father. That winter, Verde has bled for the first time and the North wind has brought, from the center of the earth, a beast to take her. It is all in a book of spells that Father is reading. An armadillo enters the room. He follows the odors of Verde. Father fights with it but he is too weak to handle the speed of its claws. Who is this being? Is he related to the boy in the chicken house? How this apocryphal legend will unravel? You will be surprised...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?045543</url></doc>
