<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="046119">
  <docid>046119</docid>
  <title>Arrival of Funeral Cortege at St. George's Chapel</title>
  <year>1901</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>News</genre>
  </genres>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">July 1901</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kaiser Wilhelm II</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>King Edward VII</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tsar Nicholas II</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The Horseshoe Cloisters at the foot of the steps up to the west door of St. George's Chapel is literally the journey's end. With the arrival of the gun carriage the open-air pageant that began so quietly at Osborne, closes in the same note of peace. A very picture of human life seems that procession of the dead -- so restful in the surroundings whence it started, to pass by and through packed streets, then this deserted cloister, empty of all sound till we seem to hear the murmur of the myriad London surging up from over the gray plains. Policemen guard either archways; the distant battlements are lined with spectators; occasionally a quaint old singing man flits on his way to take his place in the choir -- beyond that, no whisper, no stir. Then a flag company of foot guards enter the cloisters to occupy the semicircle of grass facing the steps, and the police are withdrawn. Worn out, and with the dry eyes of those who have no more tears to shed -- that was the picture of the principal mourners -- the King and Duke of Connaught -- as they stood surrounded by their royal kinsmen at the foot of the steps, white pall and crown were lifted away and the plain oak coffin was reverently hoisted to the shoulders of faithful Guardsmen. This the bier was born up the steps, the steepness of which, coupled with the tremendous weight of the coffin, made the last few yards of the progress very difficult. Very slowly the mourners mounted the wreath-lined way to the iron doors -- first the King and his only brother; then the German Emperor, the King of the Belgians, and the Kings of Greece and Portugal, the Crown Prince of Russia, whose face bears the bright tokens of a vigorous mind; the Czarewitch, young too and kindly; and many more from many kingly houses. Thus very, very slowly did they follow their kinswoman on her journey from the servitude of earth and pomp and kingship, through the iron gates she passes, a soul set free. This Film is the final and most impressive of all the many photographs we have secured of this historical pageant, and is the only animated photo secured within the walls of Windsor Castle, by special permission of the high authorities. It is unique, and of great historical value, inasmuch as this part of the ceremony was entirely private, none but the very highest personages being admitted within the cloisters. Photographically perfect.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?046119</url></doc>
