<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="046474">
  <docid>046474</docid>
  <title>Art, Poetry and Particle Physics</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Buckley, Justinian</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="UK">E</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">31 October 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">119</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>McMullen, Ken (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Berger, John (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Doser, Michael</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>John Berger is one of our most celebrated and respected writers and broadcasters. A former winner of the Booker Prize, he also wrote one of the most influential books on art of our time, Ways of Seeing, which became a landmark documentary series on BBC Television. In Ken McMullen's engaging and accessible film, Art, Poetry and Particle Physics, he travels to the world's biggest particle physics laboratory at CERN in Geneva. The film charts an extraordinary and wide-ranging series of discussions and collaborations between Berger and the leading theoretical and experimental physicists John March Russell and Michael Doser. Whether discussing particle physics, poetry, the development of the atom bomb, or the ghostly theft of a glove at the grave of the writer Jorge Luis Borges, Berger demonstrates why he is one of our foremost cultural figures as he brings an infectious and inspiring curiosity to each encounter to create a refreshingly accessible new perspective to our understanding of the value of science and culture today.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?046474</url></doc>
