<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="047326">
  <docid>047326</docid>
  <title>As for Me &amp; My House</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>hurricane-katrina</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">20 January 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Hilliard, Lionell</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Dancie, Kiana</producer>
    <producer>Hilliard, Lionell</producer>
    <producer>Mack, Jalene</producer>
    <producer>Von, Curtis</producer>
    <producer>Stuart, Kanita</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Hilliard, Lionell</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bellard, Anthony</actor>
      <role>Hakim</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ferguson, Toya</actor>
      <role>Salon Owner</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hildreth, Ashley</actor>
      <role>Imani</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jermany, Jennifer</actor>
      <role>Michelle</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kimbrough, Tjuan</actor>
      <role>Deuce</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mack, Jalene</actor>
      <role>Nicole</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Roma, Michael</actor>
      <role>Cab Driver</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sims, Rachon</actor>
      <role>Cameron</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Von, Curtis</actor>
      <role>Thomas</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A television sit-com about a blended Houston family coping with life after Hurricane Katrina, "As For Me and My House" follows the lives of single-parent sisters, Nicole and Michelle, and all their children. A modern take on the old 'Odd Couple' series from the 1970s, Nicole is a mid-30s attorney in Houston pursuing the position of partner with her law firm. At first glance, she seems to have it all together. She has the house, the car and two (2) kids in private school. But she raises them on 'happy meals' and 'blockbuster nights' because of her hectic work and socializing schedule. Her younger sister, Michelle, is a street-savvy hairstylist in New Orleans with three (3) children, all from different fathers. The irony is that, though her personal life decisions have been suspect since high school, Michelle's parenting skills far outweigh those of Nicole; as she is more hip and understands the latest teenage lingo, and is also a "tough love" disciplinarian. She also wields an uncanny respect (Nicole calls it fear) from her children often by shooting them that ever familiar mother's "look." When Hurricane Katrina claims Michelle's home, she does the obvious: With her kids in tow, she packs up her pressing combs, her tarot cards and her gumbo pot and makes the trek to H-town to move in with Nicole and her suburban family. Now both women must check their attitudes at the door and blend their differences of opinion, educational levels and authoritative styles into a flavorful, yet spicy blend of cultural gumbo. "As For Me and My House"... this ain't the Brady Bunch!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?047326</url></doc>
