<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="049571">
  <docid>049571</docid>
  <title>At This Moment</title>
  <year>1954</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Rogers, Harold</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>train</keyword>
    <keyword>railroad</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1954</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">26</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Kerbawy, Haford</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Monroe, Thomas</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Benavie, Samuel</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Allen, Mark (XXVI)</actor>
      <role>Mike Telfor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Beaman, John</actor>
      <role>Russ McGregor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Binkleman, Jack</actor>
      <role>Pete Simmons</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Englund, Pat</actor>
      <role>Kelly</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Genge, Paul</actor>
      <role>Ed Price</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gregory, James (I)</actor>
      <role>Bill Ritter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hall, Cliff (I)</actor>
      <role>Scotty</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kennedy, Bill (I)</actor>
      <role>Stranger</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Morris, Fred (II)</actor>
      <role>Johnny Duff</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A "short" documentary style, in that it does show real footage of real railroad workers in addition to the actors. At the end of the credits of the actors it says "and Operating personnel of The American Railroads." The purpose of the film is to stress the importance of railroads on the industry of America and the lives of every American. It is done by having a conversation taking place by several people in a small diner or restaurant. The person with the largest speaking part is James Gregory who became a famous Broadway, movie and TV actor. The waitress Kelly is played by Pat Englund who played in several TV shows and movies then seems to have dropped out of the business. The top billing was given to Cliff Hall as the diner owner, although he did not have the most lines. You may remember him as the president of the Racoon Lodge on The Honeymooners. The rest of the actors I did not know. The beginning of this film was cut off on the DVD where I found it. The DVD is for railroad buffs and has five vintage films about railroads from 1914 to 1954. This film started with Cliff Hall talking to a customer about railroad statistics and then goes to James Gregory explaining to two friends at a table how important the railroads are to the country's business. How he memorized all those figures I don't know, and then brought them off believable in his lines is a tribute to his abilities as an actor. Listening in to the conversation is a stranger who ends up being from the local television station. He pretends to be uninterested but ends up doing a TV show on the information. He sends the waitress a dozen roses and says he hopes she likes the TV show which is showing on the diner TV and IN COLOR! That surprised me for 1954. This show will be difficult for the average person to get unless they want to buy a two volume set of DVDs with railroad films. I took the time to write this because of the actors recognized and thought the information should be added to their list of accomplishments.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?049571</url></doc>
