<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="050154">
  <docid>050154</docid>
  <title>Atletu</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Frankel, Davey</editor>
    <editor>Mayer, Matt (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Biography</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>addis-ababa-ethiopia</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Amharic</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
    <country>Ethiopia</country>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">June 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Canada">August 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">85</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Frankel, Davey</director>
    <director>Lakew, Rasselas</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Argaw, Mesereta</producer>
    <producer>Ludwig, Susannah</producer>
    <producer>Ouwinga, Chris</producer>
    <producer>Frenschkowski, Michael</producer>
    <producer>Jensen, Lise Mette</producer>
    <producer>Tzenkova, Izabella</producer>
    <producer>Frankel, Davey</producer>
    <producer>Lakew, Rasselas</producer>
    <producer>Welch, Darryn</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Awake, Mikael Aemiro</writer>
    <writer>Frankel, Davey</writer>
    <writer>Lakew, Rasselas</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Meyer, Christian (X)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dessalegn, Abba Waka</actor>
      <role>The Priest</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gedmintas, Ruta</actor>
      <role>Charlotte</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lakew, Rasselas</actor>
      <role>Abebe Bikila</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Malmberg, Dag</actor>
      <role>Onni</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Running the streets of Rome in 1960, an unknown, barefooted Ethiopian man stunned the world by winning Olympic gold in the marathon. Overnight, Abebe Bikila became a sports legend. A hero in his own country and to the continent, Bikila was the first African to win a gold medal, and four years later in Tokyo would become the first person in history to win consecutive Olympic gold medals in the marathon. This soldier and quiet son of a shepherd would be acknowledged by many as the greatest long distance runner the world had ever known. One evening while returning to his home in Addis Ababa from training in the Ethiopian countryside, Bikila was involved in a tragic car accident which left him paralyzed from the waist down. Unable to walk and faced with the greatest challenge of his life, he struggled to maintain his will to live and in the process discovered a deeper meaning of competition, taking up archery for the Paralympics and competing as a handicapped dog sledder in Norway. Though his running career had come to a tragic end, the race of his life had a new beginning. For the first time, the true story of Bikila's epic quest for life and sport comes to the big screen. Not since Raging Bull has the life of an athlete been rendered with such emotional power and cinematic grace.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?050154</url></doc>
