<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="050621">
  <docid>050621</docid>
  <title>Attrition</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">16 November 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">61</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Joy, Anthony</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Boyd, Daniel</writer>
    <writer>Joy, Anthony</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>LaRocco, David</composer>
    <composer>Perkins, Chad (III)</composer>
    <composer>Treece, Steve</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carney, Ryan-Marie</actor>
      <role>Natalie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>DeForde, Tracy</actor>
      <role>Carrie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dziama, Susan</actor>
      <role>Jenny</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hendrickson, Kim (I)</actor>
      <role>Mother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Johnson, Sora Kim</actor>
      <role>Stacey</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kubach, Brian</actor>
      <role>Eric</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McBride, Aaron (II)</actor>
      <role>Johnathon</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mincey, James</actor>
      <role>Mike</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Radu, Nick</actor>
      <role>Brian</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wodoslawsky, Ted</actor>
      <role>Counselor</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A high school student, Jonathon, is in a cold and wintered forest - bloodied, bruised and fumbles to find a gun that he has stashed away. He loads the gun and begins to walk towards a group of other nearby high school students who are laughing and having fun in a park near school. He takes aim - ready to shoot, when a voice is heard asking him a question. The story then jumps into a scene where Jonathon is talking about his problems to what appears to be a counselor. The story moves through a series of flashbacks and flash-forwards showing Jonathon's life. When Jonathon notices a girl he likes, Jenny, he reinvests into what he thinks could be a happy relationship. However, as he is trying to dodge the bullies, he finds out that Jenny is not so interested in him after all, but is interested in fixing Jonathon up with someone else. With Jonathon's annoyance, he insults this girl as if he were a bully himself. When Jonathon ventures to talk to his parents, he discovers his mother having intercourse with another man, and now he is basically asked to hide this lie for the greater good of the family. When Jonathon's problems begin to multiply, he attempts to seek revenge, but ends up making the biggest regret of his life. A paranormal twist ending will attempt to make Jonathon realize what he has done is wrong, and give him a chance to regret his decision - or relive it.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?050621</url></doc>
