<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="050958">
  <docid>050958</docid>
  <title>Audience of One</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Henry, Kyle (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>minister</keyword>
    <keyword>number-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>religious</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">1 October 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Italy">13 June 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">16 February 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">88</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Jacobs, Mike (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Farbman, Alec</producer>
    <producer>Woods, Randy (III)</producer>
    <producer>Jacobs, Michael (IX)</producer>
    <producer>Sanders, Zack</producer>
    <producer>Woods, Matthew (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Forrest, Jeff</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Ten years ago, a Pentecostal pastor from San Francisco was praying on a mountain top when he received a vision from God to spread the Gospel through filmmaking. Using donations from his congregation, he slowly transformed his church into a fully functioning movie studio, and the production company Christian WYSIWYG Filmworks was born. After experimenting on a number of small projects, Pastor Richard Gazowsky announced that he and his WYSIWYG crew were going to make a film entitled, GRAVITY: THE SHADOW OF JOSEPH, a biblical science fiction movie that would redefine the Hollywood epic. AUDIENCE OF ONE is a documentary that chronicles the making of GRAVITY. This verite style film goes inside a Pentecostal church, where the charismatic Gazowsky leads his loyal cast and crew on an incredible journey that tests the limits of faith. From pre-production at their church, to shooting principal photography in Italy, to leasing an enormous studio on an island in the San Francisco Bay, AUDIENCE OF ONE keeps pace with an embattled church production who look to God in order to keep their dream alive. Full of humor and pathos, what transpires is a story of obsession, faith and delusion.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?050958</url></doc>
