<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="051369">
  <docid>051369</docid>
  <title>Aulad</title>
  <year>1987</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Sadanah, Vijay</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Chander (I)</producer>
    <producer>Sadanah, Vijay</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kudalkar, Laxmikant Shantaram</composer>
    <composer>Sharma, Pyarelal Ramprasad</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anand, Vikas</actor>
      <role>Barrister</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Asrani</actor>
      <role>Raja</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhushan, Bharat (I)</actor>
      <role>Doctor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deo, Ramesh</actor>
      <role>Doctor Ramesh Chander</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jaffrey, Saeed</actor>
      <role>Anand's chacha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jayapradha</actor>
      <role>Yashoda</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jeetendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Anand</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Krishna, Manmohan</actor>
      <role>Vicky's dad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumari, Lalita</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mehra, Vinod</actor>
      <role>Vicky (Guest Appearance)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Murad</actor>
      <role>Gipsy Oldman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sharma, Abhimanyu</actor>
      <role>Barrister</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Anand (Jeetendra) and Devki (Sridevi) on one hand, and Yashoda (Jaya Pradha) and Vicky (Vinod Mehra) on the other, have recently married. While Devki has a child, Yashoda is expecting. The two couples meet in a train journey, which is ill-fated as it collides with another train. Devki is nowhere to be found, and Anand believes she is dead. Vicky is dead, and Yashoda is devastated. To confound matters more, Yashoda loses her child. Anand feels sorry for Yashoda and has the doctor switch his baby for the dead one. Yashoda returns to her home and her in-laws with Anand's child, while Anand re-locates abroad. Several years later, Anand returns and is unable to keep away from Yashoda and her child. He repeatedly keeps on visiting them, to the extent that his visits get to be a nuisance, and an embarrassment. Then Anand gets a shock when he comes to know that Devki is alive. He is overjoyed to see Devki. But when Devki asks about their child, he tells her the truth, and then begins a tussle between Devki and Yashoda, over who could be the better mother, to such an extent that both are prepared to sue each other publicly in Court.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?051369</url></doc>
