<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="051911">
  <docid>051911</docid>
  <title>Autobahn</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Albrecht, Conny</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>German</language>
    <language>Russian</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Germany">8 November 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Germany">15</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Werner, Bartosz</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Krbetschek, Benjamin</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Burgazliev, Denis</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kanischtscheff, Waléra</actor>
      <role>Sergej</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Simontowitz, Ulrich</actor>
      <role>Dieter Strehlke</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Werner, Simon</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Los Angeles cop Coyle (Michael Keaton) and his partner Dickey are sent to retrieve German racecar driver and criminal HANS ULRICH from Germany and bring him back to LA. On their way to the airport to return to LA their car is ambushed, Ulrich is taken, and Dickey is killed. Meanwhile, two masked gunmen storm a German hospital and escape with Reznor, a police-guarded assassin. Coyle determines that he is going to complete his assignment and avenge Dickey's death by recapturing his prisoner and taking him to LA. Alone in a country completely foreign to him, Coyle must use all of his skill to battle the forces behind both breakouts and come to understand their connection. The truth is that Ulrich has been kidnapped against his will by European terrorists to drive Reznor to Switzerland to assassinate a political leader. The police and the Euro Security Agency, aware of the grave consequences if Reznor makes it past the border, are willing to sacrifice Coyle in order to take out Reznor. Coyle's search brings him into contact with Greta, Ulrich's ex-girlfriend, and leads him on a chase through the streets and nightclubs of Berlin. The chase quickly moves to the high-speed world of the autobahn where the only real speed limit is your own fear. On the autobahn, Coyle must match Ulrich's top-notch driving, elude the Euro Security Agency, while trying to avoid an avalanche and multiple gunmen in order to recapture his prisoner and avenge Dickey's death.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?051911</url></doc>
