<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="051937">
  <docid>051937</docid>
  <title>Autochrome</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Astbury, Jake</editor>
    <editor>Mitchell, Helena (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>autochrome</keyword>
    <keyword>revolution</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">February 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">72</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Astbury, Jake</producer>
    <producer>Mitchell, Helena (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Mitchell, Helena (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Astbury, Jake</actor>
      <role>Terra Miller</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mitchell, Helena (II)</actor>
      <role>Isabella Berretta</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Not all revolutionaries wear camo.... Isabella Berretta: Artist, sophisticate and would-be terrorist. A Londoner through and through, her contempt for the city runs as deep as her passion for it. Isabella decides to take drastic measures to convey her ideas to the people of present day London - a dark video diary in which her world of sex, cigarettes and intended revolution are captured in 24 recordings each representing one hour of her day. Her true intention for the piece is slowly revealed as time is reversed to retrace the steps of this dangerously provocative woman. Isabella effortlessly moves between her imagined plots to overthrow the city and its establishment and her most intimate thoughts as a Londoner, as an artist and as a woman. Isabella's post-millennium mentality converges with her Googled intelligence to weave a sometime-dangerous ideology. She chooses when the camera records her actions to create her dark video masterpiece - or does she? As the story re-folds the intentions of the hired filmmaker become ambiguous; is his curiosity understandable or underhanded? Can the trust of a woman so untrusting be exploited? As Londoners we live in dangerous times. Autochrome is 24 times a revolution.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?051937</url></doc>
