<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="052063">
  <docid>052063</docid>
  <title>Autopsy 8: Dead Giveaway</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Ginsberg, Arthur</editor>
    <editor>Philip, Andrew</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">TV-MA</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">7 April 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Ginsberg, Arthur</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Sweet, Jesse</producer>
    <producer>Monet, Gaby</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Baden, Michael</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gunness, Belle</actor>
      <role>Belle</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Homolka, Karla</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hughes, Christy Lee</actor>
      <role>Karla Homolka</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McGuire, Bryan Michael</actor>
      <role>Detective Kelly</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Eighth in the series of HBO's hit documentary series examining the methods and means by which forensic experts help solves seemingly unsolvable crimes. Segment 1: "Pure Evil" is the story of a 15 year-old girl who suddenly died on Christmas Eve while drinking with her sister and her boyfriend. But toxicology turns up a pattern when another girl is found encased in blocks of cement. Segment 2: "The Lady Vanishes" is the tale of Denise Eckersley who apparently vanished and then committed suicide. But saliva on the stamp of her suicide note leads forensic scientists to another conclusion. Segment 3: "Mail Rape" examines Anthony Turner who was convicted of raping three woman. Proclaiming his innocence, he fails to realize that the DNA evidence is ironclad. Segment 4: "The Bloodhound of Detroit" tells the story of a dismembered body found in a grease trap and how a dog trained to find hidden traces of blood lead authorities to the killer. Segment 5: "The Medicine Man" opens the mystery of how a healthy woman suddenly died of heart failure and how her doctor husband, who claimed he was helping her sleep, needed her dead. Segment 6: "The Belle of Them All" is the 100 year-old case of an elderly woman who was arrested in 1931 for the murders of her children and 10 men on her pig farm. Living at the turn of the century as Belle Gunness she led men to her home via a lonely-hearts ad where she butchered them and then disappeared after a fire destroyed her home.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?052063</url></doc>
