<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="052795">
  <docid>052795</docid>
  <title>Avtaar</title>
  <year>1983</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">11 March 1983</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Kumar, Mohan (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kumar, Mohan (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kudalkar, Laxmikant Shantaram</composer>
    <composer>Sharma, Pyarelal Ramprasad</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Azmi, Shabana</actor>
      <role>Radha Krishen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grewal, Ranjan</actor>
      <role>Anwar R. Ahmed</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grover, Gulshan</actor>
      <role>Chandan Krishen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hangal, A.K.</actor>
      <role>Rashid Ahmed</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Pinchoo</actor>
      <role>Seth Laxminarayan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khanna, Rajesh</actor>
      <role>Avtaar Krishen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Sujit (I)</actor>
      <role>Bawaji</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Malini, Madhu</actor>
      <role>Zubeida A. Ahmed</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Parvez, Yunus</actor>
      <role>Paan wala</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, Madan (I)</actor>
      <role>Seth Jugal Kishore (Guest Appearance)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, Shashi</actor>
      <role>Ramesh Krishen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sachin (I)</actor>
      <role>Sewak</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shivraj (I)</actor>
      <role>Gopal</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Avtaar Krishen lives a poor lifestyle with his wife, Radha, and two sons, Ramesh and Chander. He works in a factory and toils hard so that his sons can get the necessary education, and live a better lifestyle. He gets injured and crippled while working, but is compensated adequately by his employer, Bawaji. Years later his sons have grown up. While Ramesh has married Sudha and works with a bank; Chander is wooing Renu, the only daughter of wealthy Seth Laxminarayan. When Avtaar and Radha wish to go on a tirathyatra (pilgrimage), they ask Ramesh to book tickets for them, but he tells them that he has no money. When Radha gets sick, their servant, Sewak, enters Sudha's room to get some money for her treatment, as a result Radha does get treatment, but Sudha blames them for stealing her money. Avtaar asks Ramesh and his wife to get out, only to find out that the house is now in Sudha's name. AVtaar, Radha and Sewak move out and live in a shanty hut. Their hopes are with Chander, who does well in his exams, decides to marry Renu, and moves out without financially assisting his parents. Now Avtaar and Radha are elderly and dependent on Sewak, and the question remains will they resign themselves to this existence, if not, what possibly can a crippled older male accomplish, especially at this time in his life?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?052795</url></doc>
