<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="053817">
  <docid>053817</docid>
  <title>B.S.</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Halvorson, Gary</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hartle, David</producer>
    <producer>Grazer, Brian</producer>
    <producer>Klarik, Jeffrey</producer>
    <producer>Krantz, Tony (I)</producer>
    <producer>Amodeo, John</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Klarik, Jeffrey</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bagley, Lorri</actor>
      <role>Hope Fisk</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Echikunwoke, Megalyn</actor>
      <role>Shannon Cross</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Horrigan, Sam</actor>
      <role>Shovel and Rake Guy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Josepher, Wendle</actor>
      <role>Waitress</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McClintock, Eddie</actor>
      <role>Steven Goldstein</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The "BS" in question is the Fisk Academy, a small girl's boarding school in the woods of Vermont. It's a place where most of the learning doesn't take place in the classroom. The action centers on the four residents of Maple House. Away from parents and watched over only by their housemother Hope, who is perpetually on the verge of an emotional collapse, these fifteen year-old girls are forced to make their own rules and grow themselves up. There's Pepper, the former Olympic gymnast who after years of Olympic training is determined to taste life (which is why she's packed on forty pounds since the games in Sydney), Shannon, the cynical, authority resisting wild girl who's already been kicked out of eight boarding schools. Dana, who is searching to find her true self - a lapsed vegetarian, now and aspiring lesbian, next year who knows? And Andy, the most centered and mature of the girls, who on her first day at school ends up accidentally making out with her history teacher. This ain't no "Facts Of Life", kids. Rounding out this twisted world is Steven, the aforementioned twenty-four year-old history teacher who finds himself falling for one of his students. Then there's the school's seventeen year-old groundskeeper, known only as "The Shovel and Rake Guy". How would you like to be the only available guy within miles? It's nice to be him. And finally, Dr. Fisk, the headmaster of the school, whose only goal in life is to play golf and keep his girls out of jail. Fisk Academy is a wild, raucous world where anything can happen. And that's no B.S....</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?053817</url></doc>
