<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="054000">
  <docid>054000</docid>
  <title>Ba hai hong ying</title>
  <year>1992</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>Cantonese</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Hong Kong</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Germany">18</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">96</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Wing Siu, Stanley</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chin, Kar Lok</actor>
      <role>Paul</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ha, James</actor>
      <role>Sen's Partner</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Cynthia</actor>
      <role>Chin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>King, Mark (I)</actor>
      <role>Assassin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lee, Moon</actor>
      <role>Feng</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lee, Waise</actor>
      <role>Hsiong</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Chin is a cop with the Beijing military police who is in love with an artist named Hsiong. Hsiong is also connected with some local Triad figures and after a deal with another gang to buy a priceless Japanese painting ends up with a brutal gun battle, Hsiong killed one of the Beijing cops in self-defense. Chin leaves the force and searches for Hsiong, who might be in Hong Kong in an attempt to reunite with him. Then there's Feng, a tough Chinese girl who's older brother is the leader of the Triad that Hsiong worked with. It turns out that Feng and Hsiong also have a love thing going on, but when her brother died and Hsiong disappeared she was all alone. But on a particular night, Feng meets Chin when a bunch of thugs take Chin's picture of Hsiong away from her and the girls unleash their martial arts skill on the thugs. Chin and Feng become good friends and Chin stays with Feng at her condo. But things get hectic for Feng when she gets into a fight with her brother's Japanese wife Sen and is asked to turn state's evidence. Feng doesn't trust Sen because of her Japanese nationality and she thinks Sen is a gold-digging leech. Also, Sen has a personal vendetta against Hsiong. When she tried to sleep with him, Hsiong told Feng's brother and for her unfaithful behavior, Feng's brother beats her and scars her back. Sen wants revenge on Hsiong and will hurt anyone who tries to help him. Finally, Paul, a silly Hong Kong cop is thrown into the mix to protect Feng and Chin from Sen's thugs and Oshima, a Japanese agent is called in to retrieve the Japanese painting that Hsiong had, as it contains secrets from World War II that the Chinese government mustn't get ahold of. When Sen and Oshima meet, they decide to form an alliance and Chin and Hsiong finally reunite with each other, which made Feng kind of jealous. But Chin and Hsiong's happy reunion will have to wait, as Sen and her Triad thugs finally corner them and are intent on making Hsiong suffer the same pain Sen suffered. Together with Paul and Feng, the group starts a full-scale war with guns, followed by an all-out martial arts brawl with both sides using anything they can get their hands on. But when the smoke does clear though, which side will be left standing? No matter who wins, neither side will be taking prisoners. Then and only then will there be no retreat and no surrender.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?054000</url></doc>
