<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="059822">
  <docid>059822</docid>
  <title>Barierata</title>
  <year>1979</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Dimitrova, Elena (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>based-on-novel</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Bulgarian</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Bulgaria</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="East Germany">30 January 1981</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Bulgaria">11 November 1979</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Soviet Union">August 1979</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">148</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Christov, Christo (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>S. Kirov, Kiril</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Vezhinov, Pavel</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Tsibulka, Kiril</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bachvarov, Lyubomir</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barakova, Yevgeniya</actor>
      <role>Saprugata</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dimcheva, Maria</actor>
      <role>D-r Yurukova</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Georgiev, Dimitar (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Janev, Panaiot</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kirova, Konsantza</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kondov, Ivan</actor>
      <role>Sledovatelyat</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Smoktunovsky, Innokenti</actor>
      <role>Antoni Manev</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stoyanov, Gueorgui (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In this picture, the barrier epitomizes the line between reality and dreams, the pattern of harmony and happiness. The delicate, pretty, sensitive Dorotea and the sedate middle-aged composer Antoni meet by chance. He gives her shelter in his house. Famous composer falls under the spell of young Dorothea: A pretty, thin-skinned, though quite an eccentric girl. Antoni becomes the witness of a series of strange and wonderful events. She is maintaining she is able to fly, drawing him into her half real world, when miracles are worked. It turns out that Dorotea has the supernatural gift of divining and forecasting people thoughts and intentions. Gradually Antoni overcomes his initial confusion and becomes used to the parapsychological states of the girl. He penetrates her acutely sensitive inner world where the supernatural becomes natural and the impossible possible. And when he learns that Dorotea can fly, he joins her and flies with her. During this experiment he feels a surge of creativity and happiness for the first time in many years. Is all this real or imaginary? Embarrassed, as he is, he leaves on a short trip, and when finally resolved to come back to her, it is too late. Why is it that Dorotea is found dead apparently having fallen after one of her flights?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?059822</url></doc>
