<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="060582">
  <docid>060582</docid>
  <title>Basmati Blues</title>
  <year>2011</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <genres>
    <genre>Musical</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2011</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Baron, Dan (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>James, Judith (I)</producer>
    <producer>Caulfield, Monique</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Baron, Dan (II)</writer>
    <writer>Dorchen, Jeff</writer>
    <writer>Thompson, Danny (IX)</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Basmati Blues is a musical comedy set in the rice fields of India and the boardrooms of Manhattan. It's an American movie, but we steal liberally from the fun, energetic Bollywood style. This is an international film that successfully combines a Western sense of humor and story with the rich, pulsating energy of Bollywood. On one level this is a comic love-triangle, on another it is a story torn from today's headlines - a story about globalization and what happens when a multinational agribusiness company makes greed and profits its only guiding principal. The film utilizes character humor, physical comedy and some full-on musical numbers, melding into a kind of Moulin Rouge meets Network...meets the Holy Grail. Linda is a post-grad scientist who, along with her father, invented a genetically modified rice while working for an agribusiness company. She doesn't realize that the rice that works so well in her lab is not suited for third world farmers - people are not her department. Henry Gorgon, her CEO, wants to use her innocence to win the locals in India over to this new Rice9. Linda doesn't realize she's Gorgon's pawn, that she's been sent to put a friendly face to this new rice that will ultimately mean financial ruin for small farmers. In India everyone in the village welcomes Linda except Rajit, a hot-headed but warm-hearted son of a local farmer who just dropped out of college because he ran out of tuition. He's an idealistic college kid, at that age where he thinks he knows everything, which makes him insufferable, and fun to tease. Initially he's attracted to Linda - but she represents everything he thinks he should hate - she's white and foreign and rich. Completing the love triangle, Linda falls for William, a dashing but duplicitous local preppy, son of the one prosperous farmer in town - a pampered kid who never fit in. He sees Linda as his way out of this one elephant town. Rajit figures out the rice is bad for the locals, but he's alienated most of the town and lacks credibility. Eventually William also learns the rice has a dark side, but he's wooed by Gorgon into selling out the farmers - rationalizing it in the name of "progress" and a cushy job in Manhattan. The stage is set. Rajit and Linda, who belong together, fight with each other. William and Linda, who don't belong together, are drawing closer. And Linda, who came to India to help, is actually bringing doom. The fate of the village rests on whether Linda and Rajit can quit arguing long enough to admit they love each other and save the day. Tension builds to a climactic confrontation between the villagers and Gorgon's goons. Everyone has to make a decision: which side are they on?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?060582</url></doc>
