<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="061768">
  <docid>061768</docid>
  <title>Be Sharp See Flat</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Woon, Jack</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Musical</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>New Zealand</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="New Zealand">10 October 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="New Zealand">80</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Woon, Jack</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Woon, Jack</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Woon, Jack</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barraud, Elizabeth</actor>
      <role>Jocelyn</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Driver, Alistair James</actor>
      <role>Cameron</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Haycock, Keitha</actor>
      <role>Lisa</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Withey, C.J.</actor>
      <role>William</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Cameron, an aimless University student, decides to try his hand at a beginner's music course. However, due to a fortunate case of bureaucratic mix-up, he is accepted into the highly competitive Master's Class. Along comes a beautiful and gifted student, Lisa. Though Cameron is shown the door when the class discovers that he has no musical background, Lisa stands by him, seeing some sort of talent within him. With her encouragement, Cameron improves at an incredible speed, astounding everyone around him. Could this be Cameron's new dream? Cameron begins to realise his feelings for Lisa. One night, in an oddball date at a dark park, they are violently attacked by muggers. Cameron escapes with a few bruises, but Lisa ends up losing her hearing completely. Lisa locks herself away, depressed that she can no longer hear her own music, while Cameron struggles to find a way to help her. As the final concert draws near, Cameron is caught between his concern for Lisa and his newfound dream of studying music. In the end, he decides to sacrifice his chance in the concert to compose and play a song for Lisa. But will it ever reach her?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?061768</url></doc>
