<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="062365">
  <docid>062365</docid>
  <title>Beautiful Armenians</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Salibian, Tamar</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>armenian</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Armenian</language>
    <language>Arabic</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Armenia">15 May 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">59</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Salibian, Tamar</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Adamian, Ara</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bezjian, Nigol</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ekizian, Nardouhi</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Libaridian, Gerard</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Margosian, Roubina</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Margosian, Shogher</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Margossian, Zela</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Salibian, Ohannes</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>My name is Tamar Salibian. My parents are Armenian immigrants from the Middle East. I was born in the United States and raised both as an Armenian and an American. I often feel as though I am somewhere in-between two cultures, fiercely Armenian on the inside - attached to my family history and culture, but American as well. I wish to find other Armenian individuals who, like myself, live somewhere in the 'in-between.' Through interviews with various Armenian individuals, time spent with my own family and travel within the United States and the Middle East, I question what constitutes culture, how families communicate, and how we can hold on to our memories without allowing them to define us completely. The film moves chronologically, beginning with my trip from Los Angeles to the East Coast to visit my family. I return to the West Coast and subsequently travel to the Middle East to visit my grandmother, make my first trip to Lebanon, and eventually arrive at a point where I begin to accept my place within various cultures. Beautiful Armenians features candid moments with my family, interviews with close friends and relatives, and an interview with political consultant Gerard J. Libaridian that is referenced throughout the film.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?062365</url></doc>
