<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="062493">
  <docid>062493</docid>
  <title>Beautiful Things</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>new-york-city</keyword>
    <keyword>nudity</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>female-nudity</keyword>
    <keyword>love</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">31 January 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">86</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Obenson, Tambay Amadi</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Obenson, Tambay Amadi</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Obenson, Tambay Amadi</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Antoinette, Cecelia</actor>
      <role>Schola's Mother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brown, Hallie</actor>
      <role>Schola</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brown, Monifa Fola</actor>
      <role>Gabe's Sister</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Elliott, Danielle Georgette</actor>
      <role>Female Dating Ad Voiceover #1</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Obenson, Tambay Amadi</actor>
      <role>Gabe</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Life as it happens - the film's tag line - says it all. This slice-of-life film is a meditation on love and happiness. Schola and Gabe are two young artists (she an actress and he a filmmaker) struggling to make some inroads into their respective careers, while working to bring an end to the loneliness they feel as single adults in a big city. Schola and Gabe eventually cross paths on a subway train, and soon begin an instructive, romantic relationship. The film takes us through various stages of the relationship and is divided into four appropriately-labeled chapters, indicating the four stages of a relationship - from the first meeting, to the early novelty phase, continuing on as the novelty wears off and potential problems set in, and ending with a matter of choice of whether to continue on or to separate. Long contemplative shots follow the two characters as they live and grow, alone and together. The startling black and white grainy digital video photography of the film enhances its realism, and the New York City backdrop adds to its distinct persona. Made up of a series of illuminating, connecting vignettes, BEAUTIFUL THINGS believes in the power of love to conquer all.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?062493</url></doc>
