<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="062603">
  <docid>062603</docid>
  <title>Beauty and the Beast</title>
  <year>1993</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>prince</keyword>
    <keyword>beauty</keyword>
    <keyword>anime</keyword>
    <keyword>evil-fairy</keyword>
    <keyword>beautiful-girl</keyword>
    <keyword>based-on-novel</keyword>
    <keyword>magic-spell</keyword>
    <keyword>beast</keyword>
    <keyword>fairy-tale</keyword>
    <keyword>princess</keyword>
    <keyword>based-on-fairy-tale</keyword>
    <keyword>curse</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Japan</country>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Brazil">Livre</certificate>
    <certificate country="Spain">T</certificate>
    <certificate country="UK">Uc</certificate>
    <certificate country="New Zealand">G</certificate>
    <certificate country="USA">G</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Spain">1993</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">1993</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">49</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <writers>
    <writer>Grimm, Jacob</writer>
    <writer>Olesker, Jack</writer>
    <writer>de Beaumont, Jeanne-Marie Leprince</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bright, Kellie</actor>
      <role>Beauty</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cara, Irene</actor>
      <role>Beauty</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Connery, Jason (I)</actor>
      <role>The Beast</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hordern, Michael</actor>
      <role>Monsieur Du Bois</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lee, Christopher (I)</actor>
      <role>Monsieur Renard</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Based on the classic fairy tale by the Brothers Grimm, Beauty lives a happy life in the city with her father and four siblings helping and spending time with the less fortunate. That is, until the day her father finds himself in an enormous debt after the great loss of his cargo ships in the China Sea. The whole family moves to a small cottage in the country and day after day the three men, the old man and his two sons, Robert and Nathan, must work in the fields. One day, the old man receives news that one of his ships had survived, but when he arrives at the harbor, he finds that nothing valuable was saved and that his family remains in poverty. On his way home, the old man gets lost in the forest and finds a magnificent castle where he spends the night. He remembers the promise he had made to his daughter, she had asked for one simple rose, so the man cuts a rose from the many rose bushes in the castle gardens. However, as soon as the rose is cut, a horrible beast appears and tells him that he must die for having cut the rose. The old man tells about the request of his daughter, Beauty, and the beast tells him that he shall return home and bring his daughter to die instead. Though the man will rather sacrifice himself, Beauty insists on being the one who must die and arrives at the castle. Beauty spends many months at the castle waiting for her end to come, but instead, she develops a great friendship with the once terrible beast, that eventually turns to love.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?062603</url></doc>
