<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="062931">
  <docid>062931</docid>
  <title>Bedard Zamana Kya Jane</title>
  <year>1959</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Khade, Ram</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Mistri, Babubhai</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Desai, Manmohan</producer>
    <producer>Desai, Subhash</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Shah, Kalyanji Veerji</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chicoo, Master</actor>
      <role>Ramesh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Helen (I)</actor>
      <role>Dancer/Singer at OK Club</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Iftekhar</actor>
      <role>Public Prosecutor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jalil, Jabeen</actor>
      <role>Radha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Karnataki, Amirbai</actor>
      <role>Ashok's Bhabhi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Ashok (I)</actor>
      <role>Barrister Ashok</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Sudesh (I)</actor>
      <role>Advocate Mohan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pran (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shaikh (I)</actor>
      <role>Kavender</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Widower Barrister Ashok lives a wealthy lifestyle in Bombay, India along with his sister-in-law, and a young son, Ramesh. One day while driving, he accidentally runs over a woman, brings her home, cares for her until she recuperates and tells him that her name is Kamla and is homeless. He finds that Ramesh likes her, so he marries her. After a few months, he is delighted when she becomes pregnant. This delight sours considerably when he finds out through his friend, Pran, that Kamla had been frequenting the OK Club. Then he witnesses her abusing Ramesh. Finally, he drives her out when Ramesh is killed by poisoned milk. Kamla gives birth to a baby boy but Ashok takes over sole custody and names him Mohan. Years later Mohan has grown up and is now an advocate and is in love with a girl named Radha. Even though Radha comes from a poor background, Ashok has no objections and goes to meet with her parents to arrange their marriage. Watch what happens when he finds out that Radha's mother is none other Kamla.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?062931</url></doc>
