<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="063152">
  <docid>063152</docid>
  <title>Been Down That Muddy Road: The Legend of Joe Barry</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Acutt, Robin</editor>
    <editor>Carimi, Carol</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">8 August 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">70</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Carimi, Carol</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Friedman, Reena</producer>
    <producer>Fry, Rebekah</producer>
    <producer>Acutt, Robin</producer>
    <producer>Carimi, Carol</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Carimi, Carol</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Barry, Joe (IX)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barry, Joe (IX)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dr. John</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Joe Barry, the man Billboard called, "the most legendary rock and roller you've never heard of", was as synonymous with bad behavior as he was for his Louisiana swamp pop chart hits. Few know the tortured man behind the music who gave it all up at the height of pop stardom to pursue careers as diverse as pimp, preacher and mercenary.Few knew the tortured man behind the music, who struggled with personal and professional demons, giving up on music several times to pursue careers as diverse as pimp, preacher and mercenary. He threw punches and received them, shot others and got shot, was bitten by the snake and then spread the Word of God. But he always returned to his roots - the bayou country of Southern Louisiana, where he built his first guitar out of a discarded cigar box. This documentary weaves the stories of his songs into the colorful tapestry of a remarkable life. It transports you back in time to a place that is gone forever - the richly-colorful 1950's and 60's music scene of South Louisiana, Southeast Texas and New Orleans. A time when American rock and roll was forming and rules were begging to be broken. Years of reckless living took its toll on Joe's body. But these years held stories which he ached to tell one last time. In 2002, Tuff City Records moved a studio into his living room. Joe's failing health forced him to limit his singing to one minute intervals - the album took two long years to complete. But Barry vowed to finish it, even if it was the last thing he did. Rolling Stone Magazine says of the album: "On this wonderful return, Barry is in old school form... singing with tender, fighting soul."</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?063152</url></doc>
