<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="063366">
  <docid>063366</docid>
  <title>Before the Light Turns Green</title>
  <year>2000</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>color-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">13 April 2000</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">109</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Bolger, John Michael (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kattman, Dan</producer>
    <producer>Bolger, T. Michael</producer>
    <producer>Mueller, Richard O.</producer>
    <producer>Bolger, John Michael (II)</producer>
    <producer>Maxwell, Drew</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bolger, John Michael (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bergan, Christine</actor>
      <role>Kate</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Boudreaux, Beau</actor>
      <role>Jack - successful</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brosnan, KT</actor>
      <role>Dancer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Budd, Ben (II)</actor>
      <role>Jack, an artist</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Casper, Kevin</actor>
      <role>Jack's friend</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gager, Walter</actor>
      <role>Optometrist</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gannon, James (IV)</actor>
      <role>Shadow Jack (banking customer)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gillis, Richard (IV)</actor>
      <role>ER Doctor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pickering, James (I)</actor>
      <role>Jack - homeless</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pincus, David (IV)</actor>
      <role>Jack's tormentor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wegner, Michael</actor>
      <role>Jack - drunk</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>An artist, named Jack, receives a threatening prank phone call. The caller says ominously: "Hello. My name is Jack. I'm going to kill you." Thereafter, Jack begins to meet various people from all walks of life, all of whom are named Jack and seem to know him. Meanwhile, Jack attempts to complete a portrait of his girlfriend, but prior to finishing it, she breaks up with him. Jack begins to see visions of a stalker, and he begins to have terrible headaches, which seem to occur behind his eye and which effect his vision. Believing he's losing his vision (and possibly his sanity as well), he sees an optometrist, who is unable to help him. His work (as a teller at a bank) begins to suffer, and he keeps receiving threatening phone calls. After seeing his girlfriend on a date with a man named Jack, who is arrogant and successful, Jack gets in a fight. He subsequently stumbles into a street and is hit by a car. After recuperating from his injuries, he begins a new painting, a self-portrait. The painting is the key to Jack's metaphysical problems. Shot in color and black and white, the film converts to color when we see Jack's impressive artistic work. The film is a mix of drama and comedy in a neo-noir setting; it blends metafilm with psychodrama as the protagonist, Jack, is haunted by dopplegangers and beset by ailment.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?063366</url></doc>
