<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="064141">
  <docid>064141</docid>
  <title>Being Dad</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Palmeiro, Marlene</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>fatherhood</keyword>
    <keyword>maternity</keyword>
    <keyword>motherhood</keyword>
    <keyword>inspiration</keyword>
    <keyword>pregnancy</keyword>
    <keyword>husband-wife-relationship</keyword>
    <keyword>parenting</keyword>
    <keyword>prenatal</keyword>
    <keyword>information</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">7 October 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">78</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Marsh, Leslie</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hastwell, Tom</producer>
    <producer>Holt, Sam</producer>
    <producer>Jones, Troy (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jones, Troy (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>BEING DAD, provides valuable advice and experiences for dads-to-be from fathers who've recently gone through the pregnancy/delivery process. There's also a wealth of advice and information from several experts to help prepare expectant dads. The DVD features more than 40 remarkably honest dads from all around the country and all walks of life. Covering everything from how they first found out about the pregnancy right through to birth, it explores a broad range of subjects, including many rarely discussed openly like miscarriage and sex during pregnancy. The film reveals the fears, anxieties and joys that every first-time father lives through. Engaging, enlightening, entertaining and candidly truthful, BEING DAD offers anecdotal looks at the poignant, the funny and enjoyable sides of everything an expectant Dad experiences. The film's goals are threefold: 1) To help men better understand how to help and support their wives during pregnancy; 2) To stimulate discussion between couples; and 3) To bring peace of mind and reassurance to dads-to-be by dispelling any uncertainties or concerns. Though focusing on men, the Being Dad DVD is also invaluable for moms-to-be by giving them a glimpse into the mindset of men that often isn't seen or shared with their partners.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?064141</url></doc>
