<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="064184">
  <docid>064184</docid>
  <title>Being Ozzy Osbourne</title>
  <year>2000</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Fanucci, Agita</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>osbourne</keyword>
    <keyword>malkovich</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2 February 2000</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">14</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Schrader, David</director>
    <director>Stratton, Christy</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Schrader, David</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Schrader, David</writer>
    <writer>Stratton, Christy</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Stout, Damon</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Escudier, Bill</actor>
      <role>Ozzy Osbourne</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kalman, Jaime</actor>
      <role>Dottie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Messer, Kenny</actor>
      <role>Dr. Howser</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Schrader, David</actor>
      <role>Greg Schwartzkopf</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Being Ozzy Osbourne is a different spin on the found-a-mind-portal-into-somebody's-brain formula made so popular by BJM. Greg is a semi-talented but listless sock puppeteer. His aggressively frumpy wife Dotte presses him to take a temp job at a mysteriously oblique shredding company called Howser Corp. Once there, he immediately falls in love with his mean-spirited coworker, an icy vixen named Maureen. Later that day, Greg discovers a cardboard portal behind the shredder which leads directly into the troubled, tripping mind of wobbly rock star Ozzy Osbourne. After five minutes, he's unceremoniously dumped onto Forest Lawn Drive next to the 134 Freeway. Greg tells Maureen, who quickly whips up a plan to sell tickets. Things happen fast in this short, loving homage to a great comedy. It culminates in a bizarre love triangle that explores the complexities of human behavior, the metaphysical implications of mind-inhabitation and just all-around logic-defiance. Shot over a weekend immediately after the November release of Being John Malkovich, this film made the rounds in Los Angeles before being made available to Internet audiences. The timing was set to coincide with the release of Being John Malkovich on DVD and video.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?064184</url></doc>
