<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="064207">
  <docid>064207</docid>
  <title>Being the One: Document of a Delusion</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kephas, Jason</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>manson</keyword>
    <keyword>occult</keyword>
    <keyword>surrealism</keyword>
    <keyword>conspiracy</keyword>
    <keyword>matrix</keyword>
    <keyword>delusion</keyword>
    <keyword>madness</keyword>
    <keyword>hitler</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">45</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Garbanzo, Alfonso</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kephas, Jason</producer>
    <producer>LaBurt, Michael</producer>
    <producer>Thompson, Mark (XXXVII)</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Every, Simeon</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Horsley, Jake</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>LaBurt, Michael</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lawn, Mark</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rahlfs, Wolf</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>'Being the One' is an exploration both of the world we live in and of a single psyche. Neither standard narrative fiction nor documentary but a curious synthesis of the two, it tells the story of a man who believes he is "the One," the world savior/destroyer. Having apprenticed under a shaman in Guatemala, and then seen the movie The Matrix, he is convinced the movie was made to send a message to him that he is The One. He falls into delusion and grandiosity, including the belief that he is responsible for the collapse of the world trade center, and that his task is to bring about the end of consensus reality. He begins to make a documentary called The God Game: An Investigation into the Illusory Nature of Reality, for which he intends to recruit 24 individuals and subject them to intensive personal questioning over the course of a single day, during which they will enact their imaginary deaths. During the course of making the film, he is persuaded by his cameraman to enter into the action of the films as 'the One,' offering the 'red pill' (a powerful natural hallucinogen called salvia divinorum). The project collapses before they can get a finished movie, and 'Being the One' is the record of that process. It presents the character's past self and his beliefs, more or less as they manifested, framed by more sober perspectives from the present (commentary from himself and those involved). The film is about two things: reality and delusion, where the one leaves off and the other begins. It is a post-modernist satire on the nature of perception, sorcery, mind control, madness, apocalypse, The Matrix mythos, and shamanic self-empowerment. It blurs the lines between fact and fantasy, truth and fiction, reality and dream, and the until now more or less separate categories of documentary and dramatic film.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?064207</url></doc>
