<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="065763">
  <docid>065763</docid>
  <title>Berlin Lady</title>
  <year>1991</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>tv-mini-series</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>French</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="France">30 December 1991</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">240</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="France">180</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Boutron, Pierre</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Charret, Christian</producer>
    <producer>Reichel, Stéphane</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Boutron, Pierre</writer>
    <writer>Franck, Dan</writer>
    <writer>Herman, Jean</writer>
    <writer>Martin, Donald (I)</writer>
    <writer>Michaël, Simon</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Romanelli, Roland</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Abram, Martin</actor>
      <role>Göbbels</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Atzorn, Robert</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barth, Isolde</actor>
      <role>Frau Spitz</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bochner, Lloyd</actor>
      <role>Wilhelm Speer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Boschi, Giulia</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cyr, Myriam</actor>
      <role>Barbara Dorn</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Diouf, Mouss</actor>
      <role>Scipion</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Doutey, Alain</actor>
      <role>Alphonse Tourpe</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Plummer, Christopher (I)</actor>
      <role>Wilhem Speer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Renucci, Robin</actor>
      <role>Boro</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sabourin, Marcel</actor>
      <role>Marquis d'Abrantes</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Salomon, Dirk</actor>
      <role>Rudi Reinecke</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Boro's adventure begins in Paris in the late twenties. As a minor employee in a photographic agency, he works for a pittance. However, thanks to his love of life, his handsome appearance and his appeal to women, he leads a varied and turbulent life. In spite of his numerous affairs, the great love of his life is his cousin, Maryika, the famous actress from Berlin. When Boro learns that Maryika is expected in Munich for the premiere of her latest film, he decides to visit her there. Boro is disappointed in his meeting with Maryika; he has to spend the night alone on the couch. However, on the following day Maryika surprises him with a present: a Leica camera. He starts taking photos even before he leaves the shop. When one of the other customers notices this and angrily demands the film from Boro, he refuses and together with Maryika he drives off. Shortly after Boro has left for Paris, Maryika's flat is ransacked and she herself is threatened by some ruffians, who work for Friedrich von Riegenburg. He demands the film but since he is strongly attracted to Maryika, however, he spares her life. When Boro develops the film months later, he discovers who he has accidentally photographed. It is a mysterious, well-know politician, who is said to be a member of a secret European order, in a somewhat compromising situation with the pretty shop assistant of the photographic shop. Boro decides to shed light on the wheelings and dealings of the order. He thus publishes the photo. Back to Paris Boro learns that one of his many lovers, countess Albina d'Abrantes, is married to a member of this order. Boro persuades her to help him. Countess Albina hates her husband and is naturally willing to co-operate with Boro. One night, they both follow the count's car to the prohibited zone on the German border. Boro takes photos of the count spying on the French military installations at the frontier. Shortly after this, the countess tells Boro that her husband is planning a meeting with a member of the order in Berlin. Because of the publication of the photos, Maryika has warned her cousin not to set a foot inside Germany. In spite of this, Boro travels to Berlin, where, in a café, he observes the count in conversation with Friedrich von Riegenburg. When Boro visits Maryika in her apartment, her reaction is distraught. She is hiding a young persecutee, Dimitri, in the attic. As she suspects her housekeeper to be a spy, Boro's visit could be highly dangerous for her. The doorbell rings. In the doorway stands Friedrich von Riegenburg together with his adjutant Krantz. He is already informed not only of Boro's presence in Berlin, but also that Maryika is keeping a persecutee hidden in the attic of her flat. He politely lets her know that he is willing to spare them all on one condition: that Maryika accompanies him to a reception. She has no choice but to agree. The reception is a great event. All the members of the high society are gathered. Maryika is the glamourous main attraction of the evening. No one suspects that Maryika has changed roles with her friend Barbara Dorn, who is her spitting image. Maryika is already on the night train to Paris with Boro. Maryika's housekeeper discovers the change of roles and alerts Friedrich von Riegenburg. Dimitri, who is still living in the attic, hurries to Barbara's aid. They escape across the roofs of Berlin. They pursue the train in a stolen car in order to warn Maryika and Boro of Friedrich von Riegenburg. But Riegenburg is faster. He and his adjutant Krantz, catch up with the train in a plane and are able to seize the two fugitives in their compartment. Krantz indicates that he is a British spy, but when he tries to shoot Riegenburg, he finds that his gun is not loaded. Yet again Riegenburg is one step ahead. He has known for a long time that Krantz works for the British and has removed the bullets from his pistol. The game seems to be over when suddenly Dimitri and Barbara arrive. Dimitri overwhelms Riegenburg, taking him by surprise, and shoots him. They all safely reach French soil.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?065763</url></doc>
