<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="066275">
  <docid>066275</docid>
  <title>Best Friend's Date</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Teti, Scott</editor>
    <editor>Wilson, Dave (VII)</editor>
  </editors>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">28 January 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Crance, Brian</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Houze, Alyssa</producer>
    <producer>Tornes, Abdel</producer>
    <producer>Tobin, Adam</producer>
    <producer>Maynard, Kevin (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Durham, Bob (III)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Elise, Bree</actor>
      <role>Dater</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Farber, Stacey</actor>
      <role>Herself - Host</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Graham, Aubrey</actor>
      <role>Dater</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mukadam, Al</actor>
      <role>Dater</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Slatkin, Nick</actor>
      <role>Host</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Dating can be exciting, embarrassing and nerve-wracking for everyone, but for teenagers figuring out who they are, what they like, and how to act, it's all the more challenging. The N's Best Friend's Date will allow teens to eavesdrop on blind dates and see what to do -- and what not to do -- with their own romantic travails. Based on the premise that your best friend probably knows you better than you know yourself, Best Friend's Date has teens' best buddy screen and select their perfect blind date. Just how perfect remains to be seen as cameras accompany each date to find out whether the result is magic -- or tragic. Each episode will feature a best friend selecting a date for their buddy from a pool of four candidates. After putting each prospective date through rounds of interviews, challenges and various hoops, the choice is made. But that's just the start. After best friends introduce their choices to their friend and their parents, the real test begins. The young provisional couple must cope with first date jitters (sometimes first-ever date jitters) plus other surprise curveballs the show will throw at the duo -- like bowling while handcuffed together or singing karaoke on street corners. Every date ends with the inevitable moment of truth where each dater must decide whether it's a "Yay!" or a "No way!" Are we in for a budding romance, a mutual "no thanks," or heartbreaking rejection?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?066275</url></doc>
