<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="066625">
  <docid>066625</docid>
  <title>Beta Ho To Aisa</title>
  <year>1994</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Dixit, C.P.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Khanna, Praveen</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Jain, Ravindra</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anand, Vikas</actor>
      <role>Dinubhai - Raju's dad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anuradha (I)</actor>
      <role>Asha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Asrani</actor>
      <role>Bantu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bajaj, Savita</actor>
      <role>Ramanath's mom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhandari, Mohan</actor>
      <role>Advocate Chander</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ghatge, Vijayendra</actor>
      <role>Forest Officer Anand</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Govinda</actor>
      <role>Raju</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grover, Gulshan</actor>
      <role>Rakesh - J.K.'s son</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jog, Sanjay</actor>
      <role>Inspector Suraj</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khote, Viju</actor>
      <role>Poojary</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Praveen (I)</actor>
      <role>Inspector Ravi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mohan, Ram (I)</actor>
      <role>Judge</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Murad, Raza</actor>
      <role>Kunver/Raja Saheb/J.K.</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pandey, Rakesh</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Patel, Amrit</actor>
      <role>Kasturilal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Saxena, Sharat</actor>
      <role>Raaka/CID Officer Ramanath</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sudhir (I)</actor>
      <role>J.K.'s goon</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vachani, Ajit</actor>
      <role>Inspector Ram Singh</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Pregnant Laxmi is the wife of a honest Forest Officer, Anand, and lives with her two sons, Chander and Suraj; along with a servant, widower Dinubhai and his son, Raju. When Anand comes across gold bars he hides them from J.K., who shoots him down. A gravely injured Anand does get home and asks his family and they watch him pass away. The family together with Dinubhai do get away, but Dinu is shot dead, and as a result Raju is brought up by Laxmi, who subsequently gives birth to a daughter, Asha. Years later Laxmi lives the life of a widow, Chander is an Advocate, while Suraj is a Police Inspector, and Raju has taken to crime as his career. When Suraj finds out about Raju's background, they ask him to leave, and shortly thereafter Chander starts working for J.K., and Suraj starts taking bribes from him. Chander even manipulates the Court system to get J.K.'s son, Rakesh, a verdict of not guilty of Ramanath's murder. Then things get complicated when Rakesh rapes Asha and kills her husband, Inspector Ravi, on their wedding night. A devastates Asha and Laxmi approach Chander and Suraj for assistance and are told that both will not oppose J.K. and ask Asha to forget what happened and get re-married. Under these circumstances who will assist Asha and Laxmi get justice?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?066625</url></doc>
