<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="066850">
  <docid>066850</docid>
  <title>Better Than Paradise</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Gervais, Robert (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">31 May 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Williamson, Stace</producer>
    <producer>Gervais, Robert (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Williamson, Stace</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Agostinho, Vic</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gervais, Brian</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Green, Ron (X)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Heinrich, Jody</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>James, Jaemon</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Snowdin, George</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Williamson, Stace</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Forty-five year old wanna-be rocker Jim Dillion has anything less than an ordinary life. Broke, single, and unsure of life, making a reality TV show seems like the only option left to break out of his toilet drain existence. While making his reality TV show, he manages to get himself into a complicated unwanted bet with his crazy landlord, Willy. He will only win the bet if he is able to tape himself sleep with a woman named Isabella, which he just met today. Willy, his crazy landlord, makes his life a living hell as he attempts to disrupt Jims every attempt. Jim must make the ultimate decision to do what is right when he realizes that he has feelings for this person. Wanting to treat Isabella with respect, he is pressured to change himself for the better. When Isabella's ex-husband arrives, world renowned martial-arts expert Saul Cruise, Jim is required to become a true hero and battle it out against the champion in a bid to save Isabella from a cruel sadistic fate. From a down and out underdog without a direction, Jim experiences a change that will leave him better in the days to come.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?066850</url></doc>
