<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="067476">
  <docid>067476</docid>
  <title>Beyond Eyruv</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Gill, Scott J.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>jewish</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">17 June 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Mounier, John</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Tsahaye</producer>
    <producer>Mounier, John</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Mounier, John</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Schechter, Basya</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>"Beyond Eyruv" is a feature-length documentary that examines the life of a young Hasidic man-20 year old Moshe Galan- who's chosen to leave behind the only world he's known, the ultra-orthodox community, out of curiosity for the 'world out there' and an urgent need to relieve himself of the limitations inherent in such a closed community. This documentary is, at its heart, about transformation and the challenges that Moshe faces as he departs from his familiar community and enters into an unknown world and culture, a secular society. This new life that Moshe undertakes is filled with struggles as he works toward earning a High School diploma, negotiates his relationship with his grandparents who have encouraged his departure, tries to support himself, all the while, lacking the basic skills to survive in our world. Ultimately, Moshe's biggest struggle is one of faith and his relationship with God and his family who live in Israel. As the story unfolds, we see that Moshe is living in between these two worlds, not finding comfort in either. While he desperately wants to find recognition and acceptance in his new life, he's unable to leave the past behind him, making his future unclear and questionable.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?067476</url></doc>
