<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="067408">
  <docid>067408</docid>
  <title>Beyond 'The Golden Compass': The Magic of Philip Pullman</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Australia">PG</certificate>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">20 November 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">72</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Rosenberg, Michael (X)</producer>
    <producer>Isbouts, Jean-Pierre</producer>
    <producer>Schwartz, Bill (III)</producer>
    <producer>Schwartz, William A.</producer>
    <producer>Labrador, Cathie</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Isbouts, Jean-Pierre</writer>
    <writer>Schwartz, William A.</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brinkley, James Hayward</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Unlock the astonishing truths and hidden meanings inside the pages of Philip Pullman's The Golden Compass, the best-selling fantasy novel that has captured the imagination of millions worldwide. This cutting edge film examines the secret codes and symbols of Lyra's world - a parallel universe where each person is guided by their animal daemon and where dark, evil forces lurk behind facades of piousness and beauty. Utilizing the latest CG animation and rare archival footage, Beyond The Golden Compass: The Magic of Philip Pullman also includes revealing interviews with historians and experts as well as an exclusive talk with the author himself. Includes over 60 minutes of bonus features including: Exclusive interview with Philip Pullman Extended Interviews with Professors and Scholars Slide Show with Jean-Pierre Isbouts (director of Beyond The Golden Compass: The Magic of Philip Pullman) Walk-Around Interview with Nicholas Tucker (author of Darkness Visible: Inside the World of Philip Pullman) This production was not authorized, prepared, approved, licensed or endorsed by Philip Pullman, New Line Cinema, or any other individual or entity associated with the His Dark Materials books or any movies based on those books.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?067408</url></doc>
