<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="067667">
  <docid>067667</docid>
  <title>Beyond the Epic Run</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bekoski, Jason</editor>
    <editor>Katzir, Gal</editor>
    <editor>Myers, Stephen R.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">PG</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">30 April 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">92</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Rutherford, Paul (II)</director>
    <director>Sammon, Thomas</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Michael, Robi</producer>
    <producer>Hendison, Paul</producer>
    <producer>Roetheli, Joe</producer>
    <producer>Roetheli, Judy</producer>
    <producer>Rutherford, Paul (II)</producer>
    <producer>Sammon, Thomas</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Katzir, Gal</writer>
    <writer>Lynch, Dan (IX)</writer>
    <writer>Rutherford, Paul (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Haab, Gordy</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Boehiem, Jim</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Browne, Dr. Joy</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Burfoot, Amby</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ciulla, Chris Andrew</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dressen, Tom</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Granat, Dr. Jay</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Karnazes, Dean</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Katzir, Gal</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lieto, Chris</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Loraine, Corine</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Roetheli, Serge</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rooney, Kevin (VI)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tontz, Dr. Robert</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Udewitz, Dr. Robert</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zamber, Dr. Ron</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A reality film that follows Serge and Nicole Roetheli on an epic journey around the world. It begins in Sion, Switzerland in 2000. With Nicole as his crew support, following him on a motorcycle towing a small trailer, Serge sets off to run 25,000 miles, on 6 continents and through 33 countries. They sold all of their possessions to finance this great adventure and teamed up with a large Swiss Charitable Organization to visit children's hospitals and orphanages along their route. Starting out from Switzerland, the planned route of their spectacular journey would first take them through the farmlands of France, across the sea to the markets of Morocco, through the desolation and unrelenting heat of the Sahara Desert in West Africa. They would continue along the West African coastline until they reached South Africa, then travel to Madagascar, the Middle East, Asia, Australia and South America. Then heading northbound they would run along the eastern coast of the United States before finally finishing back in Europe. What unfolded over their five year journey would challenge them physically, mentally and spiritually. The hardships would pressure them in unimaginable ways and would indelibly mark their souls and their bodies. Traveling for months at a time through some of the most remote and dangerous places on earth, they pushed on. They faced the boredom and monotony of running for miles at a time on stick straight roads in sweltering heat. They faced hostel locals, foul weather, life threatening illness and unforeseen disappointments. Though at times they doubted their decision to continue, they were determined, to push on. The moments of laughter and levity, the smiles of children and families across the world welcoming them and the exciting discoveries around every unexplored corner made the challenges worthwhile...even meaningful. Through it all, they pushed on. Serge was forced to deal with the wear and tear on his body from running up to thirty five miles a day. Together they faced the unchanging landscapes at a rate of 7 ½ miles per hour. Through footage Serge and Nicole shot with their own camera and through excerpts from Nicole's personal diary, we get an intimate look into this incredible journey in "Beyond the Epic Run". It is a tale of great adventure, unending determination, lasting love and basic survival. As Serge says, "...Nothing is impossible if you are willing to pay the price for your dream."</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?067667</url></doc>
