<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="068027">
  <docid>068027</docid>
  <title>Bhai-Bhai</title>
  <year>1956</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Ramamurthy (III)</editor>
    <editor>Raman, M.V.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">A</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <directors>
    <director>Raman, M.V.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Meiyappan, A.V.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Krishan, Rajendra</writer>
    <writer>Sitaraman, Jawar N.</writer>
    <writer>Sridhar, C.V.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Mohan, Madan (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Abraham, David (II)</actor>
      <role>Baba</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arun, Master</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Babu (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chhotu, Master (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Irani, Daisy (I)</actor>
      <role>Munna Kumar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kesari</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Ashok (I)</actor>
      <role>Ashok Kumar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Kishore</actor>
      <role>Raj Kumar 'Raja'</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Prakash, Om (I)</actor>
      <role>Bulbul</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shivraj (I)</actor>
      <role>Dayashankar Kumar</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Widowed Dayashankar is a businessman who lives in Madras with his two school-going sons, Raj and Ashok. One day he catches Raj stealing some money from his vault, he beats him, locks him in a room, and threatens to cut off his fingers. A terrified Raj breaks the window and runs away, never to be heard of again. Ashok goes on to take over his dad's business, Superior Motors, which also has a branch in Bombay; gets married to Laxmi, and soon has son named Munna. One day Ashok must travel to Bombay to meet with Bulbul, the Branch Manager, to discuss business. Laxmi and Munna see him off. Then several days later, Ashok returns home and he is not the same loving husband and father anymore. He decides to sell the business, has nothing to do with Munna and Laxmi, and asks them to take some money, while he returns to Bombay. Laxmi and Munna follow him to Bombay, but are unable to locate him. They are befriended by a petty thief and pickpocket by the name of Raja, who lives with a young street dancer named Rani and her dad, Baba. When Baba finds out that Laxmi may be related to Raja and that Munna may be their child, he asks them to leave the house. Raja then takes them to Ashok, and to Laxmi's shock she finds her once-loving husband living with another woman, much younger and prettier, by the name of Sangita. Watch what happens when Sangita asks Laxmi to be the maidservant, and Ashok refuses to recognize his wife and child.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?068027</url></doc>
