<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="068024">
  <docid>068024</docid>
  <title>Bhai Thakur</title>
  <year>2000</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kothare, Shyam</editor>
  </editors>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">Unrated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <directors>
    <director>Raja (XVI)</director>
    <director>Willy (XV)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Doshi, Ramesh</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Shivram, Navin</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dharmendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Gajendra 'Bhai Thakur' Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Durrani, Siddique</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hingoo, Dinesh</actor>
      <role>Madrasi Tailor/Advocate Batliwala</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Shakti (I)</actor>
      <role>Thakur Diwan Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pachori, Amit</actor>
      <role>Krishna</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Raj, Dev (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rindani, Shiva</actor>
      <role>Thakur Ranjit Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shelly, Joginder</actor>
      <role>Lakhan Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Singh, Gurbachchan</actor>
      <role>Shankar</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Gajendra Singh lives a wealthy lifestyle in a village in India. He has never attended school and as a result does not know how to read or write in Hindi nor English. His marriage is arranged with equally wealthy Janki, the sister of Thakur Diwan and Ranjit Singh. On Hanuman Jayanti they get married but Janki is not happy and decides to leave her husband. Gajendra searches for her but when he hears that she is dead, decides to seal the Hanuman Mandir doors and remain single. Due to his kindness he is affectionately known as Bhai Thakur. Then one day a woman named Anjali, a Journalist with Modern Press, comes to Mumbai to interview him, and ends up falling in his bad books as well as falling in love with assistant, Krishna. Gajendra eventually forgives her and also arranges her marriage with Krishna - only to find out that she has a secret agenda. Gajendra also has an enemy, a bandit named Sundari, who is out to kill Gajendra as she believes that him to be the killer of her father, Lakhan Singh. The questions remains: Who exactly is Anjali, and why did Gajendra kill Lakhan Singh?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?068024</url></doc>
