<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="068265">
  <docid>068265</docid>
  <title>Bheegi Palkein</title>
  <year>1982</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Misra, Sisir</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Arya, K.K.</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kishore, Jugal (III)</composer>
    <composer>Raj, Tilak (II)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Babbar, Raj</actor>
      <role>Ishwar Acharya</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chatwal, Suresh</actor>
      <role>Prakash Acharya</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chhaya, Laxmi</actor>
      <role>Ishwar's sister</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deshpande, Sulabha</actor>
      <role>Janki Kishan Acharya</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jagdeep</actor>
      <role>Husseinbhai Madadgari</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Manmauji</actor>
      <role>Clerk at Insurance Company</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mishra, Leela</actor>
      <role>Chachi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sen, Asit (I)</actor>
      <role>Divisonal Manager</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Ishwar Acharya lives a wealthy lifestyle with his widowed mom, a sister, brother Kishan and his wife, Janki; and another brother, Prakash who is also married. Janki would like Ishwar to get married to her cousin, but Ishwar loves his childhood sweetheart, Shanti, and wants to marry her. When he is unable to convince his mom and Janki to chance their minds, he marries Shanti at the Registrar's office and brings her home, where they are not welcome and they leave. Ishwar gets a job as an Insurance Investigator, Shanti gets pregnant and gives birth to a boy. Ishwar, who has always lived a wealthy life is unable to adjust to their modest incomes, and becomes angry and bitter. He gets into an accident and is hospitalized for several months. When he is discharged he is shocked to find out that his child has passed away. He physically abuses Shanti and yells at Chachi, who was looking after the ailing child. When Shanti returns home the next day, she finds that Ishwar has left her and gone to his mom's house. With nothing to connect them to their present lives, it looks like this marriage has come to an end, and the couple, who were once so very deeply in love, may never get to see each other again.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?068265</url></doc>
