<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="068248">
  <docid>068248</docid>
  <title>Bhavni Bhavai</title>
  <year>1980</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Asher, Ramesh</editor>
  </editors>
  <languages>
    <language>Gujarati</language>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="India">125</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="default">135</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Mehta, Ketan</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Mehta, Paresh (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Mehta, Ketan</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Vyas, Gaurang (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dave, Nalin</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Desai, Gopi</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gilani, Benjamin</actor>
      <role>Prime Minister</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gokhale, Mohan</actor>
      <role>Jeevla/Raj Kumar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pandya, Kalilash</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, Om</actor>
      <role>Maanav Bhagat</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shah, Naseeruddin</actor>
      <role>Maharaja Dhiraj Chandrasen</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In a drought-stricken city in India, the emperor Maharaja Dhiraj Chandrasen, who has two wives, and no children, orders all kinds of rituals and sacrifices to appease the Rain Gods, including shaving off half his mustache, but to no avail. He is then told that his second wife has given birth to a baby boy, and he announces all kinds of festivities to mark this occasion, only to be told by the Palace Astrologer that the child's birth is going to result in his death. Dhiraj quickly orders the child to be killed. The child is not killed but enclosed in a wooden box and tossed in a river. Subsequently, the child is rescued by a childless couple belonging to the untouchables' community. And it is here that young Jeevla grows up. Years later Dhiraj has grown old, and is still childless. His palace officials find out about Jeevla, and conspire with each other to kill him, so they ask Dhiraj to make a sacrifice of a person who possesses many virtues, and they indicate that they have located such a person, whose name is Jeevla, the son of untouchable Maanav Bhagat. Dhiraj accordingly orders his men to bring in Jeevla, but Jeevla runs away with his beloved gypsy girlfriend, Ujam. When he is surrounded, he asks to meet with Dhiraj to present his demands before surrendering. Dhiraj himself travels to meet with Jeevla and agrees to all his demands. Looks like Jeevla's luck has finally run out, and he is to be killed at the hands of none other than his very own biological father.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?068248</url></doc>
