<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="069859">
  <docid>069859</docid>
  <title>Big Time: Bernard Dunne's Fight for Glory</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Pelly, Derek</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Ireland</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Ireland">30 December 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Ireland">52</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Whitaker, Ross (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Horgan, Maria</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dunne, Bernard</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Peters, Brian (VI)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Big Time is a documentary that goes behind-the-scenes with Irish Super Bantamweight boxer, Bernard Dunne, and his manager and promoter, Brian Peters. After achieving 13 Irish titles and an outstanding 119-11 amateur boxing record, Dunne began boxing professionally in December 2001. He served a three-year apprenticeship at the renowned Freddie Roche gym in Los Angeles before returning to Ireland in 2005 with an unbroken record of victories. On 11 November 2006, he defeated Esham Pickering to become the new EBU European Super Bantamweight Champion in front of his home crowd at The Point Theatre, Dublin. The fighter from Neilstown was immediately feted by the media with chat show appearances and interviews celebrating his remarkable achievement. He went on to defend his title against Yersin Jailauov of Kazakhstan and sealed the deal in the third round at a sold-out Point Depot in March 2007. This was his 23rd straight win. Months later, however, Dunne lost to Spanish challenger, Kiko 'La Sensacion' Martinez, in just 86 seconds in the first round, before many audience members had taken their seats. This fighter is still hungry though. Dunne has since won three more fights and plans to take on the World Title fight in 2009. This is his story: of incredible highs, wounding lows and fearless ambition, all set against the tough and at times cruel backdrop of Big Time international boxing.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?069859</url></doc>
