<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="072407">
  <docid>072407</docid>
  <title>Bizim otel</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>tv-mini-series</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Turkish</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Gülyüz, Aram</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ekmekçi, Yilmaz</producer>
    <producer>Inanoglu, Türker</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Küçükoruç, Vasif</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Altan, Engin</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arslan, Serhan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dasdögen, Ümit</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deger, Ipek</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Güleryüz, Sencan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Karababa, Nilgün</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Karacaoglu, Günay</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Midyat, Sermiyan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pabuccuoglu, Tarik</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Çelik, Sahin</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Cabbar of Urfa missed the chance to get educated, for there is no "Oxford" in Urfa! He is unemployed and living with Halime, his religiously wedded wife. In the end, he decides to go to Germany to work. During the first years, he sends money and letters to his family, he has two children as a result of his holiday stays in Urfa. Later, he marries Eva, whom he meets in Germany. He explains the situation to Halime, saying that he married her just to get the residence permit. He has a daughter, as the result of the "Turkish-German joint venture". They call her Gamze. Years pass. Cabbar, Eva and Gamze return to Turkey. As Halime finds out about it, planning to shoot Cabbar, she takes commando exercises with her two children. Cabbar wonders what business he could make here, seeing all the kebab and supermarkets mushrooming. Eva, sees an ad of a hotel for sale in the paper. In fact, the owner of the hotel is a sly man who is after money. His hotel is empty, often raided by the police, the owner is from top to toes in debts, he is indebted to his personnel, too. So, he makes a deal with a casting agency and shows the hotel as full, and betrays Cabbar. Cabbar and Eva is desperate, having lost all the money they saved throughout the years in Germany. The hotel personnel remains penniless, too. All together they get united to make this deserted hotel a brand new one. This follows hilarious adventures and it is the story of "The Hotel".</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?072407</url></doc>
