<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="074301">
  <docid>074301</docid>
  <title>Blaster Master</title>
  <year>1988</year>
  <type>VideoGame</type>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>plutonium</keyword>
    <keyword>tank-car</keyword>
    <keyword>frog</keyword>
    <keyword>fictional-war</keyword>
    <keyword>video-game</keyword>
    <keyword>under-sea</keyword>
    <keyword>radioactive</keyword>
    <keyword>brain</keyword>
    <keyword>underground</keyword>
    <keyword>mutation</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Japan</country>
    <country>Canada</country>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">November 1988</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Higasiwa, H.</director>
    <director>Kitazumi, K.</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kodaka, Naoki</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Meet Jason, an ordinary kid. He has a pet frog who will soon become a biology experiment. The frog's name is Fred and one day Fred has had enough of life in a bowl, so he leaps out of his bowl and out the front door. He jumps into a giant container of radioactive chemicals and mutates into a giant monster frog who jumps down a huge hole. Jason chases after his frog down the hole. When Jason lands he sees a hi-tech tank car sitting beside him. He jumps in and is off on the wildest and most adventurous adventure of his life. The radioactive chemicals have also spilled into the center of the earth, mutating God-knows-what into monsters, and they're all lead around by a Plutonium Boss, a gigantic monster bent on destruction. And the whole operation is lead by a mysterious Overlord who awaits Jason in Stage 8. Anyway, Jason must brave 8 stages of fury, battling off strange beings, be they flying, walking or crawling, and must defeat mutant bosses of every description including a giant brain, a giant crab, his giant frog, a giant robot that multiplies itself, and a giant bull. Can Jason do it? If he does, he will be a hero for stopping mutants from destroying the earth. If he doesn't, he'll be on the menu for radioactive mutant lunch.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?074301</url></doc>
