<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="075022">
  <docid>075022</docid>
  <title>Blockbusters</title>
  <year>1980</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Game-Show</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>non-fiction</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">27 October 1980</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Skutch, Ira</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ryan, Steve (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cullen, Bill (I)</actor>
      <role>Host (1980-1982)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hilton, Bob</actor>
      <role>Announcer (1980-1981)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jeffries, Rich</actor>
      <role>Announcer (1982)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Olson, Johnny</actor>
      <role>Announcer (1981)</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Game show which sought to resolve the question, "Are two heads better than one?" A single contestant competed against a team of two (related in some way but not married) to answer general knowledge questions, which allowed them to claim hexagonal boxes on a large five-by-four game board if they answered correctly. Each box had a different letter of the alphabet on it, and each question had a one-word answer beginning with whichever letter was selected by a player. The single contestant had to complete a vertical path on the board to win (a minimum of four red boxes), while the two-person team had to finish a horizontal path on the board (a minimum of five white boxes). Oftentimes, more than the minimum number of boxes were required to win a game. The first team to win a two-out-of-three-game match became the champion and played the "Gold Rush" for a chance to win $5,000 in cash. The same game board was used only with each box having one letter or as much as five initials to a phrase, title, name, etc. The champion, whether it be the single player or one member of the two-person team, had one minute to make a horizontal connection across the board. Each clue answered correctly turned the box in question gold, while incorrect answers or passes turned a box black, making it a block that a contestant had to work around. If the champion failed to make such connection, he/she won $100 per correct answer. Teams continued until winning 10 games or being defeated. The 10-game maximum was eventually extended to 20 games, allowing previously-retired champions to be brought back to the show.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?075022</url></doc>
