<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="075475">
  <docid>075475</docid>
  <title>Blood Moon Trailer</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Parr, Jeremy (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>supernatural-power</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">5 June 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ellsworth, Levi</producer>
    <producer>Palmer, Andy (II)</producer>
    <producer>Parr, Jeremy (I)</producer>
    <producer>Ellsworth, Levi</producer>
    <producer>Palmer, Andy (II)</producer>
    <producer>Parr, Jeremy (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Ellsworth, Levi</writer>
    <writer>Palmer, Andy (II)</writer>
    <writer>Parr, Jeremy (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Elias, Mark</actor>
      <role>Thomas</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ellsworth, Levi</actor>
      <role>Morgan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hyman, Leah</actor>
      <role>Julie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Silva, Bobby</actor>
      <role>The Skinwalker</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Simpson, Rob (II)</actor>
      <role>Jerry</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Devaney Gray was born on the Navajo reservation near Kayenta in Northern Arizona; shortly after her birth, her parents suffered mysterious deaths, and Devaney was whisked away by the state of Arizona. Raised in a series of foster homes; she grew up to be a loner - fiercely independent, confident and quiet. Now, she attends Canyon State University in Flagstaff, and has found a group of friends that are the closest thing to a family she has ever had. She has never been happier - yet she is still reserved, underneath her brooding exterior is a young woman in conflict; all her life she has had vivid dreams that foretell future events in the waking world, and recently she has been having violent dreams of the reservation; central to them is a shadowy figure that rises out of darkness to carve a relentless path of blood and destruction that includes every person she has ever cared about, and leads directly... to her destiny. The shadowy figure in her dreams is the Skinwalker; a shape-shifter, neither man nor spirit, with the ability to curse victims with sickness, disease, and severe hallucinations that cause their deepest fears to manifest. His genesis is tied to the Navajo creation myth where he began as a champion of the Navajo people but became corrupted by power and sought the end of humanity. He is central to the end time prophecy as well - he died thousands of years ago, but will be reborn to gather his followers and lead a dark army; his return is a harbinger of the breaking of the world. The first step in his return to power is a ruthless hunt in which he must dam the tributaries of his ancestors by killing and spiritually consuming the soul of every living blood relative; blood calls to blood, and unfortunately for Devaney and her friends, the Skinwalker is being drawn directly to her. As the Skinwalker stalks her Devaney is forced to embrace her past, confront her destiny, and come to terms with her connection to the Skinwalker, she will learn that she is at the center of a war that has raged for thousands of years, and that the final battle approaches. The sign of prophecy - battle encroaching, is the Blood Moon rising.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?075475</url></doc>
