<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="075612">
  <docid>075612</docid>
  <title>Blood and Roses</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Ramsey, Travis</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">30 October 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">105</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Schneider, Paul D.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hyden, Robyn</producer>
    <producer>Schneider, Paul D.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Schneider, Paul D.</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Aoshima, Minako</actor>
      <role>Jennifer Baldwin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dishon, Samdar</actor>
      <role>Vera</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hyden, Robyn</actor>
      <role>Carrie-Anne Rath</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kuti, Corrin</actor>
      <role>Andy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McClarnon, Zahn</actor>
      <role>Detective Brunette</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mitchell, Robin (I)</actor>
      <role>Blake Baldwin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Thomas, David Jean</actor>
      <role>Morgan Bane</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Life gets complicated for an assertive female sociopath (Carrie-Anne) when she discovers that the man she tried and failed to kill, Morgan Bane, is himself a serial killer. What's strange is that Bane seems bent, not on vengeance, but on making Carrie-Anne aware of what he calls 'the sanctity of death,' a spiritual path based on an ancient Japanese atonement ritual. Adding to Carrie-Anne's problems is her younger sister, Suzanne, who just arrived for a visit after being on spiritual retreat in India. Carrie-Anne wants Suzanne to move in with her so they can be a family again, but Suzanne has other plans: She wants her older sister to forgive their father, who sexually abused Carrie-Anne as a teen. Carrie-Anne wants nothing to do with forgiveness, and she reminds Suzanne of their promise, made years before: No contact with Dad, ever. Suzanne, a peace-maker, continues to push the issue, even as her suspicions grow that Carrie-Anne is caught up with a dangerous man, perhaps involving the railroad serial killer she keeps hearing about on the news.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?075612</url></doc>
