<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="076055">
  <docid>076055</docid>
  <title>Blowing Smoke</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kaufman, William Donald</editor>
    <editor>Spagnuolo, Mark Anthony</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>street-gang</keyword>
    <keyword>drug</keyword>
    <keyword>death</keyword>
    <keyword>police</keyword>
    <keyword>blowing</keyword>
    <keyword>doc</keyword>
    <keyword>homelessness</keyword>
    <keyword>marijuana</keyword>
    <keyword>pot</keyword>
    <keyword>camden</keyword>
    <keyword>cocaine</keyword>
    <keyword>ganja</keyword>
    <keyword>smoke</keyword>
    <keyword>heroine</keyword>
    <keyword>jersey</keyword>
    <keyword>money</keyword>
    <keyword>high</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">12 June 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">26</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Cava, Laura</director>
    <director>Kaufman, William Donald</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Cava, Laura</producer>
    <producer>Kaufman, William Donald</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Freeman, Rob (V)</composer>
    <composer>Sy-Santos, Marc</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Boylan, Kelly</actor>
      <role>Amy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Spagnuolo, Mark Anthony</actor>
      <role>Harry</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In today's world it is very common to get mixed messages on the issue of marijuana. With so much free press on the web there are plenty of sites to get information on the subject, as well as a large group of people for it, and against it. Both make some very compelling arguments but which ones tell the truth? Is there any real truth to statements like "Marijuana is a gateway drug", "Marijuana fries your brain.", "Marijuana is as harmless as eating chocolate.", and "Marijuana can cause death." This documentary will attempt to uncover the truths of these issues by dealing with the people who lived them first hand. Interviews with various people who marijuana has affected will speak their minds on camera and through their stories some truths will develop. By tackling the subject in this manner it will reinforce the notion that this documentary was not made for the purpose of skewing facts in order to get its point across; but rather to use real stories to articulate the dangers of the drug. These real stories will highlight the dangers of addiction and will come from the people who lived through the horror themselves as to better warn adolescents what to be careful of. The primary focus of this documentary is to inform but it also does so while entertaining the audience with some unbelievable occurrences.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?076055</url></doc>
