<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="076227">
  <docid>076227</docid>
  <title>Blue Blood</title>
  <year>1951</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Livingston, Roy V.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">28 January 1951</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">72</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Landers, Lew</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Darling, Scott</writer>
    <writer>Kyne, Peter B.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Caswell, Ozzie</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cheshire, Harry</actor>
      <role>McArthur</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kibbee, Milton</actor>
      <role>Ryan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Long, Audrey</actor>
      <role>Sue Buchanan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moore, Hal J.</actor>
      <role>Racing Announcer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shannon, Harry (I)</actor>
      <role>Mr. Buchanan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shields, Arthur</actor>
      <role>Tim Donovan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Talbot, Lyle</actor>
      <role>Teasdale</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tannen, William (I)</actor>
      <role>Sparks</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Williams, Bill (I)</actor>
      <role>Bill Manning</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Tim, an old race-horse trainer down on his luck, is thumbing his way from San Francisco to Los Angeles when he is given a ride by Eileen and Sue Buchanan, daughters of a wealthy Southen California race horse breeder. Tim sees "Tanglefoot", a five-year-old he had trained, and learns that the horse is destined for the dog meat packers. Eileen buys the horse with him. Tim is given the trainer job at Buchanan's, where he sells a third interest in the horse to Bill Manning, a neighboring stockman who is in love with Sue. Tim and Eileen buy "Dinner Ring" from Manning for $10,000 and enter him against Manning's horse in a futurity stake race and "Dinner Ring" wins. Now they prepare "Tanglefoot" to run in the big San Bruno race in which Manning is going to enter "Alcazar." During a trial run, "Alcazar" breaks a leg and has to be killed. Eileen, who has always been in love with Manning, gives him a sympathetic kiss, and Manning realizes it is really Eileen he loves. "Tanglefoot", because of extreme nervousness at the gate during training, worries Tim until Eileen appears in a red coat, and Tim realizes that the horse is frightened by that color. He bribes the San Bruno starter to flag the race from a position that will make it impossible for "Tanglefoot" to see the red flag. It would be great to report that a color-blind horse wins the race but, alas, that is not the case.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?076227</url></doc>
