<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="076504">
  <docid>076504</docid>
  <title>Blue Room</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>White, Sandy (V)</editor>
    <editor>Örkény, Ivan</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 January 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">5</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>White, Sandy (V)</director>
    <director>Örkény, Ivan</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>White, Sandy (V)</producer>
    <producer>Örkény, Ivan</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>White, Sandy (V)</writer>
    <writer>Örkény, Ivan</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kanaiwa, Takuma</composer>
    <composer>White, Sandy (V)</composer>
    <composer>Örkény, Ivan</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>There is often a feeling of having stepped into a world that is in the middle of rearranging itself. There is also a sense of having gained an illicit look into a workshop after dark when all the machines come to life and emulate their creators and their perceived surroundings in a mechanical danse macabre. The protagonists bear witness to a world reinventing itself. A faceless character is increasingly confused while attempting to map not only an outer landscape, but also an inner one. Blue Room challenges its' protagonists to conform to its landscapes in order to function, in order to move on. New obstacles and new settings demand new faces and new characters to be invented in response. While slowly adapting to a fragmented world the protagonists become fragmented and ever- changing. Slowly they merge and the difference between them becomes negligible until the entire process starts over again. Repeatedly, these disconnected and industrial elements find a different use and life before becoming redundant and being discarded. Ultimately, the navigation proves fruitless.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?076504</url></doc>
