<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="077063">
  <docid>077063</docid>
  <title>Bob Dylan: 1978-1989 - Both Ends of the Rainbow</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>bob-dylan</keyword>
    <keyword>rock</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">10 June 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">120</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Abbey, Josh</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Plotkin, Chuck</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Scott, Toby</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This film reviews the years from late-1978 to the release of 1989's Oh Mercy - an album that was seen by many as a huge return to form. This period of Dylan's life and career is one of the most controversial, fascinating and misunderstood of all. With the aid of rare Dylan footage, live and studio versions of the most pivotal songs, exclusive interviews with his closest allies from that time, contributions from Dylan experts, biographers and other commentators and many other features, this film provides the most detailed document of the 1980s according to Bob Dylan, ever made. Featured interviewees include: Shot of Love producer Chuck Plotkin; the same album's first engineer Toby Scott; chief engineer on Infidels and Empire Burlesque, Josh Abbey; Daniel Lanois' assistant producer for Oh Mercy, Malcolm Burn; first engineer on Oh Mercy, Mark Howard; music collaborator and lead guitarist on Empire Burlesque, Ted Perlman; legendary Jamaican rhythm partners who featured on Infidels, Sly and Robbie; Guitarist and band leader for Empire Burlesque and Knocked Out Loaded, Ira Ingber - and many others...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?077063</url></doc>
