<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="077426">
  <docid>077426</docid>
  <title>Bobo</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Satarov, Azizbek</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Russian</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Russia</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Russia">8 June 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Kazakhstan">8 September 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Russia">27</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Satarov, Azizbek</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Pavlova, Yelena</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Kurash, Arthur</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Nazarov, Daler</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Babaliev, Rustam</actor>
      <role>Bobo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nasriddinov, Khairullo</actor>
      <role>uncle Zafar</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In the 1990s people all over Asia (Asian republics, that were part of USSR) were forced to collect cotton. Military men would often patrol the roads stopping cars, vans, buses, forcing all the passengers to the cotton fields. Although their actions were illegal, no one was prosecuted. Any person, who happened to be a passenger, was obliged to collect the standard rate of output. Nothing was taken into account such as age, nationality or social status. So, the story takes place in one of these cotton fields in sunny Tajikistan. A young boy named Bobo is working for his greedy and insidious Uncle. Nothing extraordinary happens in his life until one day he meets a young woman Maria. While Bobo is showing Maria the skills of cotton collection he's becoming friends with her, and eventually falls in love with her. However, his quiet life has come to an end. His Uncle tries to possess the young girl. She rejects him, so he throws her out. Bobo leaves his Uncle and cozy life behind and goes to the City. Now he lives a hard life as a grown up independent man but he does not regret how the circumstances changed his life. Although he never meets Maria again, the image of his first love is always with him.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?077426</url></doc>
