<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="079655">
  <docid>079655</docid>
  <title>Bordenia</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">21</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Munson, Cameron</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Gerbino, Justin</producer>
    <producer>Munson, Cameron</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Munson, Cameron</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Buccino, Gloria M.</actor>
      <role>Abby Borden</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Corkum, Sarah Ann</actor>
      <role>Lizzie Borden</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Flynn, Megan</actor>
      <role>Emma Borden</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grant, Carson</actor>
      <role>Andrew Borden</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mattera, Michael</actor>
      <role>Bill Borden</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Five years ago, something terrible happened to Lizzie Borden. But today, Lizzie wakes with hopes of starting a new life as she eagerly awaits an acceptance letter to a prestigious university in Boston. However, Lizzie's bitter stepmother, Abby, has her own agenda as she threatens to kick Lizzie out of the house to make extra space for the family business. Escaping the tension at home, Lizzie starts her day at the community college accompanied by her overwhelming best friend Nancy. All seems normal, but as the day goes on and the weather gets colder, Lizzie's father, Andrew, finds an all too anticipated letter in the mail. Suspense rising, Andrew forces Abby to make a celebration dinner to surprise Lizzie, but when everything seems almost too good to be true, Abby and Andrew are greeted by a more than unwelcome guest. Hopeful for some good news, Lizzie drives home only to discover something much more intense than she expected as her dreams are hacked to pieces and the evening turns into a disturbing family reunion that Lizzie was trying so hard to avoid.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?079655</url></doc>
