<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="080959">
  <docid>080959</docid>
  <title>Boxer Boys</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Reality-TV</genre>
    <genre>Adult</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>boxing</keyword>
    <keyword>teenage-boy</keyword>
    <keyword>russia</keyword>
    <keyword>friendship</keyword>
    <keyword>brothers</keyword>
    <keyword>tournament</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Russian</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Russia</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Unrated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">108</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Kostenyuk, Igor</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Eisenlohr, David</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Stephens, Guy Russ</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dutchak, Andrey</actor>
      <role>Himself (age14)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dutchak, Kolya</actor>
      <role>Himself (age 18)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dutchak, Tolek</actor>
      <role>Himself (age13)</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Nestled low in the foothills of the Carpathian mountains lies the tiny Ukrainian region known as Bukovina. In this idyllic, storybook-like setting of cobble-stoned streets and 19th century buildings, meet three young brothers who represent the cream of Eastern European youth. Eighteen-year-old Kolya is up early this sunny morning, cheerfully preparing breakfast for his still-slumbering siblings. As he playfully rouses them from bed, the love he has for the sleepy-eyed sprites shines bright. Youngsters, Tolek and Andrey, also radiate their own puppy-like affection for Kolya as they tumble out of bed to begin what will surely be a busy and important day for all of them. Andrey, fifteen, and Tolek, just thirteen, are already local boxing favorites. Tomorrow will bring them into the ring to face even more puberty-fueled, pugilistic mayhem. But not to worry, for athletic prowess seems to run effortlessly within this tightly-bonded brood. Sleek and strong, Kolya, is already a Master of Sport wrestler. His two little brothers are working hard for their own Master of Sport degrees.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?080959</url></doc>
