<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="081254">
  <docid>081254</docid>
  <title>Boys Never Learn</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>stool</keyword>
    <keyword>paddle</keyword>
    <keyword>bare-butt</keyword>
    <keyword>couch</keyword>
    <keyword>over-the-knee</keyword>
    <keyword>belting</keyword>
    <keyword>corporal-punishment</keyword>
    <keyword>office</keyword>
    <keyword>male-nudity</keyword>
    <keyword>boxer-shorts</keyword>
    <keyword>hand</keyword>
    <keyword>beating</keyword>
    <keyword>belt</keyword>
    <keyword>discipline</keyword>
    <keyword>spanking</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">January 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">62</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Adrian (VI)</actor>
      <role>Spankee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Black, Rick (II)</actor>
      <role>Spanker</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sterne, Jeff (II)</actor>
      <role>Spanker</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tuck (I)</actor>
      <role>Spankee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Yancey</actor>
      <role>Spankee</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Despite the title, both discipliners work on the assumption that well-spanked boys learn some lessons, or at least for a while till their hide is healed, ready for another dose of rearing. First Jeff Sterne calls Adrian into his office and orders him to strip and bend over his knee to have his seat hided bright red by hand and paddle till it makes the big boy beg like a baby (14:39 min). Next Jeff has black buff Tuck naked and bend over a stool in the garage for more intense contact with Jeff's hand and a belt then his burly butt can take without having him jump up and around in obvious pain, only to be bend over again and spanked more (17:25 min). Then Jeff deals with Michael, who made the painful mistake to believe at 18 he would be too old to be spanked, till he finds bending over the bed that his macho air drowns in posterior pain as the disciplinary hand and belt keep raining down on his boxers and then on the bare (16:26 min). Finally Rick Black makes his debut as Spank This's new spanker, in a resounding way: throning on a couch, he puts Yancey (see also "Boys Will Be Boys") over the knee, first in his boxers, then bared for utter disciplinary convenience, to suffer scorching doses of hand-spanking and paddling (13:43 min).</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?081254</url></doc>
