<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="081785">
  <docid>081785</docid>
  <title>Brasil Verdade</title>
  <year>1968</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Portuguese</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Brazil</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">130</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <writers>
    <writer>Batista de Andrade, João</writer>
    <writer>Brandão, Celso</writer>
    <writer>Capovila, Maurice</writer>
    <writer>Giménez, Manuel Horacio</writer>
    <writer>Herzog, Clarice</writer>
    <writer>Ramalho Jr., Francisco</writer>
    <writer>Sarno, Geraldo</writer>
    <writer>Soares, Paulo Gil</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Feola, Vicente</actor>
      <role>Himself (segment "Subterrâneos do Futebol, Os")</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pelé</actor>
      <role>Himself (segment "Subterrâneos do Futebol, Os")</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vavá</actor>
      <role>Himself (segment "Subterrâneos do Futebol, Os")</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zózimo</actor>
      <role>Himself (segment "Subterrâneos do Futebol")</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>de Oliveira, Antero</actor>
      <role>Narrator (segment "Subterrâneos do Futebol, Os")</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Segment: "Viramundo" In the late 60's, Thomas Farkas imported equipment suitable for direct sound, and released a collection of documentaries called "Brasil Verdade" ("True Brazil"), after the Military Coup d' État in Brazil. The object of the segment "Viramundo" was to question why the Military Coup d' État in Brazil happened without any popular resistance or revolution or reaction of the society. "Viramundo" shows the saga of the northeastern migrants that arrive in São Paulo, beginning with a train arriving and ending with a train leaving São Paulo in a cycle repeated everyday. The song with lyric of José Carlos Capinam, music of Caetano Veloso and sang by Gilberto Gil (presently Minister of Culture of Brazil) foresees the scenes and gives a sonorous construction. There is a comparison between specialized and non-specialized workers, with the parallel opinions of a qualified worker and a non-qualified worker. Then it shows some workers of the civil construction and from the industry. Later, it is presented the preachers and the "umbanda" (a Brazilian religion and sort of variation of voodooism and fetishism) and their followers. The charity and the opinion of Mr. Entrepreneur are also presented in this documentary that exposes wounds in Brazilian society.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?081785</url></doc>
