<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="082736">
  <docid>082736</docid>
  <title>Brewed Awakening</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Lain, Kate</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>bicycle</keyword>
    <keyword>sustainability</keyword>
    <keyword>beer</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">29</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Lain, Kate</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Lain, Kate</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Lain, Kate</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Asylum Street Spankers</actor>
      <role>Themselves</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Finkle, Burny</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Frederickson, Jamie</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ingrassia, Peter</actor>
      <role>Silly voice #1</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lain, Kate</actor>
      <role>Silly voice #3</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>March Fourth Marching Band</actor>
      <role>Themselves</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sobey, Andrew</actor>
      <role>Silly voice #2</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Winn, Chris (III)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Sustainability. Reducing your carbon footprint. Cutting greenhouse gases. Driving less and biking more. BEER. Brewed Awakening is a quirky, off-beat documentary tale of sustainability, bikes, and beer. Set at the fun, irreverent, employee-owned, and environmentally-conscious New Belgium Brewing Company in Fort Collins, CO, this film takes a look at the oft-overlooked sillier side of sustainability-the side that wears crazy costumes, drinks beer, and sings really loudly in the shower-the side that might just actually be sustainable! So put on a feather boa, pour yourself a cold one, and get ready for something completely different. As issues like global warming, environmental impact, and carbon footprints are becoming more important to many people, this movie offers a fresh take on a topic that's usually accompanied by guilt trips and ominous music. The film should resound with people interested in helping the environment, but its eccentricity will hopefully prove irresistible to those typically less sympathetic to environmental causes and get them clamoring for spots on the sustainability bandwagon.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?082736</url></doc>
