<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="083095">
  <docid>083095</docid>
  <title>Bright Futures</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Polcino, David</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>potato-bug</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">18 December 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Polcino, David</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Polcino, David</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Polcino, David</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Polcino, David</actor>
      <role>The Dude</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Taylor, John (LXXVI)</actor>
      <role>The Business Man</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>An ordinary man and a bug are going about their business, each leading his own life and unaware of the other. Their universes intersect when the bug finds its way, after a series of close calls, onto the wrong cracker, where it is accidentally eaten. Had only the man paid closer attention to his surroundings! Due to his lack of regard for the smaller things around him, the things he considers less significant, an innocent life is lost. The same man continues his daily activities, as does a businessman somewhere in an alternate universe. The lives of the man and the businessman, each unaware of the other, are also destined to intersect, and the man finds himself, after his own adventure on a cracker, devoured unknowingly. And if the businessman had shown more regard for the smaller insignificant things around him, an innocent life might have been saved. The businessman continues his daily activities, as does the leader of a nuclear-armed nation somewhere... and through the carelessness of powers unconcerned with his existence, the businessman too is "devoured" in a nuclear conflict brought about by governments unconcerned with "insignificant" small things such as the people they represent.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?083095</url></doc>
