<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="083148">
  <docid>083148</docid>
  <title>Brigit &amp; Benny: A Modern Faerietale</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Dellaportas, Yanni</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Australia">15 April 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>McLean, Sally</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Duggan, Julian</producer>
    <producer>Richards, Jeff (VI)</producer>
    <producer>Taylor, Peter (XIV)</producer>
    <producer>McLean, Sally</producer>
    <producer>Woodlock-McLean, Margaret</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>McLean, Sally</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Dellaportas, Yanni</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Banks, Judy (I)</actor>
      <role>Grandmother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>D'Antoine, Rondon</actor>
      <role>Benny</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McLean, Sally</actor>
      <role>Brigit</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Paternoster, Harry</actor>
      <role>Man in Suit</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"Once upon a time, there was a city. A city like any other - full of people being busy." And so begins a tale of prejudice and fear, with a hint of redemption. Nicola is a child living in a perfect city, with perfectly proper people living their perfectly ordered lives, rich in material wealth and with a full and satisfied sense of their own superiority. But Nicola isn't like the others. She is a dreamer, a compassionate soul - a child. When the Strangers appear in the City's Park, living on the benches in their scruffy clothes with their dirty faces, the townsfolk are horrified. These savages, these creatures, so different to the townsfolk, must not be tolerated. The townsfolk resolve to remove them, but with every attempt, the Strangers return, every morning, to their places on the benches. So the townsfolk, not knowing what else to do, ignore them. Uniformly, across the board, they pay them no mind and pretend they're not there. Except for Nicola. Walking in the park one day, she notices the Strangers and through a simple act of kindness, learns their secret. And so the Strangers' legacy is passed to the next generation. To the ones who are destined to teach us by example the way forward to a joyous and peaceful future. To the children.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?083148</url></doc>
