<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="085372">
  <docid>085372</docid>
  <title>Bucking Broncho Contest</title>
  <year>1903</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">February 1903</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sower, Martin Thad</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The most exciting sport in the world and we offer an exceptionally fine film made at the recent world's championship contest at Denver where Martin Thad Sowder was declared the best of them all. The film is made up of the very best features of three days' sport. It starts out with a dash and rush that sets an audience wild. The first rider is mounted on a fierce specimen of mankiller. The animal rears and bucks and finally falls on the rider in an effort to crush out his life. With the greatest of skill the rider manages to fall on one side and the horse tries to roll over him. But the cowboy is too quick. Getting up, he stands astride the horse and as soon as the latter arises the rider is on his back and the bucking continues. The film is full of this sort of excitement. At one place the notorious "Steamboat" with the champion on his back gets right in front of the camera and whirls around with fury for almost a full minute. Horse and rider are in full view and almost life size. In fact, the film shows about a dozen of the worst bucking horses ever exhibited in public before. (NOTE--This film was made for the Festival of Mountain and Plain Association of Denver--the givers of the championship belt. Our photographer was honored by being made the official photographer of the entire show and he alone was permitted within the enclosure. The making of the negative was attended with the greatest risks of life and limb for the animals bucked and jumped directly at the camera several times. The film was shown the festival board a few days ago and it received their unqualified indorsement with the comment that it was really the most exciting and accurate picture of a bucking broncho contest ever made and should not be confounded with others made in inclosures and posed by riders and horses that were commonplace and tame.)</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?085372</url></doc>
