<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="086383">
  <docid>086383</docid>
  <title>Bulletproof Diva</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>seven</keyword>
    <keyword>compilation</keyword>
    <keyword>web-series</keyword>
    <keyword>web-animation</keyword>
    <keyword>webisodes</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">27</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Dillard, Jean Pierre</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kidron, Adam</producer>
    <producer>Perry, Josiah</producer>
    <producer>Wiser, Rob</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Wiser, Rob</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Tech-9</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Davis, John (XXVII)</actor>
      <role>Gabriel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fernandez, Ramon (I)</actor>
      <role>Malikai</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hunter, Heather (I)</actor>
      <role>The Bulletproof Diva</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lee, Andrew T. (I)</actor>
      <role>Machine</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>First appearing as a trailer that ran before the theatrical release of "The X-Men," this futuristic epic was one of the most popular animated series ever created for the Internet. The original seven episodes of the hit sci-fi/action series are now available on a special DVD compilation. When the forces of darkness conquer Earth and enslave humanity, one woman is tapped by God's angels to lead the fight against the demon empire. The warrior monk Machine trains her to become the ultimate demon slayer; the fallen angel Gabriel then assigns her missions that take her down into the earth's core, where the demon occupiers have built a new Hell. She does not yet understand why she was the one chosen for his task; all she knows is that the fate of mankind hangs in the balance. And some of the most dangerous demons she will have to face are the ones within herself. She must find the strength and courage to become what the Kingdom of Heaven needs in its darkest hour: the ultimate savior-assassin, the Bulletproof Diva.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?086383</url></doc>
