<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="087919">
  <docid>087919</docid>
  <title>But Some Are Brave</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Channer, Grace</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby SR</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">17 May 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">5</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Channer, Grace</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Zammit, Sarah</producer>
    <producer>Channer, Grace</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kennedy, Kathy (I)</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>In the mists of galaxy matter, a spiraling sphere thrusts itself into existence. Disappearing into the branches of a fig tree it re-emerges as a cosmic drip. In this form it is molded by 'old women' figures who are manifestations of old culture ancestors. They fabricate a thread in which chronological time, history and geography collide, producing a rhythm of images that run into each other in a collective stream of consciousness. Here events like slavery and the impacts of industrial imperialism and technology is thrust onto human communities. The emergence of a female character portrays an iconographic, emotional and psychic condition borne of those who carry the legacy of resistance. Her path propels us into the undocumented contributions of women to the struggle for global peace and equality. At the same time her voyage reminds us that she also is just a thread linking past and present to future. This journey, thwart with turmoil and difficulty grips us in an emotional rhythm, which builds to an intense and disquieting pitch. At every turn the female form becomes trapped over and over again disappearing almost into oblivion. When it seems that there is no hope, the old folkloric knowledge of the 'old women' is woven into a larger fabric inspiring hope for the future. It is a testament to the existence of the voices and identities of folk communities everywhere whose contributions inevitably encompass the full meaning of the healing spirit of resistance.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?087919</url></doc>
