<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="092147">
  <docid>092147</docid>
  <title>Can She Be Saved?</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Clomax, Tony</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>girl-fight</keyword>
    <keyword>youth</keyword>
    <keyword>middle-school</keyword>
    <keyword>violence</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Shiraz, Yasmin</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Shiraz, Yasmin</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Shiraz, Yasmin</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Author/activist/producer Yasmin Shiraz exposes the recent phenomenon of girl fights in America-the prevalence of video images featuring girls physically attacking each other. Painting a dark picture of what happens to juveniles who engage in violent activity, Can She Be Saved? provides historical, cultural and personal references to understand why teen girls are fighting and if anything can be done to make them stop. Revealing the cultural attitudes of girl fighting, Shiraz includes pop culture references, crime and violence statistics as well as news stories that hype the images of girls battling. Shiraz then interviews middle school girls from Syracuse, NY who have been labeled "aggressive" by their teachers, principals and/or guidance counselors. These girls were known to fight and get into disagreements with their classmates. In her interviews of teen girls and professionals who work with youth, Shiraz uncovers the shocking reasons behind the girls' attitudes and actions. Though the girl's reasons for fighting contrast with the professional subject's opinions, the girl's testimonies make a case for compassion instead of condemnation.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?092147</url></doc>
