<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="093055">
  <docid>093055</docid>
  <title>Cannonman</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Anderson, Stephen (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>cannonman</keyword>
    <keyword>lost-love</keyword>
    <keyword>stop-motion</keyword>
    <keyword>cannon</keyword>
    <keyword>overbearing-wife</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>greed</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">23 August 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">10</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Neilson, Douglas</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Anderson, Stephen (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Neilson, Graeme</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gidowicz, Stephan</actor>
      <role>Bearded Lady</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McGlaughlan, Gerry</actor>
      <role>The Doctor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Taylor III, Alexander</actor>
      <role>Cannonman</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Cannonman is a 10 minute stop-motion animated adventure set around the turn of the last century. Our hero Cannonman is sad and lonely, for years he has been pushed by his wife, The Bearded Lady, into ever more dangerous performances to feed the publics desire for danger and her need for fame and fortune. He dreams of being back in the arms of his long lost love, Lollipop Girl, but because of his life-long exposure to loud blasts and crunching landings he cannot come up with a plan. In steps his friend, The Dr. with his wonderful scientific mind to help him construct the greatest cannon ever built and another more secret device. As they hide their plan from the tyrannical Bearded Lady, Cannonman works out harder than ever before. His new muscular body will help him fly further than ever and keep his wife happy as she dreams of the wonders success will bring with her newly motivated Cannonman. The story builds towards its grand finish as Cannonman performs in front of his largest ever audience and attempts to fly into the arms of Lollipop Girl, without The Bearded Lady suspecting anything. Watch Cannonman go out with a bang!!!!!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?093055</url></doc>
