<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="094392">
  <docid>094392</docid>
  <title>Carica eroica</title>
  <year>1952</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>soldier</keyword>
    <keyword>colonel</keyword>
    <keyword>docudrama</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Italian</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Finland">K-16</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Finland">10 August 1956</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Italy">96</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>De Robertis, Francesco</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>De Robertis, Francesco</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Masetti, Enzo</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fabrizi, Franco</actor>
      <role>Captain Franchi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Michaelis, Dario</actor>
      <role>Captain Valli</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Modugno, Domenico</actor>
      <role>Cavalry soldier</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Reder, Gigi</actor>
      <role>Cavalry soldier</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rizzo, Alfredo</actor>
      <role>The Colonel</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In 1941 an Italian regiment known as the Savoy Cavalry is sent by Mussolini to Russia to assist the German invasion. After crossing an extensive area of Soviet territory the men arrive at a village that seems deserted. A patrol sent on reconnaissance comes under machine-gun fire from the top of a bell-tower. During the fighting that follows a young woman named Kalina is captured by the Italians, but in order to win favour with the local people she is spared. A peaceful rapport then builds up between Italian soldiers and Russian villagers, and a special fondness grows between Kalina and Captain Valli, the colonel's godson. Suddenly, the men receive orders to depart and make their way to the front line which is under Russian siege. However, the German commander does not believe the Italian presence will be effective, so on a point of honour the Savoy Cavalry decide to demonstrate their worth. Moving to the front they charge into the enemy batteries and eventually overwhelm them. Sadly, few survive the heroic charge.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?094392</url></doc>
