<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="094698">
  <docid>094698</docid>
  <title>Carmen la de Ronda</title>
  <year>1959</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Ramírez de Loaysa, Antonio</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>based-on-novel</keyword>
    <keyword>beautiful-woman</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Finland">K-12</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Spain">22 September 1959</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Finland">18 August 1961</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">February 1962</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Spain">106</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Demicheli, Tulio</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Perojo, Benito</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Arozamena, Jesús María de</writer>
    <writer>Demicheli, Tulio</writer>
    <writer>Mas Guindal, Antonio</writer>
    <writer>Mérimée, Prosper</writer>
    <writer>Sastre, Alfonso</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>García Segura, Gregorio</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bayo, Víctor</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bergía, Joaquín</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cintado, Antonio</actor>
      <role>Oficial francés</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cobos, Germán</actor>
      <role>Lucas</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Davó, José Marco</actor>
      <role>Alcalde</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Delgado, Antonio (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fernández, Félix (I)</actor>
      <role>El Dancairo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gisbert, Teresa</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>González, Agustín (I)</actor>
      <role>Guerrillero</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Guitián, Manuel</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gómez Ferrer, Pilar</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hortelano, María de los Ángeles</actor>
      <role>Micaela</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mistral, Jorge</actor>
      <role>Antonio</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Montiel, Sara</actor>
      <role>Carmen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nazzari, Amedeo</actor>
      <role>Coronel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rivero, Santiago</actor>
      <role>Andrés</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rojas, Alfonso (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ronet, Maurice</actor>
      <role>José</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tundidor, Ricardo</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Antonio is the leader of an underground armed group fighting in the village of Ronda against Napoleon's troops which have imposed French rule in 1808 Spain. Micaela is fiercely in love with Antonio but he has a passionate affair with Carmen, the region's most beautiful gypsy who lives and sings at a local inn. After a particularly bloody strike against the French, Antonio seeks shelter with Carmen who hides him at the inn's attic. Meanwhile, a spiteful Micaela goes to the French Coroner with information on Antonio's whereabouts. The Coroner orders Sargent Jose and his soldiers to raid the inn and Carmen tries to help Antonio escape but he is captured and sent to jail. Jose has realized Carmen's involvement with Antonio yet, strangely, covers up for her. The following day, everybody in town knows about Antonio's capture and Micaela's treason. Carmen beats up Micaela at the market place and is arrested by Jose but before they get to the police station she talks the sergeant into letting her escape. For this Jose is denounced and demoted to plain soldier. The Coroner summons Carmen and tries buying her cooperation against Antonio and the other rebels. Carmen pretends acceptance and suggests that the rebels are planning to attack the Coroner's palace during an upcoming party. On the night of the party, the Coroner has stationed the bulk of his troops, including Jose, to guard the place. Meanwhile the rebels attack the under-guarded jail and liberate Antonio. The news arrive at the party as Carmen sings for the guests. The Coroner now realizes that he has been deceived by the gypsy and confronts her privately but the exchange turns violent. Jose breaks in and kills the Coroner to save Carmen. He must now flee his own army and Carmen arranges for him to hide with Antonio and the rebels on the nearby mountains. However Antonio has now noticed Carmen's interest on the French soldier and provokes the man to a fight in which Jose ends up hurt. Carmen saves Jose and takes him back to the inn where she hides him in the attic. Micaela finds out and, while Carmen is away, visits Jose in the attic feeding him a bunch of lies about Carmen's real intentions. Later, Micaela tells the French authorities about Jose's hiding place. Meanwhile Carmen is arranging with the help of bullfighter (and French collaborator) Lucas a permit so that she can flee the country with Jose. Everything is set up for the escape but Antonio shows up and tells her that the getaway will be impossible since he plans to ambush the French troops when they come to arrest Jose. Carmen tries to warn Jose but Antonio stops her. From the attic's window, Jose see the French troops arrive and believes that Carmen has betrayed him. Mad with jealousy, he comes down with a gun and points it at her while she tearfully sings. The French army which has the place surrounded, orders Jose to lay down his gun. When he doesn't follow the commands they shoot but Carmen gets in between covering him with her body. More shots are fired as the gypsy and the French officer die in each others arms. Antonio and his men attack the French army. That night Ronda and most of Spain would regain its freedom.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?094698</url></doc>
