<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="094737">
  <docid>094737</docid>
  <title>Carmilla Hyde</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>revenge</keyword>
    <keyword>betrayal</keyword>
    <keyword>femme-fatale</keyword>
    <keyword>seduction</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Australia">2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Australia">110</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>De Vries, David</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>De Caux, Fiona</producer>
    <producer>De Vries, David</producer>
    <producer>Ganzis, Tony</producer>
    <producer>Gostin, Andrei</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hall, Cameron (VI)</actor>
      <role>Nathan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lindner, Annie</actor>
      <role>Millie/Carmilla Hyde</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Morgan, Cale</actor>
      <role>Ed</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tripodi, Sam</actor>
      <role>Dr. Charles Webster</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Millie Jackson, a nerdish introverted virgin, shares an old crumbling mansion with fellow uni student Sara. Sara's friend Britt, desperate to move in, hatches a cruel and cunning plot to push Millie out. Party drugged, Millie is seduced by Sara's boyfriend Nathan, to awake, naked and confused, with no memory of the night before. Deep in denial, Millie is confronted by startling images of her night of passion, filmed and mailed through the internet. Distraught, confused and plagued by conflicting emotions, Millie seeks help from her family psychiatrist Dr Charles Webster. During hypnosis, Dr Webster unwittingly awakes Millie's repressed alter ego, unleashing the wild, sexy Carmilla Hyde. Armed by a post-hypnotic trigger, Millie now has the perfect vehicle to take her revenge... to beat her tormentors at their own game of cruel deception. But the battle is with more than just her housemates. Plagued by childhood memories, and with her alter ego Carmilla slowly taking over, she returns to Dr Webster in a desperate bid to regain control.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?094737</url></doc>
