<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="095096">
  <docid>095096</docid>
  <title>Carolina Stories: Pirates of the Carolinas</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>south-carolina</keyword>
    <keyword>reenactment</keyword>
    <keyword>pirate</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">G</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">22 November 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Mayer, Bruce Y.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Mayer, Bruce Y.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Mayer, Bruce Y.</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brewer, Stanley</actor>
      <role>Pirate</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cornell, Buzz</actor>
      <role>Burly Pirate</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jarvis, Sumer</actor>
      <role>Tavern Girl/Street Peddler</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mayer, Bruce Y.</actor>
      <role>Pirate</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Perry, Joe (VII)</actor>
      <role>Calico Jack</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Prescott, Wendell</actor>
      <role>Governor Eden</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Safford, Joseph</actor>
      <role>Pirate</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wade, Jim F.</actor>
      <role>Pirate</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Piracy has been a part of North and South Carolina's history for many centuries. Their adventures have been well documented through pirate trial documents and in numerous volumes written of their bloody exploits on the high seas. South Carolina ETV examines the lives of these pirates and follows their adventures during the period known as "The Golden Age of Piracy". "This period - roughly between 1690 and 1725, was an important time in Carolina's early history," affirms Producer Bruce Mayer. "This was the era that saw pirates the likes of Stede Bonnet, Calico Jack, Edward Low, Charles Vane, Anne Bonny &amp; Mary Read - and the notorious Blackbeard, rise to prominence. This certainly must have been an extremely lively time as thousands of pirates infested the inlets and towns along the South Carolina and North Carolina coasts!" Trans-Atlantic trade was disrupted by pirates seeking their plunder - and merchant ships from ports around the globe attempted to tip-toe around these swifter pirate vessels to deliver their cargoes. Remarkably - for decades piracy was tolerated by local officials in coastal towns like Charleston South Carolina but especially around Bath North Carolina. The reasons it was discovered - was that many of these town officials were engaged in trading their protection to pirates - from the hangman's noose, for a share of the illegal plunder looted from merchant ships! Commentators on "Pirates of the Carolinas" include: Mike Brown, writer and pirate historian from Charleston, SC - Nancy Roberts, writer of over two dozen books on pirates and Carolina ghosts from Charlotte NC - John Walker, Blackbeard historian from Bardonia, New York - and David Moore, Curator of Nautical Archaeology, North Carolina Maritime Museum in Beaufort NC. Actress and voice over artist Julie Berry of London, England narrates "Pirates of the Carolinas."</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?095096</url></doc>
