<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="095890">
  <docid>095890</docid>
  <title>Cash Deal</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">28</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Dinelli, Michael Cole</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tumino, Michael</actor>
      <role>Jackie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Valli, Frankie</actor>
      <role>Harry</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A rainstorm is moving into the central part of Georgia. Harry Wolf and Jack Diamond, two salesmen-con-artists from the east coast, are headed back to their motel, in the boondocks after hitting pay dirt; they sold eighteen thousand dollar cash deal to an elderly widow. Harry, "The Wolf" an older salesman, and somewhat of a legend in the business is lost in thought after a heart attack scare in the middle of his pitch, while Jacky, the young upstart is gloating over their recent stroke of luck. There is no love lost between Harry and Jacky; Harry thinks the kid is an arrogant punk. But Jacky is thrilled to be working with the greatest salesman in the biz. The heart attack causes Harry to reassess his whole life realizing what a waste it's been. He tries to teach this kid a sense of ethic by confiding his wisdom and opening his personal life to him. But it all falls on deaf ears. Broads, cars, and money are all this kid cares about. Harry is becoming less and less patient stuck in this dingy hot room with an arrogant kid who is literally bouncing off the walls looking for something to do in this nowhere town. When Harry discovers a gold Dunhill lighter that Jacky stole from women's coffee table, he becomes infuriated and decides to teach this kid the lesson of his life, in a way only Harry "The Wolf" can pull off.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?095890</url></doc>
