<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="096123">
  <docid>096123</docid>
  <title>Cast Offs</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Steinike, Kyle</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>nature</keyword>
    <keyword>river</keyword>
    <keyword>non-fiction</keyword>
    <keyword>documentary-filmmaking</keyword>
    <keyword>environmental</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">14 June 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">11</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Sheedy, Jason (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Sheedy, Jason (I)</producer>
    <producer>Steinike, Kyle</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>McTiernan, Jeremy</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bennett, Charles (XII)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Butler, Brent</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Noble, Josh</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Quinn, Kevin (XI)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Woodward, Spud</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Boats gently part the murky depths of the Savannah waterways, leaving in their wake a trail of white foam as delicate as torn wrapping paper. These boats, which come in all different shapes and sizes, each have a story to tell: One a fishing vessel, another driven by those seeking leisure, one carries cargo bound for China, while another, a scientist heading into the field. They all nonchalantly coast along, unaware of the impending danger which lies mere feet beneath them, threatening to bring to a sudden halt not only their travels, but perhaps their lives. Like ghosts, abandoned and derelict vessels lie in wait at the bottom of the waterways, ready at a moment to jealously ensnare their unlucky prey. Savannah's waterways are littered with hundreds of sunken or half submerged vessels, which create a virtual underwater minefield daily threatening the lives and livelihoods of those who traverse these waters. These shipwrecks are varied and diverse; some carrying immense historical value, others simple shrimping vessels that suffered from a stroke of bad luck. Some ended up in their current state by accident, running aground, or perhaps hitting another submerged vessel, while others were simply scuttled or abandoned by owners who could no longer afford or find pleasure in them. Either way their threat is a real one, and unfortunately one often down played by those familiar with Savannah's waterways. Cast Offs is an exciting documentary that explores the threat posed by these sunken vessels. The problem is explained in detail by the Georgia Department of Natural Resources Coastal Resources Division as well as by local boaters who are eager to raise awareness. The documentary explores the environmental dangers that the ships can cause as well as what action can be taken to correct the problem. The viewer is invited to tag along with our team as we journey throughout the Savannah waterways and deep below the water's surface to investigate the danger and wonder behind these coastal graveyards.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?096123</url></doc>
