<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="097661">
  <docid>097661</docid>
  <title>Celebration</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Muskens, Helena</editor>
    <editor>Racké, Quirine</editor>
  </editors>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby SR</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Netherlands">1 March 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Netherlands">55</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Muskens, Helena</director>
    <director>Racké, Quirine</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Muskens, Helena</writer>
    <writer>Racké, Quirine</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Celebration is the latest version of the American Dream, a town built in 1996 in the swamp of central Florida by the master of make believe The Disney Company. Once again Disney had its thumb on the pulse of the American public: to return to community, to a neighborhood. Celebration is a beautiful, pristine and crisp town with pre-1940's architecture that takes you back to a safer, more comforting place where neighbors greeted neighbors. Almost ten years later it is the home of 8000 residents. The film shows six couples in search of utopia. It was Disney that attracted them to Celebration. They all remember their first time to Disney World, a magical and care-free place. When they heard that Disney was building a town which went back to the past instead of the future they packed their belongings and felt like modern day pioneers. "Celebration" is a documentary about people in search of a better life and a better place to live. Yet behind the beautiful facades and white picket fences is a real place with real people and real problems. When press got bad and Disney realized it couldn't control a town like a theme park they sold the town to Lexin Capital, an investment company from New York. Some people leave Celebration, disillusioned, but still in search for something new, somewhere different, a new promise. After all, the search for utopia, is a great American tradition.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?097661</url></doc>
