<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="097833">
  <docid>097833</docid>
  <title>Celeste</title>
  <year>1991</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Aragona, Gaita</editor>
    <editor>Simari, Gabriel</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Mystery</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>love</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>soap-opera</keyword>
    <keyword>soap</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Argentina</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Argentina">Atp</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Argentina">11 March 1991</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Italy">September 1992</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Del Boca, Nicolás</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Lecouna, Raúl</writer>
    <writer>Nicolás, José</writer>
    <writer>Torres, Enrique (II)</writer>
    <writer>Vaillant, Jorge</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Antier, Roberto</actor>
      <role>Daniel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Baret, Dora</actor>
      <role>Teresa Visconti</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bermúdez, Gustavo</actor>
      <role>Franco Ferrero</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bernard, Hilda</actor>
      <role>Amanda Sadowska</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bloise, Floria</actor>
      <role>Lucía's Doctor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bonelli, Andrea</actor>
      <role>Laura Corran</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brindisi, Rodolfo</actor>
      <role>Father Benito</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Casal, Raquel</actor>
      <role>Vanina</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Castel, Ana María</actor>
      <role>Victoria, Widow of an Employee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Castell, Patricia</actor>
      <role>Célica Castellini</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Del Boca, Andrea</actor>
      <role>Celeste Verardi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dragone, Silvina</actor>
      <role>Daisy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fernández, Cristina (I)</actor>
      <role>Julia Oliver</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fiore, Roberto</actor>
      <role>Ramón</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gallardou, Claudio</actor>
      <role>Felipe Castellini</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gleijer, Adela</actor>
      <role>Aída Ferrero</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Guidi, Osvaldo</actor>
      <role>Sebastián Aguirre</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lamm, Regina</actor>
      <role>Lucía Verardi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Machado, Rodolfo (I)</actor>
      <role>Leandro Ferrero</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maly, Arturo</actor>
      <role>Bruno Rosetti</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Palacios, Germán</actor>
      <role>Enzo Ferrero</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rey, Gustavo</actor>
      <role>Ramiro Menéndez</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Torres, Lucas (I)</actor>
      <role>Lucas Ferrero</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zacco, Néstor</actor>
      <role>Agüero</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Celeste is a poor girl living with her mother Lucia. Lucia has cancer, and although she tries to hide it from Celeste, Celeste discovers it. Celeste works in a plant nursery, and one day, while transferring plants, she meets Franco, whose car is stuck and he needs help. She helps him and he invites her to coffee. As they talk Franco tells Celeste the legend about the sun and moon (In Spanish Sol y Luna): St. Franciscus once gave all he had to 'Brothers sun and Sisters moon'; he thought that names have no importance and therefore he called the men Sol and the women Luna. After telling her the legend, Franco asks her name and she answers: Luna. Without knowing each other's true names, they set to meet in the same place the next day. Meanwhile, Lucia gets worse and is dying. Franco and Celeste continue to meet and they plant a tree together. They swear that as long as it lives, they will love each other. They set to meet the next day and tell their real names. That same night, Lucia dies in Celeste's arms. While Celeste mourns in her house, Franco thinks Celeste stood him up, and he pulls the tree out of the ground. Aida, Lucia's best friend, offers Celeste to move and live with her in order to leave the house, which is so full of memories. With a small number of personal things, Celeste comes into the castle of the Visconti family (Actually it's Ferrero, but all the family's fortune comes from the mistress side) The mistress, Teresa, who needs a new maid, thinks that Aida brought her a new maid, and she sends Celeste to put on a uniform. She is so manipulative, that neither Celeste nor Aida can tell her she is wrong. Celeste becomes the maid then, and almost everyone dislikes her. Teresa is a very cold woman and she treats her badly. Enzo, Teresa's son, is 'attracted' to Celeste and tries to rape her many times. Rita, the daughter, likes Celeste and they become friends. Celica, the matron, is practically a witch and she also treats her badly. Only with Leandro, Teresa's husband (who is also Aida's brother) is Celeste able to create a kind relationship. Then comes the last member of the family: After a few days the twin brother of Enzo comes home, and Celeste finds out he's no other than Franco...at first they are both angry at each other, but then they reconcile and fall in love again. But, not one of them knows the secret that Lucia kept all her life. ???</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?097833</url></doc>
