<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="098230">
  <docid>098230</docid>
  <title>Central Terminal: Saving a Buffalo Landmark</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>video-institute</keyword>
    <keyword>new-york-central-railroad</keyword>
    <keyword>canisius-college</keyword>
    <keyword>buffalo-new-york</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">3 May 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">28</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Irwin, Barbara (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Jahn, Kirsten</producer>
    <producer>Richardson, Scott (IX)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Irwin, Barbara (II)</writer>
    <writer>Jahn, Kirsten</writer>
    <writer>Richardson, Scott (IX)</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Central Terminal: Saving a Buffalo Landmark explores the storied past of the beloved train station in Buffalo, New York. Built on the cusp of the Great Depression, the Central Terminal was for many years a hub of activity, as travelers moved throughout the northeast and Midwest. Its massive arched ceilings, majestic light fixtures, and stately clock - all in the art deco style - greeted visitors, and the building itself towered above the city's East Side as a beacon of technological advancement. As train travel waned in the 1970s, the Central Terminal closed. For twenty years, it suffered from neglect and abuse at the hands of private owners. In 1997, local preservationists acquired the building, which by this time had been stripped of its grandeur and was in desperate need of repair. This documentary highlights the building's architectural and social significance, along with recent efforts to bring it back to life, all through the eyes of local politicians, architects, preservationists, volunteers and former employees of the New York Central railroad. It was produced for the Central Terminal Restoration Corporation as a means to raise awareness of this great building and gain support for its revitalization.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?098230</url></doc>
