<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="098870">
  <docid>098870</docid>
  <title>Chain Kulii Ki Main Kulii</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Chandran, Shaju</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>oliver-twist</keyword>
    <keyword>believing-in-yourself</keyword>
    <keyword>indian</keyword>
    <keyword>dada</keyword>
    <keyword>magic-bat</keyword>
    <keyword>orphan</keyword>
    <keyword>parent</keyword>
    <keyword>child</keyword>
    <keyword>hitler</keyword>
    <keyword>cricket</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">Unrated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">22 June 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="India">118</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Saluja, Kittu</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ghosh, Ken</producer>
    <producer>Rungta, Namrata</producer>
    <producer>Khamkar, Shashikant</producer>
    <producer>Agnihotri, Sweta</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Asthana, Nupur</writer>
    <writer>Shewakramani, Jay</writer>
    <writer>Tripathi, Satyam</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Merchant, Salim (I)</composer>
    <composer>Merchant, Suleiman</composer>
    <composer>Shirodkar, Sandeep</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhansali, Raj</actor>
      <role>Raghav</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bose, Rahul</actor>
      <role>Varun</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chadhury, Deeptiman</actor>
      <role>Dabboo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dev, Kapil (II)</actor>
      <role>Kapil Dev</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hussain, Nasser (III)</actor>
      <role>Mr. Father</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kenkre, Mangala</actor>
      <role>Varun's mother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Zain (II)</actor>
      <role>Karan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khera, Rajesh</actor>
      <role>Hitler</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Parashar, Lalit</actor>
      <role>Cricket Selector</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Parashara, Susheel</actor>
      <role>Bholu dada</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sodhi, Amrindher</actor>
      <role>Sonty</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Chain Kulli Ki Main Kulli, a children's film, is a journey of an orphan boy of 13 years of age who dares to dream big and thereby, proves to the world that "Believe in yourself and the world will be at your feet". The film revolves around an orphan boy, Karan, who lives in a dilapidated orphanage owned by a stern, uncouth warden, John Kakkad. Karan has two dreams, one is to have parents and the other is to be a big cricketer. His inspiration is Kapil Dev since he has been brought up on the motivating stories of India's '83 world cup win by the orphanage caretaker, Bholu Dada who is a loving and a gentle old man. Karan's best buddy in the orphanage is Daboo who often lends his gentle ears to the aspirations which Karan lives on. His dreams take a turn when one day, he lays his hands on an old cricket bat which Karan is convinced is the bat that Kapil Dev used to win the '83 World Cup, and for him the bat becomes a magic bat. One day by the stroke of luck, the coach of the Indian cricket team, spots Karan and is highly impressed by his batting skill. This happens at a time when the Indian Cricket Team is going through a rough patch. Karan and his magical bat is inducted into the Indian Cricket Team as the opening batsman along with the captain, Varun.. A wave of shock and horror runs through the nation. Accusations and altercations abound...Tempers and tantrums fly...Until the little boy marches on to the pitch and wins the match for India... Karan soon becomes the nation's heartthrob . Once rejected by adopting couples he is now the most sought after kid in the country. Only one person hates him i.e Raghav the orphanage bully...who feels that if Karan did not have the magic bat he would have never made it to the cricket team. Raghav now wants the magic bat at any cost . Karan and Varun, develop a strong emotional bond. A bond deeper than fellow cricketers. Karan has no parents and Varun has parents, but is estranged with his father and does not want to accept him. Karan strongly believes that parents are the best gift endowed by God, and succeeds in uniting Varun with his father. At the final 5th one day match between India and Pakistan, events spiral out of control and Karan's magic bat is destroyed. Karan is a nervous wreck, but Varun makes him realize that faith in oneself counts beyond anything else...The magic is in you.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?098870</url></doc>
