<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="099921">
  <docid>099921</docid>
  <title>Chaotix</title>
  <year>1995</year>
  <type>VideoGame</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>knuckles</keyword>
    <keyword>sonic-the-hedgehog</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Japan</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">K-A</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Japan">21 April 1995</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="UK">May 1995</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">March 1995</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Kobayashi, Masahide</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Shigeta, Mamoru</producer>
    <producer>Aso, Hiroshi</producer>
    <producer>Larsen, Mike (II)</producer>
    <producer>Oshitani, Makoto</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Ohshima, Naoto</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Nanba, Mariko</composer>
    <composer>Shiratsu, Junko</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Knuckles Chaotix is a spin-off of the Sonic the Hedgehog series of Genesis games. The starring character in this title is Knuckles the Echidna, who first appeared in Sonic the Hedgehog 3. Knuckles works at Carnival Island, an amusement park. It's his job to protect the park and make it a happy place for visitors. Dr. Robotnik, as usual, has an evil plan for the park. He wants the power emerald which supplies electricity to the entire island. What's worse, he has imprisoned several of Knuckles' friends in the 'combi confiner'. This contraption only allows Knuckles to free one of his friends at a time be attaching a tether between himself and them. Therefore, when you play the game you are always attached to another character. Although the basic gameplay of Knuckles Chaotix is similar to the Sonic games, the bungee cord between the two characters creates new challenges and is similar to the gameplay in the more recent Sonic Heroes. The new characters that appear are Vector the Crocodile, Mighty the Armadillo, Espio the Chameleon and Charmy Bee. There also two characters whose sole purpose is to slow you down, Heavy the Robot, and Bomb. Chaotix adds several new power-ups and 3D bonus levels also.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?099921</url></doc>
