<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="100821">
  <docid>100821</docid>
  <title>Chasing the Shadows</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kalish, David (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">23 April 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Schultz, Timothy</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kalish, David (I)</producer>
    <producer>Mazal, Jenn</producer>
    <producer>Schultz, Timothy</producer>
    <producer>McLaughlin, Mark (II)</producer>
    <producer>Robbins, Corinna</producer>
    <producer>Schultz, Timothy</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Kalish, David (I)</writer>
    <writer>McLaughlin, Mark (II)</writer>
    <writer>Robbins, Corinna</writer>
    <writer>Schultz, Timothy</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Monroe, Vicki</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zaffis, John</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Do you believe in ghosts? A recent Gallup poll suggests that 1/3rd of Americans swear they exist. A second poll from the UK suggests that there are now more people in the UK who believe in ghosts than in God. But what do they believe in? Documentary filmmaker Tim Schultz sets out on a 4-year journey for answers while exploring his own passion to know if an experience he had as a little boy could have been a ghost. He meets a cast of colorful characters including psychics, tarot reading wizards, paranormal investigators, skeptics, and scientists. His crew has journeyed into numerous haunted locations including the Stanley Hotel, which is famously known for inspiring the classic horror novel 'The Shining' and The Myrtles Plantation, which is said to be the most haunted house in America. The production of this film has been an extraordinary experience. If you accept that it is possible for a spirit to become stuck, for energy to haunt a certain location, no matter the cause of it, then it really brings up many questions about the nature of our true reality and life after death. The results are eerie, thought-provoking, and often terrifying. His journey into the paranormal reaches a climax when he attempts to contact a friend who committed suicide during the making of the film.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?100821</url></doc>
