<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="101097">
  <docid>101097</docid>
  <title>Che: Rise and Fall</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>che-guevara</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>cuban-revolution</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Argentina</country>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">7 May 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Germany">13 July 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">6 November 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">52</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Montes Bradley, Eduardo</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Liendo, Soledad</producer>
    <producer>Schapces, Marcelo</producer>
    <producer>Montes Bradley, Eduardo</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Montes Bradley, Eduardo</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Castellanos, Alberto (III)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Granados, Alberto (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mendoza, Argudin</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Oltuski, Enrique</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Villegas, Enrique (IV)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Che: Rise and Fall is the most complete work yet produced on the trials and tribulations of Argentine born Ernesto Che Guevara. The documentary is structured in three main acts. The first relates to the early years in Argentina, his friendship with Alberto Granado and the preparations for the long journey through South America on a motorcycle. The adventure served as the argument to another film The Motorcycle Diaries. The second half of the First Act focuses on the Cuban Revolution and the relationship between Guevara and Fidel Castro. The Second Act brings the audience closer to the period in Guevara spent in Africa fighting a Revolutionary War, and last but not least, we are confronted with the final days of Che in Bolivia. Che: Rise and Fall brings out for the first time the testimony of Alberto Granado himself at a crucial time when the remains of Guevara were being brought back to Cuba after thirty years in an unmarked grave somewhere in Bolivia. The documentary is a must see for all those concern with Latin American History and the Twentieth Century.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?101097</url></doc>
