<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="102253">
  <docid>102253</docid>
  <title>Chhupa Rustam</title>
  <year>1973</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Anand, Vijay</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">U</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">7 May 1973</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Anand, Vijay</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Anand, Vijay</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Anand, Vijay</writer>
    <writer>Bharati, Kaushal</writer>
    <writer>Sanim, Suraj</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Burman, Sachin Dev</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ajit (I)</actor>
      <role>Vikram Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anand, Dev</actor>
      <role>Ashwini Kumar/Natwarlal/Chhupa Rustam</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anand, Vijay</actor>
      <role>Jimmy Fernandes</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bindu (I)</actor>
      <role>Vikram's assistant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chopra, Prem</actor>
      <role>Bahadur Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hangal, A.K.</actor>
      <role>Prof. Harbanslal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Rashid (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Malini, Hema</actor>
      <role>Ritu R. Jain</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nath, Prem (I)</actor>
      <role>Williams</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sajjan</actor>
      <role>Rajendra Jain</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sudhir (I)</actor>
      <role>Lawrence</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The Government of India had granted Rs.50,000/- to Prof. Harbanslal to conduct a study in the mountains bordering Tibet with India, called the Nangla Project. Harbanslal is sure that within these ice-caped mountains lies an entire temple made of pure gold. When Vikram Singh and his son, Bahadur, find out about the Nangla Project, they abduct Harbanslal in order to force him to reveal the exact location of this temple, in vain though and end up killing him. Having failed in this venture, they kidnap the wife and son of multi-millionaire Rajendra Jain and demand that he get Bahadur married to his daughter, Ritu. Rajendra discusses this matter with Ritu, and Ritu is ready and willing to do anything for her mother and brother. Rajendra hesitates, and soon he receives his wife's thumb in the mail. Losing no time, Rajendra and Ritu make arrangements for the marriage and communicate accordingly with the kidnappers. Soon a wedding date is fixed, however, things do not go as planned as Ritu is abducted by a man called Natwarlal and taken to his hideout. While driving there, their car breaks down and they are forced to take a lift from Jimmy Fernandes, albeit at gunpoint. Jimmy drops them off at an isolated spot, leaving Natwarlal to work out the details of getting the ransom money from Rajendra. Before that could happen, Jimmy shows up and abducts Ritu. With his wife and son still held captive with Vikram and his son, Rajendra is at his wits' end as to whose life he should give priority to. Watch as events unfold to show what exactly was the motive in Ritu's multiple abductions, who is benefit by these incidents, and it's connection with the Nangla Project.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?102253</url></doc>
