<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="102254">
  <docid>102254</docid>
  <title>Chhupa Rustam: A Musical Thriller</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">A</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Kuwait">25 April 2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Sejawal, Aziz</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Mohla, Madan</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Chitragupth, Anand</composer>
    <composer>Chitragupth, Milind</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anand, Tinnu</actor>
      <role>Mama Manikchand</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Babbar, Raj</actor>
      <role>Supdt of Police Bhim Thappa</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Berde, Laxmikant</actor>
      <role>Manik (servant)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Sanjay (I)</actor>
      <role>Raja/Nirmal Kumar Chinoy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Satyendra</actor>
      <role>Sandhya's dad/Satpal's borther</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Mushtaq</actor>
      <role>Driver, Satpal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khote, Viju</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Koirala, Manisha</actor>
      <role>Nisha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kulkarni, Mamta</actor>
      <role>Sandhya</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mahadevan, Anant</actor>
      <role>Nirmal's dad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pradhan, Vishwajeet</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tahil, Dalip</actor>
      <role>Baldev Diwan Chinoy</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Nirmal (Sanjay Kapoor) studies in London, and his dad (Anant Mahadevan) lives in a palatial home in India with his mom (Navneet Nishan). Unknown to both Nirmal and his dad, mom is having an affair with an employee, Baldev Diwan (Dalip Tahil). When caught in the act by dad, they kill him and his driver, Satpal (Mushtaq Khan) and arrange an accident with the help of another employee Manikchand (Tinnu Anand). When Nirmal returns he is informed of the accident, and he believes his dad dies of a car accident. One day while romancing with his girlfriend Sandhya (Mamta Kulkarni), he comes across Satpal, who is now confined in a mental institution. Curious to see what Satpal has to say about the accident, Nirmal arranges for more qualified doctors in the big city to examine Satpal. Unknown to Nirmal, Superintendent of Police Thappa (Raj Babbar) is plotting with Raja (also played by Sanjay Kapoor) to kill Nirmal and take his place, Raja's girlfriend, Nisha (Manisha Koirala) overhears this and questions Raja, but Raja lies to her. Things start to change for the worst for Nirmal's dad and Diwanji when Raja is introduced to the family, and with the help of Thappa establishes his identity and fools everyone. But is Raja really what he claims to be? Is Nirmal really dead?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?102254</url></doc>
