<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="102834">
  <docid>102834</docid>
  <title>Chihuly in the Light of Jerusalem</title>
  <year>1999</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>West, Peter (X)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1999</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">57</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>West, Peter (X)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>McDonnell, Mark (III)</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chihuly, Dale</actor>
      <role>Himself - Artist</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"Every time I visited the Citadel, I would imagine what I could do to enhance its glory and bring attention to its soul," says Dale Chihuly. Joining forces with a team from Israel, Chihuly and his crew from Seattle create sixteen installations in Jerusalem's historic Citadel, now the Tower of David Museum of the History of Jerusalem. This exhibition was made up of more than 10,000 pieces of glass, blown in France, Japan, the Czech Republic, Finland, Israel, and the United States. The team competes with the sun and the challenges of another language and culture to construct these monumental sculptures. Chihuly explores the space, paints dozens of wildly energetic drawings, and plots out the placement of his sculptures. Before dawn each morning the sky flickers with bursts of light as welders erect steel armatures to be covered soon in glass. Chihuly creates his most radical work, the forty-four-foot-high Crystal Mountain, its jagged face of pink crystals catching the light of the setting sun. The Blue Tower soars against a wall of stone, and Niijima Floats nestle in the ancient ruins. Chihuly has transformed the Citadel into garden of color and celebration.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?102834</url></doc>
