<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="103230">
  <docid>103230</docid>
  <title>Children of South Africa</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>DiMartino, Daniel</editor>
    <editor>Levin, Jason (IV)</editor>
    <editor>Medaglia, Mark</editor>
    <editor>Presley, David</editor>
    <editor>Salsman, Zachary</editor>
    <editor>Schnitzer, Joshua</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>country-name-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>children</keyword>
    <keyword>cape-town-south-africa</keyword>
    <keyword>south-africa</keyword>
    <keyword>place-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">22 April 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">22</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Abbott, Rebecca L.</director>
    <director>O'Brien, Liam (XIV)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Abbott, Rebecca</producer>
    <producer>O'Brien, Liam (XIV)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Braff, Jason</writer>
    <writer>Martin, Alison (II)</writer>
    <writer>Medaglia, Mark</writer>
    <writer>Schnitzer, Joshua</writer>
    <writer>Taryla, Valerie</writer>
    <writer>Trowbridge, Nicole</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jones, Rebecka</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rosettenstein, David</actor>
      <role>Cecil John Rhodes</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>'Children of South Africa' is a story about the effects of colonialism and industrialism on modern South Africa. Specifically, it focuses on the thousands of townships that sprang up as a result of past colonial and industrial policies. The policies were championed by men like Cecil John Rhodes, who found the Debeers Diamond company. In order for a colossus of an industrial company, like Debeers, to produce as many diamonds at it did they had to bring in native workers from nearby and far away villages. These workers lived in camps and were not allowed to leave for the duration of there term of work (around 4-6 months). As a result, the families of the workers would often make the trek after them and live outside the camps. From this, townships sprang up, shanty towns that are home millions and sometimes measure 40 miles in diameter. The townships, however, present a variety of health care and educational issues. With South Africa having the largest HIV/AIDS infected population on the continent the townships suffer the most. 50% of the township's populations have HIV/AIDS. As a result of this and many other reasons, thousands of children are left without parents. They turn to the streets in order to survive. There are, however, many trying to help. The documentary further analyzes some of the orphanages and shelters that are constantly trying to save these children, as well as Kami the Muppet, who is the first HIV positive Muppet in the world.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?103230</url></doc>
