<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="103715">
  <docid>103715</docid>
  <title>Chinese Restaurants: Latin Passions</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bejtic, Zinka</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
    <language>Portuguese</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Netherlands">24 November 2005</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="South Korea">10 October 2005</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">10 March 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">80</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Kwan, Cheuk</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Mérinat, Monika</producer>
    <producer>Shek, Randy</producer>
    <producer>Tse, Linda</producer>
    <producer>Kwan, Cheuk</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Kwan, Cheuk</writer>
    <writer>Martin, Margaret S.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Giancola, Dino</composer>
    <composer>Lumb, Janet</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Latin Passions, based on the 15-part documentary series Chinese Restaurants, tells the story of the Chinese Diaspora through its most recognizable and enduring icon - the family-run Chinese restaurant. Filmmaker Cheuk Kwan visits Peru, Brazil, and Argentina exploring Latin passions in Chinese communities that have established themselves in South America. Lima-born Luis Yong is a medical doctor who took over a rundown restaurant, San Joy Lao, in the city's Chinatown. The charming and outgoing doctor hosts Chinese cooking shows on TV and promotes the marriage of holistic Chinese medicine and health-conscious Chinese cuisine. As Peru celebrated the 150th anniversary of the arrival of Chinese coolies, and as subsequent generations of Chinese focus on the importance of education, Yong is becoming a legend in Lima's rejuvenated Barrio Chino. Lee Ho Shau and his future wife Wong Yim Sheung swam from China to Macau, and freedom, during China's Cultural Revolution in the 1960's. They made their new life in Sao Paolo dedicated to perfecting the fine art of Chinese cuisine. On the eve of the 2002 World Cup final, their son, Luis, recounts his passion for football and what it means to grow up Chinese-Brazilian. As Brazil won its championship, the streets of Sao Paulo exploded as Luis celebrated with tens of thousands of fans. 77-year old Foo-Ching Chiang came to Buenos Aires in the 1960's and became the "Spring Roll King" of Argentina. His Casa China is a restaurant and cultural center bridging Argentinean and Chinese cultures. Chiang's fervent ideal of internationalism is tempered by his own solitude. While his family lives elsewhere in this planet, he lives his remaining years amidst the melancholy music of the seductive tango. Together, these community and personal histories illustrate the wider story of Chinese migration, settlement and integration. These stories celebrate the resilience and complexity of the Chinese diaspora and expand the definition of what it means to be "Chinese" today. They highlight the fluidity and highly personal nature of identity, and the human impulse to find passions in life wherever they call their home.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?103715</url></doc>
