<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="103864">
  <docid>103864</docid>
  <title>Chip Daniels' Video Studbook</title>
  <year>2000</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">110</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tucker, Cole</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>As a director, Chip Daniels brings his years of porn experience in front of the lens to the features he crafts for Centaur Films. This title is a compilation of eleven entire scenes from earlier works he directed (mainly from the late nineties, so more recent, award-winning titles like "Manhunter" are not included). With an emphasis on ultra masculine, men-in-uniform characters, the eleven scenes in this two-hour compilation run the gamut: hairy hunks, slender young twinks, and so on. All the scenes involve one-on-one encounters; no three- or four-way group setups. Each scene has a brief introduction by Mr. Daniels, but there is still, of course, no context or continuity offered. From "Hot Cops", 'Officer' Joe Romero has Jeff Jagger in custody in the back seat of the squad car. After he spies Jeff stroking his stiff dick with his cuffed hands, he pulls off the road for a suck-and-fuck on the hood of the car. Young, smooth Jeff bottoms for the rugged Joe. Shawn Justin dominates Lyle Brandon in the second scene, from "Hot Cops 2". This is a very verbal bedroom encounter between well-matched macho models. The third clip has Chad Donovan and K.C. Hart in a scene from "Hot Cops 3". The two big-dicked studs go at it, with Chad coming out on top. Chad Knight gets plowed in and on a jeep by Bo Summers in a scene from "Marine Crucible". Set outdoors in the mountains of Southern California, at climax both guys shoot their loads on Chad's chest while he's on his back on the hood of the jeep. Another verbal encounter is Sam Crockett topping Alex Kincaid on a desktop in a clip from "Hot Firemen". From the same title is another scene, with the compact and muscular J.T. Sloan servicing New Yawker Johnny Hansen alongside a fire truck. Johnny commands the action in his thick accent, and J.T. sucks him until he pops a load on his face and neck. He then fucks J.T., on and alongside the fire truck. Continuing the fireman theme are two scenes from "Hotter Than Hell", the first with hunky furry-chested Logan Reed 'rescuing' slender blond Kevin Kramer from the charred ruins of his house. Logan fucks Kevin on the singed sofa and coffee table. The next clip features chiseled 'fireman' Vince Rockland anally assaulting John Ross, after spanking his butt with his belt until it is rosy pink. In a scene from "Game Master", tanned, tattooed, and muscular Cole Tucker works over Kyle McKenna's ass, using both his cock and an assortment of dildoes. At climax, Kyle shoots his load all over Cole's chest tattoos. The final two clips in this compilation are from "Time Cops". In the first, Zachary Scott and youthful Nick Chevalier have an encounter in the bedroom. Zachary is endowed enough and limber enough that he can lean over forward and lick the tip of his own cock! He fucks Nick, and at climax showers cum onto Nick's chest and shoulders. The second scene has broad-shouldered top man Brock Masters fucking slender young Sandy Sloane in a hay barn romp. Audio and video quality are top-notch, and the lighting, camera angles, and editing at least show competence, if not great artistry. DVD extras include chapter selection, a photo gallery of stills, and a four-minute preview clip for "Man Academy". There are also static cover shots for 19 other Centaur Films titles.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?103864</url></doc>
