<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="103923">
  <docid>103923</docid>
  <title>Chirag Kahan Roshni Kahan</title>
  <year>1959</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="UK">U</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <directors>
    <director>Goel, Devendra</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Goel, Devendra</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Ravi (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Begum, Mumtaz</actor>
      <role>Ratna's mother-in-law</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Irani, Honey</actor>
      <role>Raju</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Rajendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Dr. Anand</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumari, Meena (I)</actor>
      <role>Ratna</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Prem, S.K.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, Madan (I)</actor>
      <role>Dr. Mehta</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sen, Asit (I)</actor>
      <role>Anand's dad's Solicitor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sunder (I)</actor>
      <role>Advocate S. Prakash</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A pregnant Ratna loses her husband, eventually gives birth to a son, Raju, in a hospital where she is treated by renowned Dr. Anand. Four years later, Anand re-enters their lives and starts becoming a frequent visitor. This does not auger well with Ratna's mother-in-law and Bela, her husband's sister, who make her life miserable, eventually forcing Anand to stop visiting. Shortly thereafter Anand gets married to a nurse, Maya Verma. Maya is a spendthrift,does not get along with Anand, and eventually finds out that she cannot conceive. When Anand's dad passes away, he leaves considerable wealth to Anand's child, including a monthly allowance of Rs.10,000/-. Maya initially plots with an advocate, S. Prakash, who is Bela's husband, who had assisted her in getting married to Anand, to try and prove that her late father-in-law was insane, and when that fails she and her aunt, Nurse Sarla Verma, concoct a plot that Ratna's son is really Anand's biological son, leading to their lawyer filing a custodial case in Court. The question remains is Raju really Anand's son, will Ratna readily give away her child, and is Maya capable of bringing him up?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?103923</url></doc>
