<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="103992">
  <docid>103992</docid>
  <title>Chitchor</title>
  <year>1976</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Ahmed, Mukhtar (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Musical</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">105</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Chatterjee, Basu (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Barjatya, Ajit Kumar</producer>
    <producer>Barjatya, Kamal Kumar</producer>
    <producer>Barjatya, Rajkumar</producer>
    <producer>Barjatya, Tarachand</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Chatterjee, Basu (I)</writer>
    <writer>Ghosh, Subodh</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Jain, Ravindra</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chaturvedi, Shail</actor>
      <role>Chaubey</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dubey, C.S.</actor>
      <role>Postman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ghatge, Vijayendra</actor>
      <role>Sunil Kishan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hangal, A.K.</actor>
      <role>Pitamber Choudhry</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kamal, Ritu</actor>
      <role>Meera</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Palekar, Amol</actor>
      <role>Vinod</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shrestha, Raju</actor>
      <role>Deepak Kumar 'Deepu' Agnihotri</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Pitamber Choudhry is a schoolmaster who lives in a small village, Madhopur, in India with his wife, and daughter, Gauri. His two other daughters are already married and live in Bombay. His daughter, Meera, has written to him that she has seen a suitable boy, who is an Engineer, returned from Germany, and would like him to be considered as a groom for Gauri. Pitamber and his wife are overjoyed and he goes to the railway station to meet the young man and bring him home. After meeting with him, both he and his wife approve of him and allow Gauri and him to get to know each other. They are ready to go ahead with the wedding as both Gauri and the young man seem to like each other. Than their lives are turned upside down, when they receive another letter from Meera informing them that the Engineer had to go to Delhi, and his arrival has been delayed. Watch what happens to the young man, when he finds out that nothing is going to be the same anymore between him and Gauri on one hand, and her parents on another, and also watch how the Choudhrys get together to welcome their new and genuine son-in-law, Sunil Kishan.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?103992</url></doc>
