<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="104713">
  <docid>104713</docid>
  <title>Chris &amp; Steve</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Wilson, Robert Grigsby</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>roadtrip</keyword>
    <keyword>puppet</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Jette, David</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Roberts, Joseph L.</producer>
    <producer>Gordon, Dan (VI)</producer>
    <producer>Gordon, Dan (VI)</producer>
    <producer>Jette, David</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Jette, David</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gordon, Dan (VI)</actor>
      <role>Chris</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harmon, Amy K.</actor>
      <role>Glenda</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Roberts, Joseph L.</actor>
      <role>Steve</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Chris, a puppet and an aspiring actor, rides in a car with his loser friend Steve. They are at the start of a road trip to Los Angeles where Chris has an audition for a television show. The two bicker about nonsense, as friends are wont to do, until they stop to pick up a seductive hitchhiker named Glenda. Her sad story fails to convince Chris, but she charms Steve easily, and they ride on into the night. After dark, Glenda bewitches Steve, slinking into his lap as he drives. Chris wakes up just as they nearly crash the car, and Steve begs Chris to drive so he can entertain Glenda in the backseat. Chris drives the car with his mouth as long as he can, then pulls the car over and climbs onto the hood of the car to practice his lines in the moonlight. The next day he is woken abruptly by passing cars and sees that Glenda has made off with their wallets. Steve is heartbroken, and Chris tries to cheer him up with a song from his upcoming audition. They pull into a nearby store only to find they've traveled in a circle and wasted an entire day of their trip. Chris receives a call from the casting director telling him they've already cast the part, and Chris is heartbroken. They decide to go to Vegas instead, and they drive off, best friends forever.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?104713</url></doc>
