<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="104823">
  <docid>104823</docid>
  <title>Christina</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kramer, Benedikt Maria</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>German</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Greece">9 December 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Ireland">17 March 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Poland">1 December 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Kramer, Benedikt Maria</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Kramer, Benedikt Maria</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Florian, Schanz</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gossger, Stephanie</actor>
      <role>Christina</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grabow, Wolfgang</actor>
      <role>Father</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grimm, Michael</actor>
      <role>Peter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Siebenschuh, Frank</actor>
      <role>Marius</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"There has to be one man that suits you", Mrs Stein tells her daughter. But Christina believes she has already found "her man". To earn the living of herself and her boyfriend, an unsuccessful painter, Christina works as a telephone hostess at a sex hotline. It's a job that doesn't mean anything to her, as she assures Peter. Secretly however, it makes her suffer. Peter feels deceived and calls on Christina to find another job. This gets down to an argument in which Christina reveals her existential fears to Peter, using the same phrases as her mother - what are they supposed to live on after all: Just on love? Peter escapes from the flat leaving Christina back alone. The phone rings, signalising another hotline customer, and this time, Christina almost doesn't pick up. Eventually, she answers, perhaps out of habit. But perhaps also in order to flee from her own loneliness. But unlike the usual callers, this man doesn't seek after a quick satisfaction. He tells Christina he has only a few minutes left to live. Christina is a film about solitude, about the loneliness in the company of people you love but still don't get through to.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?104823</url></doc>
