<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="106887">
  <docid>106887</docid>
  <title>Circle the Wagen</title>
  <year>2010</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Flack, Austin</editor>
    <editor>Green, Ryan (III)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>road-trip</keyword>
    <keyword>car</keyword>
    <keyword>cross-country</keyword>
    <keyword>route-66</keyword>
    <keyword>volkswagen</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">30 June 2010</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Green, Ryan (III)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Green, Ryan (III)</producer>
    <producer>Pecoraro, Charlie</producer>
    <producer>Torstenson, Dave</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hickerson, Gary</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pecoraro, Charlie</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Torstenson, Dave</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wiens, Matt Joseph</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Circle the Wagen is a feature length narrative documentary about America's love affair with Volkswagen and the underground community that makes the joy of driving part of the joy of living. Two guys, Dave and Charlie, are on a mission to save a 1972, baby blue, Volkswagen bus from the scrap heap. Problem is they're in Los Angeles and the bus is in Oklahoma. Solution; an underground network of regular folks who happen to own old Volkswagens; bugs, buses, Karmen Ghias and the rest of those lovable, air-cooled autos. The network is The A.I.R.S List; the air-cooled, inter-state, rescue squad and if you were to check out the website you would find dozens and dozens of stories of how regular people around America have come to the rescue of regular people stranded by the side of the road in their much loved rust bucket. Circle the Wagen tells the story of the people's car from its ominous beginnings in 1930's Nazi Germany, through the glorious hippie days and into the future. And by paralleling the journey of the best selling auto in history we see first hand how today's Volkswagen community rallies around two strangers, our new friends, Dave, Charlie and the baby blue bus affectionately called, "the Croc."</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?106887</url></doc>
