<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="106854">
  <docid>106854</docid>
  <title>Circle Canyon</title>
  <year>1933</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Burroughs, Frances (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Western</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>land-swindle</keyword>
    <keyword>oil</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Unrated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1933</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">48</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Adamson, Victor</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Adamson, Victor</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Adamson, Victor</writer>
    <writer>Tuttle, Burl R.</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Adamson, Victor</actor>
      <role>Henchman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hamson, Mark</actor>
      <role>Tom (Lucy's Father)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hazel, George</actor>
      <role>Sam Black</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Holbrook, Allen (I)</actor>
      <role>Vic Byrd</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Leland, Harry</actor>
      <role>Mat</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mathews, June</actor>
      <role>Clara Moore</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McCall, William (I)</actor>
      <role>Deputy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McClary, Clyde</actor>
      <role>Henchman Pete</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Osborne, Bud (I)</actor>
      <role>Sheriff</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Roosevelt, Buddy</actor>
      <role>Chris Morell</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Scott, Ernest (I)</actor>
      <role>Express Agent</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tyke, John</actor>
      <role>Jim - Clara's Nephew</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This was remade less than a year later by Monogram as "'Neath the Arizona Skies" starring John Wayne,and the character role names went unchanged, indicating that Monogram either didn't know about this film when they paid Burl Tuttle for it a 2nd time in less than a year or didn't care.Tuttle might have concluded that any film produced by Victor Adamson was so far out of the Hollywood mainstream---even for independent, Poverty Row productions---that Monogram wouldn't know they were buying used goods.The simplified plot has two different gangs attempting to wrest control of valuable Oklahoma oil lands from an orphaned girl(Clarissa Woods), who is aided in her fight by her adopted father Chris Morrell(Buddy Roosevelt.)This film has a character named Jim Moore, who is the younger brother of the heroine Clara Moore(June Mathews.)The role of Jim Moore was played by a minor Gower Gulch, poverty row hanger-on named Johnny Tyke,(billed as Bob Williamson in this film), who later was on the short end of a real life knife fight with another western poverty row player named Blackjack Ward.But, somehow or another some uninformed source,evidently seeing the name of Bob Williamson on the cast list decided that the Bob Willimson in this film was the silent-film actor Bob Williamson, who hadn't made a film in nearly ten years, and changed the site credits to reflect his incorrect assumption.If shown a still of both Johnny Tyke and Bob Williamson, this source most likely wouldn't know one from the other.Actually, it's evident he doesn't, or it wouldn't have been incorrectly changed.But maybe the source should have watched the film first and would have realized that in 1933 Bob Williamson(I) was nearly 50 years old and could not have been the actor playing the role of the 30's-something Jim Moore. Johnny Tyke, billed as Bob Williamson(for whatever reason not excluding the possibility Johnny Tyke didn't want to be found)played the role of Jim Moore in this film and Bob Williamson (I) did not.Other than the lead, many of the players in Victor Adamson films were obscure players who seldom appeared in other films---"many" and "seldom" are the operative words here---and the actor, Mark Hamson, who played "Tom Byrd" in this film was one of those but the source that decided that Bob Williamson(I)was the actor behind the Bob Williamson credited in this film(he wasn't)must have also been the source that decided to replace the credited Mark Hamson with an actor that doesn't exist named Mark Harrison (IV).The mind boggles...replace a credited name with a name that doesn't exist? The young girl that plays the adopted Lucy Morrell in this film is credited on the film as Clarissa Woods.That has been changed to Claire Wood, a young actress in Universal's 1934 "Student Tour" by somebody. Clarissa Woods and Claire Wood may or may not be the same actress, but if so then the source that changed Clarissa Woods to Claire Wood should have put(as Clarissa Woods) in the attributes column because she is billed as Clarissa Woods.And FYI to the source that thinks Harry Leland played a character named "Mat" in this film; a "mat" is an object and "Matt" is a name and the character played by Harry Leland in this film is named "Mad Matt".The same character is played by George "Gabby" Hayes in the "Neath the Arizona Skies" remake and he is also named "Matt(Downing)." You might want to run over to that listing and change that to "Mat" also.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?106854</url></doc>
