<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="107992">
  <docid>107992</docid>
  <title>Clash A' Da Tight 1's</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Parker, Oliver (IV)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">4 June 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">28 June 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">78</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Nygh, Ted</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Nygh, Ted</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Hines, Ian (II)</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Inspired by the talent surrounding him, and frustrated by the lack of respect for it, Teddy Nygh took a camera to the streets, determined to show the art of hip hop - get to the heart of hip hop - and to reveal the inspirational people who create it. It is winter 2005. Along the journey the importance of his mission became more and more obvious; to expose this often neglected and misunderstood art to global audiences and to question the stereotypes and the negative press. Over the ensuing months it became clear that this was a huge responsibility - to convey the artists' messages, and to tell their stories, with honesty and truth. Summer 2007. After months of traveling the corners of north, east, south and west London, not to mention flying to the other side of the globe to Australia, recording over fifty interviews and more than two hundred hours of footage, followed by several months and thousands of hours of editing.... C.A.D.T.1's had arrived. ABOUT CLASH A' DA TIGHT 1'S An Award winning 'Rapumentary' where one man and his camera take you on a journey deep into the heART of British and Australian underground Hip Hop. We travel from the cold grimy streets of London to the warm sunny beaches of Sydney. Along the way, we get to meet some of the most inspirational and talented artists the UK and AUS have to offer. The mission is to expose the often neglected and misunderstood heART of Hip Hop. In doing so, many social issues are uncovered, especially around inner London, where poverty, gun and knife crime, postcode rivalry, youth issues and poor housing are serious problems. The viewer is taken to where it happens when it happens making the film raw, powerful and insightful but most of all real. The overall message is one of optimism and hope, of course there is controversy, its CLASH A' DA TIGHT 1'S.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?107992</url></doc>
