<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="108108">
  <docid>108108</docid>
  <title>Class of 83</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Swanson, Brian (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>ground-zero</keyword>
    <keyword>number-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>art</keyword>
    <keyword>911</keyword>
    <keyword>september-11-2001</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">03</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="USA">55</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Soderling, Kurt E.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Fischer, Mark (IV)</producer>
    <producer>Soderling, Kurt E.</producer>
    <producer>Fischer, Scott (I)</producer>
    <producer>Songer, Melinda</producer>
    <producer>Walsh, Brigid</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Soderling, Kurt E.</writer>
    <writer>Songer, Melinda</writer>
    <writer>Walsh, Brigid</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Caroccio, Mike</composer>
    <composer>Delguadio, Dennis</composer>
    <composer>Negron, David</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>CLASS OF '83 The Class of '83 from Long Island's Half Hollow Hills High East was special. In a time and place where relationships were built to last a lifetime, including those with your high school sweetheart, this class knew that they could always count on each other. But September 11, 2001 brought the Class of '83 even closer together than they had ever imagined. Chris Panatier and Tom Collins, two extraordinarily charismatic pillars of the group, were killed on that day. The friends with whom they shared these halls and sports fields would be those who would rally in keeping their memory alive. As their twenty-year reunion approaches, these friends unite to create a place to reflect upon the extraordinary lives of Chris and Tom and the meaning of the friendships that they cherished. With the guidance of landscape artist/classmate Gus Wade and a remarkable donation from world-renown sculptor, Bret Price, classmates from across the country reunite on Long Island to work hand and hand to transform an unappreciated section of the High School into a museum quality sculpture garden. The dynamics of these relationships resume as if they've never left each others' company for a heart-felt tribute that helps to heal the wounds from that tragic day in September of 2001.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?108108</url></doc>
