<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="108165">
  <docid>108165</docid>
  <title>Classic Concentration</title>
  <year>1987</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Game-Show</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>non-fiction</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">22 February 1991</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Breslow, Marc</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Cutt, Timothy J.</producer>
    <producer>Ryan, Steve (II)</producer>
    <producer>Johnston, Gabrielle</producer>
    <producer>Johnston, Gabrielle</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bean, Orson</actor>
      <role>Himself - Host</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Goodson-Cutt, Marjorie</actor>
      <role>Model (????-1991)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>James, Art</actor>
      <role>Substitute Announcer (1991)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Trebek, Alex</actor>
      <role>Host</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Winfrey, Kent</actor>
      <role>Himself - Contestant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wood, Gene (I)</actor>
      <role>Announcer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wood, Gene (I)</actor>
      <role>Announcer (1987-1993)</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Revival of the classic NBC game show where two contestants, one a returning champion, faced a computer-generated board of 25 squares. Game play was the same as before: Each contestant called out a pair of numbers on the board, which contained the names of prizes and WILD and TAKE cards (the latter two explained later). No match passed control to the opponent, but a match gave whatever prize was named or a TAKE marker, revealed two pieces of the rebus (identifying a person, phrase, place, thing, etc.) and allowed him/her a chance to solve the rebus. WILD cards provided an automatic match; revealing two WILD cards in the same turn earned a $500 bonus, while uncovering the third take meant a $1,000 bonus and the opportunity to reveal up to five pieces of the rebus at once. Contestants uncovering a TAKE card (red and green cards, with a color match required) could, upon a correct match, elect to hold onto the marker to wait for their opponent to collect a better prize or to take back a desired prize their opponent had already taken. Only upon correctly solving the rebus does a player actually win what he/she claimed from the board; the loser forfeits all his gifts. The winner played a bonus game that used a 15-square board, with a car used as a grand prize. The model names of eight cars (e.g., FIREBIRD, JUSTY, 323, etc.) appeared on the board, with one of them not having a match. Contestants successfully matching the seven car names within 35 seconds won the last car named and retired the player undefeated; otherwise, an extra 5 seconds was added to the clock each for each subsequent trip to the bonus game (later in the show's run, uncovering a "FIVE BONUS SECONDS" card and winning the game added 5 more seconds to the clock). The rules affecting a champion's reign, aside from winning a car and leaving undefeated, changed throughout the run at first, it was one loss and done (early on, contestants could also win more than one car); later, players cold lose twice before their defeat; still later, a best-of-three format was used, while the rules reverted back to the second format even later. An annual tournament of champions (with participants determined by cash winnings) offered a trip-around-the-world as a grand prize during the first year; during the second through fourth years, a luxury car was the top prize. Production of "Classic Concentration" ceased during the summer of 1991; the network aired reruns through January 1994.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?108165</url></doc>
