<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="108234">
  <docid>108234</docid>
  <title>Classmates of Anne Frank</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Haramatti, Hilla</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>wwii</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>anti-semitism</keyword>
    <keyword>holocaust</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hebrew</language>
    <language>English</language>
    <language>Dutch</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Israel</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Israel">15 December 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Romania">28 November 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Israel">58</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Boers, Eyal</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Coster, Aliza</producer>
    <producer>Boers, Eyal</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>Theo (Maurice) Coster, a famous games' creator from Israel, renews contact with six of his and Anne Frank's former classmates, only to discover an astonishing and confusing truth about the village where he was hiding during World War Two. Set against their childhood locations in Amsterdam, Westerbork Transit Camp and their current homes in Holland and Israel, these former classmates discuss their relationships with Anne and how they survived the war. Through these discussions, the film takes a bold and illuminating look at the different Dutch attitudes towards the war years in The Netherlands and towards the Holocaust. Anna Frank's Diary confirms the tragedy of the Holocaust and continues to debunk Holocaust deniers. The documentation of Anna's classmates, now in their eighties, strengthens the impact the Diary has on the world. The story of Anna's classmates is not only illustrated through interviews and discussions between the classmates themselves, but also through photographs, archival footage, personal scrapbooks and letters and other new resources.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?108234</url></doc>
