<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="108447">
  <docid>108447</docid>
  <title>Cleanse &amp; Build Inner Qi</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Sher, Sarah</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Sport</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>qi-gong</keyword>
    <keyword>martial-arts</keyword>
    <keyword>qigong</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 October 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">84</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Sher, Sarah</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Milton, John P.</producer>
    <producer>Smith, Nancy (V)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Khechog, Nawang</composer>
    <composer>Nakai, R. Carlos</composer>
    <composer>Richardson, Stan</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Milton, John P.</actor>
      <role>Host</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Smith, Bill (XVII)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The living energy of nature-known as qi in Chinese medicine-is a power you can channel for improving your own health. On Cleanse &amp; Build Inner Qi, qi gong master John P. Milton teaches you how to use that energy to purify and renew your physical body down to a cellular level. As he guides you with precision and clarity through each time-tested technique, you will experience the pure, revitalizing power of qi suffusing all major organ systems. The Qi Gong for Long Life series condenses the most essential lessons from qi gong and t'ai chi expert John P. Milton into three DVDs, giving you the chance to experience an authentic qi gong retreat at your own pace. Cleanse &amp; Build Inner Qi includes 12 easy-to-use reference cards to let you take your qi gong practice outdoors, where you will be able to tap into the natural healing energy from the world around you. This is qi gong as it was meant to be practiced-transmitted from an experience master under the open sky, where you can truly channel the qi of heaven and earth to strengthen you health, increase your vitality, and enrich the years of your life. Perfect for use as a self-healing practice, or for enhancing any medical and fitness regimen.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?108447</url></doc>
