<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="110664">
  <docid>110664</docid>
  <title>Collateral Damages</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Gumpel, Emily</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">5 September 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">67</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Sauret, Étienne</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Labro, Anne</producer>
    <producer>Sauret, Étienne</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Dempster, Stewart</composer>
    <composer>Vitiello, Stephen</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Butler, Jack (III)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Romeo, Pete</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ruvolo, Philip</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Hi it's me, I'm not dead and our whole world has just changed. When I do remember. Scrap Metal. Emotions are running very high. Lucky enough to live through the scene. How an ant would feel walking around on Broadway. Instincts take over. I want to be with my wife and kids, but I can't do it. There were too many questions. I think I can handle it. It's still yesterday. Trucks are gone. I'm contaminated. What's the matter with you? Why are you like that? These few months of my life are not focused on them. They don't understand. Losing it. Fresh Kills. Bred into all of us. You needed that normalcy. They sent the experts in. There's a little Buddha, he's supposed to keep me safe. Seeking counseling. I look forward to fires more than ever. To remember what I did. Rigs ripped apart. I feel like I haven't seen it all and I'm frightened about that. It hasn't really hit me. Maybe it will hit me one day. Collateral Damages is about the psychological impact 9-11 had on NYC firefighters. Featuring firefighters from Engine 6, Rescue 2, and Engine 285, these men share personal testimonies of the emotional and mental anguish of an aftermath with no end. In addition to its hour-long feature, Collateral Damages has more than two hours of extensive special features, including the dismantling of the Rescue 2 rig and never before seen footage of Fresh Kills, the crime scene no one knew about. 20% of the proceeds are donated to the Engine 6 Memorial Fund and the Rescue 2 Family Fund.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?110664</url></doc>
