<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="111217">
  <docid>111217</docid>
  <title>Columbia Sports Reel: Army Football Champions</title>
  <year>1946</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Sport</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>american-football</keyword>
    <keyword>u.s.-military-academy</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Approved</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">19 September 1946</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">9</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Foster, Harry (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Blanchard, Felix</actor>
      <role>Himself - West Point Football Player</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Davis, Glenn (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself - West Point Football Player</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hickman, Herman</actor>
      <role>Himself - Penn Football Coach</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stern, Bill (I)</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This Sports Reel short takes a look at the prior 1945 season of the Black Knights of West Point (Army Academy)as one of the best collegiate football teams of all time. They actually were but there were some underlying reasons that both the Army and Navy service academies were the cream of the crop in the mid-forties; all of the non-4F college players were either at Army or Navy or were playing for service teams at Great Lakes Naval Training, Fort Sill, Oklahoma and the like. And Army and Navy did not play these teams. Their schedule was confined to one tough game each against Notre Dame and each other, and the rest against East Coast and Ivy League creampuffs.But schedules aside, this Army team, with Mr. Inside (Doc Blanchard) and Mr. Outside (Glenn Davis)and the likes of Tex Coulter, was capable of competing against the best of the pre-war college teams from schools such as Texas, Minnesota, Michigan and Texas A&amp;M. War-time conditions, situations and schedules discounted, the 1945-46 Army teams were all they were cracked up to be...even if they didn't take the field against very many good teams.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?111217</url></doc>
