<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="113834">
  <docid>113834</docid>
  <title>Confessions of a Slacker</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Rayment, Kieran</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>drunk</keyword>
    <keyword>dark-comedy</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">8 June 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">5 September 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">17</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Rayment, Kieran</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>McDuffe, Paul</producer>
    <producer>Bourgeois, Patricia</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Rayment, Kieran</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Harrold, Matthew</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hickey, Mikael</actor>
      <role>Jack</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Joy, Theresa</actor>
      <role>Taylor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McDuffe, Paul</actor>
      <role>Coffe Shope Dude</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Twenty-five, drunk, two-timed, worn out, and dumped, Jack is having a mid life crisis of sorts. Working at a gas station by day, and trying to be a writer by night, Jack has always, at best, had a tentative grip on sobriety. But when his writers block wont diminish, and his supposed soul-mate informs him she's leaving him for his best friend, Jack finds an all new way of hitting rock bottom, with a little help from his drunken obnoxious friends. After some severe misadventures due to binge drinking, Jack is forced to face some demons. Reflections on broken bones, broken hearts, and a run in with two black angels, Jack thinks he's having a moment of clarity. But after he's informed of his Ex-girlfriend moving in with his now ex-best friend, Jack decides to invite his demons out for another round. When his ex-girlfriend, and his barely functioning liver give him a final reality check, Jack has no choice but to give himself a good hard look. But admitting you have a problem and doing something about it are two very different things.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?113834</url></doc>
