<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="114086">
  <docid>114086</docid>
  <title>Connect 5</title>
  <year>1996</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Fisher, Andy (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">91</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Fisher, Andy (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Duplass, Mark</producer>
    <producer>Duplass, Jay</producer>
    <producer>Fisher, Andy (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Fisher, Andy (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bernstein, Jesse (I)</actor>
      <role>Darwin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Duplass, Jay</actor>
      <role>Duplass, L. Jay</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Eyo-Ita, Charles</actor>
      <role>Custer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fisher, Andy (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Langham, Joseph</actor>
      <role>Evil Man</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Madden, Robert</actor>
      <role>Pitt</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McKinstry, Scott</actor>
      <role>Capslock</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Russo, Steve (IV)</actor>
      <role>Dumptruck</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A loverlorn tanning salon employee, a homey grandma and her bad-ass biker tenant, a lame gang, a nosediving intellectual, and a dis-uniting father and son. Connect 5 is the chance for these absurdly real people to risk it all. These five stories are bound together by a roving evil man, who "pushes" them out of the rut of life. Charity, the tanning salon chick, dumps her boyfriend for the tender affection of a ten-year-old. The lame gang battles fist to fist with the legions of Satan. Norma hires a young stud biker to be the "man of her house." Frank and Frank take a ride down memory lane that ends in a 50 car emotional pile-up. Capslock recircuits his computer network to locate a girl obsessed with her vagina. And the evil man himself? He wanted a van. A big black rapist van. With no windows. Like a big fat hammerhead shark. This would be Satan's van. An evil van... for an evil man. But all he got was a mauve Geo prism with primer. So he crushes a dog, hi-jacks an ice cream truck, rocket-vomits on yuppies, kidnaps a chicken named "Balls," tongue-kisses Charity, rips the doors off his Geo metro and let "Balls" the chicken shit all over the backseat. He's making a list, checking it twice, and he's packing a big sack of whoop-ass.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?114086</url></doc>
