<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="114665">
  <docid>114665</docid>
  <title>Contra viento y marea</title>
  <year>1962</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Mexico</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Gómez Urquiza, Zacarías</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Aguilar, Luis (I)</actor>
      <role>Chui</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Alban, Ernesto (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fuentes, Alma Delia</actor>
      <role>Margarita</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mejía, Alfonso</actor>
      <role>Son</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moreno, José Elías (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A native Italian man, has a prosperous fishing business in the Pacific coast of México. His partner, Chui, is a very experienced fisherman, who likes going on the boat and fishing with the other workers. One day, the Italian man receives a letter from his two children, who are living in Europe, telling him that they will travel to México. Margarita is a charming and beautiful girl, who works in an inn. When the kids arrive, they behave in an arrogant way with their father, telling him that in Europe they had a good education and now they're quite different from him. The father is sad about them, finding out that they despise him in a very cold manner. So, Chui and other people prepare a plan, in order to give the children a lesson: fake the father's death. The daughter and the son are very depressed and cry their father's death. However, they will fight with Chui and the lawyer about the father's inheritance. Without a penny, the kids will demand the entire running of the fishing business, but they don't know anything about managing an enterprise. Meanwhile, the father is hidden and he's regretted about all the farce, because he finds out that his children actually love him. Chui concludes that the kids will have to begin from down, the boy as a fisherman and the girl as a packer. The experience will turn the kids into a more kind persons, finding out that they love their father very much.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?114665</url></doc>
