<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="115670">
  <docid>115670</docid>
  <title>Corner of Your Eye</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Spencer, Jesse (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">16 September 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">96</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Spencer, Jesse (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Spencer, Jesse (II)</producer>
    <producer>Altieri, Mitchell</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Spencer, Jesse (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Gerzevitz, Kevin</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lanning, Drew</actor>
      <role>Paul</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ross, Aaron (I)</actor>
      <role>Sam</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Sam, Sarah and Paul have a problem. They're all going insane. They imagine terrifying, spying eyeballs peering at them all the time. They can't sleep, and all their dreams are starting to blend together, so they can't tell reality from fantasy. It doesn't help that Sam kind of has a "thing" for Sarah - and he's not sure if she feels the same way. It's not as if they really know each other; they just exchange glances at each other at the Coffeeshop during the day, while in their dreams they love, hurt, grope and explode each other. Whatever this disease is, it starts with a flirt, and ends with insanity. But our trio is able to overcome it by listening to a strange, magically innocuous tune! That's well and good for an innocent crush, but what about a real relationship? Will Sam, Sarah and Paul be emotionally screwed for the rest of their lives, or can they find ways to live in each other's insane lives happily? Is Sam doomed to be the bitter cynic? Will Sarah forgive herself for hurting Sam, or just continue on in denial? Will Paul ever just, grow up? The "Corner of Your Eye" sees their romances from an alien perspective, and watches, long after the "happy ending" is over.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?115670</url></doc>
