<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="116961">
  <docid>116961</docid>
  <title>Couples Only</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Atwater, Gina</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>friendship</keyword>
    <keyword>kids-and-family</keyword>
    <keyword>skating-rink</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">October 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">9</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Atwater, Gina</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Thompson, Jayda</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Masferrer, Marta Alicia</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Artov, Marlene</actor>
      <role>Dily</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cowley, Jed</actor>
      <role>D.J.</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Edmonds, Shenell</actor>
      <role>Casey</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hart, Skylar</actor>
      <role>Stacey</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Henney, Katie</actor>
      <role>Jenny</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jones, Justin (XII)</actor>
      <role>Walter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Russo, Anthony (V)</actor>
      <role>Lex</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Dily has only one desire: to participate in the "couples only" skate. No one, however, has ever asked Dily to skate. Dily's only companion is Walter. Although he comes in handy when Dily encounters Lex, the rink bully, Walter can't skate. So, when Dily meets the new girl Jenny, she abandons Walter in pursuit of becoming popular and finding a couples partner that way. The next day, Dily comes to the rink dressed in what she thinks would make Jenny proud of her. What she finds, however, is that Jenny is too ashamed to acknowledge their friendship around the popular kids. While in the bathroom, Dily overhears an altercation between Jenny and Lex. She saves Jenny in the knick of time, but Jenny runs away. Convinced she really is alone, Dily goes out to the rink to skate by herself and embrace her isolation. Someone, however, has mysteriously dedicated a song to her. That someone is Jenny, and Dily finally gets to skate in the "couples only" skate. While skating with Jenny, however, Dily sees Walter, alone on the sidelines. Dily leaves Jenny and goes to Walter, confessing the "couples only" skate isn't all it's cracked up to be. She realizes that her friendship with Walter has been the only true thing in her life for the past couple days, and the two of them decide to embrace the fact that they have each other.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?116961</url></doc>
