<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="117026">
  <docid>117026</docid>
  <title>Courage: Profiles in Creativity</title>
  <year>1998</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Mrnka, Mark</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">October 1998</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">62</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>McDaniel, Deanna</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Boyce, Rob 'Sluggo'</producer>
    <producer>Mrnka, Mark</producer>
    <producer>McDaniel, Deanna</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Moder, Christian</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>August, Bille</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Franti, Michael</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Guzman, Suzanna (I)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Herd, Stan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lithgow, John (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Palmiotti, Jimmy (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Quesada, Joe</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>With a bent toward inspiring even the direst cynic, COURAGE: Profiles in Creativity takes a close-up look at the courage needed to transform the ordinary into the extraordinary. Through the work of 20 unique individuals including corporate presidents, painters, rap musicians, and scientists, the film takes us on a powerful journey into the very essence of creativity. It examines what creativity is, how people get started, its' role in our society, the link between creativity and spirituality, and personality traits of the highly creative. With the candor of actor John Lithgow, the wisdom of author John Gardner, and the academic expertise of Harvard Professor Teresa Amabile, we discover what makes for an optimum creative environment and how to get back to our instinctual roots. Conversely, COURAGE explores the effects of creativity gone awry. A thought-provoking and humorous journey from precarious beginnings to full scale accomplishments, COURAGE inspires audiences to dust off the old paintbrush and unlock their own distinct creativity. Additional individuals interviewed include Director Bille August, Opera Diva Suzanna Guzman, World Champion runner Lynn Jennings, crop artist Stan Herd, whose canvases are fields around the globe which can only be properly viewed from the air; Jimmy Palmiotti and Joe Quesada, creators of the comic book "Ash," the basis for a forthcoming Dreamworks feature animated film; Lead singer/songwriter of "Spearhead," Michael Franti; award-winning scientist and MIT professor, Alexander Rich; Apple Computer Designer Robert Brunner; Principal dancers of Buglisi/Foreman Dance, as well as other individuals.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?117026</url></doc>
