<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="117225">
  <docid>117225</docid>
  <title>Cover Story</title>
  <year>2000</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Malayalam</language>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Vijayan, G.S.</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Sagar, R.D.</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Augustin</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dev, Rajan P.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gopi, Suresh</actor>
      <role>Vijay</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Madhavan, T.P.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Menon, Biju</actor>
      <role>ACP Anand S. Nair</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rizabawa</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Siddique (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sreekumar (I)</actor>
      <role>Sachidanandan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Varghese, N.F.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Venu, Nedumudi</actor>
      <role>Chandrashekara Menon</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Chandrashekar Menon is a retired Judge and lives an upper middle-class lifestyle in Southern India along with two grandchildren. His son and daughter-in-law are out of town for a few years. While returning home one day, he gets to meet his new neighbor, Jasmine, and both become very friendly. Then one day when Jasmine goes to ask Chandrashekar for help finding her contact lens, she instead finds his dead body, shot in the head at close range. She also sees the blurred outline of a human being, but due to her extreme myopia, is unable to identify the assailant. The police are summoned and Jasmine is questioned. This is where she gets to meet dynamic Newsperson and Executive Director of True Vision, who also helps her to re-locate to another flat, as the people in the neighborhood were casting aspirations about her, her character, and her relationship with Chandrashekar. But Jasmine's ordeal is not over as another dead body lands in her shopping cart. This body is of the retired DCP Mohan, and the police immediately think that Jasmine is the suspect. Her background is thoroughly checked all the way from Chennai to Bombay, where her parents lived. They find out that her mother, Saraswati, is a Hindu, and father, a Muslim. Both had separated. Watch what happens when things spiral out of hand and a new twist is added to this bizarre case when more people turn up dead.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?117225</url></doc>
