<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="117519">
  <docid>117519</docid>
  <title>Cph Remix</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Sangstad, Mikkel</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>copenhagen-denmark</keyword>
    <keyword>graffiti</keyword>
    <keyword>art</keyword>
    <keyword>street-art</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Danish</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Denmark</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Denmark">13 December 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">39</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Gudnason, Runar</director>
    <director>Gutkin, Ulrik</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Gudnason, Runar</writer>
    <writer>Gutkin, Ulrik</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Phobos Peepl, The</composer>
    <composer>Woody (VI)</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Copenhagen is a small, but famous capital in Europe. It's known for Tivoli, the Little Mermaid, the Royal Family etc. But Copenhagen also has a very different visual part. Everywhere around the city street-artists are adding their stories, emotions and expressions on the walls and tunnels. Copenhagen Remix is shot during the biggest "fairytale" event during the last four decades in Denmark: The royal wedding between Crown Prince Frederik and his Australian fiancée, Mary Donaldson. While the city is dressing up for the royal event, two local artists are working intensely in the streets with their arts. Meanwhile a desperate graffiti remover from the city council is trying to clean up the "mess" before the giant event. The film follows the two artists in their work and gets close to the human need to express itself. It's a need that even the graffiti remover has to acknowledge in the end of the film. During the two artists work - and other artists work in the city picture - we sense the organism of a big modern city in Europe.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?117519</url></doc>
