<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="117626">
  <docid>117626</docid>
  <title>Crackie</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Darlington, Chris</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Czech Republic">July 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Canada">15 September 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">94</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>White, Sherry</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Buckley, Rhonda</producer>
    <producer>Ripley, Jennice</producer>
    <producer>White, Sherry</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>White, Sherry</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Andrews, Duane (II)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Booth, Kristin</actor>
      <role>Gail</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Greeley, Meghan</actor>
      <role>Mitsy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hynes, Joel</actor>
      <role>Duffy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maggs, Jane</actor>
      <role>Vickie</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Life on the Rock never seemed easy, but for Mitsy it is especially rough. The teenager has been abandoned by her mother, a particularly unfit parent prone to both the bottle and the sex trade. She is left to be brought up by her mercurial grandmother Bride, who is well-meaning but oppressively suffocating. Mitsy's dreams for the future hinge on her desire to be a hairdresser, but her current emotional well-being revolves around a wee dog named Sparky, an unwanted canine misfit to whom she becomes hopelessly attached. After Bride agrees to let Mitsy take the dog in as a pet, the teen tries desperately to create a happy, safe place for Sparky to thrive - basically, she wants to offer the dog the kinds of comforts she has never known. But Mitsy's life is shaken once more when her mother returns to Newfoundland. Even though Mitsy is thrilled, Bride wants nothing to do with her never-do-well deadbeat daughter. It's a family made up of three wildly dysfunctional generations, always poised to clash. And in the midst of it all, Mitsy is learning about her emerging sexuality and developing a crush on a local bad boy who works in a rather grim fast food joint.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?117626</url></doc>
