<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="117795">
  <docid>117795</docid>
  <title>Crash Landing: Stories of Survival</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Brian, Polly</editor>
    <editor>Fannin, Luke</editor>
    <editor>Howard, Bill (III)</editor>
    <editor>Malkie, Scott</editor>
    <editor>Wichard, Karl</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">5 February 2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">50</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Howard, Bill (III)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Warren, John (X)</producer>
    <producer>Kelly, Brian J.</producer>
    <producer>Howard, Bill (III)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Kelly, Brian J.</writer>
    <writer>Parker, Gary (XVI)</writer>
    <writer>Warren, John (X)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Wolpe, Mike</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Majors, Lee (III)</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In Crash Landing: Stories of Survival, pilots from Vietnam to the Persian Gulf War tell their heart-pounding survival stories. The program, narrated by Lee Majors, shows how Aviation Survival Training makes the difference in the most defining moment of a pilot's life. Experience the fear and drama as pilots are shot down over hostile territory and how they are forced to rely on their training to survive the elements and evade enemy forces. Crash Landing takes viewers through a grueling six-week survival course, and presents important lessons from the instructors who teach lifesaving principles to aviation pilots. At the same time, Crash Landing looks back into history to tell some of the most harrowing tales of survival including the rescue of Bat 2-1, the largest pilot rescue operation in American history made famous by the Hollywood film Bat 21 starring Gene Hackman and Danny Glover. Crash Landing tells the story through aviation footage, interviews with survivors, and other recordings made during actual rescues.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?117795</url></doc>
