<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="119572">
  <docid>119572</docid>
  <title>Crossroads</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Pyatte, Steve 'Papaw'</editor>
    <editor>Risk, Daniel</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>death</keyword>
    <keyword>prison</keyword>
    <keyword>frankenstein</keyword>
    <keyword>drinking</keyword>
    <keyword>crash</keyword>
    <keyword>indianapolis-indiana</keyword>
    <keyword>automobile</keyword>
    <keyword>funeral</keyword>
    <keyword>dead</keyword>
    <keyword>driving</keyword>
    <keyword>accident</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-short</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">20 September 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">19</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Pyatte, Steve 'Papaw'</director>
    <director>Risk, Daniel</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Risk, Daniel</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Pyatte, Steve 'Papaw'</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Franklin, Virgil</composer>
    <composer>McKenzie, Kris (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Becker, Donald A.</actor>
      <role>Samuel Warner</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gould-Dougherty, Gemma</actor>
      <role>Sarah Warner</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moore, Jan (III)</actor>
      <role>Kelley Warner</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pyatte, Steve 'Papaw'</actor>
      <role>Joe</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Maddy McGuire had tried numerous times to save her failing marriage, unsuccessfully. Her husband Joe loved to drink...and had no problem getting behind the wheel of a car while drinking. Joe's drinking caused him to lose his job, which placed a heavy financial burden on them. The stress was becoming more than Maddy could handle. It wasn't the money issues that caused the constant arguing...it was Joe's drinking. Joe didn't think he had a drinking problem. He was convinced he was just fine. He was wrong. Dead wrong. While traveling down a dark country road one evening, arguing over the issues at hand, they are suddenly propelled into a nightmare that no one should have to experience. A head-on collision takes the lives of four innocent people...because Joe, once again, refused to listen to the voice of reason and makes the deadly mistake of drinking and driving. Enter Samuel Warner to deliver a powerful message with the help of his wife, Kelley and their twelve-year old daughter, Sarah. Watch as this very dramatic, and sometimes gruesome film, unfolds into a lesson learned the hard way. Joe finds out that he cannot turn back the hands of time...no matter how much he wishes he could.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?119572</url></doc>
