<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="119924">
  <docid>119924</docid>
  <title>Cruzando</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Marks, Dan (III)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>one-word-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Alvarado, Mando</director>
    <director>Escamilla, Michael Ray</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Barrera, David</producer>
    <producer>Marks, Dan (III)</producer>
    <producer>Weaver, Jeremy Gram</producer>
    <producer>Fenton, Abby Paige</producer>
    <producer>Miller, Pete (II)</producer>
    <producer>Alvarado, Mando</producer>
    <producer>Escamilla, Michael Ray</producer>
    <producer>Garza, René</producer>
    <producer>Rodriguez, Liza (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Feldman, Enrique 'Hank' C.</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Alvarado, Mando</actor>
      <role>Diego</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barrera, David</actor>
      <role>The Matador</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Campisi, Tony</actor>
      <role>Earl</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dardaris, Janis</actor>
      <role>Grace</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Escamilla, Michael Ray</actor>
      <role>Manuel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Helan, Maria</actor>
      <role>Maia</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kennedy, Sarena</actor>
      <role>Taquita</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Leon, Nina</actor>
      <role>Earl's wife</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ortiz, Gilberto</actor>
      <role>Hector</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rodriguez, Gerardo (I)</actor>
      <role>Ignacio</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>What do you do if the day your first child is to be born is also the same day your father is to be executed? If you're twenty-six-year old MANNY, you use your father's impending execution as an excuse to flee the daunting responsibility of fatherhood. There's only one problem: Manny lives in Monterrey, Mexico and his father sits in on death row in Texas. Against his wife's wishes, Manny embarks on an ill-planned quest to cross the border to see his father, hoping that the trip will buy him time and insight into his upcoming responsibility. CRUZANDO is a road-trip tale about friendship, fatherhood, and self-discovery that winds itself through the distinct culture of the Texas-Mexico border. The film combines off-beat humor with pathos in showing a young man discovering who he is and what he is meant to be. Accompanied by his childhood best friend, he embarks on a journey in which he crosses paths with luchador coyotes, renegade cowboys, desert angels, and a host of others along the beautiful, surreal, and unforgiving border region known as El Valle. It's the story of Manny - a man who must confront his past in order to move forward, a husband who must overcome his fear of responsibility, and ultimately, a son who must learn to become a father. Crossing a border is never easy...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?119924</url></doc>
