<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="120116">
  <docid>120116</docid>
  <title>Crystalis</title>
  <year>1990</year>
  <type>VideoGame</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>post-apocalyptic</keyword>
    <keyword>video-game</keyword>
    <keyword>interactive</keyword>
    <keyword>tragedy</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <countries>
    <country>Japan</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Japan">13 April 1990</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">26 June 2000</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Arakawa, Minoru</director>
    <director>Bauer, John (I)</director>
    <director>Comair, Claude</director>
    <director>Kôno, K.</director>
    <director>Lincoln, Howard</director>
    <director>Tsumura, Scott K.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hieke, Andrew</producer>
    <producer>Kôno, K.</producer>
    <producer>Thomason, Faran</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Kôno, K.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>O., Yoko</composer>
    <composer>Schwedler, Lawrence</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>October 31 1997, global warfare erupts that destroys most of the earth. To put an end to the warlike ways, a group of scientists build a tower in the sky operated by a computer. People try to rebuild, and society reconstructed resembled a blend of fallen technocracy, classical mythology, and medieval tales of knights, while outside the walled or otherwise guarded towns are strange mutations like anthropoid tigers, and machines sent by an out-of-control computer in the tower. One of the scientists, Mesia, has been taken out of a cryogenic freeze, and has scattered four swords, representing wind, fire, water, and thunder, which are the shattered components of Crystalis. These are taken by vampiric creatures soon after she hides them. Another scientist is revived, and bursts out of a cave. His memory fails him, but the townspeople are eager to guide him into rescuing the leaders of the society, giving him armor and spells, and eventually leading him to destroy the dark forces that have taken advantage of the post-apocalyptic conditions. Eventually, he learns that the tower, for all its good intentions, is the source of the strife, and must find a way to enter and destroy the central computer.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?120116</url></doc>
