<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="120670">
  <docid>120670</docid>
  <title>Cubes</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Cirelli, Craig</editor>
    <editor>Sherry, Jason</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>nudity</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>black-comedy</keyword>
    <keyword>dark-comedy</keyword>
    <keyword>language</keyword>
    <keyword>low-budget-film</keyword>
    <keyword>office-work</keyword>
    <keyword>cult-comedy</keyword>
    <keyword>slacker</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">18 June 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">24 March 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">99</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Sherry, Jason</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Zdancewicz, Mark</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Zdancewicz, Mark</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Holgate, Sara</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chorey, Jessica</actor>
      <role>Lindsey</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Evans, Jack (VII)</actor>
      <role>Barry</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Korin, Greg</actor>
      <role>Henry</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McGuigan, Conor</actor>
      <role>Elliot</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stegura, Jeremy</actor>
      <role>Paul</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stylinski, Steve</actor>
      <role>Ted</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Cubes is about the relationships formed of necessity when two people get partnered up in cubicles. Our personal lives tend to invade our workspaces, and we are often forced to share both with people who we might not ordinarily choose to spend time with. Sometimes we might get along well enough to become "work friends" with our cubicle partners, and perhaps go out for the odd drink. More often, however, these are people who we would feel at least slightly uncomfortable around in the supermarket, away from the confines of the cube. In Scene 1, Henry and Charlene while away the office day playing spirited (and often mean-spirited) games at the expense of their co-workers. But the fun comes to an end when Charlene catches her boyfriend in a compromising position, and enlists an unwitting Henry to get revenge. In Scene 2, Laurie's idyllic life is thrown into turmoil and she is forced to look to the nearby Charlene for an unlikely sympathetic shoulder. In Scene 3, Laurie has to figure out how to survive working side by side with Ted, the company freak. In Scene 4, Barry, a cocky new programmer, comes face to face with the inevitability that is Ted. In Scene 5, a torrid office affair faces trouble as Barry and Lindsey get honest with each other. And finally, in Scene 6 Laurie returns to work only to find that the more things change, the more they stay the same.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?120670</url></doc>
