<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="122250">
  <docid>122250</docid>
  <title>Cuvari noci</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Makarevic, Timur</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Bosnian</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby SR</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Bosnia and Herzegovina</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Croatia">27 July 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Italy">September 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">87</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Kabil, Namik</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Djapo, Adis</producer>
    <producer>Baksic Camo, Amra</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Kabil, Namik</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Alic, Haris</actor>
      <role>Policajac</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kabil, Namik</actor>
      <role>Specijalac</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lizde-Kurt, Belma</actor>
      <role>Zeraldina</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pavlovic, Milan (II)</actor>
      <role>Brizla</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Piralic, Vahid</actor>
      <role>Mahir</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ukaj, Alban</actor>
      <role>Pekar</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In a one-night introspection we follow Mahir on his duty as a night guard in a furniture showroom in present-day Sarajevo. Mahir is married to Geraldine for three years and still they have no children. So Mahir becomes convinced that he is pregnant. From that moment, he keeps throwing up. His best friend is Brizla, the next-door night guard at the sanitary ware showroom. They meet and play their ritual game "Home-you-go". Brizla suspects something is wrong with Mahir but still does not have a clue that Mahir is pregnant. War veteran neighbor is making their night harder, triggering the alarm system, which alerts the police to inspect. Former soldiers are still in uniforms, but they are now just guards, guarding the furniture from themselves. The resolution comes with the morning coffee, end of the day for friends. Mahir announces that he is back to normal and he does not throw up anymore. Mahir was not throwing up intentionally in the first place nor was he aware of the invisible connection to his wife. Nightguards is about making this connection visible without ever mentioning it.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?122250</url></doc>
