<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="123039">
  <docid>123039</docid>
  <title>D.I.D.</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>McGuire, Brandt</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">15 June 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>McGuire, Brandt</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>McGuire Sr., Gary</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>McGuire Sr., Gary</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stumpf, Brandon</actor>
      <role>Chief of Police</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In Southern New Hampshire there is a typical small NE town by the name of Colesville, at least typical until a family from Virginia relocates there to start a new life. Recently married, Tom and Jean Phillips have moved to Colesville and applied for positions in the school system. Tom is hired as an elementary school teacher and Jean becomes the new student counselor at the high school. After months of getting settled into their new jobs and new house, Jean sends for her teenage son, Wayne Garrison, to join her and Tom. Since Jean has never been away from her son for more than a few days she is anxiously looking forward to having her family back together. Unfortunately, the day before Wayne's scheduled arrival, Jean dies in a horrible accident. In the three days following her death mysterious things begin to happen in the town of Colesville. Was Jean's death an accident and another isolated incident or one of many mysterious events that are happening? Arriving just in time for his mother's funeral Wayne, understandably in a state of shock, is thrust into an uncomfortable situation. He is with a step father he barely knows, is expected to attend a new school where his mother worked, and is introduced to a number of Colesville citizens, each with their own personal agenda.  What are people's real intentions? Are their concerns real or are they hiding something? Like Jean's death and Beth's disappearance, what really happened then and what is really happening now? Wayne unintentionally and unwittingly becomes involved in solving the answers to all of these questions.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?123039</url></doc>
