<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="123466">
  <docid>123466</docid>
  <title>Da da xiao xiao yi jia chun</title>
  <year>1980</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Chang, Shao Hsi</editor>
    <editor>Chiang, Hsing-lung</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Mandarin</language>
    <language>Cantonese</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Hong Kong</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Hong Kong">1980</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Canada">22 October 1980</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Mou, Tun Fei</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Fong, Mona</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Hsin, Han Pai</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Chen, Yung-Yu</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chan, Eddie (I)</actor>
      <role>Hsu Man-tso</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chan, Shen</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chen, Szu Chia</actor>
      <role>1st Sister-in-law</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cheung, Chok Chow</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chien, Szu-ying</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ching, Miao</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chu, Ching (II)</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Hsu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chu, Norman</actor>
      <role>Hsu Liang-chung</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hua, Lun</actor>
      <role>Hsu Liang-jen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hung, Kuo-hua</actor>
      <role>3rd Sister-in-law</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lin, Chen Chi</actor>
      <role>Tsen Kai-szu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lo, Wan-Yin Angelina</actor>
      <role>2nd Sister-in-law</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wei, Hung</actor>
      <role>Mr. Hsu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Yu, Yung Henry</actor>
      <role>Hsu Liang-hsiao</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The childhood exploits of the 4 adolescent Hsu brothers orbit around the family's love and indulgence of their spoiled youngest son. Even after the passing of their poor but decent long-suffering parents, the older Hsu sons have now grown into adulthood either married or concentrating on careers. They reunite and continue their doting ways towards their still-single youngest brother. The once animated &amp; mischievous Man-tso has grown up shy, reserved &amp; still-single on the hunt for his own true love. One rainy day waiting at the bus stop and armed with only an umbrella, Man-tso crosses paths with a pretty young girl Kai-szu stepping off the bus wet without rain-gear. His chivalry sparks a rapport and the opportunity to walk Kai-szu home, not once but daily like clockwork come rain or come shine. Impressed, Kai-szu agrees to a first date but not without notice of Man-tso's nosy brother &amp; sister-in-law. Their budding courtship is short-lived after the brothers inadvertently derail their romance and the repelled Kai-szu leaves him due to a misunderstanding. Meanwhile she is diverted by the courtship from a son of a rich family. With his outlook changed, the gutted young Man-tso tries to shake the memory of Kai-szu while moving on with life not knowing that she still loves him. How can the lightning bolt of serendipity strike twice for Man-tso to find his dream girl?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?123466</url></doc>
