<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="123665">
  <docid>123665</docid>
  <title>Daadi Maa</title>
  <year>1966</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Awdhut, Shivaji</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Prasad, L.V.</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Sharma, Mukhram</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Roshan (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Abraham, David (II)</actor>
      <role>Balram</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Choti, Mohan</actor>
      <role>Balram's son</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jankidas</actor>
      <role>Ramdas</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kanhaiyalal (I)</actor>
      <role>Totaram</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kashinath (I)</actor>
      <role>Shankar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khote, Durga</actor>
      <role>Daadi Maa/Maharani</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Ashok (I)</actor>
      <role>Pratap/Raja</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mehmood (I)</actor>
      <role>Mahesh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mukri</actor>
      <role>Bihari</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Raj, Dilip (I)</actor>
      <role>Shomu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rehman (I)</actor>
      <role>Dr. Bharati</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Pratap lives a wealthy lifestyle in a mansion along with his mother, Maharani. He is married to Parvati but the couple are childless. Then differences arise between the two on one hand, and Maharani and Pratap on the other. Parvati leaves and moves in with Dr. Bharati and his wife, while Pratap moves out to his own mansion. When Pratap gets the news that Parvati has given birth to a boy, he goes to visit her and secretly abducts the child. When he is unable to find a woman to breast-feed the child, he patches-up with Parvati and she moves back in along with an orphaned child, Shomu. The couple name their child, Shankar, who becomes friendly with Shomu much to the chagrin of Pratap, who instructs his staff to house Shomu in the stables. Parvati loves both boys equally, and the two children grow up almost like brothers, with Shankar falling in love with wealthy Seema, and Shomu wooing village belle Shaguna much to the displeasure of her to-be father-in-law, Balram, who complains to Pratap, who, in turn, asks Shomu to leave. Subsequently Shomu falls very ill and Parvati wants to go and see him. Pratap makes it clear that if she leaves - then she will not be welcomed back. The question remains what will Parvati do under these circumstances?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?123665</url></doc>
