<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="124266">
  <docid>124266</docid>
  <title>Dahej</title>
  <year>1950</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">149</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Shantaram, Rajaram Vankudre</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Desai, Vasant (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Begum, Mumtaz</actor>
      <role>Chanda's mom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dewan, Karan</actor>
      <role>Suraj</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jayashree</actor>
      <role>Chanda</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Prithviraj</actor>
      <role>Thakur (Chanda's dad)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ulhas (I)</actor>
      <role>Vakil/lawyer (Suraj's dad)</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Thakur (Prithviraj Kapoor) is a proud and dignified man with an only daughter, Chanda (Jayashree) who is of marriageable age. His wife (Mumtaz Begum) and he receive a suitable proposal from the house of a lawyer and his wife (Ulhas and Lalita Pawar respectively). They accept this proposal, and during this process, Thakur makes it clear to the lawyer that he is unable to afford any dowry, to which the lawyer agrees, thinking that Thakur is very wealthy and will give plenty to his daughter. This does not happen and the marriage is almost cancelled. The groom, Suraj, (Karan Dewan) accepts the bride without any dowry. The marriage proceeds and the party returns home. For days the couple are left alone together. Then Chanda's mother-in-law gets agitated over the lack of dowry and starts harassing Chanda. The lawyer dies suddenly during a court case, and Chanda is blamed for his death. Eventually Chanda is thrown out of the house, and Suraj is unable to do anything. At this point in time, Thakur decides to sell everything and give it all to Chanda's mother-in-law, who is now planning to get Suraj married again. But will this gesture resolve Chanda's problems?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?124266</url></doc>
