<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="124536">
  <docid>124536</docid>
  <title>Daisy</title>
  <year>1988</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Lenin, B.</editor>
    <editor>Vijayan, V.T.</editor>
  </editors>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Malayalam</language>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Pothan, Prathap K.</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Khalid (I)</writer>
    <writer>Pothan, Prathap K.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kailash (I)</composer>
    <composer>Sharma, Pradyuman (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harish (I)</actor>
      <role>Pradeep</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hassan, Kamal</actor>
      <role>James</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Laxmi (I)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Pradeep Menon is a troubled teenager who studies in a Boarding school in Southern India. He is regarded as a trouble-maker in school, and is often punished by his teachers and headmaster, at times often severely. When beautiful Daisy Thomas joins this school, he makes fun of her on the very first day, thus beginning a series of misadventures that result in more punishment for him. This also brings him close to Daisy and both are attracted to each other. Daisy understands why Pradeep is so aggressive, and offers him considerable support. She is shocked to see how rude he is toward his mother, Malti Menon, but is unable to do anything about it. Things improve considerably when Malti is confined in hospital and Pradeep goes to visit her, thereby improving their relationship. Pradeep starts to respond positively to Daisy's support and is all set to turn a new leaf. Then Pradeep's world is turned upside down when he witnesses Daisy in the arms of a male - a complete stranger. Shocked at this, Pradeep has no alternative but to regress to his self-destructive phase, alienating himself from everyone. The question remains who is the "other" man in Daisy's life?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?124536</url></doc>
