<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="124564">
  <docid>124564</docid>
  <title>Daisy and the Women of the Future</title>
  <year>1998</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 May 1998</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">75</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Vicenty, Jose</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Castro, Abel</producer>
    <producer>Vicenty, Jose</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Baez, Fernando</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lopez, Daisy</actor>
      <role>Herself (interviewed)</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Daisy and the Women of the Future is an in-depth view of the life of Daisy Lopez, a transsexual, and five pre-op transsexuals in New York City as they each dissect their lives and the meaning of -- What Is The Woman Of The Future? Daisy Lopez had her sex change in 1995, at the time this film started shooting. She once owned an apartment for her escort services for discriminating gentlemen only, where she had a couple of the "girls" working for her. Daisy is a role model to some, and hated by many. The film intertwines with the introduction of Donna McGarth, an egotistical,"don't give a damn type of girl", who appeared on numerous talking shows around the country. Tara "The Latin Goddess" who has no shame of who she is, and a way of confronting gay bashers on the streets. Dana Rodriguez, who despises Daisy for her sex change, has no respect for Daisy, because she believes that Daisy acts like a gay man. Joey (aka Yolee) a former employee of Daisy's escort services, was a former pre-op transsexual, and decided not to be a woman. Each character gives her view about life, hormone therapy, religion, HIV, and many secrets are revealed.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?124564</url></doc>
