<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="125005">
  <docid>125005</docid>
  <title>Daman: A Victim of Marital Violence</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Onir</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
    <language>Assamese</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">A</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">4 May 2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Lazmi, Kalpana</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>India, Government Of</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Lazmi, Kalpana</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Hazarika, Bhupen</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bania, Indra</actor>
      <role>Sardar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barua, Ishaan</actor>
      <role>Bisnu Prasad Saikia</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barua, Kalpana</actor>
      <role>Chameli</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bishaya, Dinesh</actor>
      <role>Naren</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bishaya, Jharna</actor>
      <role>Putoli</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Das, Chetana</actor>
      <role>House Servant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Das, Girija (I)</actor>
      <role>Mukut Saikia</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Goswami, Moyola</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Goswami, Nippon</actor>
      <role>Surya Narayan Goswami</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jaffrey, Bharti</actor>
      <role>Laxmi Goswami</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kharghoria, Bishnu</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Koshal, Ranjan</actor>
      <role>Sailen Mahanta</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Monalisa (I)</actor>
      <role>Dancer (song "Bhagwati")</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shinde, Sayaji</actor>
      <role>Sanjay Saikia</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Suri, Sanjay</actor>
      <role>Sunil Saikia</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The Saikias are a wealthy family, consisting of father, mother, and two unmarried sons, Sanjoy and Sunil. Sanjoy is the elder of the two, who refuses to marry, and the rest of the family have to live with his temper tantrums, alcoholism, and patronizing prostitutes. They decide to get him married to a woman named, Durga, who comes from a lower caste, &amp; a poor family, who they believe will be able to live with Sanjoy and his weaknesses. Sanjoy initially refuses to marry Durga, but when his mother threatens to cut him off from her will and estate, he relents and marries her. Thus begins Durga's nightmare with Sanjoy - right from day one. On the very first night Sanjoy decides to spent it with a prostitute named Chameli, who gets pregnant. He subsequently forcibly has sex with Durga, and gets her pregnant too, but blames her pregnancy on Sunil. Durga gives birth to a daughter, Deepa, much to Sanjoy's disappointment, as he had expected a son. Years pass by, Deepa is now 12 years old, and Sanjoy decides to get her married to an older male, and he refuses to listen to anyone, and severely beats up Durga in the presence of the rest of his family. One stormy night during a brawl between the brothers, Sunil is killed. Durga feels alone, threatened, and afraid that her daughter might be forced to re-live her horrors - she and Deepa run away. Sanjoy files a complaint with local police, alleging that Durga has abducted Deepa. Durga and Deepa re-locate to Guwahati, and find support from unexpected quarters - where they grow and thrive. Then one day, Durga sees Sanjoy at the local drug store buying some alcohol. Has her biggest nightmare returned to take possession of her and Deepa?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?125005</url></doc>
