<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="125721">
  <docid>125721</docid>
  <title>Dancing on the Brink of the World</title>
  <year>2010</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>based-on-novel</keyword>
    <keyword>bank-heist</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <producers>
    <producer>Tavener, Ginny</producer>
    <producer>Sweitzer, Keith</producer>
    <producer>Duffield, Grahame</producer>
    <producer>Handler, Ruby</producer>
    <producer>Jacobs, Michael J.</producer>
    <producer>Willcock, Roland</producer>
    <producer>Duffield, Grahame</producer>
    <producer>Willcock, Roland</producer>
    <producer>Wooll, Nigel</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Coyne, James (II)</writer>
    <writer>Rowland, Andrew (II)</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Conor Morgan has the perfect plan: recruit a team with hearts of larceny to pull off the greatest techno-heist in modern banking history. The stakes: close to a trillion dollars. The target: neXus, the world's premier credit and debit card payments system, operated by the power of invisible money. With futurist weapons inspired by Zulu and Mongol battle strategies, the crew crashes neXus computer systems worldwide in a daring transcontinental robbery. But a Delta hit team of Enforcers hunt them down as Morgan's plan unravels. Dancing on the Brink of the World is interwoven with elements of the mysterious. Recurrent prime numbers and echoing super symmetries converge in a morality tale of friendship and trust, betrayal and vengeance. In San Francisco and London, Morgan's team is on the run from the most sinister assassin since Jack the Ripper, with a ransom of untraceable diamonds, a dazzlingly erotic heroine and the ghostly messengers of ancient Celtic gods.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?125721</url></doc>
