<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="126013">
  <docid>126013</docid>
  <title>Dangerous Diva's Devious Disguises</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>revenge</keyword>
    <keyword>naked-woman</keyword>
    <keyword>vignette</keyword>
    <keyword>bedroom</keyword>
    <keyword>softcore</keyword>
    <keyword>thief</keyword>
    <keyword>bondage</keyword>
    <keyword>secretary</keyword>
    <keyword>heirloom</keyword>
    <keyword>safe</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 July 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">45</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chance, Loren</actor>
      <role>Dangerous Diva</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Facella, Franziska</actor>
      <role>Secretary</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Indica, Jade</actor>
      <role>Woman with Heirloom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Luster, Ruby</actor>
      <role>Accomplice</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mathews, Molly</actor>
      <role>Woman Seeking Vengeance</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Dangerous Diva is up to her old tricks. First, she pretends to be a newspaper reporter and pumps a naive woman for information about her priceless family heirloom and then, returning after dark, she breaks into the woman's bedroom, steals the bauble and leaves the victim naked, bound and gagged. In the next sequence, Diva sneaks into an office building and captures an innocent secretary, leaving her tied and helpless. When the device she's seeking isn't in the company safe, Diva forces the frightened woman her to reveal that the object hasn't arrived yet and the messenger doesn't know the secretary by sight. Diva strips the office worker, dons her clothes and heads out for the rendezvous leaving a writhing blonde struggling to free herself. In the last sequence, a beautiful brunette seeks vengeance against Dangerous Diva for leaving her tied up in her bathtub. Diva is overpowered and left roped and muzzled as her apartment fills with smoke that the arsonist and her henchwoman have set. Diva manages to slip her bonds and traces the two would-be killers to their lair and then leaves them stripped naked, ball-gagged and roped together.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?126013</url></doc>
