<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="127158">
  <docid>127158</docid>
  <title>Dark Fall II: Lights Out</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>VideoGame</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Mystery</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>england</keyword>
    <keyword>haunted</keyword>
    <keyword>lighthouse</keyword>
    <keyword>island</keyword>
    <keyword>time-travel</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">T</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">24 August 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Oku, Desmond</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Stevenson, Robert (IV)</producer>
    <producer>Boakes, Jonathan</producer>
    <producer>Verdier, Luc (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Boakes, Jonathan</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Boakes, Jonathan</composer>
    <composer>Kavan, Jan (II)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Boakes, Jonathan</actor>
      <role>Malakai/James Woolff</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Clark, Matt (XI)</actor>
      <role>Robert Shaw</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Demarion, Robert</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Philippou, Philip</actor>
      <role>Telephone Voice</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>White, Myles (II)</actor>
      <role>Ghost Boy Child</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This point-and-click adventure game is a follow-up to Dark Fall: The Journal and not really a sequel since Lights Out has completely different locations, story and characters. In this game you play Benjamin Parker, a cartographer, who has been commissioned to map the treacherous shores and waters of Trewarthen, England. Over the centuries, many ships and fishing vessels have run aground there, claiming countless lives beneath the Fetch Rock Lighthouse. It is hoped that his maps will help navigation through the fog in that area. Upon arriving, Parker is given little to go on by his employer except that the light from the lighthouse has suddenly gone out without explanation and he should go investigate. Making his way to the darkened Fetch Rock Lighthouse, he soon discovers that the three lighthouse keepers have disappeared without a trace! Sifting through information left behind, Parker finds evidence of a another presence; something else is here! Is the lighthouse haunted? What happened to the three men? Why did the lights go out? And, what is the real reason he was asked to come here? To find those answers, Parker will be mystically transported to different periods in the lighthouse's time-line. Exploring in first person style, interacting with objects, reading materials and puzzles.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?127158</url></doc>
