<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="132828">
  <docid>132828</docid>
  <title>Dead Creek</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kromm, Michael</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>zombie</keyword>
    <keyword>dead</keyword>
    <keyword>creek</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">15 September 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">14</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Boe, Edward</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Avella, Joe (II)</producer>
    <producer>Boe, Edward</producer>
    <producer>Petrik, Michael</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Avella, Joe (II)</writer>
    <writer>Boe, Edward</writer>
    <writer>Petrik, Michael</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>King, Jim (VII)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Avella, Joe (II)</actor>
      <role>Phillip</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Meersman, Peter D.</actor>
      <role>Archie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Petrik, Brad</actor>
      <role>Overton</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pollack, Brian A.</actor>
      <role>Donald</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wenzel, Ricky</actor>
      <role>Lincoln</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A group of five friends are spending their weekend, like many horror fans have, making a zombie movie to call their own. They have their gear packed and their spirits up. They make their way to an isolated cemetery bordering an equally isolated town that is just perfect as the setting of a horror movie. Lincoln, Donald, Overton, Archie, and Phillip set up at their location, never fully noticing the stumbling 'drunks' that are limping around them. After the start of filming Donald, acting as 'zombie number 1' storms off to the car to wash some funny tasting fake blood out of his mouth. Phillip follows him to make sure everything's all right, and as an excuse to smoke. While the other guys are busy setting up the 'exploding chest bit', Donald wanders off towards the edge of the cemetery trying, unsuccessfully, to get some reception on his cell phone. He wanders down to a peaceful little creek, and notices a horribly mangled animal lying dead on the bank. Meanwhile, back at the car, Phillip learns that something funny is happening in the United States. It has been reported as a possible terrorist attack, but either way people are getting sick and dying... sort of. He runs off to find Donald so they can get to safety. Donald has found a stick that he is using to poke at the dead animal, until it springs to life and bites him on the arm, and that's when all hell breaks loose!!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?132828</url></doc>
