<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="134347">
  <docid>134347</docid>
  <title>Debit</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>McKenzie, Mitchel</editor>
    <editor>Silverstein, Aaron</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>jobless</keyword>
    <keyword>petty-criminal</keyword>
    <keyword>theft</keyword>
    <keyword>car-theft</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">19</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>McKenzie, Mitchel</director>
    <director>Silverstein, Aaron</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>McKenzie, Mitchel</producer>
    <producer>Silverstein, Aaron</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>McKenzie, Mitchel</writer>
    <writer>Silverstein, Aaron</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>McKenzie, Mitchel</composer>
    <composer>Silverstein, Aaron</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lieblich, Jerry (II)</actor>
      <role>Frank</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McKenzie, Mitchel</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pedroche, Jon</actor>
      <role>John</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Schmidt, Dustin</actor>
      <role>Jerry</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Silverstein, Aaron</actor>
      <role>Victor</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>After being called into his boss's office, Victor, a scheming nitwit with anger issues, sits unflinching. Victor leans forward menacingly and demands a raise. His boss immediately responds by firing him. Enraged and out of ideas, Victor loses control. Victor and Jerry, his roommate and ex-coworker, sit dejectedly at their kitchen table. Moneyless, and on the verge of eviction things can't seem to get any worse until Victor's dangerously simple-minded friend, John, comes over to visit. In desperate need of some quick money, Victor devises a plan to steal debit cards from anyone with robbery insurance. Immediately John is in, and after some clumsy convincing, Jerry is too. As they drive up to an apartment chosen at random, Victor tells Jerry to wait in the car, as he and John do "All of the bad things." After disguising themselves in a ski mask and a brown paper bag, Victor and John make several unsuccessful attempts at breaking in, before accidentally be let in by their first victim, Frank. Inside, Frank proves to be untrustworthy and more severe measures must be taken in order to find his debit card. Meanwhile Jerry sits quietly outside, before being harassed by an extremely friendly yet creepy man likely under the influence of heavy narcotics. After a short conversation, the man steals the car, leaving Jerry alone on the sidewalk. Inside, Victor is becoming increasingly impatient and threatens to shoot Frank's face if he doesn't produce a debit card. His yells soon attract Jerry's attention who bursts through the apartment door startling Victor who accidentally pulls the trigger. Instantly, Victor, Jerry, and John become hysterical and run from the apartment. Stopping to catch their breath, Jerry yells furiously at Victor for shooting Frank's face. Victor and Jerry become entangled in a fight as John looks on helplessly. Infuriated by Johns pleas to stop fighting, Victor charges John who, frightened, shoots Victor. In shock, Jerry leaves the two huddled on the pavement, only to find his car engulfed in flames.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?134347</url></doc>
