<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="134675">
  <docid>134675</docid>
  <title>Deconstruction: House of the Future</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Jacquelin, Pierson</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">31 August 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Latka, Bill</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Latka, Bill</producer>
    <producer>Harding, Monique</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Latka, Bill</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Transcenders</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Downs, Jonathon</actor>
      <role>Contractor #3</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hanneman, Steve</actor>
      <role>Host</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Palmer, Steve J.</actor>
      <role>The Construction Guy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Walton, William (II)</actor>
      <role>Carpenter</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Deconstruction witnesses the construction of a house of the future to discover how it will keep us safe and relaxed, entertained and connected. The science behind new building materials and procedures, renewable energy technologies, and smart technologies are explored. Concrete has been around forever, but a building material called Autoclaved Aerated Concrete offers energy efficiency, sustainability and amazing fire resistance. The factory used to make it solves the mystery of its composition. A robotic house-building machine is in development that will build homes on earth, and even the moon. The space program is also bringing products like Aerogel insulation to home building. Renewable geothermal energy from the earth, and solar and wind power will become a key to sustainability. Not only will smart house technology become a partner that takes care of us at home, but it will also become more powerful and easier to use. The house of the future is here, and Deconstruction brings it to you.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?134675</url></doc>
