<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="134986">
  <docid>134986</docid>
  <title>Deep Springs: A Desert Education</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>education</keyword>
    <keyword>elite</keyword>
    <keyword>school</keyword>
    <keyword>isolation</keyword>
    <keyword>ranch</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Belgium">10 September 2006</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">17 November 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">66</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Bove, Christof</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bove, Christof</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>An hour's drive from the nearest small town, Deep Springs College sits high on a desert plateau in the White Mountains of Eastern California. Founded in 1917 by L. L. Nunn, an industrialist and philanthropist, the school is one of the most prestigious educational experiments in America. Limited to twenty-four young men, who come from the top 2% of the Nation's academic pool, the College offers a full, two-year scholar- ship to all admitted. Born of the philosophical allegiances of its founder, the Deep Springs experience is intended to "train the leaders of tomorrow." In 1921, Mr. Nunn explained the purpose of Deep Springs to the school's student body: "The growth of the human race toward God is inevitably in the hands of the few. In a sense they are doomed to lead... The purpose of Deep Springs is to help in the training of the few... These forerunners, pacemakers, who anticipate progress perhaps by decades are those who break the trails and point the way. They are the voice crying in the wilderness." The isolated environment and rigorous curriculum are not all that distinguish Deep Springs. Without the conscientious participation of each student, the college would not function. Along with maintaining the Deep Springs cattle ranch and alfalfa farm, the students are responsible for admitting future students, as well as hiring and firing faculty. By accepting the school's scholarship, they accept the burden of responsibility unusual for people so young.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?134986</url></doc>
