<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="135302">
  <docid>135302</docid>
  <title>Definition</title>
  <year>1974</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Game-Show</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>non-fiction</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">15 November 1976</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <writers>
    <writer>Muir, E. Roger</writer>
    <writer>Nicholson, Nick (III)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Christopher, Jean (II)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Devall, Dave</actor>
      <role>Announcer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Eastwood, Jayne</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lewis, Shari (I)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Macnee, Patrick</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McLean, Bob (III)</actor>
      <role>Host (1974-1975)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Perry, Jim (II)</actor>
      <role>Host</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Perry, Jim (II)</actor>
      <role>Host (1975-1990)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ward, Robin (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Weston, Steve (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In the mid 1970's and through the 1980's, Jim Perry hosted this Canadian hangman-type game show, with long-time local Toronto weatherman Dave Devall as his announcer. Some have called it an early prototype or rip-off of "Wheel of Fortune" without the wheel, but the two shows started broadcasting at approximately the same time (Definition may slightly pre-date 'Wheel'). In typical Canadian (low budget) style, it featured bored housewives from Hamilton or Scarborough, Ontario who were teamed with Canadian film and television celebrities to solve a puzzle, with the grand prizes awarded on the show often being along the lines of a Schaeffer pen set and a vacuum cleaner. However, there were occasional 'Tournament of Champions' weeks during which they gave away a car as the grand prize for the tournament champion. Most of the celebrities were more locally known than international stars, but there were occasional early appearances by Martin Short or others who have since become more widely known. What most people remember about the show was its jazzy little theme, which was actually composed by Quincy Jones in the 1960's. The theme was heard in later years as a sample on the Canuck rap group Dream Warriors' hit single "My Definition of a Boombastic Jazz Style." It was also heard over the titles in the film Austin Powers: International Man of Mystery, which may explain why it was a bigger hit in Canada than in the U.S. The tune later appeared in Austin Powers: The Spy Who Shagged Me and made a prominent appearance in the opening sequences of 'Austin Powers: Goldmember'. Jim Perry, meanwhile, went on to host "Sale of the Century," in which a contestant broke a record by winning more cash and prizes than anyone else in game show history.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?135302</url></doc>
