<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="135469">
  <docid>135469</docid>
  <title>Dejiny Jaroslava Sabaty</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Hansalová, Hedvika</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>History</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>communism</keyword>
    <keyword>czechoslovakian-history</keyword>
    <keyword>1968</keyword>
    <keyword>czechoslovakia</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Czech</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Czech Republic</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Czech Republic">30 October 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Czech Republic">79</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Janecek, Vit</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Janecek, Vit</writer>
    <writer>Patocka, Jakub</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cibulka, Petr</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jelinek, Lukas</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Madrova, Eva</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sabata, Jan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sabata, Jaroslav</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sabata, Vaclav</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Uhde, Milan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vaculík, Ludvík</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zaoralek, Lubomir</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Czech(oslovak) modern history appears to be full of paradoxes and as a logical consequence is, that we can find persons holding similar structure of their personal histories. Jaroslav Sabata belongs among them. Born in a wealthy family become communist after WWII and later one of main protagonists of Prague Spring in 1968. He opposed Russian invasion and so he turned into opposition soon. Spent more that 7 years in prison and was active as Charter 77 member and spokesman. He talks about the Prague Spring and the Vysocany's Czech Communist Party Congress, Charter 77, which he signed, the establishment of the Civic Forum in Brno, the division of Czechoslovakia, which he actively resisted, and the mooted privatization of Barrandov Studios, which he rejected. Besides members of his family, other important protagonists and opponents of Jaroslav Sabata appear before the camera such as the person who filed his documentation for the Communist Party in 1968, the politician Milan Uhde, Sabata's fellow pupil from secondary school and political prisoner Eva Madrová, the writer Ludvik Vaculik and Petr Cibulka, who published part of the list of agents and collaborators who worked with the communist secret police. Sabata's reflections on his history and the history of these "great" events raise a lot of questions that are very relevant now and will continue to be relevant for some time to come. Some compare idea of the film to The Last Bolshevik by Chris Marker.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?135469</url></doc>
