<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="135938">
  <docid>135938</docid>
  <title>Delphine, the Baker's Assistant</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Haugen, Ingvild</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>French</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">3 December 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">12</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Ives, Lyndon</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ives, Lyndon</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Ives, Lyndon</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Tomczyk, Stefan</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maimone, Silvana</actor>
      <role>The Boss</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wilson, Mark (XXIII)</actor>
      <role>The Guy</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Set in a French Patisserie in London, 'Delphine' is a meditation on the nature of contemporary society and of nature in general. The story follows a pretty baker's assistant, constantly overworked and under-appreciated by her demanding boss and belligerent customers. A glint of light comes in the shape of an attractive guy who enters the bakery and presents Delphine with an invitation to call him, before quickly leaving. This hope however is dashed when her boss rips up the piece of paper, leaving Delphine despondent. More toil and grief follow until one day Delphine stumbles upon an ants nest in the backyard of the bakery. She ponders whether to pour hot water over the ants to eliminate the nest, but is called back to work before doing so. That night she dreams about the ants and by the morning is mixing them into the scones to sell to the customers. Finally, Delphine gets the recognition she deserves. The new scones are a great success and prove profitable for her greedy but happy boss. However, upon finding that the attractive guy was already with someone else, Delphine decides to add more sinister ingredients to the mix, this time with dire consequences...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?135938</url></doc>
