<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="136178">
  <docid>136178</docid>
  <title>Demolishing and Building Up the Star Theatre</title>
  <year>1901</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>new-york-city</keyword>
    <keyword>urban</keyword>
    <keyword>engineer</keyword>
    <keyword>construction</keyword>
    <keyword>demolition</keyword>
    <keyword>time-lapse-photography</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Unrated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">April 1901</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">2</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Armitage, Frederick S.</director>
  </directors>
<plot>This film shows the demolition of the historic Star Theatre building (formerly Wallack's) at the corner of Broadway and 13th Street, New York. To secure this unique picture a Biograph camera was kept constantly at work by specially devised electric apparatus for weeks, during which time exposures were made every four minutes, 8 hours a day. Before the contractors began their work of tearing down and after the last vestige of the building had been removed, 15 seconds of exposure at normal speed were made. Thus in the finished positive one views at first the old Star Theatre standing as it had for years looking down with serenity upon the bustle of Broadway traffic. Then as if struck by a tornado of supernatural strength, the building begins to crumble. Chimneys totters, walls cave in, and whole stories vanish, until at last the site shows only a cellar excavation; and the Broadway cars with the sidewalk procession continue as if nothing unusual had happened. When this view is shown in the reverse, the effect is very extraordinary.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?136178</url></doc>
