<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="137593">
  <docid>137593</docid>
  <title>Der Ein Euro Clip</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Esquerre, Christian</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Musical</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Germany">26 March 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Germany">5</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Schreiber, Klaus (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Koethner Kaul, Jens</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Koethner Kaul, Jens</writer>
    <writer>Schreiber, Klaus (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Herre, Max</composer>
    <composer>Thomas, Nikolaí</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Agon, Maria Lucia</actor>
      <role>Dancer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bormann, Susanne</actor>
      <role>Woman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dello Iacono, Angelo</actor>
      <role>Dancer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fournier, Héloise</actor>
      <role>Dancer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Griess, Jana</actor>
      <role>Dancer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Karner, Elisabeth (II)</actor>
      <role>Dancer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kees, Leandro</actor>
      <role>Dancer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lo, Fang-Yun</actor>
      <role>Dancer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Marschall, Elisa</actor>
      <role>Dancer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mateus, René Alejandro Huari</actor>
      <role>Dancer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Naujoks, Ingo</actor>
      <role>Man</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Orgs, Guido</actor>
      <role>Dancer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Schikora, Matthias</actor>
      <role>Dancer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zhukov, Sergej</actor>
      <role>Dancer</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>THE ONE EURO CLIP (lyrics) Each against each other. Why should I even bother? Cain and Abel Tower o' Babel Since dawn of times we always fight To keep what God gave us by right 'Cause if you have, why share With people who don't care? We're dancing the Euro. You'll reap what you sow The One Euro Opera Dance with the cash flow. Judges are by nature wise They know when to moralize For the poor There's no cure But when bankers are on trial Then there's plausible denial Law and Nature both are bitter It's survival of the fitter! Quickly, hurry, faster If you're slow, it's your disaster Craving! Craving! Cry the ravens They will feast on those who fall There's no mercy, none at all One man is another's meat And you are dead unless you eat! Fate will play with rags and riches In an endless game of chess And unless the fortune switches - Too bad for the Euro-less! Each against each other Why should I even bother? Cain and Abel Tower o' Babel Since dawn of times we always fight To keep what God gave us by right 'Cause if you have, why share With people who don't care? We're dancing the Euro ... Music: Nikolai Tomas (lyrics by Klaus Schreiber) story: View onto the lights of Ruhr. A view at the urban transport network, the skylines of the cities, the dynamics and power of the region. One center leads across to the next. Where one city ends, the other one commences... The day begins and people swarm to work, crossing a big square, all having one goal, all moving... One person enters the scene in a completely different pace. He puts down his collecting box and waits. One Euro coin drops. The man looks up and sees a beautiful, young woman. Their eyes meet, but she has to go on... Fascinated he looks after her so fascinated that he drops his 1 Euro which rolls away onto the street. The Euro jumps down a stairway to the subway. The man chases after the Euro... A racy pursuit through the Ruhr area starts leading into the subway, trough the streets, to the noble business- and banking world, along the coal-mines, to trend-setting architecture, to traditional industry, into a most glamorous entrepreneur château and finally into a big wig functionary of German football. The protagonist runs and runs and everybody after him... The 1EURO;-Clip represents the ascent of a man with the capital of 1EURO; during just one day. This 1 Euro turns the man from beggar into winner of the jackpot, white-collar professional, banker, Broker, big industrialist, owner of a villa and finally into functionary of Schalke (soccer)...He achieves everything: economic power as well as social influence. Everything? At the end this 1EURO; brings him back to where he began: to the collecting box in the pedestrian area. The EURO; is the only thing left from his fabulous wealth... Here the beautiful, young lady of the morning comes back. The evening comes and she seems to be on her way home. The man takes the EURO; and buys a rose and presents it to her... You can get everything you want ... even love. Ruhr 2010.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?137593</url></doc>
