<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="142484">
  <docid>142484</docid>
  <title>Destino de mujer</title>
  <year>1997</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Guillén, José</editor>
  </editors>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Venezuela</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Venezuela">3 March 1997</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Bolívar, César</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Andrade, Daniel (IV)</producer>
    <producer>Rioboo, Sandra</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Romero, Mariela (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Amundaray, Raúl</actor>
      <role>Artemio</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Balzi, Ernesto</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Baute, Carlos</actor>
      <role>Pedro José</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brito, Mario</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bueno, Lucio</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bürkle, Yul</actor>
      <role>Arnaldo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Camacho, Carlos Humberto</actor>
      <role>Luis Miguel (1997)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Capote, Tatiana</actor>
      <role>Giselda</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chimaras, Yanis</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>D'Isidoro, Wanda</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>David, Juan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dos Ramos, Kimberly</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Escamez, Alexis</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ferrer, Lupita</actor>
      <role>Aurora</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Flores, Jeanette</actor>
      <role>Angelina Salcedo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Francia, Carmen</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fuentes, Chony</actor>
      <role>Irma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Galué, Henry</actor>
      <role>Alfredo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lamarca, Roberto</actor>
      <role>Ignacio</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lander, Pedro</actor>
      <role>Ramon</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Martín, Pedro (III)</actor>
      <role>Izaguirre</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Messutti, Roberto</actor>
      <role>Augusto</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Reyes, Jorge (IV)</actor>
      <role>Víctor Manuel Santana</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Romero, Rafael (III)</actor>
      <role>Rodolfo Anzola</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Valcárcel, Javier</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Álvarez, Alberto (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Victor Manuel Santana and Mariana Oropeza are two brilliant economists who meet while competing for an important international contract. From the moment they set eyes on each other, tension fills the air. Mariana finds Victor Manuel arrogant, chauvinistic and domineering. For Victor Manuel, Mariana is the typical rich girl: spoiled and presumptuous. What they cannot even imagine is that they are meant to be together and that their destinies were intertwined many years ago. Victor Manuel has only one purpose in life: to avenge the murder of his father. Twenty three years ago, a powerful and despotic millionaire named Alfredo Oropeza raped Aurora, fiancee of landowner Esteban Colmenares, and murdered him in front of his son, Victor Manuel. After becoming an orphan, Victor Manuel was adopted by one of his father's employees, Ramon Santana. In spite of having led a happy life as part of the Santana family, the terrible memory of that fatal afternoon has stayed in Victor Manuel's mind like an obsession. And now that he has become a wealthy businessman, he is ready to execute his plan to destroy Oropeza, starting by ruining him financially. With this purpose, he begins buying stock in the Oropeza companies, eventually taking over them. Victor Manuel's vengeance intensifies when he finds out that the beautiful Mariana is none other than the daughter of his worst enemy. Now, more than ever, he is determined to marry her so he can humiliate her, making her pay for her father's sins. But Victor Manuel never counted on falling so deeply in love with Mariana, who only agrees to become his wife in order to save her father from bankruptcy. However, with time Mariana will also start having intense feelings for Victor Manuel and soon, they will both be consumed by a fiery passion that their pride will not allow them to acknowledge. Little by little, on the long road to revenge, Victor Manuel begins to discover details that shed light on the tragic events of his past, as well as coincidences that link him more and more to Mariana.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?142484</url></doc>
