<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="142516">
  <docid>142516</docid>
  <title>Destiny</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Smith, Parrish</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby SR</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 December 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">25</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Smith, Parrish</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Smith, Parrish</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Smith, Parrish</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Bumaye</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ali, Sahr</actor>
      <role>Nia Gaskin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Frye, Leslie</actor>
      <role>Adult Destiny</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hill, Steve (IX)</actor>
      <role>Young Destiny's Father</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jetter, Tina</actor>
      <role>Young Destiny</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Martin, Ken (IV)</actor>
      <role>Thug #1</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sitler, David</actor>
      <role>Doctor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Suber, Met</actor>
      <role>Pastor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Theobald, Marc</actor>
      <role>Thug #2</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Thompson, Al (II)</actor>
      <role>Paul Gaskin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wilson, Brian Anthony</actor>
      <role>Chris</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Nine out of ten parents choose to abort their baby, whenever they are diagnosed with Down Syndrome. Oh yeah... that's a fact. Often times it's even recommended by the doctor, but there's a flaw... Out of the ten babies diagnosed, two or three are perfectly normal... For Paul and Nia Gaskin, it was simple, first get married, bathe in their marriage for two years, and then extend their family... with a child. But to the couples surprise, their baby was diagnosed with Mosaic Down Syndrome, the rarest form of DS. Anger, dispair, confusion, grief and any other devasting words hit the Gaskins household hard. Now faced with a grappling decision, Nia's determined to keep her child, but Paul decides otherwise... As a cop, Paul's job is clear, to uphold the law, save the good, and arrest the bad. But as man, husband, and now father, his job is not so clear. Troubled with his child's illness, his wife's torn spirit, and a troublesome marriage, Paul has a lot on his mind. In opting to abort, Paul still seeks advise from his pastor, friends, and his partner, Chris. While on a stakeout, Chris and Paul have a meaningful conversation which leaves Paul still confused and searching for answers... why him? Out of all the healthy babies, why is his child cursed with this crippling disease? "Destiny" comes to a climatic conclusion, when Paul and Chris finally confront the two criminals they were awating on their stakeout. During their confrontation, one the criminals, the Indian, breaks out into a Carl Lewis, causing Paul to chase after him. After a hard foot chase, Paul corners the Indian into a back alley. The Indian is unarmed but won't allow himself to be arrested without a fight. Wham!... Blow after blow, the Indian continues to hit Paul with stunning jabs and crushing hooks sending Paul crashing to the pavement. The force of the fall is so hard, Paul's gun tumbles from his reach. With death in his eyes, and venom in his speech, the Indian grabs the gun and points it an inch from Paul's temple. Battered and bruised, with blood dripping down Pauls face, he's scared for his life. The Indian firmly grabs Pauls throat. Slowly and coldly, the Indians taunts him, "Yeah look at you... you scared little b$%#*". Wham!... the Indian swiflty bangs Pauls head against the concrete, sending him unconscious... It's unlcear how long Paul was under, a minute, ten minutes, or maybe thirty. But what is clear is that when Paul regained consciousness, Paul had a complete and utter change of heart about aborting his baby. Why? What did Paul see while he was unconscious? What vision was revealed to him about his family.... his child... and his Destiny???</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?142516</url></doc>
