<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="142916">
  <docid>142916</docid>
  <title>Detective Naani</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bhatia, Deepa</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">22 May 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="India">140</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Mukherjee, Romilla</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Chatterjee, Urmilla</producer>
    <producer>Mukherjee, Jolly</producer>
    <producer>Mukherjee, Romilla</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Mukherjee, Romilla</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Barve, Shailendra</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Adhikari, Dr. Hemu</actor>
      <role>Mahesh Pal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bruno (XX)</actor>
      <role>Bruno the Dog</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chauhan, Mohit (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chavhan, Abhijeet</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gokhale, Shubhangi</actor>
      <role>Madhu Pal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gulati, Shweta</actor>
      <role>Neeti Tipnis</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Zain (II)</actor>
      <role>Nakul</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mazdiasni, Goolshan</actor>
      <role>Piloo Billimoria</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nayyar, Ankur</actor>
      <role>CID Inspector Bhatia</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pandey, Hemant</actor>
      <role>Tattu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Parchure, Atul</actor>
      <role>Petook</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Singh, Sanjay (IV)</actor>
      <role>Goonda Choti</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Varma, Amit (II)</actor>
      <role>Rohan Malhotra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vatsa, Sanjeev</actor>
      <role>Raj Yadav</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wadkar, Jaywant</actor>
      <role>Goonda Pakya</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Spunky, independent 75 year old Naani is on her way back home from her daily morning walk. She looks up to see a strange little girl peeping from the window of an apartment belonging to a newly-arrived couple. Naani's curiosity is aroused, plunging her into a full-blown murder mystery where some neighbors will come to her aid, some will be indifferent and some will prove to be very dangerous. When the CID dismisses Naani's case due to lack of hard evidence, she turns into a detective. She uses her homespun wisdom to solve the mystery in classic "whodunit" style. Naani's eccentric methods of investigation lead to a series of quirky, often humorous incidents. Along for the ride are a team of unlikely deputies - her dog Bruno, 2 inquisitive little grandchildren Nakul and Anjali, her divorced daughter Priya, teenagers Neeti and Rohan, and the elderly Mr.Pal who serves as Naani's binocular-toting ground floor spy. Clue after clue leads Naani to a racket where the stakes are high, the criminals ruthless, and their leader, very powerful. As she gets too close to their trail, she endangers herself. But Naani &amp; Co. rise to the occasion with some sharp thinking and heroic derring-do. They win the day with a little help from the CID. Naani's dogged mission to save one terrified little girl forms the emotional spine of the film. Yet it's an adventure that touches the lives of all the homemade detectives involved. Little Nakul wins the respect of the real CID, the two squabbling teens fall in love, Naani's divorced daughter and the dashing CID Inspector share a whiff of romance and old Mr. Pal finds a renewed energy and interest in life. "Detective Naani" has all the ingredients of one's favorite movie recipe - suspense, thrills and emotions garnished with liberal lashings of humor, leaving a pretty good taste in the viewer's mouth.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?142916</url></doc>
