<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="143476">
  <docid>143476</docid>
  <title>Devi Durga Shakti</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Raju, J.D.G.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Pughalmani</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Shah, Pratik</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Rajkumar, S.A.</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chakravarthy, Vinu</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Devayani</actor>
      <role>Ratna</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Meena (I)</actor>
      <role>Rajeshwari/Renuka/Devi Maa</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ramki</actor>
      <role>Mohan Dholakia</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ravi, Nizhalgal</actor>
      <role>Ratna's dad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Senthil</actor>
      <role>Kalicharan</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Young and beautiful, Rajeshwari, is the priestess of Devi Maa Durga's temple in a small village in Southern India. She is well-known and respected by everyone in the region, including Mohan Dholakia, who plays the drum, and is treated as her brother. Rajeshwari is blessed by Devi Maa and can walk on bed of nails without coming to any harm. The villagers all take turns to feed Rajeshwari and Mohan. Every night Rajeshwari journeys with a fire-lit torch to light up a small temple of Nagraj. During one of her journeys, she meets with the new Forest Officer Shankar and both fall in love. Mohan wants them to get married and accordingly a date on the 15th of the month is fixed for the marriage. Unfortunately, the 15th is the day that Devi Maa Durga assumes the form of Devi Maa Kali to slay demons and sinners. Shortly thereafter, Rajeshwari's body is found, torn apart by a tiger. When Mohan goes to light her funeral pyre, the body appears to come alive, and Mohan is told that Rajeshwari's soul is unhappy and not at peace. The villagers fear going near the temple, as word spreads that the Devi Maa has killed one of her closest devotees, and many others may also suffer the same fate, people start to move out of the village, and the temple is shut down. Amidst this fear and chaos, a warlock named Kalicharan is ready to assume the shape of a fearsome demon to locate the gold and jewelery that are buried near the temple. The question does remain, did Devi Maa Durga, the Protector, really kill her devotee?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?143476</url></doc>
