<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="143978">
  <docid>143978</docid>
  <title>Dharma: The Warrior</title>
  <year>1999</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Rao, Rama (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Tamil</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">1999</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Chandrashekhar, S.A.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Aleem, M.A.</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Deva (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Devan (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Koppikar, Isha</actor>
      <role>Nisha S. Raj</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Raali</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rami Reddy</actor>
      <role>Karimbhai</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ravi, Nizhalgal</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sriman</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vannan, A. Mani</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Dharam Singh lives in a village in Varanasi, India, along with his dad, Vikram, mom, and a sister who is of marriageable age. He has a married sister, Amritha, who lives in Matunga, Mumbai, along with her husband and a daughter, as she got married without her parents' blessings they have not been in touch for several years. In order to accumulate enough wealth for his sister's marriage, Dharam decides to re-locate to the Persian Gulf, and for that purpose travels to Mumbai, meets Amritha and her family, and pays Twenty Thousand Rupees to get his passport and visa to get a job in Dubai. Unfortunately, he loses his money, as the agent is arrested by the Police. He meets and falls in love with wealthy Nisha Raj, Amritha's friend, much to the chagrin of her gangster dad, Shyam, who threatens the entire family and asks Dharam to leave Mumbai. With no money to buy his way back home, Dharam meets with Chandru, his childhood friend, and gets hired as a gangster in Karimbhai's gang and re-locates in live in the Dharavi slums. Estranged from his sister, not able to return home, ashamed of telling Nisha about his new job, things spiral out of control, resulting in a gang war in which Nisha must be used as a bait - by none other than Dharam himself.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?143978</url></doc>
