<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="144719">
  <docid>144719</docid>
  <title>Diarmaid &amp; Strongbow</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Maldea, Irina</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>History</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>wales</keyword>
    <keyword>ireland</keyword>
    <keyword>abbess</keyword>
    <keyword>norman</keyword>
    <keyword>medieval</keyword>
    <keyword>viking</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Irish Gaelic</language>
    <language>Welsh</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Ireland</country>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Ireland">15 October 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Ireland">50</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Culleton, Brendan</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Culleton, Brendan</writer>
    <writer>Taft, Michael</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Farrelly, Columb</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Perhaps the key event of Irish history in the last thousand years was the arrival a small group of cousins on the Wexford coast in 1169. Of mixed Norman and Welsh blood, their followers predominantly Welsh and Flemish, they hurled themselves into the mêlée of contemporary Irish politics, at the invitation of the Irish themselves, and ended up almost conquering the whole country. If they had been sunk by a storm, or wiped out on landing, Irish history could have been very different. It they had succeeded in capturing the whole country, could this could have led to a happier outcome, with a strong Norman/Irish state along the lines of the English kingdom? For the King of England was also Duke of Normandy, and a vassal of the French king. Could Strongbow have become King of Ireland and still be Earl of Pembroke? Irish people still debate fervently the "800 years of oppression". In few other countries will we find events from so long ago linked with contemporary politics. Let's have a look at the real story, what really happened. Its a very exciting adventure story, involving Irish, Norman and Viking Kings, adultery, burning monasteries, looted towns, Vikings fleets, Norman knights, Irish axe-men, acts of courage and generosity, acts of vengeance and horror, blinding of hostages, raped abbesses. Troubadours sang songs about this great adventure all around the world of Western Christendom.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?144719</url></doc>
