<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="148769">
  <docid>148769</docid>
  <title>Die dunklen Lichter</title>
  <year>1997</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kutschker, Thomas</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>History</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>light</keyword>
    <keyword>city</keyword>
    <keyword>experimental-film</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>German</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Germany">April 1997</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Germany">13</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="default">35</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Kutschker, Thomas</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kutschker, Thomas</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Kutschker, Thomas</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Stories about artificial light from three centuries telling anecdotes about the former sights to our world. Words, sounds and pictures seem to be indepen dent, disconnected as the appearance of light itself, if you try to understand it. But they are woven into each other. Following their own logical construction. Looking back at the old times of celluloid the shadows in these images, where one sees the grain, tell more stories than bright and short cut pictures. Take a walk in a town that seems to be silent - that is made out of parts of different towns. Views that make you curious to discover the world at night in front of your doors. Streets, passages, housing and industrial areas - details and perspectives, which remain unre-garded during the day, tell stories in their shadows and reflexions, which appear at night. Surfaces, which seem to be built for a movie and are set alive by light and filmstock. Macro images of lightsources bring closer the im-materiality of light. A subjective world made out of stories, music and images.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?148769</url></doc>
