<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="150030">
  <docid>150030</docid>
  <title>Digger 3D</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Buck, Douglas</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>digit-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>number-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>3d-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Gallagher, John A.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Fox, Michael B.</producer>
    <producer>Lancellotti, Stephen</producer>
    <producer>Brooks, Nicholas (V)</producer>
    <producer>Caminer, Sylvia</producer>
    <producer>Gallagher, John A.</producer>
    <producer>Segal, Gregory (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Lancellotti, Stephen</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Mannix, Ernie</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Broccolini, Christina</actor>
      <role>Beans</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Coots, Joe</actor>
      <role>Priest</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cullen, Samantha</actor>
      <role>Amanda</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cunningham-Eves, Katherine</actor>
      <role>Detective Miller</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>DeLuca, Doug (I)</actor>
      <role>Police Officer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Eliav, Danelle</actor>
      <role>Rachel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gilmartin, James (I)</actor>
      <role>Digger</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gooding, Christina</actor>
      <role>Trisha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Heins, Trevor</actor>
      <role>Joshua</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Highfield, Helen</actor>
      <role>Flashback Victim</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Knotts, Jon</actor>
      <role>Rick Davis</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kristoffer, Heidi</actor>
      <role>Holly</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lancellotti, Erica</actor>
      <role>Louise</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Martin, Hugh (VII)</actor>
      <role>Edward</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Schneider, Adam (II)</actor>
      <role>Frank</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Segal, Gregory (I)</actor>
      <role>News Cameraman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sibley, Tom</actor>
      <role>Jose</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Holly Chambers has never quite recovered from the brutal attack that emotionally crippled her -- especially since no one believes it happened. Holly lives in the dorm of a rural college campus and has dropped out of society in a self-imposed seclusion. Her paranoia is crippling, her only coping mechanism self-medication as she continues on her downward spiral. It's Spring Break on campus and there has been a mass exodus for all the college party destinations, but Holly can't help but notice her roommate has not returned from her date in the woods. Holly begins a search to find her missing roommate, but her credibility is questioned by authorities after causing a stir a year before about her alleged kidnapping. Holly continues on her path despite the popular opinion that she is crying wolf once again. Holly gathers a select few to help find her missing roommate, but the deeper they dig into the case the more questions they raise. The clues lead the group to the woods, the same woods where an abduction changed Holly's life forever. A brief encounter with a local homeless man, Jackson, uncovers the urban legend of Joshua Bauer and his history in the woods. Joshua was abandoned in the wilderness by uncaring parents and was raised by the brutal hand of the local gravedigger. Physically and emotionally tortured, Joshua was never properly socialized; instead he became a monster enslaved by his father to dig graves by hand. Joshua's life as a prisoner comes to an end when he rebels with a vengeance, killing his father and anyone else who enters his territory. He has become Digger. As Holly continues her search for her roommate she crosses paths with Digger, finding herself face to face with all of her fears. Holly must overcome her nightmares in order to survive Digger and discover what truly happened to her missing roommate and prove that there really is a killer in the woods.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?150030</url></doc>
