<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="150705">
  <docid>150705</docid>
  <title>Dinner with Cupid</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Hefner, David</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>cupid</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">14 October 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">11</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Randall, Charles (IV)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Harley, J. Jesse</producer>
    <producer>Hefner, David</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Randall, Charles (IV)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Friedrich, Joseph</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Estandia, Greg</actor>
      <role>Mark Felch</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harley, J. Jesse</actor>
      <role>Lucky Patron</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Schmoll, Raymond</actor>
      <role>Cupid</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wanicur, Jonah</actor>
      <role>Jimmy</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Cupid is an over the hill drunk love angel who shoots the wrong guy. In doing so, he must convince a man to dump his love, or suffer the violent wrath of the universe. Set to the backdrop of a West Hollywood Italian Restaurant, it opens with a brash alcoholic man tormenting a helpless server. Jimmy, AKA The Wrong Guy, nervously enters the establishment, having been summoned by an unknown source. When he meets Cupid, he is perplexed by the mysterious alcoholic before him. The conversation turns nervous when the ever teasing Cupid tells Jimmy that he's here to talk about his girlfriend, Katy. Tensions rise and fall as Cupid explains his problem to the disbelieving Jimmy. To offer up a demonstration of his power, Cupid retrieves a high-tech blow gun and shoots an unsuspecting young woman in the back of the neck. The dart interrupts her in the middle of telling her close friend she doesn't want to ruin their friendship. When the dart penetrates her soul, she is, to the great delight of her admirer, seductively aroused. In the end, Jimmy refuses Cupid's request and storms out of the restaurant making a huge scene.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?150705</url></doc>
