<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="151344">
  <docid>151344</docid>
  <title>Dirty Laundry (Air It Out)</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Hammarberg, Erik</editor>
    <editor>Newby, Shannon (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">25 November 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Newby, Shannon (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Schirmer, Jeff</producer>
    <producer>Centeno, Jason (II)</producer>
    <producer>Newby, Shannon (I)</producer>
    <producer>Walker, Dr. Linda</producer>
    <producer>Newby, Shannon (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Newby, Shannon (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Clever, Chuck</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Coleman, Justin (I)</actor>
      <role>Jerry</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Coleman, Peter (IV)</actor>
      <role>Chas</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>El, Rasheda</actor>
      <role>Tamika</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Frey, Jeremy (I)</actor>
      <role>Nilla</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hester, Clarence</actor>
      <role>Melvin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hopkins, David O.</actor>
      <role>Mac</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Price, Robert (I)</actor>
      <role>Pumpkin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Reynolds, Eddie (I)</actor>
      <role>Stony</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wilson, Brian Anthony</actor>
      <role>Jerome</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>'Dirty Laundry' -The story of one night in an all night Laundromat where the characters air their 'Dirty Laundry' and become clean of their life problems by nights end. This comedic and touching story opens with the lead character MAC awakening from a nightmare at 2:13 AM. When he cannot return to sleep he walks around the corner to the 'all night' Laundromat to wash his clothes. To his surprise, the overnight attendant is JERRY an old friend from high school. As they discuss old times, TAMIKA an attractive woman comes in with her very massive, strong and heinous looking boyfriend JEROME. Mac realizes he once encountered Tamika through a long ago one-night stand. When the menacing looking boyfriend leaves to participate in some illegalities, Mac begins to make jokes about her to Jerry. Tamika overhears them and is so furious; she promises them insufferable pain when Jerome returns. As the night goes on, Jerry tries to calm the mounting situation as Mac continually pushes Tamika's buttons. While Mac and Jerry are awaiting impending doom, numerous colorful characters find their way into the Laundromat such as "MELVIN" a 45-year-old philosophical pizza deliveryman, and "AGNES" an elderly bag lady who talks more to herself than to other people. But, before this very eventful night comes to an end, everyone who enters this Laundromat will find themselves asking question about life, morality and normality.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?151344</url></doc>
