<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="152574">
  <docid>152574</docid>
  <title>Divorce</title>
  <year>1984</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Kothari, N.D.</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Khanna, Usha</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhattacharya, Abhi</actor>
      <role>Doctor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bindu (I)</actor>
      <role>Jayant's wife</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Birbal</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ghatge, Vijayendra</actor>
      <role>Ajay Oswal/Shyam</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jagdeep</actor>
      <role>Chakram</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jankidas</actor>
      <role>Chakram's dad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jasmin (I)</actor>
      <role>Seema/Geeta (As Jasmine)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Satyendra</actor>
      <role>Seema's dad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Karnad, Girish</actor>
      <role>Jayant Oswal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Latkar, Sulochana</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Oswal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maruti, Guddi</actor>
      <role>Chakram's to-be bride</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mehra, Raj</actor>
      <role>Jayant's father-in-law</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mukherjee, Keshto</actor>
      <role>Shankar dada</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Polson</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shivpuri, Om</actor>
      <role>Mr. Oswal</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Mr. Oswal (Om Shivpuri) is a very rich, influential, and domineering man, who lives with his wife (Sulochana) and two sons, namely Jayant (Girish Karnad) and Ajay (Vijayendra Ghatge). Mr. Oswal convinces his elder son, Jayant, that he cannot marry the girl he loves, Chandra (Sharmila Tagore), but must marry the girl of his choice. Jayant is disheartened, but agrees to marry the girl of his father's choice (Bindu). Ajay is disappointed with his brother's decision, as he too has fallen in love with Seema (Jasmine), the daughter of a college teacher (Satyen Kappu). Ajay does not listen to his dad, and elopes with Jasmine and marries her. They settle down, he takes on the job of a taxi-driver, and Seema works as a nurse in a hospital. One night Ajay sees Seema leaving their house with a man, and files for divorce, accusing her of infidelity. Seema is devastated. After the divorce, Ajay joins the army, and goes to war in Bangla Desh, who is with war against Pakistan. Back in the Oswal home, Mr. Oswal has learned that his choice of daughter-in-law has not been a good one; his wife is seriously ill and missing her younger son, little knowing that circusmtances are leading them to nothing but a tragic end. Who was the man that night with Seema? Will things go back to normal in the Oswal family?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?152574</url></doc>
