<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="152602">
  <docid>152602</docid>
  <title>Divorce: Not Between Husband and Wife</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Urs, Suresh</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">U</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">December 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="India">140</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="default">140</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Ramanan, M.J.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Chakravarthy, Appsara</producer>
    <producer>Ramanan, M.J.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Lajan</writer>
    <writer>Sandeep (I)</writer>
    <writer>Srinivasan, Athindran</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Ilayaraja</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bedi, Mandira</actor>
      <role>Renuka Joshi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chatterjee, Tannishtha</actor>
      <role>Kamla</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dabi, Snehal</actor>
      <role>Raju</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dave, Parth</actor>
      <role>Pranav Joshi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lagoo, Reema</actor>
      <role>Judge</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Musthafa</actor>
      <role>Nimith</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shroff, Jackie</actor>
      <role>Jackie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sood, Sonu</actor>
      <role>Siddharth Joshi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vyas, Shri Vallabh</actor>
      <role>Veda</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zutshi, Rajendranath</actor>
      <role>Shyam</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>An 8-year-old kid, Pranav, is the only son of a rich couple Sidharth and Renuka. Sidharth works for a Multinational Company as an officer whose job requires a lot of traveling. In a way, Sidharth is also obsessed with his job and, therefore, is unable to give any time to his child and wife. Renuka, on the other hand, is a highly skilled and a dedicated Media correspondent working for a private channel. She also faces the same problem of giving time to her child and husband. They are running with the mechanized professional objectives like any other conventional human beings of the contemporary age. The end result is that Pranav misses out on his parents and becomes a victim of suppressed emotions. Meanwhile, Pranav gains the friendship of his neighbor, Jackie, a loner. An advocate by profession, Jackie is also a hardcore alcoholic with a very cool and unconventional attitude towards life. This growing intimacy between the two of them creates insecurity in the minds of Sidharth and Renuka, who try various means to deviate Pranav, but their attempts make Pranav more intimate to Jackie. During one of Jackie's court sessions, Pranav accompanies Jackie to watch the proceedings. The case is about a divorce between a husband and a wife. Pranav asks the meaning for the word "divorce," and Jackie explains that it is a separation between two people who do not like each other. For the first time, Pranav asks whether he can get divorced from his parents since he does not like them. Though Pranav did not mean what he said, Jackie is shocked and convinces Pranav against it. In another incident that follows, Shyam, a drug addict and a resident of the apartment building in which Pranav resides, commits suicide due to a failed relationship. Pranav understands from a depressed old man that suicide is "freedom from all worries." These incidents create an indelible mark in the mind of Pranav, who thereafter threatens Jackie that he would commit suicide if he was not getting a divorce from his parents. Jackie conveys the seriousness to his parents. Sidharth and Renuka plan come home early in turns, but they still do not address the actual problems of Pranav, who wants to share a lot with his parents. But as a result of the professional demands, Sidharth and Renuka start quarreling with each other for not sticking on to their plan. Now Pranav decides to campaign for the divorce with all his heart. Jackie is unable to convince Pranav this time and agrees to take up the case on Pranav's behalf for granting the separation. As an outcome the Judge instructs the government to devise a new penal code to handle the case where the kid himself can file a complaint against his parents. The new penal code is created, and the final verdict by the Judge becomes the climax of the film.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?152602</url></doc>
