<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="152637">
  <docid>152637</docid>
  <title>Diwali</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Giann Antonio, Corey</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>kinetik-films</keyword>
    <keyword>mehul-shah</keyword>
    <keyword>diwali</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">15 October 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">70</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Shah, Mehul</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Shah, Mehul</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>ToTeras, Robert</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhandari, Gaurav</actor>
      <role>Parag</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhatia, Ramesh (II)</actor>
      <role>Vinod Sharma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kennedy, Hilary</actor>
      <role>Rachel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mali, Kajal</actor>
      <role>Nina</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mali, Tushar</actor>
      <role>Rahul</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mallick, Jyoti</actor>
      <role>Madhu Sharma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mani, Elizabeth</actor>
      <role>Priti Sharma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shah, Mehul</actor>
      <role>Mihir Sharma</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This touching story follows the lives of three children, Anjali, a young English Literature major, her brother, Mihir, a medical student, and Priti, a young mother as they all come home during the time of Diwali, the Indian new year and celebration of lights. Each child is burdened with various dilemmas in their lives that they hide from one another. Anjali, a bright and outgoing girl, seems distraught over her wild life in New York City. If hiding her situation wasn't worse enough, her trip home brings an unexpected surprise for her as her meddlesome aunt Lina decides to set her up with Parag, a young doctor, who is part of Anjali's past. What does their past hold? Are they able to keep the secret of not knowing one another? What exactly happened to Anjali that uneventful night? Mihir has problems all his own. After being kicked out of medical school, Mihir is forced to come home and confront his inner demons of hiding his true passion from his family and maintaining the status quo of the "respectable" young man. Priti and her daughter Nina come home for Diwali time as well, yet Priti seems to be troubled by mention of her husband, a successful investment banker. What happened to their relationship? All these issues are answered and brought together as the true meaning of family and friendship collide in this compelling film.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?152637</url></doc>
