<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="154591">
  <docid>154591</docid>
  <title>Dollgatory</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">1 June 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">85</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Vogiantzis, Tony</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Vogiantzis, Tony</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Vogiantzis, Tony</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Doss, Joe</actor>
      <role>The Pharos</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fawzy, Mounira</actor>
      <role>Question Woman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fawzy, Sarah</actor>
      <role>Josie Crups</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Giacco, Paolo</actor>
      <role>God</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Marr, Kassandra</actor>
      <role>Natasha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mclean, Conor</actor>
      <role>George Speedopoulos</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pantelidis, Jean</actor>
      <role>Jean</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vogiantzis, Tony</actor>
      <role>Officer Malone</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Meet George Speedopoulos, an unsuccessful entrepreneur and to add to his misfortune, owns a dead end dollar store. Things are not going very well for George, he's flat broke, and to top it off, he must deal with the craziest clientele who drive him passed the point of sanity. George decides that the only remedy to end his problems is to murder the unholy one...his wife Gina! His master plan - kill Gina, collect life insurance, pay off his debts, close the dollar store, and it &amp; smooth sailing. As one may expect, things don't go according to plan, and George finds himself dead. He awakens in the dollar store, stuck in a purgatory world. As punishment from God, George is trapped there for eternity unless he can redeem himself for his crime. In order to be granted redemption, George must perform a seemingly impossible task - restore faith in all the dollar store regular psychopaths which come in and cause havoc. The clientele, their goal - do what it takes to ensure George fails his trial with God, Judgment day.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?154591</url></doc>
