<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="155349">
  <docid>155349</docid>
  <title>Don Quixote</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>based-on-novel</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Ukraine</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Ukraine">18 December 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">85</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Crombie, Robert (II)</director>
    <director>Meyer, Nicholas</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Crombie, Robert (II)</producer>
    <producer>Foster, David (III)</producer>
    <producer>Heppe, Ryan E.</producer>
    <producer>Van Rellim, Tim</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Cervantes y Saavedra, Miguel de</writer>
    <writer>Meyer, Nicholas</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Theodorakis, Maro</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>A poor middle-aged Spanish gentleman becomes so addicted to reading tales of fabulous adventures that he loses his mind. Believing himself to be the hero of one of his books, he renames himself Don Quixote, and he sets out on his horse Rocinante to rescue his imaginary lady-love Dulcinea from the power of an evil magician. To our mad knight everyday objects such as windmills and flocks of sheep are changed into giants and armies which must be defeated in battle if he is to rescue Dulcinea. In the company of his faithful squire, Sancho Panza, these comic adventures become ever more tragic as, sane madman and wise fool, they roam the roads of Spain in pursuit of an impossible dream. In 2002 one hundred of the world's most famous writers from 54 countries voted Don Quixote the world's all-time best novel. Yet there is no "normal" cartoon version of this incredibly famous and funny book, even though Don Quixote, with its double vision of the world, is ideally suited for animation. Every middle-class parent the world over knows that Don Quixote is a book their children should read, or failing that, at least watch! "What a unique monument is this book! How its creative genius, critical, free, and human, soars above its age!" - Thomas Mann "Cervantes is the founder of the modern era. The novelist need answer to nobody but Cervantes. Don Quixote is practically unthinkable as a living being, and yet, in our memory, what character is more alive." - Milan Kundera "Don Quixote begins as a province, turns into Spain, and ends as a universe." - V.S Pritchett</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?155349</url></doc>
