<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="155552">
  <docid>155552</docid>
  <title>Don't Go</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Lordy, Tiff</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">PG</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">15 February 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">17</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Epps, D. Kevin</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Norris, Clare (I)</producer>
    <producer>Epps, D. Kevin</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Epps, D. Kevin</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Harrison, Frankie</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carter, Justin Michael</actor>
      <role>Malcolm James</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Coleman, Ajarae</actor>
      <role>Lacey</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Croom, Barika</actor>
      <role>Taylor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>DeVonish, Marisa</actor>
      <role>Sierra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fisher, Kia</actor>
      <role>Carmen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fowler, Brandi</actor>
      <role>Gabrielle</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Glover, Kenyon</actor>
      <role>Dean</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hawthorne, Fred</actor>
      <role>Narrator/Kevin</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Kevina King is preparing to reconcile in her relationship with boyfriend Malcolm James. As she does her best friend Lacey confronts her over all of the problems with the relationship. As the two argue back and forth the conversation gets more and more contentious, culminating in Kevina forcing Lacey to angrily storm out. Meanwhile Malcolm is at his home arrogantly entertaining two women and bragging to his best friend Dean on the phone. He upsets both women with his verbal and physical and forces them out. He also upsets the peace in Dean's home as he unsuccessfully attempts to justify his friendship with Malcolm to his sister and his girlfriend. While this is going on, Kevina is in the final preparations to go see Malcolm. As she is ready to leave, she believes she hears her friend Lacey returning to stop her. Instead she is confronted by someone totally unexpected: her future self, her Spirit. Kevina's Spirit tells her what is to come and what she needs to do. Kevina resists but her Spirit is too strong. She convinces Kevina to end her relationship with Malcolm and take back control of her life. Not willing to let go, Malcolm attempts to regain control until he too is shown a glimpse of the truth.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?155552</url></doc>
