<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="156091">
  <docid>156091</docid>
  <title>Donkey Kong Country</title>
  <year>1994</year>
  <type>VideoGame</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>jungle</keyword>
    <keyword>barrel</keyword>
    <keyword>armadillo</keyword>
    <keyword>donkey-kong-junior</keyword>
    <keyword>bee</keyword>
    <keyword>mine</keyword>
    <keyword>banana</keyword>
    <keyword>crocodile</keyword>
    <keyword>frog</keyword>
    <keyword>beaver</keyword>
    <keyword>swordfish</keyword>
    <keyword>orangutan</keyword>
    <keyword>snake</keyword>
    <keyword>rocking-chair</keyword>
    <keyword>vulture</keyword>
    <keyword>cane</keyword>
    <keyword>king</keyword>
    <keyword>donkey-kong</keyword>
    <keyword>nintendo</keyword>
    <keyword>monkey</keyword>
    <keyword>octopus</keyword>
    <keyword>old-man</keyword>
    <keyword>pirate</keyword>
    <keyword>water</keyword>
    <keyword>rhino</keyword>
    <keyword>pirate-ship</keyword>
    <keyword>mine-car</keyword>
    <keyword>ostrich</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>bird</keyword>
    <keyword>barrel-throwing</keyword>
    <keyword>oil-drum</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">K-A</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Japan">26 November 1994</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">23 November 1994</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Stamper, Tim</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Stamper, Tim</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Wise, David (II)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bayliss, Kevin</actor>
      <role>Donkey/Diddy/K. Rool</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>One morning, Donkey Kong awakes to find that his entire banana hoarde has been stolen. He also finds that his friend Diddy has been stuffed into a barrel. Donkey rescues Diddy and together they go off to find who did this. Who actually did the deed was King K. Rool, king of the Kremling army, the terror of Donkey Kong Country. Donkey and Diddy must brave mines, forests, tree tops, lakes, factories, caves, glaciers, ancient ruins and a pirate ship and get help from their friends Rambi the Rhino, Enguarde the Swordfish, Winky the frog, Expresso the Ostrich, and Squawks the Parrot. Using teamwork, Donkey Kong and Diddy Kong must battle off furious foes like Klump the Kremling army general, Krusha the Arnold Schwarze-Kremling who's also incredibly stupid, Klap Trap though he looks small he's got a mean jaw, Krash the mine cart driving Kremling who drives like a maniac on the mine tracks so watch out! Croctapus the evil being in the lakes, Gnawty the beaver, and the evil King K. Rool himself! Along the way, get help from your fellow Kong family members like Cranky who will offer his advice, as well as sarcasm, Funky who can use his barrel plane to send you to levels you've already completed and Candy who can save your game for you. It's up to you to save the day!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?156091</url></doc>
