<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="157452">
  <docid>157452</docid>
  <title>Double Identical Twins: 4 Years Later</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Hudnell, Kevin</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">10 March 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Schiff, Eric</producer>
    <producer>Family, Afsheen</producer>
    <producer>Nadell, Sue</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Nadell, Sue</writer>
    <writer>Schiff, Eric</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Licari, Michael</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Morris, James (XXIV)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Morris, Kurt</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Morris, Robbie</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Morris, Sammy</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In this update of the original special "Double Identical Twins," we follow the further adventures of the Morris family, who grew from three members to seven after the birth of an extremely rare set of quads: two identical boys and two identical girls. These days Kurt and Geana Morris have their hands full with big brother Sammy (now 6) and four busy 4 year-olds: Anna, Ella, James and Robbie. After re-capping the birth of the quads and the highlights of their first three years (including footage of the family from the update special" Babies, Babies, Everywhere"), we're off and running in the midst their hectic lives today. Since we saw the quads last, they've done a lot of growing, and the family has braved medical and life challenges including a serious accident that landed Sammy in the E.R. and a fire in the family home. While all the kids are adorable and engaging, Anna has been diagnosed with a mild form of Cerebral Palsy, Ella may have hearing problems, and the two boys continue in behavioral and motor skills therapy. Meanwhile, Kurt and Geana do their best to juggle family, their relationship and careers - braving it all with a sense of humor and a determination to live their best lives.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?157452</url></doc>
