<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="159352">
  <docid>159352</docid>
  <title>Dream House</title>
  <year>1983</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Game-Show</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">4 April 1983</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bartlett, Debbie</actor>
      <role>Hostess</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Eubanks, Bob</actor>
      <role>Host</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gilbert, Johnny (I)</actor>
      <role>Announcer</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The grand prize given away on "Dream House" was stated in the title...a brand new house! Two married couples, including a returning champion, competed. The rules to the front game were modified several times during the show's 14-month run, but basically were as follows: Host Eubanks reads a toss-up true-false question. The couple who guesses correctly wins $50 and the right to select one of four topics on a topic board. Correct answers to these multiple-choice questions were worth $100 per correct guess, while the opponents could win the cash if an incorrect answer was given. The opponents could also challenge and give their own answer if they believed a wrong answer was given; however, the original couple won an additional $50 if they answered correctly and the opponent's challenge was unsuccessful. If nobody was correct, Eubanks simply read another toss-up question. The leader after all four questions were played won a prize. Round 2 was played in similar fashion, with double values ($100 for toss-ups, $200 for topic questions). The highest-scoring couple after two rounds won the game, a room of luxury furniture (usually worth $5,000 or more) and advanced to the bonus round; if the couple won by at least $1,000, they also received a new car. In the bonus game, the object was to unlock the "Golden Doors" (which concealed the show's grand prize) by correctly guessing a three-number combination. Four possibilities were provided each number (e.g., 2459, 1823, 5170). One number was knocked off at the outset, with one more number erased per return visit. The couple could eliminate up to three more numbers (one per row) with correct answers to the questions; still more numbers could be withdrawn by correctly answering questions in the front game. The couple then entered the combination they thought would unlock the Golden Doors. The lights surrounding the door lit progressively to suspensful music; if the couple correctly guessed the combination--denoted by the top bar of lights lighting--the couple won the house and celebrated to great fanfare. If the combination was incorrect, Eubanks showed the correct combination and the couple returned the next day. Couples winning five games automatically won the house. Before the start of the show, the couple chose what house they wanted to play for (described at the beginning of the show), with several styles available; the houses were usually worth $100,000 or more. In addition to married couples playing, weeks were devoted to single parents and their children, siblings and engaged couples playing for their dream house.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?159352</url></doc>
