<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="159350">
  <docid>159350</docid>
  <title>Dream House</title>
  <year>1968</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Game-Show</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>non-fiction</keyword>
    <keyword>quiz-show</keyword>
    <keyword>partially-lost-tv-series</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">27 March 1968</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Mifelow, Alan</director>
    <director>Schneider, Dick</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Darrow, Mike</actor>
      <role>Emcee (1968-1970)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gould, Chet</actor>
      <role>Announcer (1968-1970)</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>While new houses had periodically been offered as grand prizes on previous game shows, such as the original "Price is Right," never was there a show which offered a new home as the top prize...that is, until "Dream House." In this game hosted by Mike Darrow, two couples, including a returning champion, competed to win a brand new home worth $40,000 or more. The game was a basic general knowledge quiz, with several rounds played and multiple-choice and true-false questions asked. Cash amounts were awarded for correct answers, depending on the round and other factors. The top scoring couple of the day was the champion and won a room of furniture, valued at $3,000 or more. If the couple won a certain number of shows (seven on the daytime series, four on the prime-time version), the couple won their dream house. Before the show, the couple chose what type of house they wanted to play for--it could be a house using contemporary, ranch, farmhouse and modern styling (worth $40,000 or more); or they could opt for a far-less expensive alternative, such as a vacation cottage, modular home, houseboat or motorhome (still worth at least $8,500). The show would be revised in 1983 under the same name, with Bob Eubanks as host.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?159350</url></doc>
