<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="160089">
  <docid>160089</docid>
  <title>Drift Style</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bradley, Marshall (II)</editor>
    <editor>Meader, Ben</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Sport</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>race</keyword>
    <keyword>drift</keyword>
    <keyword>motorsport</keyword>
    <keyword>drifting</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Allen, R. Douglas</producer>
    <producer>Leitz, James</producer>
    <producer>Ogden, Jay</producer>
    <producer>Mullen, Chabin</producer>
    <producer>Spasic, Milan</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Miller, Billy (VII)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Eagle, Eddie</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The Circuit City Formula Drift Pro Championship Racing Series.Formula DRIFT Championship is recognized as the North American professional drifting championship series. As the first official series in North America, Formula DRIFT has taken competitive motor sports to the extreme attracting fans and car enthusiasts from all walks of life. This high-skilled, high-powered motor sport where drivers intentionally maneuver their cars into well executed, controlled sideways slides at high speeds through a marked course, has more than 60 professional drivers competing in all seven competitions this year.* Most diverse driver background and vehicle models of any drifting league in the world * First drifting Championship to have works teams (auto maker supported) Judged on execution and style, rather than who finishes the course in the fastest time, Drifting is a guaranteed crowd pleaser, and is often compared to the freestyle nature of skateboarding and motocross. Drivers and Formula DRIFT also serves as ambassadors for the sport of drifting bringing exhibitions to traditional/mainstream motor sports events across the country which have included: multiple Champ Car World Series races, American Le Mans, USAC, NASCAR Busch North &amp; Featherlite Southwest and the SPEED World Challenge, among others.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?160089</url></doc>
