<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="161475">
  <docid>161475</docid>
  <title>Due</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Di Franco, Linda</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Italian</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Italy">17 September 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">11</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="Italy">15</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Sparano, John</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Campanile, Luigi</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Sparano, John</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Simone, Franco</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Negahban, Navid</actor>
      <role>Daria's Fiance</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Opinato, Mario</actor>
      <role>Carlo</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In order to get be true to her faith, Daria must marry her non-Catholic husband within the Church. Unfortunately, her fiancé is a Muslim and no priest will give his blessing. She travels to her hometown to ask her friend, Carlo, for a favor. Carlo, now the local priest in Tricase, once was hopelessly in love with Daria. She feels he is the only one who will help her. Carlo still wanders the town among the ghosts of the intense relationship he and Daria had, wondering if he has finally moved on through his love of God. When Daria arrives in town, Carlo relies on his dedication to the Church to help him make the right decision. Daria's beauty and proximity weigh heavy on him. When he turns down her request, he wonders if he is being true to the Church or his own broken heart in not wanting her to be happy. Stunned at the rejection, Daria pushes Carlo to see just how far his devotion to the Church will go. She discovers that his love for her is still close to the surface. Daria positions herself as a sexual threat to Carlo's vow to the Church. She knows that Carlo will have no choice but to do as she says, thus leaving no open door to their relationship. When he grants her wish, her joy is marred by her thoughts of what would have been, and her own desire to close their relationship off forever.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?161475</url></doc>
