<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="162153">
  <docid>162153</docid>
  <title>Duniya Na Mane</title>
  <year>1959</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Dharamvir</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">U</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <directors>
    <director>Avadhoot, V.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Aggarwal, K.</producer>
    <producer>Rehni, M.M.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Kanwal, Jagdish</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Mohan, Madan (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhagwan, Master</actor>
      <role>Bhagwandas</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Choti, Mohan</actor>
      <role>Sundermukh's assistant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Haksar, Rajan</actor>
      <role>Sundarmukh Ram</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Helen (I)</actor>
      <role>Stage Dancer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Irani, Daisy (I)</actor>
      <role>Young Geeta</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Pradeep</actor>
      <role>Raja</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Latkar, Sulochana</actor>
      <role>Meera Bai</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mukhtar, Sheikh</actor>
      <role>Jaggu Bihari/Rattan Lal</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Geeta Lal lives a wealthy lifestyle with her businessman dad, Rattan, who runs a vehicle showroom in Bombay. She meets with Raja, a new-comer to Bombay, and both fall in love with each other. Geeta introduces Raja to her dad, who approves of him, and he sets a date for their formal engagement, which will take place on the same day as Geeta's birthday. Rattan asks Raja to invite his parents, and finds out that his father is deceased, but his mom will be attending the ceremony. On the day of the ceremony, Rattan meets Raja's mom, a woman named Chanchal, and angrily breaks off any contact with Raja. A baffled and heartbroken Geeta must now find out why her dad, first approved Raja, and then rejected him. What Geeta does not know is that Raja does not love her - he is only out to avenge the death of his real mother, who was run over by Rattan's car years ago. Geeta also does not know that Rattan is not her biological father, but a brutal killer, who had knowingly killed her very own father, Madan. Watch as events unfold and the impact these have on Geeta, Rattan, and Raja.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?162153</url></doc>
