<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="162311">
  <docid>162311</docid>
  <title>Durante</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Musical</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>one-word-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Sekula, Andrzej</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>James, Durante Romano</producer>
    <producer>James, Mancuso</producer>
    <producer>Mancuso, James</producer>
    <producer>Messick, Kathy</producer>
    <producer>Owens, Stephen F.</producer>
    <producer>Raidl, Angela M.</producer>
    <producer>Romano, Durante James</producer>
    <producer>Cavanaugh, Timothy Patrick</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>James, Durante Romano</writer>
    <writer>Messick, Kathy</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Durante-Everybody Wants To Get in The Act_ is the true life story of Jimmy Durante, a timeless myth of an ugly duckling that transforms into a beautiful swan via his music and comedy. Jimmy's gripping odyssey, through downfalls and successes, breaks our hearts and puts them back together again; unraveling the tapestry of an awkward young man who desperately wants to fit in, but is destined to stand out. Referred to as a comic spirit who makes the world seem worth bothering about again_ Jimmy's Goodnight Mrs. Calabash_ echoes in America's soul. His raucous story with a tender message holds a volatile love story at its heart and yet the supporting roles boast an ensemble cast as authentic and colorful as the era demands. Taking Jimmy from the Cyrano of the cellars to the top comedy act of the Twenties, Broadway, and beyond to international stardom, this story holds an incredible soundtrack! The tale is woven with seductive ragtime, early jazz, and ballads that only Jimmy can sing making you believe fairy tales do come true! Setting the precedent for nightclub comedy and at the forefront of every show biz genre, the Schnozzâ is a legend and proving market whose music and character transcend time. Not just a tale about fitting in, this is a story about the struggles of an extraordinary performer who needs to find himself beyond his nose; to accept himself as an ordinary man. Everybody Wants To Get in The Act_ co-author is James Durante Romano. His father is the eldest son of Jimmy's sister Lillian. Lillian's husband abandoned his family returning to Italy. Jimmy childless stepped in to help raise his nephews. This is truly an inside view of one of Americas most beloved entertainers.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?162311</url></doc>
