<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="162506">
  <docid>162506</docid>
  <title>Dust to Dust: The Health Effects of 9/11</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Small, David (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>ground-zero</keyword>
    <keyword>world-trade-center-new-york</keyword>
    <keyword>number-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">11 September 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">65</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Dehncke-Fisher, Heidi</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Martinez, Luis (VI)</producer>
    <producer>Karplus, Marisa</producer>
    <producer>Ravitz, Josh</producer>
    <producer>Gessner, Hal</producer>
    <producer>Dehncke-Fisher, Heidi</producer>
    <producer>Kennedy, Bruce (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Kennedy, Bruce (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Buscemi, Steve</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Five years after 9/11, the terrorist attacks on the World Trade Center continue to claim the lives of American citizens. The violent collapse of the buildings released hundreds of thousands of pounds of deadly materials into the air - including carcinogens such as asbestos and benzene, lead and mercury from the thousands of crushed computers, and other toxins such as PCPs, PAHs and silicon particulates. Yet in the immediate aftermath of the disaster, the federal agency responsible for safeguarding the public health - the Environmental Protection Agency - reassured everyone that their air was safe to breathe. Now more than ever - it seems that this was not the case. Countless first responders - emergency technicians, police officers, and firefighters - have grown ill as a result of their exposure to toxins from the smoldering pile that once was the World Trade Center. Some have contracted severe respiratory problems such as chronic asthma and reactive airway disease. Others have been diagnosed with more serious illnesses such as leukemia, pancreatic cancer, mesothelioma and kidney disease. And though initially regarded as heroes, they have been abandoned by their government in their quest to seek medical treatment and financial help for their families. Featuring interviews with prominent scientists, EPA officials and the now-sick heroes of 9/11, Dust to Dust is a tragic, cautionary tale about heroism, survival, and ultimately betrayal. Narrated by actor and former firefighter Steve Buscemi, the film thoroughly explores and exposes this under-reported health crisis of unprecedented magnitude.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?162506</url></doc>
