<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="162563">
  <docid>162563</docid>
  <title>Dutch Wife 28</title>
  <year>1998</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>anime</keyword>
    <keyword>number-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>hentai</keyword>
    <keyword>android</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Japanese</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Japan</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Australia">R</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">45</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Midoriyama, Hiroshi</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Hatta, Hogara</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cummings, Mayblissa</actor>
      <role>Kozue</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Long, Hughie B.</actor>
      <role>Yakuza</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Snackwell, Syndi</actor>
      <role>Satomi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Underhill, Sebastian</actor>
      <role>Masaki</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Woodward, Buddy</actor>
      <role>Aiwa</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Ever wonder how the cretins of this world typically get the nice girls? Aiwa certainly falls into that catagory: he spends his days endlessly obsessing over a girl named Kozue whom he can never have and runs every chance encounter with her through his mind. Oh yes, he's got it bad... To put his mind a little more at ease, Aiwa ordered a little something special to brighten up those long nights, but it so long to arrive that he totally forgot about it! Now, true to form, the company has messed up his order and sent him, well something...different. But just how different he's about to find out! When Aiwa opens his box from the company, he finds out that technology is a little better than he bargained for, and Aiwa is in for the surprise of his life. Inside is Satomi who is just about exactly what every man is looking for: loyal, pure-hearted, cheerful ... and utterly insatiable. It doesn't take long for Aiwa to learn just how perfect his new little friend is, and how his life is no longer entirely his own. But even as perfect as she is, Aiwa's still dreaming of Kozue. Of course, he's not above a little (or even a lot!) of practice until the day he can finally score with the girl of his dreams... Now, all he's got to do is to find the off button before Kozue comes over again....</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?162563</url></doc>
