<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="162942">
  <docid>162942</docid>
  <title>Dylusions of Grandeur</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Roberts, Rickie-Lee</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">June 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>McShane, Danny</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Holmes, Ella</producer>
    <producer>Roberts, Rickie-Lee</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>McShane, Danny</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Yeandle, Dylan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Dylan Yeandle moved to Australia from a small town in Tasmania to try and become famous. Is this something he can achieve or is he destined to just be an everyday ordinary person? 'Dylusions og Grandeur' follows Dylan Yeandle's transition from adolescence to adulthood as he strives to become a famous entertainer. Dylan's coming of age journey begins after an appearance on the TV show 'Pop Stars'. This appearance on national TV gave him a taste of how good it could feel to be the center of attention. It fueled his desire to become a famous entertainer. This is the catalyst that sparked his sense of discontent with his home of Tasmania and drew him away from this childhood home to the unfamiliar setting of Brisbane, Australia. After a string of failed auditions in Australia, Dylan eventually accomplished a position in the top 25 of the popular TV show 'Australian Idol'. After a larger, second taste of stardom, Dylan became hungrier then ever to break free of what he considered a boring life. Dylan's odd style of performance became a novelty that 'Australian Idol' exploited until they had no further need of it. At this point, Dylan was asked, "what kind of a performer are you?". This question stumped Dylan because not only did he not know what kind of a performer he was, he had no idea of who HE was. This question of identity is one that lies at the heart of all coming of age films. Dylan's process of maturing throughout his journey consists of repeated clashes between his desire to be a famous entertainer and the reality of his situation, enforced by an unbending social order. Even though Dylan has huge dreams and enough talent to possibly achieve these dreams he still has to work to live. With no tertiary education the only job he could get was stacking shelves at a local IGA supermarket. This mundane job caused Dylan to question his identity even more. Ultimately Dylan never figures out who he truly is. Does anyone ever figure this out though? Dylan comes to terms with not knowing who he is and realises that it is okay not to know.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?162942</url></doc>
