<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="163926">
  <docid>163926</docid>
  <title>E-SWAT: Cyber Police</title>
  <year>1990</year>
  <type>VideoGame</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1990</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
<plot>As a member of the Cyber Police force in the city of Liberty, your job is to clear the streets of crime, terminate the most-wanted criminals and put them behind bars. There are 15 stages to complete, and have you patrolling through Liberty streets, car yards, stadiums, restaurants, the CBD, and boat docks. There are bosses on some stages. While you're patrolling the streets, you can pick up ammunition, and the amount you get varies. For example, on some levels, ammo may be worth 10 bullets, while in others, you may get 60 bullets. Some bosses attack in several ways. For example, the first boss breathes fire at you, the second boss throws a boomerang and the third attempts to hurt you with anchor. Note that the bosses are not just people. You'll come face-to-face with an ape, tiger, jeep, and cyborgs. Once you defeat these first three bosses, your rank goes up to captain to assistant chief, and finally to chief. Furthermore, once you've been promoted to chief, you will be given a cyber suit, which is described by the game as a 'long-range supersonic powered suit' which contains two Turbo-Booster Thrusters, and provides extra ammunition and protection. You'll also have it for the duration of the game. And this is where the fun begins, because you'll have to arrest criminal masterminds like Dirty Duffy, Rats Lee, and anyone else who has a record for theft, murder, or narcotics.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?163926</url></doc>
