<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="164347">
  <docid>164347</docid>
  <title>Earth Made of Glass</title>
  <year>2010</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bomse, Seth</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">87</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Scranton, Deborah</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Carolin, Reid</producer>
    <producer>Scranton, Deborah</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Söderqvist, Johan</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kagame, Paul</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>On August 6th, 2008, against the backdrop of the world's deadliest war in neighboring Eastern Congo, Rwandan President Paul Kagame issued a report detailing the French government's hidden role in the 1994 Rwandan genocide. Three months later, his closest aide, Rose Kabuye is arrested by France on charges of terrorism. Meanwhile, Jean-Pierre Sagahutu, a genocide survivor haunted by his father's unsolved murder, scours the Rwandan countryside on a fifteen-year-search for clues - ultimately finding himself confronted with his darkest desire: being face-to-face with his father's killer. As President Kagame fights to free Rose from France and finally expose the shocking truth about what truly happened in Rwanda fifteen years ago, Jean-Pierre journeys to the scene of the crime, and the doorstep of a killer, to uncover the chilling facts behind his father's death. As each relentlessly pursues the truth they find themselves faced with a choice: to take revenge or turn the other cheek... Despite having never met, the story of a President and an ordinary citizen become inextricably linked in this groundbreaking film. Bound by a deep love of country, an insatiable need for the truth, and a hunger for peace, Jean-Pierre and President Kagame set in motion both the rebuilding of a family, and of an entire nation. Above all, their stories shake the very foundations of what it means to forgive - blazing a trail towards ending hatred and violence throughout Africa and the world.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?164347</url></doc>
