<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="165302">
  <docid>165302</docid>
  <title>Ed &amp; Vern's Rock Store</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Leps, Christopher</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">18 January 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">42</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Leps, Christopher</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Madison, Alex</producer>
    <producer>Bucaro III, Joe</producer>
    <producer>Leps, Christopher</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cullen, Peter (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Leno, Jay</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McQueen, Chad</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Thompson, Trampas</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>At the end of World War II, the United States experienced economic growth that remained constant through the late 1950's. It was during that time that Americans fell in love with the automobile. As a result, the Sunday drive was born, and with it, so was the roadside pit stop. These rest stops found their place in American culture and became synonymous with day trips. But over the years, many of these small businesses died off. They fell victim to progress, and society stood by as larger franchises pushed them out of business. The Sunday drive became a thing of the past. But in the Santa Monica Mountains, there is a stretch of road where the Sunday drive is alive and well. The Rock Store was originally used as a stagecoach stop in the early 1900's. What began as a simple grocery store in the first half of the twentieth century evolved into a motorcycle mecca. In addition to its fame as a motorcycle haven, the Rock Store gained notoriety as one of the top motorist destinations in the United States, and eventually became an epicenter for star sightings. But despite their success over the years, owners Ed and Vern Savko have not been without their share of adversity. Yet through it all they've remained dedicated to their ideals they established for their small business nearly fifty years ago. Through devotion, the Rock Store has become nothing short of an icon, earning its place among the artifacts of Americana.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?165302</url></doc>
