<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="168294">
  <docid>168294</docid>
  <title>Ek Din 24 Ghante</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">7 November 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="India">95</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="default">95</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Balani, Anant</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Dholakia, Devang</producer>
    <producer>Jindhal, Vijay</producer>
    <producer>Suchanti, Vivek</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Chakravarty, Sanju</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bose, Rahul</actor>
      <role>Virendra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Das, Nandita</actor>
      <role>Sameera Dutta</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Vinit</actor>
      <role>Mr. Patel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lilliput</actor>
      <role>Stage actor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mehta, Shilpa</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Dutta</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mishra, Piyush (I)</actor>
      <role>Police Inspector</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sadanand, Kabir</actor>
      <role>Hitman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Subramaniam, Shivkumar</actor>
      <role>Mr. Dutta</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zutshi, Prithvi</actor>
      <role>Mr. Kapoor</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Sameera Dutta is an enlightened and intelligent young woman, who knows exactly what she wants of life. She belongs to an upper class family, and lives with her mom and dad, a business executive. She is in love with a young man by the name of Virendra, who comes from a poor family, and is disliked by her dad. Nevertheless, Sameera loves him, and will not marry anyone else, despite warnings from her dad. One day, Virendra telephones Sameera and asks her to bring in two lac rupees as he has to pay off debtors, otherwise they will kill him. Sameera is shocked at this huge amount, but fears for Virendra's life, asks her dad for this money, and he refuses. She forces him to give her the money at gunpoint, and then drives to where Virendra is waiting for her. There is curfew on in Bombay due to riots and violent clashes, and as a result Sameera's car is damaged; then a man tries to shoot her down, but she escapes on foot, on to meet her sweetheart. It is here that Sameera will find out the truth, that has been so oblivious to her all this time.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?168294</url></doc>
