<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="168354">
  <docid>168354</docid>
  <title>Ek Raaz</title>
  <year>1963</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Samanta, Shakti</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Nadiadwala, A.A.</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Gupta, Chitra</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Agha</actor>
      <role>Champaklal Maadupki/Shankar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Begum, Mumtaz</actor>
      <role>Beena's mom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jamuna (I)</actor>
      <role>Beena</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kala, Jeevan</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Kishore</actor>
      <role>Kishore Kumar Verma/Arun/Peshawarimal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Madhumati</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Musharraf, Mirza</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pran (I)</actor>
      <role>Arun</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, Madan (I)</actor>
      <role>Chunilal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sharma, Niranjan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Beena lives a wealthy lifestyle in scenic Ooty, India, along with her widowed mom, cousin Sushma, and maternal uncle, Khushalchand Peshawari. Her marriage has been arranged in her childhood with wealthy Arun, who is the son of businessman Girdharilal and Kamla. One day she and Sushma go to the railway station to receive Kishore Kumar Sharma, a singer, who is scheduled to perform locally, and bring home a young man who they introduce to their dad. After the performance another male claiming to be Kishore Kumar Sharma shows up, and the fake one flees, but not before making a lasting impression on Beena. She does meet him again, this time as her uncle's employee, Peshawarimal, and when his cover is exposed, he flees again. The third time she meets him at her future in-laws house where he is known as Kishore Kumar Verma and works as an Accountant with their business. Beena and Kishore overcome their misunderstanding and rekindle their romance, little knowing that soon Kishore will be on the run again - this time from the Police, for killing Girdharilal's employee, Chunilal.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?168354</url></doc>
