<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="168360">
  <docid>168360</docid>
  <title>Ek Sapera Ek Lutera</title>
  <year>1965</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">U</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">1965</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Kumar, Naresh (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kumar, Naresh (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Khanna, Usha</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Apte, Madhu</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Avtar, Ram</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bansal, Indira</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Begum, Mumtaz</actor>
      <role>Rajmata</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dutt, Uma</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Feroz</actor>
      <role>Mohan/Vijay Pratap Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Rashid (I)</actor>
      <role>Chaudhary (Radha's Father)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Shyam (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumkum</actor>
      <role>Radha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sunder (I)</actor>
      <role>Badluram</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Sundergarh's greedy prince stabs his father to death so that he can accede the throne. The dying King curses his son that he too will die at the hands of his son. The Prince then is crowned the King. Shortly, thereafter his wife gets pregnant, and the King plans to kill his child, in order to foil his dad's curse. His wife gives birth to twins, one of which is left with her, and the other taken away by the King and disposed off in a nearby forest to be eaten by wild beasts. The child in the palace grows up to be Vijay Pratap Singh. The child left in the forest is rescued by a band of snake-charmers, and grows up to be called Mohan. Mohan is in love with Radha, and both plan to marry. But Radha's parents want to marry someone else. So Radha and Mohan decide to elope together. The villagers are angered at this, and question Mohan, who denies eloping with Radha. Mohan is asked to leave the village, and he goes toward Sundergarh, where he finds out that the Prince is his look-alike, and it was Vijay who had eloped with Radha. He approaches Radha, but Radha, who is now called Prem Pyari, refuses to recognize him, nor have anything to do with him. Mohan is heartbroken, severelly beaten and left for dead. He survives, and recovers, bent on avenging his humiliation at the hands of the cruel Radha and Vijay, and he will not let anyone come in his way.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?168360</url></doc>
