<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="169747">
  <docid>169747</docid>
  <title>El charango</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Goenka, Tula</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">9 February 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">25</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="USA">22</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Virga, Jim</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Goenka, Tula</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>The short Spanish language documentary El CHARANGO explores the relationship between the Bolivian stringed instrument, known as the charango, and Cerro Rico (Rich Mountain). Cerro Rico in Potosi, Bolivia is the richest silver deposit the world has ever known. It was discovered in 1545 by Spanish conquistadors, who enslaved the local indigenous people. They also imported African slaves to mine the silver. It is said that 8 million people died in the mines of this mountain while providing Spain with immense wealth. Potosi, by the way, is the highest city in the world at an elevation of 14,000 feet. The Spanish culture spread into Potosi during this time, and the local people became aware of something they had never seen or heard before: a stringed instrument. Forbidden from ever playing the Spanish guitar, the miners copied it and created the charango. Even today, nearly 150 years after the end of Spanish rule, the charango ! continues to be a companion to many in Potosi, miners or not. Although the documentary primarily focuses on the charango it is not a historical piece. The story of the charango symbolizes the larger struggle for human rights and a quest to keep traditional culture alive among indigenous people, and the people of Potosi in particular. It is a story of the fight for survival of the human spirit on this earth and the struggle of indigenous people for their rightful place in modern day society. El Charango introduces viewers to several charango players including the most renowned charango player in the world today, Ernesto Cavour Ayamaro. The film also journeys into the bowels of the mines of Cerro Rico as it observes what lies beneath.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?169747</url></doc>
