<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="173373">
  <docid>173373</docid>
  <title>El rey de los huevones</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Fillios, Danielle</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
  </languages>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Peru">1 March 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Chile">31 August 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Quercia, Boris</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Darriba, Mailo</producer>
    <producer>Asensio, Miguel (II)</producer>
    <producer>Izquierdo, Diego</producer>
    <producer>Izquierdo, Diego</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Riveiro, Manuel</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Acosta, Tamara</actor>
      <role>Sandra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Belloni, Ernesto</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Goldi, César</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hurtado, Diego (II)</actor>
      <role>Adrián</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jibaja, Angie</actor>
      <role>Eva</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Piñango, Rhandy</actor>
      <role>Mario</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Quercia, Boris</actor>
      <role>Anselmo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vilches, Daniel</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Anselmo works as a taxi driver at the international airport in Santiago, Chile. He is a decent man with good intentions who earned the nickname "The King of Fools" when he returned a very large sum of money that a passenger left in his car to the police. He is secretly in love with Sandra, the girlfriend of his best friend and neighbor,Mario. Anselmo has never attempted, out of respect for his friend, any kind of affectionate behavior toward Sandra. All of their lives become turned upside-down when Eva, Anselmo's beautiful passenger, convinces him to take care of her four-year-old son. Seduced by the gorgeous woman, Anselmo agrees to it without realizing the mess into which he is getting himself. The child turns out to be a kleptomaniac and involves Anselmo in all sorts of trouble. Sandra takes pity on Anselmo and helps him take care of the child. The closeness between the two provokes the attraction they both feel for one another to surface, causing them anguish and confusion. When Eva arrives to retrieve her son, she involves Anselmo in some sketchy business. Anselmo tries to flee, but he does not want to abandon the child with whom he has begun a mutual caring relationship. On the other hand, his relationship with Sandra begins to get out of hand and even more irresistible. Anselmo is constantly tempted to change the way he is, to leave his honor at his side in order to make the most of the opportunities that present themselves to him, as much in his love life as in his physical well-being. Nevertheless, and to his dismay, he will continue to bear the throne of "The King of Fools" until the end of the film.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?173373</url></doc>
