<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="174721">
  <docid>174721</docid>
  <title>Elan</title>
  <year>1947</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kadri, Shamsudin</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Urdu</language>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">1947</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">133</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Khan, Mehboob (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Naushad (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Himalaywala</actor>
      <role>Sajjad Haque</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mishra, Leela</actor>
      <role>Javed's mom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nawaz, Shah (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Reehan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Surendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Javed</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>After the passing away of his dad, Javed lives a poor lifestyle with his widowed mom in India. Since they cannot afford to live independently, they live with his mom's younger sister, Mrs. Haque, who lives a wealthy lifestyle with her husband and son, Sajjad. Mrs. Haque is very cruel toward her sister, compelling her to leave and bring Javed up on her own. Years later Javed has grown up, has acquired a sound education, returns home, to find that his mom is learning to read and write with the help of a beautiful young woman, Nazparvar, and soon both the youngsters fall in love with each other. Javed's mom approaches Nazparvar's dad to get them married, but at the same time her sister, who is now widowed, convinces Nazparvar's dad that Sajjad would be a better choice for his daughter, as a result the marriage takes place leaving both Javed and Nazparvar heartbroken, and they go separate ways. Years later they will meet again - this time Javed will be a lawyer - while Nazparvar, who is now a mother of a young son, Riaz, will be accused of killing her husband!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?174721</url></doc>
