<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="175678">
  <docid>175678</docid>
  <title>Elli and the Astronaut</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Camilleri, Alex (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">17</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Camilleri, Alex (II)</director>
    <director>Denega, Mark</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Balooja, Shashi</producer>
    <producer>Almodovar, Mike</producer>
    <producer>Camilleri, Alex (II)</producer>
    <producer>Denega, Mark</producer>
    <producer>Genova, Vincent</producer>
    <producer>Tapias, Indira</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Camilleri, Alex (II)</writer>
    <writer>Denega, Mark</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Camilleri, Chris</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Flory, Louise</actor>
      <role>Elli</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Schueller, Mishi</actor>
      <role>Jonah</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"Elli and the Astronaut" is a short film about a married couple who struggle to overcome the greatest possible distance that can separate two people. Elli, a beautiful but sad woman, begins to look in unexpected places in search of her absent husband, Jonah, a courageous space explorer whose ship is far beyond the barrier of radio communication. As Elli's obsessive search escalates, she begins to lose touch with the tangible world in favor of a reality she can only share with her lost husband. Throughout the film, Elli and Jonah both attempt to dream themselves into the same world. Yet as the film progresses, the audience begins to understand a darker truth about the nature of Elli and Jonah's shared dreamscape. Are they really joining one another at these spiritual meeting points? Or is one of these characters forcibly inducing these visions in order to cope with their loneliness. Ultimately, "Elli and the Astronaut" allows the viewer to complete the story based upon his or her own beliefs about the power of love and the power of illusions.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?175678</url></doc>
