<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="175612">
  <docid>175612</docid>
  <title>Elle fait fondre la glace</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Braun, Deborah (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>French</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby SR</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="France">-12</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="France">24 January 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="France">10</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Padova, Ron</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Padova, Ron</producer>
    <producer>de Lajarte, Séverin</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Padova, Ron</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Padova, Ron</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>St. Petersburg. Winter twilight in the Summer Garden. A man in black-- the letters P, O, E, T printed in white on his back-- sees the statue of a Muse come to life... and starts to follow her into the night, reciting the poem she inspires. Simultaneously, some expressions show up on the sheet of snow covering the city: a pattern of dead leaves, calligraphy by an invisible hand, the "A" of an electric light tube set ablaze by a tongue of fire.... But the magic powers of this mysterious beauty, Anastasia ("Resurrection"), work more directly: she switches on the street-lamps by snapping her fingers; the church bells ring with her laughter; crying, she brings rain.... Vasilevsky Island, across from the Hermitage, violins trembling under the starless sky. Striding along the Neva, the heroine is undressed-- like a butterfly emerging from a cocoon-- provoking an eclipse of the rising sun. Whose bleeding reflection on the frozen river pours out "LAVA" : a huge inscription turning from red to yellow. Next to his Muse changed into a living flame, the poet melts into an ink stain... before the thaw carries everything away.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?175612</url></doc>
