<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="176194">
  <docid>176194</docid>
  <title>Em Teu Nome</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Papel, Marcio</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Brazil</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">September 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">100</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Nascimento, Paulo</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Rodrigues, Beto</producer>
    <producer>Chemale, Homero</producer>
    <producer>Costa, Marilaine</producer>
    <producer>Nascimento, Paulo</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Nascimento, Paulo</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Muller, Renato</composer>
    <composer>Trento, Andre</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Buarque, Sílvia</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Feldens, Julia</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Machado, Leonardo</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Troncoso, César</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In the early seventies, Latin America was going through a period dominated by military dictatorships. In Brazil, the regime was at its peak. Society got organized and resisted in a number of ways. Some political groups chose armed resistance to fight the regime. From this context, In Your Name... tells the story of Boni, a humble architecture student who joins armed resistance, but has his own doubts and fears about it. Boni fears for his family, his girlfriend and the future, which grows uncertain day by day. Like many others, Boni is arrested, tortured and banned from the country in the exchange for the Swiss ambassador amongst the so-called Grupo Dos 70. At his Chilean exile, with his wife Cecilia he starts to work and get to know the Chilean people. This experience makes him start looking at the world in a more open, humane way. The military coup overthrows Allende and changes life all over again. With Cecilia and their son Boni flees to Algeria and later to Paris, where he is elected President of the Comitê Brasileiro da Luta pela Anistia (Brazilian Committee of the Fight for Amnesty). He returns to Brazil nine years after being banned.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?176194</url></doc>
