<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="176584">
  <docid>176584</docid>
  <title>Emma Blue</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kalogeropoulos, Yannis</editor>
    <editor>Pan, Kant</editor>
    <editor>Vasilopoulou, Georgina</editor>
    <editor>Webster, Ion</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>devil</keyword>
    <keyword>adultery</keyword>
    <keyword>sex-comedy</keyword>
    <keyword>light-romance</keyword>
    <keyword>seduction</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Greece</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="France">15 March 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>MacLean, Robert (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ashby, Paul (II)</producer>
    <producer>Papadopoulos, Sophie</producer>
    <producer>Koutsomitis, Yiannis</producer>
    <producer>Spentzos, Alex</producer>
    <producer>Kiourti, Ioanna</producer>
    <producer>MacLean, Robert (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>MacLean, Robert (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Strofalis, Marios</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arfani, Lenika</actor>
      <role>Woman in shorts</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Argyros, Lambros</actor>
      <role>Second bodyguard</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Artemiou, Ioanna</actor>
      <role>Second woman kissed in bar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Atsimovits, Nina</actor>
      <role>Third woman kissed in bar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Botsford, Eileen</actor>
      <role>First woman kissed in bar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Burk, Anthony</actor>
      <role>First Cop</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fraghias, Tassos</actor>
      <role>Tough Cop</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ioannou, Stergios</actor>
      <role>Boombam</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kamilaki, Myrto</actor>
      <role>Fat Blue Girl</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lakhmaniuk, Roman</actor>
      <role>First bodyguard</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Madee, David</actor>
      <role>Inspector Akros</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mandylor, Costas</actor>
      <role>Del</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mirou, Despina</actor>
      <role>Blue Girl</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Norman, Zack (I)</actor>
      <role>Victor Vronski</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rokakis, Anthony</actor>
      <role>Shocked waiter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rose, Peter (V)</actor>
      <role>Maitre d'hotel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Skinner, Duncan</actor>
      <role>Erik Schumacher</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Staikos, John E.</actor>
      <role>Proctologist</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Del, the Devil, is flying happily in the sky when suddenly he spots- Emma Shumacher, a middle-aged woman, good looking, wealthy, living in a beautiful house by the sea, but lonely. She has no children and her husband Eric, a lawyer and business man, to whom she is utterly attached, neglects her thoroughly by fooling around with young girls. But life has a secret plan for her. One day while lying next to the sea with a sexy photograph of an ad on her lap, in a dreamy mood, desperate in her misery, she experiences an enlightening moment! The visit of a man, who appears suddenly swimming towards her from nowhere makes her feel that for the first time in her life some secret wish of hers has come true. This same man appeared to her in a dream! Did she call him? She is stunned, but decides to welcome this turn of fate. Darcy Delane ("call me Del"), the mysterious visitor, has supernatural qualities. Who is he? She invites him to dine with her, obviously enchanted by him, and when her husband appears strange things start happening. The married couple enter their real crisis period after Del makes Eric confess his constant infidelity and the fact that their privileged life is over since Eric lost all his money to a crook named Victor. The next day Del declares to the husband that he is in love with his wife! Eric and Emma are both shocked, each for a different reason. In a moment of coquetry, and to make Eric jealous, she asks Del, who is an artist and an art dealer, to make a statue of her. At the same time Del offers Eric his help to get rid of the crook who is ruining his life. "Kill him!" is the plain solution. From now on we follow the crazy trip of Eric, bewitched by Del, trying repeatedly to kill Victor but without success. He doesn't have it. He is not "bad enough" as Victor tells him, to complete a task like that! Del promises to help him by "coaching"! Meanwhile Emma's statue is ready and in a moment of inspiration Del brings it alive! Eric is infatuated by the statue and takes it/her to his place-but because of his immense desire he is unable to perform the act with the very beautiful Blue Girl. He is impotent! Emma experiences perfect passion with Del, Eric experiences with Blue Girl and Victor total misery, and Del celebrates his success with Emma on cloud 9. But not for long. Emma, in a moment of awakening, hesitates, and longs for the real self that she has lost. Del, the amoral teaser of the world, feels defeated and angry, but in the end decides to bring Emma and Eric back together. He settles everything by offering the Blue Girl to Victor in exchange for Eric's business. Victor, meanwhile, gets greedy and wants more than Blue Girl from Del. But nobody can put the devil in a corner! So-</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?176584</url></doc>
