<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="176806">
  <docid>176806</docid>
  <title>Empire Earth</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>VideoGame</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>History</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>fictional-war</keyword>
    <keyword>video-game</keyword>
    <keyword>strategy</keyword>
    <keyword>raw-material</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="South Korea">All</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <producers>
    <producer>Robinson, Rich (V)</producer>
    <producer>Hsieh, James</producer>
    <producer>Payne, Jon (II)</producer>
    <producer>Perez, Ross</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Lima, Ed</composer>
    <composer>Maitland, Steve</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Doolin, Nikolle</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fielding, David J.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gottlieb, Jeremy</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Letendre, Ken</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mitchell, Frank (V)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Weeks, Doug</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In Empire Earth, you'll command history's best-known civilizations, such as those of the Greeks, English, French, and Germans, or evolve your own as you choose from more than 100 unique attributes. You'll colonize or conquer surrounding territories and establish new settlements; plan and build walled towns and city-states; and construct temples and hospitals to protect and enhance your growing empire. Your town centers inspire defenders to fight harder, and can be transformed into powerful capitals. Wood, coal, oil, and other natural resources provide raw materials for expansion. More than a dozen technology tracks offer numerous opportunities for further advancement. Train more than 200 types of combat units from every era in history, including the future on earth. Instantly improve the combat abilities of your troops with specific upgrades. Lead your armies to glorious victory with the help of Charlemagne, Churchill, and other great heroes from not only yesterday but also today and tomorrow. Fight in good weather during the day on an open plain, or carry out surprise assaults in the black of night or the dead of winter. Attack unsuspecting enemies with stealthy submarines and aircraft. Soften up an enemy position with artillery fire, carpet-bombing, or offshore shelling, or launch ballistic missiles. Wage epic sky battles with more than 30 types of aircraft, such as Sopwith Camels, Spitfires, F-15s, Apache gunships, and B-2 bombers. Fight massive naval engagements with more than 40 different ships, from 16th-century ships of the line to modern aircraft carriers. Board and capture enemy vessels. Train colossal and intelligent mechs to fight the battles of the future. In Empire Earth, the military option is just one possible path to victory. Surreptitiously convert an enemy's citizens with furtive priests. Instruct a prophet to invoke devastating calamities, such as volcanoes, earthquakes, and plagues. Pick away at opponents' populations by taking over their citizens. Construct wonders of the world that endow your civilization with special abilities while demonstrating its superiority.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?176806</url></doc>
