<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="178570">
  <docid>178570</docid>
  <title>Energy Crossroads: A Burning Need to Change Course</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Fauchere, Christophe</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>sustainability</keyword>
    <keyword>peak-oil</keyword>
    <keyword>renewable-energy</keyword>
    <keyword>oil-crisis</keyword>
    <keyword>biofuels</keyword>
    <keyword>wind-power</keyword>
    <keyword>energy-crisis</keyword>
    <keyword>climate-change</keyword>
    <keyword>global-warming</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">5 November 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">55</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Fauchere, Christophe</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Johnson, Joyce (VIII)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Fauchere, Christophe</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Most experts agree that global peak oil production, when demand exceeds supply, will occur within the next 15 years and will drastically change the very fabric of our industrialized world. As fossil fuels power every facet of the American economy, how can we avoid an energy crisis and a possible collapse of our economy? Today, China and India have aspirations to attain our western quality of life; but at the rate and the way we use the world's energy resources, their ambition will be physically impossible. In addition to increasing geopolitical conflicts, the process of extracting and using these crucial resources is endangering the very own habitat that we depend on to prosper as a species - pushing the earth's climate and ecosystem to a point of no-return. It is clear that in order for us to survive our modern self-destructive societies, we will have to change course drastically and as fast as possible. Scientists and experts agree that the use of renewable energy such as solar and wind power, coupled with higher efficiency and conservation, will be key factors in preserving our quality of life and paving the way to a sustainable world for our children. Will America be up to the task as it consumes 25% of the world's energy, 85% of which comes from non-renewable fossil fuels?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?178570</url></doc>
