<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="183271">
  <docid>183271</docid>
  <title>Eugene Walter: Last of the Bohemians</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Clem, Robert (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Biography</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>expatriate</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>gay-interest</keyword>
    <keyword>fellini</keyword>
    <keyword>cookbook</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">29 October 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">70</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Clem, Robert (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Wier, Tommy</producer>
    <producer>Clem, Robert (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Stark, Donald</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Clark, Katherine (V)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Walter, Eugene (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Alabama-born Eugene Walter lived a magical life, reportedly running away from home at age three, living in the back room of a bookshop at ten, painting coffins in rural Mississippi while in the Civilian Conservation Corps in the late 1930s and serving as a cryptographer in the Aleutian Islands during World War II. That was before he took an ice cream freighter to France in the late 40s, met and worked with the American born princess who published the world famous literary journal Botteghe Oscure, helped found the Paris Review and acted in the films of Federico Fellini while translating most of the latter's screenplays into English. Along the way he won the Lippincott Prize for first novelists, a Sewanee Review Fellowship in poetry, and became the epicenter of the expatriate community in Rome, where his parties were legendary. Not bad for someone who barely graduated high school and never had a bank account. Eugene Walter was truly an original, a man who made up each day as it came, one of the last of the true Bohemians.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?183271</url></doc>
