<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="184778">
  <docid>184778</docid>
  <title>Evil Things</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Perez, Dominic</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">13 March 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">94</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Perez, Dominic</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Perez, Dominic</producer>
    <producer>Valdez-Steckler, Mario</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Perez, Dominic</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cadden, Gail</actor>
      <role>Aunt Gail</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Casillo, Laurel</actor>
      <role>Cassy Crawford</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hooper, Morgan</actor>
      <role>Mark Schaefer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maslyn, Ryan</actor>
      <role>Leo Pugliese</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Matcharashvili, Zurab</actor>
      <role>Filmaker</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mersdorf, Elyssa</actor>
      <role>Miriam Dearing</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Weiss, Torrey</actor>
      <role>Tanya Kochen</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>It's Miriam's 21st Birthday. As a birthday gift, Miriam's aunt Gail has decided to lend Miriam her beautiful country house for an entire weekend. Aunt Gail's country house is amazing. It's a four bedroom house surrounded by breathtaking mountains and miles and miles of woods. Miriam invites her young college friends Cassy, Mark, Tanya and Leo to join her at the country house for what looks to be the most amazing weekend ever. Of course they all jump at the chance to spend a free weekend in the country, in the middle of nowhere. Miriam's friends are totally in the mood for a big time party weekend. They're also anxious to escape the dark and gloomy concrete jungle known as Manhattan. Miriam, Cassy and Tanya bring the food. Mark brings the beer and Leo, the aspiring filmmaker, brings his new video camera. Leo hopes to produce a short movie by documenting every amazing moment of this weekend getaway. Unfortunately, what Leo ends up capturing on camera is not a weekend of peace and tranquility, but a nightmarish descent into pure terror.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?184778</url></doc>
