<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="184835">
  <docid>184835</docid>
  <title>Evita: The Documentary</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Montes Bradley, Eduardo</editor>
    <editor>Serra, Emiliano</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Argentina</country>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">6 April 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">64</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Montes Bradley, Eduardo</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Liendo, Soledad</producer>
    <producer>Montes Bradley, Eduardo</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Montes Bradley, Eduardo</writer>
    <writer>Montes-Bradley, Nelson</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Long after Evita was embalmed and secretly buried under a fictitious name in Milan, the former First Lady of Argentina once again was catapulted to fame after Andrew Lloyd Webber's stage musical. A few years later, Alan Parker's movie adaptation of the same would contribute the necessary ingredients to transform a historical character into a Hollywood fantasy of mythical proportions. But the complexity of the circumstances surrounding her life, her quest for glory and tragic ending deserved a more realistic approach and that is exactly what Eduardo Montes-Bradley accomplished with his outstanding portrait of the legendary woman. "Evita", the documentary, unveils the genuine and ambiguous nature of the young actress that ruled -with iron fist- the lives of millions. More than three thousand photographs, hundreds of hours of archival footage and recordings produced by the Peronist propaganda machine half a century ago, were unearthed and meticulously researched to bring this dynamic, larger-than-life protagonist back to life. "Evita", spares no conflict, nor softens the sharp edges of a questionable life placing the unfeigned character back in her real dimension.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?184835</url></doc>
