<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="186044">
  <docid>186044</docid>
  <title>Extra: In the Background of a Dream</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Olwage, Nena</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Italy">16 May 2002</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">17 October 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">51</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Straus, Topher</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Abbott, Michael W.</producer>
    <producer>Cooper, Jon (I)</producer>
    <producer>Atkinson, Kate (IV)</producer>
    <producer>Straus, Topher</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Johnston, Bobby (II)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bates, Catfish</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bates, Helen</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Collins, Emmy</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Duncan, Angus</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dunn, Shannon</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Joy, Carl</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Millkie, Ron</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Schweiger, Daniel</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wilfley, Grant</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In the world of Hollywood and celebrities, known mostly for its glamorous lifestyles and big dreamers, there exists a segregated underworld, a subculture where dreams are rarely realized and whose contributions go unappreciated. EXTRA: In the Background of a Dream offers the first true glimpse of the most common Hollywood experience, documenting the plight of movie ?extras?, or as they?re known in the business, ?background artists?. Through numerous hours of interviewing and observing on sets, including Little Nicki, 13 Days, The Beach Boys (TV), V.I.P. (TV), and a national commercial, EXTRA: In the Background of a Dream is a raw examination of the extra?s world of hope and disillusionment. Taking a behind-the-scenes look at two families immersed in ?background? life, EXTRA: In the Background of a Dream focuses on: Catfish Bates, a responsible, proud extra supported and respected by his loving wife Helen. Eking a living off an extra?s meager pay, Catfish and Helen is a story of a couple united in their commitment to each other and chasing the Hollywood dream. Patty Reed and her two daughters exist on a combined income of $6,000 a year and are haunted by dreams of Hollywood. Fourth-generation extras, the Reeds dream of stardom, but are split by their motivations for persevering against overwhelming odds to succeed. EXTRA: In the Background of a Dream is filled with one-of-a-kind characters filled with dreams of fame and fortune, all struggling for work, recognition, and burdened with the stark realities of an unforgiving industry. Documenting lives facing extreme adversity, EXTRA takes the audience through heartache, laughter, disappointments, and success? with an appreciation for the people audiences see, but never notice.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?186044</url></doc>
