<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="186212">
  <docid>186212</docid>
  <title>Extreme Ghostbusters: The Ultimate Invasion</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>VideoGame</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">E</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">March 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <writers>
    <writer>Aykroyd, Dan</writer>
    <writer>Ramis, Harold</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Highly paranormal activities have just been detected in New York City. Professor Whitman at the City Museum has alerted the Extreme Ghostbusters of these most disturbing phenomena. However, before they leave, Janine takes a rather strange phone call telling them to meet in a narrow alley. They quickly discover that the meeting is a trap! Mirror Demon, an evil ghost, has kidnapped and cast a spell on Janine. The Extreme Ghostbusters must act fast to save their friend and find out who is behind this latest threat. Each character has their own features and can be selected at any time. In over 21 missions with 7 different levels, find special weapons ranging from the laser pistol to the laser lasso as well as secondary equipment. Challenge and deal with original ghosts and spectres with various skills as you progress. Top their ingeniousness to put an end to the chaos. The game offers different bosses, several difficulty settings, 4 playable characters (Eduardo, Garett, Roland and Kylie) with different characteristics and training levels as well as a multi-player mode. This game is also compatible with light-guns.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?186212</url></doc>
