<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="186589">
  <docid>186589</docid>
  <title>Eye on the Guy: Alan B Stone &amp; the Age of Beefcake</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>photographer</keyword>
    <keyword>bare-chested-male</keyword>
    <keyword>beefcake</keyword>
    <keyword>gay-interest</keyword>
    <keyword>homosexual-history</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Brazil">12 November 2006</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">7 June 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">48</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Monette, Jean-François (I)</director>
  </directors>
<plot>A documentary about pioneer photographer of male "beefcakes" Alan B. Stone, the film tells about his life, times and achievements in a short, but comprehensive film. This is shown through vintage footage, old pictures, and varied interviews, revealing a quiet photographer and businessman, suffering from excruciatingly painfully arthritis since his late teenage years, who became his time's master of homo-erotic photography, while remaining in many ways a common suburban dweller. Though he did love in the suburbs, he was in love with his city of Montreal, perhaps his third biggest love after photography and his male models. This is explored through old pictures, and many samples of his work. He quietly revolted against the moral conventions of post WWII Canada, exposing the beauty of thousands of body builders, fishermen, construction workers, cowboys, and the like, at a time when extreme discretion was required. His "muscle" magazines of the 50s and 60s gave way to the openly porn gay magazines which began to circulate in the late 60s, early 70s.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?186589</url></doc>
