<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="187449">
  <docid>187449</docid>
  <title>Facing Sudan</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>War</genre>
    <genre>History</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>darfur</keyword>
    <keyword>sudan</keyword>
    <keyword>genocide</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">31 March 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Janu, Bruce David</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Janu, Bruce David</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Clarke, Lorne</composer>
    <composer>Flannery, Tom (II)</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Brian Burns is a seemingly ordinary person. When we meet him, he is sweeping the floors in a suburban high school. But looks can be deceiving. Brian has a story to tell. It is a story of suffering. It is a story of death. It is a story of refugees running for cover at the ominous sound of a plane engine. But it is also the story of strength, courage and hope. It is the story of Sudan. Told through the eyes of ordinary people, living seemingly ordinary lives, Facing Sudan is truly about the Sudanese people struggling to survive. It is the story of the countless thousands who live day to day in refugee camps. It is the story of the world's reaction to the atrocities and violence in that war-torn African nation. The film demonstrates that seemingly ordinary individuals can do extraordinary things. A custodian. A housewife. A pediatrician. A grandmother. Seemingly ordinary individuals. Yet these individuals have a story to tell. It is the story of Sudan and what it takes to make a difference there.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?187449</url></doc>
