<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="188227">
  <docid>188227</docid>
  <title>Fallen Dreams</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Samray, Daniel</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">27 December 2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">80</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Samray, Daniel</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Samray, Daniel</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Samray, Daniel</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Blu Peter and Freedom of Sound</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Beed, Coral</actor>
      <role>Alice</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cilenti, Enzo</actor>
      <role>Arthur</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Elliot, Oliver</actor>
      <role>Trevor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gold, Richard (I)</actor>
      <role>Ian</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gregory, Leo (I)</actor>
      <role>Rob</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sparrows, Walter</actor>
      <role>Tramp</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A seemingly close group of friends living in a big private building find out they have less than twenty four hours to vacate the property. Not having anywhere to go they start to question the value of their meaningless existence. Karen is seven months pregnant. Her boyfriend, Ian, is currently out of work and is trying to get his life back in order before their baby is born. However, without a fixed abode he is finding it hard to find a job. Arthur is Ian's best friend who is having an affair with Karen. He thinks the baby she is carrying is his and not Ian's. Alice is going out with Trevor who is obsessed and addicted to sex with multiple partners and is turned on only by girls who are currently seeing someone else. Jim is an old man living in the basement of the property with a lot of hatred for the young guys living upstairs. In the tension of the last day, their relationships are tested to the limit when they're involved in a homicide forcing them to question what their friendship is based on.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?188227</url></doc>
