<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="188399">
  <docid>188399</docid>
  <title>False Colors</title>
  <year>1914</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">17 December 1914</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Smalley, Phillips</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Weber, Lois</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carr, Dixie</actor>
      <role>Dixie Phillips</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Farrington, Adele</actor>
      <role>Housekeeper</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Foote, Courtenay</actor>
      <role>Son of Butler and Housekeeper</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Marriott, Charles (I)</actor>
      <role>Butler</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Smalley, Phillips</actor>
      <role>Lloyd Phillips</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Standing, Herbert</actor>
      <role>Marc Herbert</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In 1895, noted actor Lloyd Phillips leaves the stage after his wife dies in childbirth. Blaming his infant daughter Dixie for his wife's death, Phillips leaves her with Mrs. Hughes, his housekeeper. Meanwhile, Mrs. Moore, a wardrobe mistress who has kept a scrapbook on Phillips, must raise her infant daughter Florence alone when her husband dies. Eighteen years later, Mrs. Hughes has squandered all of Phillips' money on her ne'er-do-well son Bert. Dixie then leaves and goes to New York where she receives a part in a Broadway play from Marc Herbert, her father's friend. When Phillips returns looking for Dixie, Mrs. Hughes and Bert convince Florence, Bert's new wife, to pose as Dixie. She soon is disgusted by the plot, however, and returns to her mother, with whom Dixie now lives. Meanwhile, Herbert innocently sends Phillips word of Dixie's success, but when he goes to see her, she bitterly rebukes him. Phillips again leaves, but eventually he and Florence realize their feelings for each other and are able to marry after Bert dies in a burglary attempt. After Mrs. Moore's death, Dixie is reconciled to her father.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?188399</url></doc>
