<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="188752">
  <docid>188752</docid>
  <title>Family Court Crisis: Our Children at Risk</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">January 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">13</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Russell, Kathleen (III)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Russell, Kathleen (III)</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>This powerful political documentary exposes an untold story that the mainstream media has avoided for years - the systemic breakdown of America's family court system. This is a tragic and true story that viewers will struggle to believe. Not since the Catholic Church pedophile scandal has the United States seen this level of institutional collusion and corruption harming innocent American children. The fact that this sort of scandal is taking place in the American judicial system defies the imagination. The film lays out its horrific tale explaining how it happens. Interviews with parents whose lives have been ravaged by the system are interspersed with first-hand accounts of the atrocities from veteran attorneys, child abuse experts and others who make a living in the system. Divorce courts across America routinely remove children from parents who complain of domestic violence and/or child abuse and send the kids directly into the homes of their violent, neglectful, dangerously mentally ill, or abusive parents. Protective parents not only lose custody of the children they are trying to protect, but the court then forces them to pay hundreds of thousands of dollars in fees to therapists, special masters, evaluators, counselors and attorneys for their children. Many parents go bankrupt, making court appeals impossible. The family law 'machine' operates as Big Business, and a sophisticated cottage industry preys upon desperate parents and children who are trying to escape family violence. The film urges viewers to talk about the brewing family law crisis with lawmakers and others who can fix the broken system.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?188752</url></doc>
