<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="189431">
  <docid>189431</docid>
  <title>Fantasy</title>
  <year>1982</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Musical</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Reality-TV</genre>
    <genre>Game-Show</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">13 September 1982</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>de Moraes, Ron</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Heatter, Merrill</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Jet 88</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Armstrong, Bill (VI)</actor>
      <role>Announcer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gilbert, Johnny (I)</actor>
      <role>Announcer (May-October 1983)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Goldner, David</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lemmon, Chris</actor>
      <role>Remote Correspondent</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>MacRae, Meredith</actor>
      <role>Remote Correspondent</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Marshall, Peter (I)</actor>
      <role>Host</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Scarpelli, Glenn</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wopat, Tom</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"Fantasy" was all that the title implied: Ordinary people from all over the United States would write in to have their wishes granted on national television. Although some of the fantasies were downright fatuous (e.g. one man wanted to twist his ankles inward on national television), and some of the musical acts were equally silly and at times contrived (e.g. one group who called themselves the "Rhythm Rascals," who played old-timey music and purported they performed at Disneyland's Diamond Horseshoe Revue, was actually three groups who previously appeared on the program combined into one group), "Fantasy" was definitely at its best when it focused on human interest stories, such as reuniting long-lost family members or friends and helping those who could not afford basic family needs (e.g. one Chicago area teen's parents were financially unable to get him braces, and the "Fantasy" staff helped make that a reality). Despite the aforementioned goofiness of some of the contestants' wishes, "Fantasy" had a habit-forming "hook" about it, and this was definitely a series that could be enjoyed by the whole family (in today's climate of trashy daytime talk shows and soap operas, a wholesome show like "Fantasy" would most certainly be a welcome breath of fresh air). Unfortunately, NBC pitted the program against then red-hot "General Hospital" on ABC, and as a result "Fantasy" suffered anemic ratings; some NBC affiliates didn't even air the show, contributing to that problem. "Fantasy" left the air 13 months later on Friday, October 28, 1983.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?189431</url></doc>
