<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="189625">
  <docid>189625</docid>
  <title>Far Off Town Dunedin to Nashville</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Judge, Paul (II)</editor>
    <editor>Sutherland, Bridget</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>New Zealand</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">28 August 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="New Zealand">80</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Sutherland, Bridget</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Judge, Paul (II)</producer>
    <producer>Sutherland, Bridget</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Sutherland, Bridget</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Heavy Eights, The</composer>
    <composer>Kilgour, David</composer>
    <composer>Lambchop (II)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Elliott, Ramblin Jack</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Heavy Eights, The</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kilgour, David</actor>
      <role>Kilgour</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lamchop</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>'Far Off Town - Dunedin to Nashville' is a documentary about New Zealand underground rock legend David Kilgour and his journey from the small NZ town of Dunedin to Nashville to record with his friends in the alternative country band 'Lambchop'. Alongside the story of Kilgour recording his album with Lambchop the documentary captures a slice of Nashville during the time he spent there with particular emphasis on the independent music scene and cultural mood of the city. The film offers a window onto Kilgour's creative process and unique footage of Lambchop's world as David journey's from Kurt Wagner's basement, to the recording studio of maverick producer Mark Nevers, to the underworld haunts of the Nashville music scene. 'Far Off Town' provides a glimpse into the world of independent record making in Nashville while focusing on the creative process of song writing and recording, exploring the mood of the music through evocative and poetic imagery. The story culminates with a journey through the blue ridge mountains to the home of Kilgour's indie label - Merge Records in Chapel Hill.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?189625</url></doc>
