<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="189666">
  <docid>189666</docid>
  <title>Far on Foot</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Goldman, Jason (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">September 2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">22</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Smith, Stephanie R.M.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Mailand-Hansen, Nanna</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Leigh-Thinnes, Casey</writer>
    <writer>Smith, Stephanie R.M.</writer>
    <writer>Thinnes, Casey-Leigh</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Levin, Geoff</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>DeMasi, Kacee</actor>
      <role>Transient</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Horsey, Martin</actor>
      <role>Christopher Cartwright</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Far on Foot is a darkly humorous drama that follows Sophie Cartwright, a journalist who takes on the responsibility of a lifetime as she persuades her dying father, Christopher, to undergo a last hope, alternative cancer treatment abroad. Having just landed on U.S. soil, their strained relationship begins to surface as Christopher's suitcase fails to arrive at the baggage claim, marking the first of many unlucky and disastrous incidents as they endeavor to reach the clinic. Sophie's attempts at pacifying her father are met with irritation and scorn, but nothing will prepare them for the almost 'supernatural' fate that is about to hit them. After a doomed taxi ride and an overly superstitious Israeli driver who refuses to continue, the shocked couple are forced to continue their journey on foot, whilst sharing an uneasy truce. The surreal labyrinth of downtown L.A, provides the backdrop to an emotional voyage that will opens old wounds. As their odyssey begins to wear on them, prospects of finding the clinic become alarmingly grim as their alien surroundings turn on them. Unable to contain their long-hidden and irreconcilable grievances, the dispirited pair drop all pretense at civility. When their brutal argument is abruptly terminated by Christopher's sudden deteriorating health and palpable frailty, they are forced, for the first time in their relationship to confront their fears and vulnerabilities with unexpected consequences.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?189666</url></doc>
