<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="189755">
  <docid>189755</docid>
  <title>Fareb</title>
  <year>1996</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>remake</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">A</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <directors>
    <director>Bhatt, Vikram</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Pandit, Jatin (I)</composer>
    <composer>Pandit, Lalit</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deshpande, Makrand</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dhawan, Sunil</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gunaji, Milind</actor>
      <role>Inspector Indrajeet Saxena</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jaiswal, Divya</actor>
      <role>Neeta</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Faraaz</actor>
      <role>Dr. Rohit Varma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kunika</actor>
      <role>Prostitute</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lath, Ashok</actor>
      <role>Ashok</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pradhan, Vishwajeet</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Dr. Rohan Verma (Faraaz Khan) and his wife, Suman (Suman Ranganathan) re-locate into their own spacious bunglow, after Dr. Verma's appointment as a doctor. Within a few days of their taking up residence, their home is broken into, and a physical confrontation ensues, with the thief escaping. The police are summoned, and take a report. The attending Police Inspector, Indrajeet Saxena (Milind Gunaji) is very helpful, and the Vermas get very friendly, and often get together. Inspector Saxena also comes to the assistance of Suman, when she is wrongly charged with possession of drugs. But Inspector Indrajeet's friendiliness starts showing it's true colours when he reveals that he is physically attracted to Suman. He attempts to break up their marriage; a number of police complaints are filed against Dr. Verma; he is also charged with stealing his own vehicle; his house gets broken into; and eventually he is arrested and held behind bars. With Suman alone, who is protect her from the vile attentions of Inspector Saxena? The Police?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?189755</url></doc>
