<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="194451">
  <docid>194451</docid>
  <title>Films That Suck</title>
  <year>1999</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Baker, Marvin</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>nashville-tennessee</keyword>
    <keyword>europe</keyword>
    <keyword>rolling-stone-magazine</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby SR</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">83</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Baker, Marvin</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Gillis, Ann (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Baker, Marvin</writer>
    <writer>Fontaine, Douglas</writer>
    <writer>Gillis, Ann (II)</writer>
    <writer>Ridley, Read</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Stanton, Michael</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brown, B.J. (I)</actor>
      <role>Police Officer at Pool</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hart, J.D.</actor>
      <role>JD</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hoffmann, Gaby (II)</actor>
      <role>Rolling Stone Editor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Morris, Andy (II)</actor>
      <role>Andy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ormond, Tim</actor>
      <role>Bela Lugosi's Godson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ridely, Read</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ridley, James</actor>
      <role>Writer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ridley, Read</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wall, David (IX)</actor>
      <role>Executive Director of Line Dance</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Read Ridley's independent films acquired minor cult status in Europe. Intrigued, Rolling Stone Magazine Germany sends reporter Andy Morris to Nashville to do a cover story on Ridley and intends to break the indie film story before the mainstream media discovers him. In Nashville, Andy Morris discovers that Read Ridley is a hard man to track down. Nobody seems to know the guy or how to find him. Andy Morris rents some of Ridley's movies and is horrified to discover his movies in fact, suck, big time. What's worse, he finds himself completely unable to persuade anyone else that Ridley is a joke, including his editor who demands the story and will get it with or without his cooperation. Morris is being tortured from all sides. Ridley himself is plunged into his own particular hell as he makes the rounds to hustle up money to complete yet another awful movie. Through out the movie, we see select 60 second clips of some of Ridley's work, horrendous low budget fare like Doctor Beyondo Eats Lead, Bite Me, and his most recent work Free Admission Free Beer, the silent movie soon to become a big hit on campus. The film's message? Only in America could an independent broke-dick filmmaker with an overwhelming lack of talent actually get away with this crap and be successful. Apparently it's what you DO with that lack of talent that's important. Unfortunately, Andy Morris learns the hard way that in Hollywood business is a bigger word that show as Ridley's new movie 'Free Admission Free Beer' becomes an international box office smash.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?194451</url></doc>
