<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="195088">
  <docid>195088</docid>
  <title>Finding Rudolf Steiner</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>theosophy</keyword>
    <keyword>occult</keyword>
    <keyword>anthroposophy</keyword>
    <keyword>eurythmy</keyword>
    <keyword>rudolf-steiner</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">30 September 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">87</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Antonelli, David</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Antonelli, David</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chase, Bert</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kugler, Walter</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kühl, Johannes</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wilby, Nelson</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Finding Rudolf Steiner is a visually entrancing journey into the occult philosophy of clairvoyant Rudolf Steiner set against a background of modern moral and social decay. This film has been selected for the 2006 Calgary International Film Festival. The film presents fragments of interviews with leading international experts on Steiner's spiritual vision in counterpoint to archival footage and riveting visuals from the streets of Rio de Janeiro, Buenos Aires, and Detroit. Steiner died in 1925 and was one of the most profound and original thinkers of the twentieth century, known as much for his clairvoyant explorations into the true nature of man as he was for the creation of Waldorf Education and biodynamic farming. In a world increasingly dominated by technology, materialism, and the threat of a growing international police state, the individual is faced with many challenges. Finding Rudolf Steiner probes into the heart of a spiritually bereft world in which materialistic science and traditional religion are at odds, yet neither can come up with a solution to draw man out of his self-created chaos and push him forward. Contrasting rare footage of Eurythmy performances (a type of modern dance created by Steiner) with beautiful sequences from the streets of Detroit and Buenos Aires, and shocking footage from violent video games, this film washes over us in waves of contradictory imagery, allowing the viewer to make his or her own decisions as to where western society is going and how we might look inside ourselves to discover our own spiritual nature and limitless creative forces for personal and social rejuvenation.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?195088</url></doc>
