<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="195575">
  <docid>195575</docid>
  <title>Fire on the Mountain: Bald Knobbers as Heroes or Villains of the Ozarks Frontier?</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Blalack, Damon</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>History</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>ozark-mountains</keyword>
    <keyword>hanging</keyword>
    <keyword>mask</keyword>
    <keyword>vigilante</keyword>
    <keyword>missouri</keyword>
    <keyword>outlaw</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">22 April 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">29</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Blalack, Damon</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Albers, Ingrid</producer>
    <producer>Sheets, Vonda</producer>
    <producer>Swan, Rick (II)</producer>
    <producer>Blalack, Damon</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Barrett, Roland</composer>
    <composer>Squires, Gray</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Albers, Matt</actor>
      <role>Andrew Coggburn</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Copeland, Curtis</actor>
      <role>Nat Kinney</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Walker, Lee (XIV)</actor>
      <role>Bull Creek Dave Walker</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In 1880's Taney County Missouri a group of respectable men led by the giant Nat Kinney set out at night to instill justice to an outlaw-infested region of ineffective law protection. As peace saw return the group disbanded, successful in their motive. What happened then was a resulting unforeseen tragedy: Neighboring counties adopted the style of the former group, developing a fearsome disguise and violence in the name of their own self-righteous needs. The ensuing carnage made worldwide headlines, the history of which would be quickly buried by descendants of either side of the issue once the government took action. In an effort to restore this stranger-than-fiction epic to the annals of the history books it was purposefully omitted from, Fire on the Mountain investigates the non-racially motivated vigilantes' rise-and-fall, as told through the words of modern-day descendants of those involved, and separating the fact from the fictional account that is propagated today through the tourism of the Branson, MO entertainment attractions.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?195575</url></doc>
