<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="196001">
  <docid>196001</docid>
  <title>First Mission</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
    <language>English</language>
    <language>Dutch</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Argentina</country>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Conen, Boris Paval</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Van Doorn, Jose</producer>
    <producer>Cervi, Natacha</producer>
    <producer>van Gestel, Frans</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Jurgens, Barbara</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gernandt, Tygo</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rietman, Mark</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Marina was a skater but an error led to a fall, and a badly damaged knee put an instant end to her athletic career. However, with the same boundless energy and determination as she pursued her sport, she studies medicine and then goes off to Latin America, an idealistic young doctor. It is her first mission for Artsen zonder Grenzen (the Dutch Medecins sans Frontieres), and her expectations are high. Marina wants to make a difference, and she has the firm intention of making her first mission a success. The reality, however, is more complicated. When she arrives at her base - a dilapidated little hospital in the jungle - she immediately wants to get going, organize, operate as she pleases. But she wants too much, too soon. She discovers that good intentions sometimes do more harm than good. And that the difference between theory and practice can be very complex. Marina has to cope with rules she doesn't understand, leading to conflicts with colleagues, and with local remedies that are at variance with her (Western) medical ethics. She comes to know frustration, rage, fear, violence, pain and death, the theft of supplies, intimidation by a local rebel leader. However, above all Marina is confronted with her own powerlessness, the limits to what you can do both as a human being and an aid worker. Marina won't settle for that. Then when a special little boy (Oli) is seriously injured on top of that - and it may even be her fault - she starts to have serious self-doubts: am I fit for this work? At the lowest point in this crisis - her birthday, by the way - she throws herself into Barry's arms. However, his fear of commitment is written all over him. But to go back to the Netherlands is not an option; she has to save Oli's life, she has to work out who is stealing her medicines, she has to look after her sick PC, Thijs.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?196001</url></doc>
