<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="196281">
  <docid>196281</docid>
  <title>Fish in a Barrel</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>pike</keyword>
    <keyword>barrel</keyword>
    <keyword>fish</keyword>
    <keyword>indigo</keyword>
    <keyword>gambling</keyword>
    <keyword>michigan</keyword>
    <keyword>management</keyword>
    <keyword>dukes</keyword>
    <keyword>animal-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>lake</keyword>
    <keyword>hazard</keyword>
    <keyword>love</keyword>
    <keyword>newbauer</keyword>
    <keyword>manipulation</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <producers>
    <producer>Crayton II, Hulon E.</producer>
    <producer>Newbauer, Mark B.</producer>
    <producer>Newbauer, Beth</producer>
    <producer>Vogel, Dan (II)</producer>
    <producer>Hampton, Sanford</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Newbauer, Mark B.</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Alan Fiske, as a diversion to his recent plans for suicide, takes an interest in his "arch-enemy's" girlfriend, Summer, whose arrival in town for a surprise visit at Rick's family's lake cottage proves to be more than everyone bargained for. Alan and Rick engage in a game of high stakes poker and in a battle of the egos, Rick bets his father's yacht against Alan's bait shop paychecks and loses. Rick does not go quietly into that good night. His dad's threats to relinquish his car, privileges and, most importantly, his inheritance, force Rick to demand a re-match and, at Alan's decline, Rick offers to throw in his girlfriend, Summer, to sweeten the pot. Alan complies at a chance to win her heart. In order to avoid any chance of cheating, the boys settle on a fishing contest: To catch the legend of their lake, Mike the Pike, whose head has a not-so-handsome price on it from the town loon, Freddy Bannister. He is hell-bent on avenging a recent, very 'personal' loss at the jaws of Mike the Pike; a town legend notorious for leaving his prey running for shore.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?196281</url></doc>
