<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="196232">
  <docid>196232</docid>
  <title>Fish Fry</title>
  <year>1944</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>fish</keyword>
    <keyword>dentures</keyword>
    <keyword>cat</keyword>
    <keyword>pet-shop</keyword>
    <keyword>goldfish</keyword>
    <keyword>andy-panda</keyword>
    <keyword>cat-versus-fish</keyword>
    <keyword>kids-and-family</keyword>
    <keyword>pet-store</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Australia">G</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">19 June 1944</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">7</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Culhane, Shamus</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Lantz, Walter</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Hardaway, Ben</writer>
    <writer>Schaffer, Milt</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Calker, Darrell</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stander, Lionel</actor>
      <role>Cat</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tetley, Walter</actor>
      <role>Andy Panda</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Andy buys a goldfish from a pet store. As he's carrying it home, balanced on his head, a garbage-picking cat sees it and becomes obsessed. First, he tries a simple grab from the other side of a fence, but the fish first fights its way out of the cat's mouth, then bites the cat (twice, the second time with vicious looking dentures). The cat next pretends to be a desert explorer, dying of thirst. When Andy gives him some of the water from the bowl, but not the fish, the cat takes a more direct approach, ditching the disguise and strong-arming Andy. This sends Andy into a cement mixer, but the cat quickly falls, spilling the fish (along with an attached puddle) down the street and into a sewer. As the fish comes out the other end, the cat is waiting with a frying pan and barbecue. The fish slowly realizes it's hot, and leaps high into the air. By now, Andy is ready, and catches the fish in his bowl. They head back to the pet store, where Andy comes out with a very mean-looking dog, which sends the cat away, crashing into things.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?196232</url></doc>
