<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="196741">
  <docid>196741</docid>
  <title>Five to Life</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Nicholson, Zac (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">3 April 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">14</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Nicholson, Zac (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Nicholson, Zac (I)</producer>
    <producer>Mendoza, Kris</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Nicholson, Zac (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carlin, Eileen</actor>
      <role>Annette</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dauer, John</actor>
      <role>Ben Taylor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grant, Carson</actor>
      <role>Ed Stone</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McKeon, Robert</actor>
      <role>Steve Birmingham</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McMichael, Lucy</actor>
      <role>Judy Edwards</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Miller, Richard (VIII)</actor>
      <role>Dr. Jack Kaiser</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nicholson, Tom (I)</actor>
      <role>Man on Oxygen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wolpert, Bill</actor>
      <role>The Thinker</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Ben Taylor, a young man from a well-to-do background, arrives at Dr. Jack Kaiser's private practice early one morning. Early for his appointment, he is accosted by one of the creeps sitting with him in the waiting room. Steve Birmingham, a product of the society he is trying to leave, attempts to sell Ben a stock while sneering at the sick and elderly patients around them. When his name is called, Ben escapes the uncomfortable conversation and hastily makes his way into the inner corridors of the clinic and awaits the good doctor. Dr. Kaiser enters the examination room and is startled to see such a young patient in his midst. Since the law was passed legalizing assisted suicide, the doctor has grown accustomed to helping patience much older than the one he sees before him and tries to persuade the kid from following through with his decision to kill himself. Nevertheless, as the law states, Dr. Kaiser is unable to do anything but fulfill his patients' wishes, and so after a frustrating debate which starts to explain a little why Ben has ended up at the clinic, Dr. Kaiser finds himself staring down as a boy who is young enough to be his son, presses the red button and administers the toxins which will slowly do him in. As the light dims on Ben's world, we are taken out into the waiting room where Nurse Annette calls for the next patient on the list.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?196741</url></doc>
