<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="197956">
  <docid>197956</docid>
  <title>Flood Tide</title>
  <year>2010</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2010</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
<plot>An experimental narrative film about a journey down a river in the midst of ongoing economic and ecological collapse. The film tells the story of a group of friends who, driven by dreams, desperation, and a sense of adventure, decide to build a boat out of scrap materials. As they begin to build, more people gather at the river, assembling vessels out of trash. They set out down the river to make a new life, inspired and uncertain. The tale of these unlikely vessels and their crews is framed by the story of one friend who remains behind. He withdraws to a basement, lost in his work, crafting dystopian tableaux from a collection of relics and photographs. When package arrives containing artifacts from the boats- a colored glass bottle, a weathered piece of lace, a diary, an envelope of snapshots- each object contains a fragment of the narrative, revealing the pieces of two divergent but inextricably linked journeys. FLOOD TIDE is an eco-fairytale whose story is shaped by a real and often unpredictable journey down a strange and meandering river, a polluted estuary that is tidal and flows both ways. As the boats and the crews drift along changing landscapes, weather, engine trouble, incidental interactions and unforeseen adventures all contribute to the emerging story. The film was shot amid the Swimming Cities of Switchback Sea, a project dreamed up by the artist Swoon and built by an eclectic group of artists and performers. In the summer of 2008, the crew built and floated seven large, boat-sculptures down the Hudson River, putting on performances in towns along the way. While documenting the real life journey, FLOOD TIDE is an independent fictional feature film that uses the voyage as its centerpiece. The film is loosely structured around the journey and largely improvised by non-actors playing themselves with fictionalized trajectories. The primary cast includes the bands Dark Dark Dark and Fall Harbor, members of which were actual crew on the boats.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?197956</url></doc>
