<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="199132">
  <docid>199132</docid>
  <title>Foo Fighters: Hyde Park</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Wrench, Mark 'Reg'</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Australia">M</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Australia">4 December 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">80</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Wickham, Nick</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Patten, Emer</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grohl, David</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hawkins, Taylor (I)</actor>
      <role>Drummer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lemmy</actor>
      <role>Guest</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>May, Brian (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself - Guest</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mendel, Nate</actor>
      <role>Bassist</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shiflett, Chris</actor>
      <role>Guitar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Taylor, Roger (I)</actor>
      <role>Guest</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Recorded at Hyde Park in London, June 17th 2006, this 76 minute performance sees the Foo Fighters rock through some of their most popular material in front of a massive crowd, quoted in some media as nearly 100,000 people. At the time of this show, the band were touring in support of their excellent double album, In Your Honor. There have been a number of different members come and go in this band, however their current line-up has been the most stable. The musicians performing here include: Dave Grohl (vocals, guitar) Nate Mendel (bass) Taylor Hawkins (drums, vocals on Tie Your Mother Down) Chris Shiflett (guitar) There are a number of highlights that make this show worth seeing. After a blistering performance of Breakout, Dave welcomes Lemmy Kilmister (Motorhead) on stage for a rendition of Shake Your Blood, a song on which they collaborated for Dave's Probot project. It is fantastic to see the song performed live, almost as much as it is to see the glee on Dave's face as he shares the stage with his hero. Later, Brian May and Roger Taylor of Queen join the lads for a run through Tie Your Mother Down, featuring Taylor Hawkins on vocals.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?199132</url></doc>
