<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="199518">
  <docid>199518</docid>
  <title>Footprints</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Weeks, Victoria</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>nasa</keyword>
    <keyword>earth</keyword>
    <keyword>science-on-a-sphere</keyword>
    <keyword>sphere</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">29 January 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">16</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Louden, Sharon M.</director>
    <director>Starobin, Michael (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Starobin, Michael (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Gribou, Andre</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Foucheux, Rick</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The Earth is not flat. That's the conceptual spark for a new film created at the NASA Goddard Space Flight Center. Using an advanced media projection technology called Science On a Sphere developed by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), FOOTPRINTS is the first fully produced film of its kind. The movie presents advanced satellite data and other visual effects on a dramatic spherical screen, affording viewers a chance to experience planets and planetary science in a way that's more natural to their actual appearance. The Earth guest stars in a variety of guises, from depictions of the biosphere to planetary views of city lights at night to dramatic examinations about the science of hurricane formation. Other moons and planets make exciting cameos too, with special presentations of Mars and Earth's moon. What's more, the two agencies have announced that they're releasing this new production to a consortium of science museums that already have Spheres on display. In ten U.S. cities this fall FOOTPRINTS will join other supporting Spheres on public exhibition.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?199518</url></doc>
