<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="201613">
  <docid>201613</docid>
  <title>Four Weeks, Four Hours</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">24 June 2006</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Italy">12 September 2006</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">7 October 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="France">80</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="USA">76</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Van Hurkman, Alexis</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Van Hurkman, Alexis</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Van Hurkman, Alexis</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Beecher, Judi</actor>
      <role>Alexis</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Escamillo, Scott</actor>
      <role>Pilot</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lambert, Elizabeth (IV)</actor>
      <role>Susan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pierpoint, Eric</actor>
      <role>Larry</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"Four Weeks, Four Hours" tells the stories of two women, each stranded in the desert on opposite sides of the globe. A photographer on assignment (Kaylynn Raschke-Artistic License, Nash Bridges), is trapped across the border in a war-torn middle-eastern country when her plane crashes, killing the pilot (Scott Escamillo). Her will to survive is tested as she treks back across the border on her own, haunted by the memory of the pilot. Halfway around the world, a Malibu socialite (Judi Beecher-The Shield, Law and Order) is lost in the desert of the American southwest when her husband (Eric Pierpoint-Enterprise, Alien Nation) dies of a heart attack after a car breakdown. Impatient for help and clueless about the ordeal before her, she walks back to town in the blistering heat of the noon-day sun. Both women are pushed to the limits of their endurance and beyond - the photographer over four weeks, the wife within four hours - as each story simultaneously unfolds. Their every choice makes the difference between life and death.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?201613</url></doc>
