<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="202201">
  <docid>202201</docid>
  <title>Francine</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Freeman, Nathan Ross</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">PG-13</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">12 March 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">15</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Freeman, Nathan Ross</producer>
    <producer>Kinzer, LaMyra</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Freeman, Nathan Ross</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kinzer, LaMyra</actor>
      <role>Francine</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Jones, a middle aged professor, tries to commit suicide, by drug overdose, over a student, Francine, who set fire to and hung herself over her love for him. He fails in his suicide attempt. During his near death experience while being electric-paddled back to life a strange dressed Victorian man advises he must go to a house on the beach. He reaches the beach. The house and a Russian Olive tree are the only entities for miles. He is confronted by luring demonic women, cohorts of Francine, who try to kill him on the beach. But they are barred from entering the house by Geist, the spirit whom haunts it. Jones escapes into the house where Geist offers him asylum. But, now, he must survive Geist's haunts that connive to drive him insane. From this point he spends timeless seasons, surviving the relentless onslaught of the women on the beach lure him into diabolical traps and try the most violent ways to kill him and the torturous hauntings in the house by Geist. Jones not only survives Geist haunts, and retains a tad bit of sanity, he also defeats the three demonic women in a morbid showdown that sends their decomposed bodies to the bottom of the sea. But, Jones realizes his victories have not set him free. In fact now he is trapped at this beach house alone. And his sanity begins to deteriorate into dementia from this solitude confinement. His desperate plea for Geist to come back to set him free conjures not Geist nor the women. His victories and confinement have only offered him up to the burnt corpse Francine herself who approaches steaming and charred from the sea. Because Geist is gone Francine can now enter the house. Francine offers Jones an extraordinary deal for his sanity and freedom. A deal that demands he engage her in a ritual of morbidity that turns his hair completely white. When Jones returns to the university he finds the months he has spent away has only been 7 days. And the students on campus marvel at the head of whiter shade pale hair Jones solemnly bears.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?202201</url></doc>
