<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="202960">
  <docid>202960</docid>
  <title>Freak Show</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Parten, Craig</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 December 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Parten, Craig</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Parten, Craig</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Davidson, Paul (VIII)</composer>
    <composer>Erickson, James (II)</composer>
    <composer>Parten, Craig</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Amatulli, Joe</actor>
      <role>Paul</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Davidson, Paul (VIII)</actor>
      <role>Mr. Fantastic</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Erickson, James (II)</actor>
      <role>Bobby</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Guardino, James (II)</actor>
      <role>Tommy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Howe, Paul (I)</actor>
      <role>Pete</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hynes, Matt</actor>
      <role>Charlie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nawrocki, Chris</actor>
      <role>Steve</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Negron, Sam</actor>
      <role>Tony</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Parten, Craig</actor>
      <role>Kane</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Poccia, Cory</actor>
      <role>Billy</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>It's Bobby Ross's Last night of freedom, and his friends have decided to throw him a bachelor party he will never forget. but what they don't realize is that the entertainment is a group of crazed blood thirsty killers and the night takes a horrific turn for the worst. Led by Kane and his two disciples Sunshine and Mr. Fantastic, the boys are forced to enter into a diabolical game of Wheel of Fortune. Unlike the traditional game this wheel doesn't have prizes on every square. One by One Bobby and his friends face the wheel, and spin to see their fate. As the plot unfolds Bobby and his best friend Steve learn the motive behind the groups killing spree and must fight to survive the blood bath that they might be responsible for causing. The whole movie is like a day in the life of...., With a huge ensemble cast of wacky characters, most of the scenes take place in one house, with a huge cemetery finale. Freak Show is the second full length feature by Locked and Loaded Productions. Many of the L&amp;L veterans like ,Craig Parten, James Erickson, Cory Poccia, and Anne Marie Stefani have returned for the second film, they have also been joined by Newcomers Chris Nawrocki, Paul Davidson, Joe Amatulli , and several others.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?202960</url></doc>
