<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="203608">
  <docid>203608</docid>
  <title>Freight Train</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Hammond, Zachary (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">9 January 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Stronach, John</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Dusi, Mike</producer>
    <producer>Tarnol, Marvin</producer>
    <producer>Stronach, John</producer>
    <producer>Tarnol, Brent</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Tarnol, Brent</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Powell, Chris (VII)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Adell, Josh (I)</actor>
      <role>Dr. Hartunian</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ayers, Tom</actor>
      <role>Jack</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dusi, Mike</actor>
      <role>Nurse</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Levine, Jason (V)</actor>
      <role>Patient</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lewis, Chauntal</actor>
      <role>Donna Jo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mayeux, Rosalee</actor>
      <role>Harmony</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Palese, Joe</actor>
      <role>Joseph</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tarnol, Brent</actor>
      <role>Adam</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wall, J.J.</actor>
      <role>Dr. Katz</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The pressure of a father's strict belief set, can sometimes lead their children to make rash and irreversible decisions. Seventeen-year-old Donna Jo's father has always stressed the importance of celibacy until marriage. So much so that her primary feelings towards her father are embarrassment and resentment. After one of his many sermons on abstinence, Donna Jo and her boyfriend Adam, drunkenly decide to have sex. What happens next is an unexplainable and unfathomable series of events. Only ten minutes after they consummate their relationship, Donna Jo begins to feel noxious. Immediately after rushing her to the hospital, Adam realizes something is not right. When the doctor tells Adam that Donna Jo is pregnant, a million thoughts rush to his head. How could this happen? Was she unfaithful? What did he do to deserve this? Over the next few days, the young couple realizes that there are no logical answers. The birthing process is moving along at a frantic pace. Adam is faced with reality of becoming a father in only nine days. This character driven dark comedy shows the trials and tribulations of young love, overbearing parents, growing up at a "freight train's" pace.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?203608</url></doc>
