<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="204163">
  <docid>204163</docid>
  <title>Freudian Eyebrow</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Inbody, Scott</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby SR</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">February 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">80</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="USA">80</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Mouton, Dr. Stephen</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Farrell, Shea</producer>
    <producer>Mouton, Dr. Stephen</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Mouton, Dr. Stephen</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Marfisi, Dan</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Blair, Gregory</actor>
      <role>Phyno Zeit</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fanaberia, Daniel</actor>
      <role>Rob</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kim, Christina July</actor>
      <role>Flip-flop</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Marquand, Adrienne</actor>
      <role>Wendy 1</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maryott, Kirsten</actor>
      <role>Interviewer</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Trichotillimania, an impulse control disorder involving involuntary self-injury by pulling scalp hair, eyelashes and facial hair is discussed by Dr. Skinner with a blonde patient, followed by her interpretation of some mirrored ink blots. Students dissatisfied with their final grade agree to participate in a midnight psychology experiment in order to have a 'full grade boost.' The experiment is unexpectedly run by Board of Director's member of the Pharmaceutical corporation. Some subjects are given roles as 'Confederates' to fake their performance during the experiment. A date rape drug is believed to have been switched during the experiment as one of the subjects experiences weird visions and unusual behavior. Subjects are reconvened after the aborted experiment and given large cash payments in agreement for keeping silent about the night's events. The group is unsure about the rationale behind the large checks because only minor events had occurred during the midnight experiment. They agree to a pact to call each other if they figure out why they are being compensated. Rob discovers the 'true' reason for the money and they all agree to meet to discuss his findings, except for one participant who has invested her money and done many good things and prefers to remain 'blissfully happy' without knowing why she has received this blessing.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?204163</url></doc>
