<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="204887">
  <docid>204887</docid>
  <title>From Dust</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Chander, Nirmal</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>acupuncturist</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>United Arab Emirates</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="United Arab Emirates">13 December 2005</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Canada">4 May 2006</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">25 April 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">70</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Dhawan, Dhruv</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Dhawan, Dhruv</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kennedy, Emma (II)</composer>
    <composer>Richter, Michael (III)</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Filmed in Sri Lanka FROM DUST is a cinematic expose that takes an incisive look at a government's response to a natural disaster. Shot in the aftermath of the Asian tsunami this documentary brings us into close contact with three people and questions why survivors in Sri Lanka weren't allowed to rebuild their homes along Sri Lanka's coastline. This critically acclaimed film follows two survivors and an aid worker over the course of a year in Sri Lanka after the tsunami: Ravi is a young entrepreneur who lived near the coast in the city of Galle. He lost his father and sister in the tsunami and now has to support his remaining family. As he tries to rebuild his home, the Sri Lankan government declares a ban on building within 100 meters of the coastline. Ravi and his neighbors are promised new land on which to rebuild and from the confines of a tent, they begin to wait. Cyril saved his wife and child in the tsunami and now shelters them in a tent. He is a fisherman who lost his boat and now fishes from a wooden stilt wedged in the ocean. His home was within 100 meters of the ocean and he is told that he cannot rebuild but will be relocated to flats 10km away up in the hills. He tries to move on with life but contemplates the future. Cameron is an acupuncturist from Australia, who flew to Sri Lanka 2 weeks after the tsunami. Amidst treating people and trying to help them rebuild, he soon discovers that aid workers are also being prevented from rebuilding homes. Cameron begins to question the Sri Lankan government's response to this disaster and soon discovers the ulterior motives behind the 100 meter rule. Following a span of major natural disasters in 2005, this film reveals life in tents and ulterior motives that are stalling the rebuilding effort in Sri Lanka - revealing an untold story about a "100 meter rule" and the opportunities that arise in the wake of a natural disaster.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?204887</url></doc>
