<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="204931">
  <docid>204931</docid>
  <title>From Here to Infinity: The Ultimate Voyage</title>
  <year>1994</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>galaxy</keyword>
    <keyword>astronomy</keyword>
    <keyword>science</keyword>
    <keyword>space</keyword>
    <keyword>educational</keyword>
    <keyword>supernova</keyword>
    <keyword>kids-and-family</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">43</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Barrett, Don (IV)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Goodman, Robert H.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Barrett, Don (IV)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stewart, Patrick (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself (Narrator)</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>There are more stars in the sky than grains of sand in all the beaches and deserts of Earth. This documentary uses computer graphics and deep-space photographs to explore the 'macro' universe beyond planet Earth. Leaving Earth orbit, we pass by the outer planets Mars, Jupiter, Saturn, Neptune, and Pluto/Charon. We then pass through the Oort Cloud, reservoir of comets, which extends up to 2 light-years from the Sun. Our Sun's nearest stellar neighbors Proxima and Alpha Centauri are next, but there is probably no life there. After a discussion of SETI (Search for Extraterrestrial Intelligence), we head for the star Geminga. Now a rapidly-spinning pulsar, about 342,000 years B.C. it was a supernova 50 light years from Earth, visible in our day sky. In the constellation Orion, Betelgeuse may become a supernova soon. We see new stars being born in the Orion "star nursery" nebula. Moving on to the center of our galaxy, we enter a worm hole to the Andromeda Galaxy. Andromeda, along with our Milky Way, is a part of the Local Group of galaxies. There is evidence of a Great Attractor whose gravity is pulling on every galaxy within 200 million light-years. Among the galactic groups are enormous empty voids. Our voyage of the imagination ends at the Great Wall of Galaxies at 325 million light-years, the biggest thing in all the universe (so far).</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?204931</url></doc>
