<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="205044">
  <docid>205044</docid>
  <title>From River to Sea</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Hopper, David (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>los-angeles-california</keyword>
    <keyword>filmmaker</keyword>
    <keyword>jewish-girl</keyword>
    <keyword>motherhood</keyword>
    <keyword>self-discovery</keyword>
    <keyword>thirty-something</keyword>
    <keyword>family-history</keyword>
    <keyword>russia</keyword>
    <keyword>travel</keyword>
    <keyword>mother-daughter-relationship</keyword>
    <keyword>divorce</keyword>
    <keyword>slovakia</keyword>
    <keyword>family-relationships</keyword>
    <keyword>ukraine</keyword>
    <keyword>journey</keyword>
    <keyword>germany</keyword>
    <keyword>jewish</keyword>
    <keyword>jew</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">80</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Fink, Susan (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Fink, Susan (II)</producer>
    <producer>Machtus, Emerson</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Fink, Susan (II)</writer>
    <writer>Hopper, David (II)</writer>
    <writer>Machtus, Emerson</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Himmelman, Peter</composer>
    <composer>Rauelsson</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>"From River To Sea" is an emotional, heartfelt story about journeys, decisions and modern life - a story not unlike that of many women we know. As a small glimpse into the realities of what it means to be a mother in our times, we follow Susan Fink, a filmmaker, whose life after a devastating divorce is at a crossroads. She is 36, without a home of her own, and living with her daughter in her mother's one-bedroom apartment. Her spirit is broken and the relationships with her mother and daughter have been harmed by despair and neglect. While on a trip to Eastern Europe, attempting to film the realities of post-war Jewish life, she confronts her own demons and decides to repair the damage with her mother and daughter. She transforms the journey into one of discovery and fulfillment - seeking advice and learning about herself along the way. Shot on location in Slovakia, Russia, Germany, Ukraine, and Los Angeles, the film follows Susan, her mother, and her daughter on their travels. Using their shared Jewish tradition and her heart as a guide, Susan struggles to heal and reconnect the three generations - searching for a way to heal herself, and bring them all back together once again.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?205044</url></doc>
