<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="205254">
  <docid>205254</docid>
  <title>Front</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Chia, Noi Kheng</editor>
    <editor>Lee, Genevieve (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>News</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Singapore</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Singapore">19 June 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Singapore">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Goodenough, Gail</director>
    <director>Ong, Marcia</director>
    <director>Sivalingam, Esan</director>
    <director>Tan, Cheryl Anne Shi-An</director>
    <director>Tay, Bratina</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Tay, Bratina</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Chan, Jaclyn</writer>
    <writer>Seah, Chang Un</writer>
    <writer>Sivalingam, Esan</writer>
    <writer>Sivalingam, Sunita (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Big Bang &amp; Fuzz</composer>
    <composer>Electrico</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself (2006-2008)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Leong, Hossan</actor>
      <role>Himself (2007)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Phin</actor>
      <role>Himself (2006-2007)</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A program dedicated to the inner artiste and voyeur in all of us. FRONT explores the world of the Arts with a difference. Serious yet fun, informative yet entertaining; this is a show with attitude that is current and always has the pulse of the audience. Fronted by two fashionable, hip and in-the-know presenters, the stylized show is fast and frenzied, making the arts accessible with never a dull moment in between. Everything you ever wanted to know about arts and music, packaged in a half hour weekly, fresh and edgy magazine program, featuring lifestyles of the arts crowd, insights into the creative process, reviews on all genres in the arts field, coming attractions, a quick guide to what's happening and what's not, performances by local, regional and international acts, little known facts and trivia behind the scenes and retrospectives on world renowned Asian artistes. Each story and segment tackles a different angle on the very diverse arts field. The idea behind every story, profile and angle is to show the seldom seen face of the arts and artistes - to show the psyche behind their artistic panache, the decisions that led them to where they're at, what they (and their works) embody, to feature those that took the path less traveled with a unique mindset and drive. Eclectic. Engaging. Entertaining.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?205254</url></doc>
