<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="206264">
  <docid>206264</docid>
  <title>Fuga y misterio</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Mourino, Martin</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">GP</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">8 October 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">33</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Mourino, Martin</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Mourino, Martin</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Albertini, Jose</writer>
    <writer>Mourino, Martin</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Bromfman, Pedro</composer>
    <composer>Garcia, Gustavo (V)</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>RUNAWAY &amp; MYSTERY (Argentine Chronicles in the City of Los Angeles) For the last three decades, the US has been one of the main destinations chosen by people from all around the planet, seeking for a better life. When it comes to the West Coast, Los Angeles is the place that receives most of that immigration. People from different countries, with different cultures and backgrounds, land in Los Angeles, some searching for a dream, some running away from a ghost, some looking for experience, and the list goes on... RUNAWAY &amp; MYSTERY unfolds the experiences and the impressions of four people from Argentina that decided to live in Los Angeles, paying different prices. The same way their grandparents or great grandparents emigrated to Argentina a century ago, they came to Los Angeles looking for something that they might have or have not found. Homesickness, struggle, loneliness, family, legality, etc., are all topics that any immigrant can relate to, regardless the nationality. In a city that can be as much entertaining as hostile, these four people from South America tell about how high is the price to live in America, and if it is worth paying.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?206264</url></doc>
