<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="206839">
  <docid>206839</docid>
  <title>Funeral Leaving the President's House and Church at Canton, Ohio</title>
  <year>1901</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>News</genre>
  </genres>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Roosevelt, Theodore</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In this picture we show a most perfect view of the front entrance of the McKinley home in the background. The hearse which is to bear the President's body to its last resting place drives into view. The Admirals of the Navy and Generals of the Army form lines in the rear. President Roosevelt takes his place at the head of the Cabinet and immediately the body emerges from the front door, borne on the shoulders of the soldiers and sailors. As it passes through the lines of Diplomats, Admirals, and Generals, all heads are uncovered. The sailors and soldiers descend the steps slowly to the sidewalk and then the body is placed in the hearse. Here we secured another life size view. The hearse starts slowly away and President Roosevelt and his Cabinet walk toward their carriages. Then with the aid of our panoramic device we followed the hearse until it passed out of view down Market street. This scene dissolves into a picture of the body leaving the church at Canton, borne on the shoulders of the sailors and soldiers and placed again in the hearse. From the time the casket appears at the church door it does not pass out of the view of our camera until the doors of the hearse are closed upon it. We follow it constantly with our panoramic device, and the views are perfect and life size. The hearse finally starts away for the cemetery, followed by the famous Black Horse Cavalry, Troop A, of Ohio.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?206839</url></doc>
