<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="207058">
  <docid>207058</docid>
  <title>Fur</title>
  <year>1979</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Marzano, Joseph</editor>
  </editors>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Marzano, Joseph</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Marzano, Joseph</writer>
    <writer>Russo, Mike (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Drumheller, Elizabeth Ann</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fontana, Roseann</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Russo, Mike (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wade, Billy (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A mysterious antique store owner (Joe Marzano) sells an unusual fox furpiece to a young man in drag (Billy Wade). He goes to a telephone to describe the exciting purchase to his boyfriend (also Billy Wade), but in the phone booth he is attacked and killed by the evil Fur. Much later, a woman (Roseann Fontana) buys the Fur at a garage sale. Walking home past a foreboding cemetery, she is also left lifeless by the frightening Fur. A young man (Mike Russo) stumbles across her body, removes the Fur and takes it with him as he heads home to his wife (Elizabeth Ann Drumheller). A storm approaches, so he reaches to close a window. The window slams on his neck, and he dies instantly. The house goes dark when the storm causes an electrical problem. Unaware of her husband's death, the woman goes downstairs with a flashlight. The malevolent Fur springs to life and chases her through the house, attacking and killing her. Back at the old antique stop, the store owner displays a devilish smile as he examines the Fur.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?207058</url></doc>
