<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="208069">
  <docid>208069</docid>
  <title>G.I. Joe: Sgt. Savage and His Screaming Eagles</title>
  <year>1994</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>sergeant</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">22</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Rich, Dorie</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Freeman, Bonni</producer>
    <producer>Bacal, Joe</producer>
    <producer>Griffen, Tom</producer>
    <producer>Kettler, C.J.</producer>
    <producer>Hack, Michael</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Goldfine, Lloyd</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Katsaros, Doug</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barr, Kathleen (I)</actor>
      <role>Lady Jaye</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chalk, Gary</actor>
      <role>General Blitz</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chapman, Brent</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Christopher, Julian</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Donovan, Michael (III)</actor>
      <role>Sgt. Savage</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kaye, David (I)</actor>
      <role>General Hawk</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McNeil, Scott (I)</actor>
      <role>Cobra Commander</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>O'Smith, Robert</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In 1944, Master Sergeant Robert Steven Savage lead a squad of men into Berlin. He was betrayed by one of his fellow soldiers, Krieger, a double-agent for the Axis Powers. Krieger had Savage's entire squad killed and used Savage-himself as a guinea pig for various genetic experiments. Savage was then cryogenically frozen and sealed inside a secret bunker. 50 years later, G.I. Joe discovered the hidden bunker and, thanks to efforts from Doc, successfully thawed Savage out. Thanks to Krieger's genetic experimentation, Savage now has super-human strength, speed and agility. However, his powers are unstable and fluctuate violently. General Hawk leaves Savage in charge of a group of talented but irresponsible sergeants facing court martial and quickly whips them into shape. They dub themselves "the Screaming Eagles". Krieger, now taking on the guise of General Blitz, leader of the terrorist organization, the IRON Army, plots to attack a space platform and steal a NASA rocket with a satellite inside which will give him control over the world's computers. Sgt. Savage and his Screaming Eagles learn of Krieger's plot and deploy for action.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?208069</url></doc>
