<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="208230">
  <docid>208230</docid>
  <title>Gaano kadalas ang minsan</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Filipino</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Philippines</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Philippines">17 June 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Tejada Jr., Gil</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Garbes-Severino, Des</writer>
    <writer>Michael Perez, Don</writer>
    <writer>Zialcita, Danny L.</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Agustin, Marvin</actor>
      <role>Dr. Louis Antonio 'Louie' Almeda</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Aliwalas, Victor</actor>
      <role>Dr. Thomas 'Tommy' Romero</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Andolong, Sandy</actor>
      <role>Gloria Cervantes</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Avelino, Paulo</actor>
      <role>Jared Luna</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Corcuera, Jesi</actor>
      <role>Raquel 'Rocky' Perdigon</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ortile, Bryan Spark</actor>
      <role>Alvin Medrano</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ramirez, Biboy</actor>
      <role>Rolando</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>dela Cruz, Maybelline</actor>
      <role>Chanda</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Gaano Kadalas ang Minsan is about the intertwined love and lives of Louie , Lily and Elsa. Elsa and Lily are best friends despite their social differences. Elsa's family owns the hospital where Lily and her boyfriend Louie work as a nurse and as a doctor respectively. Unknown to Lily, Elsa is secretly in love with Louie and will even plan a scheme to send the nurse away. Lily, who dreams of being wealthy, grabs the opportunity when she gets an offer to work abroad. But Louie opposes her decision and their misunderstanding leads to separation. Elsa then finds the chance she has been longing for-to get Louie's affection. Several months later, Lily returns to the country hoping she could be with the man she loves. But she will discover that her best friend and her boyfriend will get married soon, and she decides never to bother them again. But time and destiny seem to have their way of leading people back together. Several years later, Lily's child Alvin (Bryan Spark Ortile) will be diagnosed to have a fatal heart problem. The only thing that Alvin wishes is to meet his father, which Lily couldn't give until Elsa, who cannot bear a child, learns about her problem. Elsa then offers her former best friend an irresistible proposal: to lend her husband Louie to pose as Alvin's father. For the sake of her son, Lily gives in to the proposal. Louie, Lily and Alvin will be living in the same house. The former couple will pretend they are in love with each other especially when they are with Alvin. But will their make-believe relationship lead to something real? Will Elsa ever regret lending her husband to Lily? Who will Louie end up with: Elsa or Lily?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?208230</url></doc>
