<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="208823">
  <docid>208823</docid>
  <title>Galaxy Force 2</title>
  <year>1988</year>
  <type>VideoGame</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1988</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <composers>
    <composer>Walker, Martin (IV)</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>In this distant Galaxy exist many systems harboring life. Trade and communication have arisen between these star systems, as has a great, dark force threatening these distant civilizations. To fight this dark menace the Space Federation was formed, but has met with little success. The enemy calls itself The Fourth Empire and has now attacked Junos, jewel of the Galaxy. The Junos star system, once so beautiful is only ashes now. And on these ashes The Fourth Empire is building the strongest fortress of all time, from which to complete their conquest of the galaxy. The Space Federation must end this evil menace! Thus is launched Galaxy Force, to strike a hammer blow against the forces threatening civilization. Fortunately, having done this duty of saving Junos people and destroying The Fourth Empire, a combatant of Galaxy Force returned to the ship. The Junos star system comprises of five planets, the jewel of the Galaxy is Junos, with Velteor, Malkland, Orthea, and Ashutar. You must fight The Fourth Empire through five levels, traveling through space, over land and sea, through caverns and ultimately destroying the fortress at the end of each level. You will come across many different life forms, as well as the more conventional fighter craft. But their aim is the same; to destroy You. Lock-on to the enemy and destroy them with the use of your missiles or laser gun. The sixth mission is on the way to The Fourth Empire's fortress. You travel through never ending tunnels, through construction sites, and ultimately to the fortress itself. Destroy this with everything you have.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?208823</url></doc>
