<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="208967">
  <docid>208967</docid>
  <title>Galle Road: The Volunteer Diaries</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Maslennikov, Vasily</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>German</language>
    <language>Russian</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Sweden</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Sweden">3 February 2006</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="France">26 November 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Russia">14 November 2006</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Georgia">7 December 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">93</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Kamionsky, Alexander</director>
    <director>Klebanov, Sam</director>
    <director>Maslennikov, Vasily</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kamionsky, Alexander</producer>
    <producer>Klebanov, Sam</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Kamionsky, Alexander</writer>
    <writer>Klebanov, Sam</writer>
    <writer>Maslennikov, Vasily</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Golovachev, Valentin</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>This documentary was never planned. Sam Klebanov and Alexander Kamionsky both came to Sri Lanka on vacation, landing in Colombo in the morning of December 26, 2004, just an hour before the tsunami hit the island's coastline. The devastation was enormous. Over 35,000 people were killed and around half a million lost their homes. In the aftermath of this catastrophe, thousands of people, who happened to be in this region, became instant volunteers. They were not professional relief workers but ordinary people from around the globe. Most of them were just tourists, while the others were Sri Lankans who wanted to help their fellow countrymen, permanent foreign residents of the island, or people who rushed there from all over the world to help the victims. These spontaneously organized groups became the major relief force in the affected areas. And long before the internationally established organisations took their first steps in the region, they had commenced operations without delay. Sam Klebanov and Alexander Kamionsky joined one of these groups (IMPAKT Aid), which provided water, food, medicine and other essential supplies for thousands of survivors on the South-West coast of Sri Lanka. And as film professionals they took care to constantly record their work using a small, non-obtrusive mini-DV camera. This documentary is based on the forty hours of footage that they shot during their many trips along the principal costal highway - GALLE ROAD. It consists of many different but interwoven stories - the stories of people who made a difference.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?208967</url></doc>
