<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="209298">
  <docid>209298</docid>
  <title>Games Without Frontiers</title>
  <year>2012</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>irish-republican-army</keyword>
    <keyword>terrorism</keyword>
    <keyword>ireland</keyword>
    <keyword>irish</keyword>
    <keyword>suspense</keyword>
    <keyword>troubles</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">12 June 2012</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Knappe, David G.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Knappe, David G.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Knappe, David G.</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mulcahy, Jack (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>As the son of an assassinated IRA leader, Brian O'Donnell has long cherished what many saw as his birthright. He would be the man who would bring the Irish Republican Army into the modern age and root the British out of Northern Ireland in a glorious battle. Brian pioneers new fundraising techniques through the theft and sale of proprietary information from one business to another. He taps the mother load when an American pharmaceutical company pays Brian an endless stream of money as the company builds profits on stolen designs. Brian ascends to a seat on the Army Council. But when Sinn Fein opens a secret dialogue with the British, Brian is enraged as his destiny is to be denied - in favor of diplomacy. Brian breaks with the IRA to form his own political party as he continues to receive funds from the American Company. Joining Brian as his Lady Macbeth, is another IRA operative, Ashley Brennan, a one-woman death squad who possesses all the charms of an innocent young girl. Enter John Farrell, Special Forces Veteran of the first Gulf War and now the Vice President of a Fortune 500 company, enjoying a meteoric rise in the international marketplace. Through the persistent research of Colin Jefferies, (a Fleet Street reporter who looks more like an Oxford Don), John discovers his company is funding Brian's operation. Failing to convince the authorities, John's struggle to infiltrate the operation takes a challenging turn when his only advocate appears as a lovely MI5 assassin, Kiera Harrison. Kiera is a fascinating, complex heroine. Or is she an anti-heroine? When she was a UVF soldier, Kiera used sex as a weapon to lure and kill numerous IRA figures. When they were both young, Kiera was part of a hit team that assassinated Brian's father and very nearly killed Brian. After a UVF bombing she participated in mistakenly kills a British official, she is kidnapped by MI5 and is given the choice of serving British Intelligence or prison. With her experience of sectarian warfare with the IRA, she chooses to be bound to MI5. Already under constant threats of reprisals for her nefarious activities in the past, Kiera is a study in contrast and depth as she has had to forego intimacy in her uncertain world. Together, Kiera and John uncover Brian's plan to disrupt the All-Party-Talks and to orchestrate sectarian violence in the North, while he milks the media for sympathetic coverage. Brian then buys the services of rogue units, far removed from the leadership of the IRA and the UVF to carry out operations in their name. Brian intends to usher events from the sidelines for his own political rise and a future run for the first Prime Minister of a Re-unified Ireland. A new complication arises as the once stoic Kiera, has fallen for John, a happily married and unattainable man. Intrigue and raw human emotion coalesce to forge a thrilling conclusion that shapes the future.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?209298</url></doc>
