<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="209253">
  <docid>209253</docid>
  <title>Gamemaster</title>
  <year>1997</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">X</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brandon, Kyle</actor>
      <role>Kyle</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cruise, Tommy</actor>
      <role>Tom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>DiMarco, Dino</actor>
      <role>Dino</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Erik, Carl</actor>
      <role>Carl</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McKenna, Kyle</actor>
      <role>Kyle</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sloan, J.T.</actor>
      <role>J.T.</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tucker, Cole</actor>
      <role>Cole</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>West, Cutter</actor>
      <role>Cutter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wilder, Peter</actor>
      <role>Pete</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Hot-wire your mind and make your wildest fantasies come true. Play with cops, robbers, marines, leather studs and denim clad villains. There's an ambitious setup here and a very clever way of linking scenes, but it gets screwed up a bit by seriously crappy acting (even by porn standards) and a seeming inability by the director to cut to the chase. It starts out with devastatingly cute Tommy Cruise (maybe he's the one that's been having an affair with Kyle Bradford) being rather playfully assaulted by Peter Wilder and Dino DiMarco. Burly leather god, and former Mr. Drummer, Kyle Brandon lumbers by and scares away the baddies. Far from being grateful, Tommy is pissed. You see, he explains, "it's just a game," and disappears. In his place on a barrel in the alley, Brandon finds a card advertising gamemaster.com. Intrigued, Brandon goes home and checks it out, but not before he strips down to his unflattering CK briefs. It takes a long time for Brandon to get into his scene. And while the filmmakers didn't have to build a fake web site to be used in the movie (though I bet they could get people to do it very cheaply these days), anyone with a DVD player is web-savvy enough to know that you'd never go to a web site and have some unseen hand type out 'Welcome to Gamemaster' on the screen. I know I'm being picky here, but it wouldn't be an issue if the director didn't spend an inordinate amount of time showing you the way to get into the site. But with the preliminaries done, and with the donning of a suspiciously handy pair of virtual reality glasses, Kyle is in. He chooses the S/M Leather feature (big shock) and finds himself chained to an enormous X with drooling top man Carl Erik waiting for him. Erik is truly a sight to behold in full leather garb - rock hard muscles and an even harder cock that he has trussed up in a series of leather straps. To my surprise, big and burly Kyle Brandon is a natural bottom and really seems to get pleasure out of being tied up and dominated. Leather and S/M really isn't my thing, but I know enough about it to know that while these two are hot together and get into their toys, it isn't particularly extreme. It seems more like dress-up. But for those with vanilla dreams of leather and tit clamps, the scene will work like a charm. When it's over, we see suit-and-tie office guy Carl Erik on the phone to his buddy Cutter West to tell him about this great site he was just at. Erik should never be given lines other than 'tighten that hole,' since his thick German accent makes everything he says incomprehensible. Erik tells the blonde, slightly balding Cutter about the great new Gamemaster site. After showing us how to get into the site again, and with the use of another pair of VR glasses, Cutter is in. He chose 'Military Maneuvers' where he plays a sergeant who challenges Private J.T. Sloane to a marksmanship contest. Once a lot of dull conversation and dead spots is gotten past, Cutter and J.T. go at it. I've always been a fan of J.T., whose body and look only seems to get better. It was also quite nice to see a thickly muscular guy like him take Cutter's big snake up the ass. J.T. calls up his friend Kyle McKenna, who still seems to be in bed, and tells him about what a great time he had a gamemaster. Kyle decided to check it out. Again, we get to see how to get into the site, but we're coming upon the highlight of the movie, so it's OK. Dark and rippling Kyle chooses 'Cops and Robbers' and he's the cop. He comes home after a long day of work and is surprised by tattooed sex pig Cole Tucker burglarizing his home. In a very sexy and semi-believable way, Cole forces Kyle to strip and gets off on his humiliation. We all know that Cole is a born top man and he doesn't disappoint here as almost splits Kyle in two with his enormous cock and a big, greasy black dildo. In the worst bit of acting in the flick, Cole is then a nerdish computer geek who spends a long time calling his pal, the smooth and boyish bottom Tommy Cruise. Cruise chooses 'Back Alley Thrills' and this one truly cuts to the chase. After being cornered by Peter Wilder and Dino DiMarco, they roughly rip off Tommy's clothes and get right to the fucking. Tommy squeals in delight, or maybe pain, as he takes Dino's enormous salami in the caboose while Peter rams his dewy lips with his king size cock. It's certainly not the best porno out there, but there are definitely reasons to recommend - namely Tommy Cruises' bottom boy enthusiasm and Cole Tucker's tough, top man attitude. All they really need to do was cut out the dead air between and before scenes to make it something truly hot. But then again, that's what the fast forward button is for.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?209253</url></doc>
