<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="209838">
  <docid>209838</docid>
  <title>Gangotri</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Music</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Bhojpuri</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">16 November 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Chhadha, Abhishek</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Sawant, Deepak</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Chhadha, Abhishek</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bachchan, Amitabh</actor>
      <role>Thakur Vijay Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chawla, Bhoomika</actor>
      <role>Gangotri</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kunal, Singh</actor>
      <role>Jaswant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Malini, Hema</actor>
      <role>Thakurain Savitri V. Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shravani</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tiwari, Manoj (II)</actor>
      <role>Bajrangi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tiwari, Shivam</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The movie takes off from the point where Ganga finished. Bajrangi enters an empty house, remembering Thakur Chacha who is in prison. Then Jaswant and his son at an assembly of the villagers threaten them that when Jaswant's daughter Gangotri is out on the streets the villagers have to shut themselves in or they will be in deep trouble for even catching a glimpse of the lady. Kunal Singh and the son kill their driver's brother who is on his way back to the village since he catches a glimpse of Gangotri. The driver's attempts to avenge his brother's death results in Bajrangi getting an opportunity to touch, pull, hold and roll on the ground with Gangotri. She promptly falls in love with Bajrangi and asks him to fill sindhoor in her maang. Later when Gangotri is shown pining for Bajrangi, her mother insists she should be married off. At the marriage ceremony Gangotri and Bajrangi announce that they are already married to each other. Bajrangi leaves for his house to inform his family about the wedding. Meanwhile Thakur Vijay Singh who has so far only been seen in jail is actually Bajrangi's long-lost father. Then much fighting and squabbling later the villains are vanquished and everybody lives happily ever after.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?209838</url></doc>
