<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="210481">
  <docid>210481</docid>
  <title>Gas Attack</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Sweden">25 January 2002</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Netherlands">30 January 2002</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Israel">January 2003</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="UK">2 July 2002</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Greece">17 November 2001</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="France">12 October 2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="France">71</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Glenaan, Kenneth</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hart, David (V)</producer>
    <producer>Kingsley, Sam (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Joffe, Rowan</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>de Wardener, Max</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brennan, Liam</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Calder, Morag</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hassan, Benae</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ventry, Laurie</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zen-Aloush, Sherko</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Father Sherko (Sherko Zen-Aloush) is increasingly concerned that his daughter Resa (Benae Hassan) is getting sick. Presenting themselves at the hospital they encounter a number of asylum seekers from their block, all demonstrating similar symptoms. At first it looks like an epidemic of flu, but soon it appears to be something infinitely more sinister. Quickly the civil and emergency services are beyond breaking point and it emerges that the authorities are powerless to halt this disaster. When Asylum Support Unit worker Rabeena Dhondy (Robina Qureshi) arrives at Sherko and Resa's flat she finds the little girl is suffering from an extremely bad cough. At the hospital, the doctor Annie Millbrook (Morag Calder) diagnoses flu. Shortly afterwards one of the Resa's neighbours Hamez (Salah Hussein) dies from what the hospital are still calling flu. Quite naturally the asylum seekers are getting worried and a meeting is arranged with them by the hospital. Robina arrives at Sherko and Resa's block of flats to find ash swirling around like a fine snow. Robina goes straight to see Brian Cooper. Back at the hospital it looks as if Resa and a number of the other patients are feeling much better. Doctor Annie Millbrook is suspicious though...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?210481</url></doc>
