<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="214060">
  <docid>214060</docid>
  <title>Ghayal Sherni</title>
  <year>1988</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Mohan, A.</editor>
    <editor>Satishkumar, C.</editor>
  </editors>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Bapaiah, K.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ahuja, Ajay Kumar</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Khanna, Usha</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Aruna (III)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jayanthi</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kaikala, Satyanarayana</actor>
      <role>Ravinder 'Ravi'</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Krishna (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nutan Prasad</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Ravinder is a Chief Engineer with the Municipality of a small town om Southern India, where his brother, Raghuram, is a Police Inspector. The two brothers live together in harmony with Raghuram's wife, and two daughters. Ravinder is expected to marry Aarti, Raghuram's sister-in-law. When Ravinder attempts to demolish a dilapidated building that houses 37 families, he meets with opposition from them and a woman named Rajni. During a storm the building collapses, and both Rajni and Ravinder assist the dwellers to find alternate accommodation in a Municipal Godown, much to the chagrin of Dharampal, the local Chairman of the Municipality. Both Rajni and Ravinder fall in love and want to get married. Dharampal entraps both Rajni and Ravinder in a web of lies and deceit, and when they try to escape, Rajni ends up killing Raghuram. As a result she is arrested and held in a cell. The question remains will Ravinder continue on to marry someone who is charged with killing his brother, and if so, what will be the impact on his sister-in-law and his nieces?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?214060</url></doc>
