<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="214343">
  <docid>214343</docid>
  <title>Ghosthunter</title>
  <year>2000</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Cozens, Simon</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">25 September 2000</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">20</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Corris, Simon</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Corris, Simon</producer>
    <producer>Reddihough, Alison</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Corris, Simon</writer>
    <writer>Reddihough, Alison</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Pheloung, Barrington</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Finlay, Frank (I)</actor>
      <role>Charlie Fielding</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kidd, Josie</actor>
      <role>Emily Fielding</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Two lonely figures are bought together by ghostly disturbances in a Sussex guest house. Charlie, the ghosthunter, and a widower for two years is searching for the contact with his wife that will release his melancholy since her death. He now feels it's his duty to help the transition of lost spirits. His methods are very simple and it is perhaps this informal approach that lead many to underestimate and doubt him. Charlie takes any criticism in his stride, if asked to help he will, otherwise he is content to be left alone. Sarah, the researcher, compelled to find her own purpose in life, investigates the myths surrounding a small village. Invariably driven to uncover the facts, she ploughs through the rumours and superstition surrounding a sinister group that operated in the village around the turn of the century. Their respective journeys bring them together as Charlie recognizes something of his own unhappiness in Sarah. The spiritualist and the factualist who together uncover the horrors locked within the walls of an abandoned church. Charlie helps Sarah to find her purpose but can he find his own inner peace?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?214343</url></doc>
