<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="214595">
  <docid>214595</docid>
  <title>Giant Sized</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kaczor, Kris</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>melodrama</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">13 June 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">22</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Kaczor, Kris</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Jano, Sami</composer>
    <composer>Kaczor, Kris</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Clepps, Kevin</actor>
      <role>Edward James</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Eid, Omar</actor>
      <role>Edward James</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Evangelista, Greg</actor>
      <role>Edward James</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>After school young Edward James watches his mother watch television. He has an appreciation for china dolls. Solitary and outcast, Edward is a gentle and humbling character. Never threatening, he possesses the quality of each human being that is not provided with the confidence or intellectual capacity to cut through the rigors of cruel humanity. One day however, when Edward leaves his yearbook on his desk, a girl named Tonya secretly writes a message of praise to him. While his years are spent in isolation and bagging groceries at a local market, he often turns to the girl's message for sustenance. Edward's devotion to china dolls develops into a great skill for restoring them. He happens upon several tarnished dolls at a garage sale and buys them all. Many years later, when he has finally restored the dolls he has collected, Edward decides to return them to the house where he bought them. The woman who answers the door quickly realizes they belonged to her daughter, Tonya. "Giant Sized" is a lyrical take on the nature of meaning and the passage of time. The pulse of Edward James' life over twenty five years conveys a monotony and dreamlike distance from reality and other people. And yet Edward suffers no alienation. The bleakness of his life does not stop Edward from cherishing what life has offered him--a single note of praise in his high school annual from a girl named Tonya. What Edward does not realize is the truth behind Tonya's note. He is unaware that his life is stained with the infinite variegation of callous reality. He fails to see that everything is giant sized.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?214595</url></doc>
