<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="214590">
  <docid>214590</docid>
  <title>Giant Maximus</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Starck, Nathaniel</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Edmonds, John (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Dean, Dave (I)</producer>
    <producer>Edmonds, John (I)</producer>
    <producer>Miller, Joel (II)</producer>
    <producer>Starck, Nathaniel</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Miller, Joel (II)</writer>
    <writer>Starck, Nathaniel</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>van Buuren, Armin</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Corsten, Ferry</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dean, Dave (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Digweed, John</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Edmonds, John (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kleinenberg, Sander</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Miller, Joel (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sasha (XII)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>van Buuren, Armin</actor>
      <role>Himself/Narrator</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Listen to Armin Van Burren, our host and one of the top ranked DJ's in the world, as he takes us through the biggest dance event in Los Angeles history and one of the biggest New Years events ever. Packed to capacity Giant Maximus was a night to remember, with over 10,000 people in attendance. Here it is! Featuring Sasha, John Digweed, Ferry Corsten, Sander Kleinenberg, Armin Van Burren, and more... Hear how these legends inspired one another and watch as they all come together in one place for one night only! We invite you enter the world of Giant Maximus a carnival... Where the only thing that eclipses the fantasy is the music... Giant Maximus chronicles this epic night through the eyes and music of Armin Van Burren. Listen to how Armin started, who inspired him, how he got to where he is today, and what to expect out of him in the future... Told through not just his words but his music find out what makes Armin Van Burren the biggest name in the DJ world... all while listening to new his newest material... Nowhere else was a line up like this on New Years and now no where else can you find a line up like this on DVD...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?214590</url></doc>
