<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="214749">
  <docid>214749</docid>
  <title>Gift of Love</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Wood, Jason (X)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">17</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Giles, Daniel (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Wood, Jason (X)</producer>
    <producer>Giles, Daniel (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Giles, Daniel (II)</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>5 years ago, Dan Giles, a welder, was helping to dismantle the interior of Saint Vibiana's cathedral in Los Angeles. Saint Vibiana's was damaged by years of wear and earthquakes. It was bought privately with the intention of renovating it into an arts, entertainment complex, restaurant and nightclub. Back to the gates, Dan was asked to remove a set of gates and discard of them. He asked the foreman of St. Vibiana's for a receipt and off he left with over a ton of perfectly sculpted metal. Instead of scrapping them he brought them home and researched the majestic gates. As it turns out the gates are an historical and spiritual shrine forged in the honor of Our Lady of Guadalupe. Dan than began his journey on where to place the gates. Sounds easy enough, eh? Well, after the story appeared in the L.A. Times, a media firestorm erupted on where the gates should go. "Gift of Love" is a short version of a feature non-narrative film titled "Attitude Matters" (still in post-production). "Attitude Matters" uses the story of the gates to weave a comprehensive web of philosophy and comparative religion while "Gift of Love" focuses solely on the gates. As a work derived from a larger work, "Gift of Love" stands firmly on it's own two feet.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?214749</url></doc>
