<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="215454">
  <docid>215454</docid>
  <title>Girdap</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Aydin, Onur</editor>
    <editor>Karamahmutoglu, Talip</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Turkish</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Turkey">21 March 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">95</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Karamahmutoglu, Talip</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Karamahmutoglu, Talip</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Aydin, Onur</writer>
    <writer>Karamahmutoglu, Talip</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Genc, Alican</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Altin, Rahman</actor>
      <role>Ekonomi Hocasi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bilen, Ozan</actor>
      <role>Umut</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Canpolat, Emre</actor>
      <role>Suleyman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Iris, Ibrahim</actor>
      <role>Ismail</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Saka, Fuat</actor>
      <role>Ibrahim Hodja</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sürmeli, Ali</actor>
      <role>Salman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Yöntem, Selçuk</actor>
      <role>Father</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Umut, who is a young man in his twenties, is accepted to study in Istanbul University. He finds two flatmates and a flat on a billboard at his University's café. Umut is a son of a middle class Turkish family, who has an apolitical view of the world at the very beginning of his university days. He and his other two flatmates discover mystical, as well as supernatural events happening in the house that they live in. These experiences affect Umut in an unusual way by encouraging him (indirectly) to be close to Islam as a way of finding answers. Umut enjoys this new life style of Islam at first. Everything goes perfect for him. However, new life brings new friends and new environment with it. His new environment pushes him to a more political religious world; as a result of this; Umut's religious life is not just limited by the holy book or the religion's pure requirements. His religious life becomes politicized. In other words, he becomes a fundamentalist. This transfiguration forces him to get away from his lover, old friends and family. Umut becomes a violent and irresponsible man after becoming a fundamentalist. Spite and hate now fulfills his veins. This ideology and a wrecked soul take Umut to become a suicide activist. One Turkish national celebration morning Umut puts on a bomb device and takes it with him to a touristic place. He ends his life by activating the bomb inside a bus that is full of innocent tourists. What we understand at the end of the movie is that...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?215454</url></doc>
