<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="216529">
  <docid>216529</docid>
  <title>Giving Thanks</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Schreier, Danielle</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>student</keyword>
    <keyword>animal-welfare</keyword>
    <keyword>thanksgiving</keyword>
    <keyword>environmentalism</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">4 October 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">47</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Schreier, Danielle</director>
  </directors>
<plot>"Giving Thanks" (2007) redefines the traditional animal welfare film through one woman's unconventional journey with a Thanksgiving turkey. This unique and moving film begins with an examination of the history behind Thanksgiving and America's transition from small, family farms to the factory farms of today. The filmmaker interviews countless subjects, including a turkey plant operator who has 'adopted' one of his birds and turned it into a pet. Having viewed countless turkeys in abusive conditions, the filmmaker wonders if she can't similarly espouse a turkey. She concludes that this year she will raise, instead of eat, a Thanksgiving turkey. When the filmmaker learns that the bird she has rescued from a production farm is so sick that it is barely alive, she realizes quickly that she was in for a far more of an adventure than she could have anticipated. In her desperate plight to save her new pet she visits multiple animal sanctuaries and learns more about factory farming and the turkey industry than she could ever have imagined. The only question that remains is if her rescued turkey will survive long enough to ever enjoy freedom.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?216529</url></doc>
