<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="218600">
  <docid>218600</docid>
  <title>Going for Gold: The Bocuse d'Or, Part Two</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Osghian, Edi</editor>
    <editor>Versteeg, Nick</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>cuisine</keyword>
    <keyword>lyon</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Versteeg, Nick</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Versteeg, Nick</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mills, Chris (XII)</actor>
      <role>Chef</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>O'Grady, Tracey</actor>
      <role>Chef</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Robertson, Jim (V)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In this second documentary on the Bocuse d'Or culinary competition in Lyon, France, in January, 2001, Chris Mills of Canada and Tracy O'Grady of the USA continue in their efforts to break into the top ranks of world cuisine during a grueling 5-hour cooking session that leaves no room for error. The chef who makes the best-tasting and best-looking food will walk away with a golden statue, a nice financial bonus, and an everlasting place in the journals of culinary history. We see how Chris Mills traveled to France two months before the competition to practice his platters of food under the watchful eye of a former Bocuse d'Or winner. Tracy O'Grady brings to Washington the only female chef to ever win the Bocuse d'Or from Luxembourg. Then Tracy practices her platters at the Culinary Institute of America in New York to get feedback from the instructors who collectively have dozens of years of experience under their chef's toques. The story continues from Lyon, France, home of the Bocuse d'Or, and the gastronomic capital of Europe. Chris and Tracy do their last-minute ingredient shopping while the first half of the contest takes place. At the competition hundreds of rabid fans cram into a small stadium in front of the kitchens. The supporters are ready to make as much noise as possible while cheering on the chef from their home country. On Day Two of the contest the two North American chefs compete, and you'll see all the action as they race against the clock to get their gleaming silver platters of food ready for the discerning panel of judges.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?218600</url></doc>
