<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="219680">
  <docid>219680</docid>
  <title>Goo chak sam fong fong</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Cantonese</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Hong Kong</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Malaysia">18SG</certificate>
    <certificate country="Hong Kong">IIB</certificate>
    <certificate country="Philippines">PG-13</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Hong Kong">6 November 2003</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Philippines">28 April 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">86</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Cheang, Pou-Soi</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Cheang, Pou-Soi</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cheung, Steven</actor>
      <role>Ben</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Choi, Charlene</actor>
      <role>Nancy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chou, Lawrence</actor>
      <role>Keith</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chung, Gillian</actor>
      <role>Linda</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fong, Alex (I)</actor>
      <role>Mr. Cheung</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kwan, Kenny</actor>
      <role>Jerry</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wong, Ho-Yin</actor>
      <role>Nick</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Nancy, a near-despicable Hong Kong girl who's bitchy and petulant, and even grifts money from Keith, a pathetic guy who blatantly adores her. After discovering him reading her mail (a common occurence, it would seem), it comes to light that her long-lost father, Andy Jihuai, is requesting a family reunion. With the promise of some sort of inheritance, Nancy travels to the ancestral rural home to find a passel of relatives she's never met, much less cares for. The eldest brother is Deon Ting, followed by single mother Deon, fourth brother Nick, fifth brother Jerry, sixth sister Linda, and eighth brother Ben. For those keeping score, Nancy qualifies as the seventh sister, while third brother Sam wasn't able to attend. Deon, the second sister,also dragged along her young daughter Fanny, and the manor has a crusty servant named Wong. These salient details are related to Nancy by Lawyer Cheung, who has other news to impart: Ting died shortly after sending the letters to his offspring, which means the family reunion is now a funeral. Despite being birthed of six different mothers, the children are all entitled to a share of the family estate. However, there are conditions. At precisely midnight for seven consecutive days, the children must worship their father's still present corpse, which resides in a chair like the king of the mansion. Even more, they must hug one another at the end of each evening. However, weird things start to occur as soon as they arrive and they try to decipher the reasons for the strange happenings..... otherwise one of them will be next!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?219680</url></doc>
