<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="219809">
  <docid>219809</docid>
  <title>Good Grief</title>
  <year>1998</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Callaway, Justin (I)</editor>
    <editor>Mcquerrey, Katie</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">77</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Dickson, Andrew (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Blalock, Jason</producer>
    <producer>Dickson, Andrew (II)</producer>
    <producer>Gray, David (VII)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Dickson, Andrew (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Gardner, Jeff (II)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Burian, Al</actor>
      <role>Magnus</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Coleman, Ali</actor>
      <role>Loris</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gray, Dave (II)</actor>
      <role>Chuck</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mack, Bethe</actor>
      <role>Darcy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Meltzer, Richard</actor>
      <role>The author</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stevens, George (V)</actor>
      <role>Chuck's Dad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Toddoroff, John</actor>
      <role>Sylvan</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"Good Grief" is a loose version of the "Peanuts" gang (notice the names) as high school kids who are into role play games. A group of seniors who have been into a fantasy role playing game named Monsters &amp; Mayhem has begun to expand into normal teen activities, but Chuck wants the gang to stick with the games. Chuck has the idea to use their spring break to go off on a real treasure hunt for a golden statue that was buried for a publishers publicity stunt and never found. He also is motivated by the fact that he needs the money to go somewhere better than community college so that he won't be bothered by the jocks from his school that will be attending there. With help from another meek member, he convinces the gang to change the plan of renting beach condos to the treasure hunt. Chuck's crush Loris gets her boyfriend and former group member Magnus to drive his car on the trip. They get away from home, relax, but then more jocks hassle the group, and most of that as usual is directed toward Chuck. His later response to the jocks is awash in a fog of reality and the game, but he learns to defend himself. As the search for the statue becomes hopeless, he remembers that there is another way to find the statue, and it is his humility that gets him what he really needed all along.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?219809</url></doc>
