<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="220133">
  <docid>220133</docid>
  <title>Goodbye Bear</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Carr, Ian (II)</editor>
    <editor>Wesman, Andrew</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">20</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Carr, Ian (II)</director>
    <director>Wesman, Andrew</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Carr, Ian (II)</producer>
    <producer>Wesman, Andrew</producer>
    <producer>Carr, Ian (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Wesman, Andrew</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Cmiel, Matthew</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bradbury, Lisa</actor>
      <role>Mother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cirocco Jr., William</actor>
      <role>Teenage Male</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dog, Phoebe the</actor>
      <role>Terrence</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gelernter, Richard</actor>
      <role>Marty/The Bear</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ho, Ellen (II)</actor>
      <role>Teenage Female</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>LoPinto, Andrea</actor>
      <role>Racoon</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Low, Marilyn</actor>
      <role>Mother/Lamb</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Momota, Grace</actor>
      <role>Sissy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wesman, Andrew</actor>
      <role>Wolf</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>'Goodbye Bear' chronicles a young girl, Sissy, who lives in a world of childhood fantasies and wild imagination. With her best friend and pet dog Terrance by her side there are few adventures Sissy would not go on. However, when Sissy's father, Marty, learns his wife plans to leave him, he makes a terrible decision. Fueled by fear and desperation Marty kidnaps his own daughter, threatening to further destroy an already crumbling family. Sissy joins her distraught father on this new kind of adventure. Unlike her normal adventures this one takes her far from home to scary and dark parts of the world. For Sissy, her father is nothing but a large bear, an archetype she has absorbed from bed-time stories and children's television. Her father's fear of a wife relentlessly pursuing him and a very uncertain future are inaccessible to his daughter. To survive with his daughter, Marty must learn that Sissy is not something that can be stolen. Sissy, in turn, must lose some innocence to see through the 'bear' façade, perceiving the true face of her father and the extent of his misery if she ever hopes to help him. With a relentless wife close at their heels, and the police just one wrong turn away, Marty and Sissy may never solve the pains that lead them on their greatest adventure.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?220133</url></doc>
