<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="220418">
  <docid>220418</docid>
  <title>Gopalaa</title>
  <year>1994</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Jain, Akash</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Khanna, Veena R.</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Malik, Anu</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bindu (I)</actor>
      <role>Jwalamukhi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chatwal, Suresh</actor>
      <role>Major Anand's superior</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chopra, Prem</actor>
      <role>Rudra Pratap Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ganguly, Roopali</actor>
      <role>Pooja Anand</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gorilla</actor>
      <role>Rudra's goon</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khanna, Ramesh</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Kiran (I)</actor>
      <role>Mahamaya B. Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lagoo, Shreeram</actor>
      <role>Chief Minister</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mohan, Mac</actor>
      <role>Swant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Murad, Raza</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pal, Amrit</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pandey, Chunky</actor>
      <role>Major Anand/Gopal 'Gopala' Anand</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pandey, Rakesh</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Parvez, Yunus</actor>
      <role>Chattanmiya</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rindani, Shiva</actor>
      <role>Shemaroo</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Rudra Pratap Singh has assembled an army and would like to conquer India and enslave it. His plans are thwarted by brave Major Anand, who completely and single-handedly brings his entire empire down but is unable to apprehend Rudra his brother, Bhanu, and nephew, Mahamaya. Rudra decides to avenge this humiliation and waits for the right time. Then Anand gets married to Pooja, and shortly after their honeymoon, Rudra, Bhanu and his men attack the couple, and Anand gets killed. A pregnant and devastated Pooja identifies Rudra and Bhanu and gets them arrested, but they are able to get verdicts of not guilty. An enraged Pooja kills Bhanu in the courtroom, is arrested, tried, and sentenced to be hanged. When she is about to be hanged, she faints as she is expecting, and as a result her sentence is turned to life imprisonment. In prison she befriends a bandit named Jwalamukhi and gives birth to a baby boy, who is named Gopal, as he is born on the same day as Lord Krishna. Five years later Pooja attempts to escape with Gopal, but is shot while Gopal manages to run away. Years later the mother and son will be fated to re-unite - and this is when Pooja will find out that Gopal is now known as Gopalaa, a hoodlum who is a hit man - and a minion of none other than Rudra!!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?220418</url></doc>
