<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="220831">
  <docid>220831</docid>
  <title>Gothicfest</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Milan, Christopher</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 July 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">28</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Sieloff, Cliff</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Sieloff, Cliff</producer>
    <producer>Sieloff, Cliff</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Esch, En</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Levi, Charles</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Levy, Victoria</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sieloff, Cliff</actor>
      <role>Himself - Interviewer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Swan, Jeff (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Gothicfest 2005 is a Documentary about North America's Largest Gothic Festival And Expo. This historic event was captured on film with interviews and live performances. "Gothicfest 2005" featured: Hanzel Und Gretyl, Slick Idiot with En Esch and Guenter Schulz formerly of KMFDM, Project .44 with Levi Levi (The Thrill Kill Kult), Grigori 3, Slave Driver, Deepest Symphony, Ofearia, 13 Winters, Dies Mali, Rosenguard, Withering Soul, Ghost Orgy, Drake, Reverend Agony, Rachael's Surrender featuring Elysabeth Grant the vocalist for Black Tape for a Blue Girl, Psionic, Methodical, Terminal Bliss and Dead Girls Corp! Exhibit booths by: Transylvania Imports, Design Toscano, DeFacto Clothing, Lollipop Magazine, Top Notch Tattoos, Michelle Belanger, Corvis Nocturnum, Cutterz Edge, The Gothic Council of Chicago, Phaedra's Philtres, Theatrikil Productions and Dark Candles Plus Nickolaus Pacione, Twilights Muse Jewelry, Red Scream Magazine, Satanic-Sluts.com, Gashley Darcane, Witchschool.com, Bone Daddy Creations, Jerry Ohlinger's Movie Material's Store, Grave Grrrls, The Dungeon, and CyRen Gear.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?220831</url></doc>
