<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="221327">
  <docid>221327</docid>
  <title>Grahan</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">16 February 2001</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Kuwait">5 March 2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Nair, Shashilal K.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Shroff, Ayesha</producer>
    <producer>Shroff, Jackie</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Raja, Karthik</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jog, Anant</actor>
      <role>Vidyarthi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Koirala, Manisha</actor>
      <role>Parvati 'Paro' Shastri</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Potdar, Achyut</actor>
      <role>Chief Minister Jagdish Acharya</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Purandhare, Prasad</actor>
      <role>Sanjay Jagdish Acharya</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Raghuvaran</actor>
      <role>Advocate Raghu Sinha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shroff, Jackie</actor>
      <role>Advocate Jaggan 'Jaggu' Sinha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zutshi, Rajendranath</actor>
      <role>Parvati's husband</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Widowed Chief Minister Jagdish Acharya lives a wealthy lifestyle along with his daughter, Sunita and son, Sanjay. One day he gets a phone call from the Police Commissioner, informing him that a woman has filed a F.I.R. (First Information Report) of Rape against Sanjay. A shocked Jagdish, instructs the Police Commissioner to proceed according to law. Thereafter, while touring Jagdish has a heart attack and dies. Sunita is asked to be the new Chief Minister, which she accepts. After the funeral, the Police arrest Sanjay, hold him in a cell, and he is tried in Court. Sunita's boyfriend, Advocate Jaggan Sinha, whose brother, Raghu, is also a lawyer, represents Sanjay, examines the documentation, examines the witnesses as well as the complainant herself, and proves it before the Judge that the complaint was politically motivated by Journalist Vidyarthi, as the complainant, Parvati Shastri, did not exhibit any signs of rape nor was there any proof of her involvement with Sanjay, the Judge concurs, and Sanjay is set free. Shortly thereafter, while the Archarya family celebrates Sanjay release, Jaggan finds out that Sanjay did indeed abduct and rape Parvati. Watch what happens when Jaggan decides to re-open the case, much to the chagrin of Sunita and his very own brother, who decides to represent Sanjay against Jaggan.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?221327</url></doc>
