<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="222637">
  <docid>222637</docid>
  <title>Green Diggity Dog</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>color-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>animal-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">97</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Maynard, Hoot</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Huertas, Jon</producer>
    <producer>Maynard, Hoot</producer>
    <producer>Dial, Allen (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Maynard, Hoot</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Howard, Trevor (II)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bannick, David</actor>
      <role>Ole Kroftmeirer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Estevez, Joe</actor>
      <role>T.J. Starko</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Huertas, Jon</actor>
      <role>Tim Porter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ianniello, Valarie</actor>
      <role>Brittany Lazure</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lieber, Paul (I)</actor>
      <role>Gov Porterini</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rippey, Stephen</actor>
      <role>Joe Starko</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Schiess, Richard</actor>
      <role>Elway</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>What do a mobster, a dog and peanut butter have in common? Bellman Tim Porter is about to find out. On a routine bag checkout, Tim Porter discovers there is nothing routine about this day. Tim finds the hotel's guest, T.J. Starko, naked, dead, and with over three million in cash. Torn between doing the right thing or keeping his newly found fortune, Tim summons the help of his co-worker and hopeful love interest, Brittany Lazure. Brittany coerces Tim into a high stakes gamble of stealing the cash and the dead body. With a very ripe, dead mobster and a whole lot of money, Tim and Brittany make their escape. But, their escape isn't as clean as they had hoped. The dead mobster's brother, Joe Starko, is quick to pick up on their trail. While Joe combs Tim's apartment for clues, Tim's wacky friend and paintball junkie, Elway shoots the intruder with a paintball pellet. Joe abducts Elway and the only thing keeping him alive is the fact he knows where Tim and Brittany are. Tim and Brittany find safety at a mountain home in Jackson Hole, Wyoming. Their pleasant evening is soon shattered when Joe and Elway show up at the house and all hell breaks loose. Now they can either sweat to death in a sauna or give up the money...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?222637</url></doc>
