<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="223045">
  <docid>223045</docid>
  <title>Grief</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Stayman, Marc</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">11 January 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">10</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Stayman, Marc</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Sharei, Marcus M.</producer>
    <producer>Stayman, Marc</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Stayman, Marc</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Neipp, Sam</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bohle, Annette</actor>
      <role>Lacy Cillians</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brady, Patrick M.</actor>
      <role>Robert Cillians</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Camberos, Nanishka</actor>
      <role>Rose</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hussain, Omar</actor>
      <role>Ayden</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kudrov, Shelly</actor>
      <role>Mandy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stayman, Marc</actor>
      <role>Dr. Martin Blondell</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Weaver, Scot</actor>
      <role>Marc</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Robery Cillians is a confident and successful man who is used to being in control. His wife Lacy is just as used to living a life with few responsibilities. Their marriage is provides each with just what they need until Robert gets a call that changes everything. His kid brother has been hurt in Iraq and has lost a leg. Robert is consumed with guilt and feels responsible for his brother's injuries as he spirals into depression and self doubt. Lacy is concerned for her husband's well being but as he slips deeper into depression she slowly begins to realize that his illness means that she has to start assuming a level of control in her life that she is not emotionally prepared to deal with. Robert and Lacy's friends are baffled by Robert's deterioration and are helpless to do anything about it. They have always know him to be a hard charging supremely confident individual who always was in control of his life and sometimes the lives of those around him. They all secretly admire him and are drawn to his strength. They can't understand what his happening to him and he can't explain it. In a desperate attempt to regain control of his life, Robert takes action to makes things right in his own special way.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?223045</url></doc>
