<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="224206">
  <docid>224206</docid>
  <title>Guerrilla News Network: The War Conspiracy</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <editors>
    <editor>Marshall, Stephen (III)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">January 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">4</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Marshall, Stephen (III)</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Scott, Peter Dale</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In 1970, at the height of the Vietnam War and on the heels of Nixon's announcement that U.S. troops would invade Cambodia, a mild-mannered English professor at UC Berkeley completed a startling book called The War Conspiracy. Yet, despite the fact that the author's publisher was Bobbs Merrill, a major literary brand, the book never reached the public domain. Little did the professor know there were powerful forces working behind the scenes to prevent its release. He would later discover that through its ties to ITT, a major shareholder in Bobbs Merrill, the Central Intelligence Agency was able to suppress the book. What was it about The War Conspiracy that so frightened the CIA and prompted them to deter its release? And who was this upstart writer who had pried so deeply into the covert machinations of U.S. intelligence that he had become one of the few American authors ever to have his work suppressed by an agency of the United States government? As you will discover, the CIA had good reason to intercept the work of Peter Dale Scott, then a relatively unknown poet and political dissident. For The War Conspiracy was more than an intellectual treatise on the virtues of disarmament. It was a riveting investigation of the CIA, the oil companies and their manipulation of U.S. foreign policy in order to escalate the Vietnam War. In his review of the book, Noam Chomsky remarked on Scott's "meticulous and fascinating analysis of intelligence conspiracies and the links between the 'intelligence community' and corporate power." Now, three decades after the sabotaged publication of the book, Guerrilla News Network presents a beat-driven, design-enhanced video of The War Conspiracy. In addition, we are featuring an in-depth interview with Professor Scott regarding the new War on Terrorism and how it parallels his research in the Vietnam era. We are also honored to present an exclusive publication of the Introduction to The War Conspiracy, revised and re-edited on the thirtieth anniversary of the book's conception. Welcome to the 'deep political' world of Peter Dale Scott...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?224206</url></doc>
