<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="224639">
  <docid>224639</docid>
  <title>Gulabi Raaten</title>
  <year>1990</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Rajagopal, K.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">1990</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Venu, P.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Khan, A. (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Venu, P.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Prakash, Jeeva</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Devan (I)</actor>
      <role>Vijay 'Viju'</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mohan, Raj</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ravi, Pujappura</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sreekumar, Jagathi</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vijayan (III)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Sexy Advocate Sheela Mathur lives a wealthy lifestyle with her brother and his wife in India. One day while at the Blue Diamond Restaurant, she witnesses a man beating up three others, including the son of the local I.G. of Police. She intervenes, but is shoved aside. When the police arrive, she identifies the culprit, and has him arrested. Subsequently she finds out that the culprit's name is Vijay and he is not only of good character but was also assisting a young woman who had been sexually molested by the three men. Guilt-ridden, she withdraws her identification, bails out Vijay, and after a series of misunderstandings, both of them fall in love with each other, much to the chagrin of Sheela's lover and ex-husband, Vasu (aka King Cobra). Vasu has her stalked and photographed in a intimate photo with Vijay, blackmails, and even attempts to molest her, but is stopped by Vijay. This was Vijay and Sheela's last meeting. Years later they will meet again - this time Sheela will be a Judge and Vijay will be a man who has been accused of killing Vasu. Watch what happens during the trial and the impact Vijay's presence has on Sheela.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?224639</url></doc>
