<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="224683">
  <docid>224683</docid>
  <title>Gulf War Syndrome: Killing Our Own</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Martini, Christopher</editor>
    <editor>Muschamp, Tom</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>War</genre>
    <genre>History</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>tendonitis</keyword>
    <keyword>scleroderma</keyword>
    <keyword>skin-cancer</keyword>
    <keyword>hypodermic-needle</keyword>
    <keyword>iraq</keyword>
    <keyword>antibody</keyword>
    <keyword>vaccine</keyword>
    <keyword>cnn</keyword>
    <keyword>thyroid-cancer</keyword>
    <keyword>chronic-fatigue-syndrome</keyword>
    <keyword>biothrax</keyword>
    <keyword>gulf-war-illness</keyword>
    <keyword>soldier</keyword>
    <keyword>military</keyword>
    <keyword>lymphoma</keyword>
    <keyword>walter-reade-hospital</keyword>
    <keyword>anthrax-vaccine</keyword>
    <keyword>rheumatoid-arthritis</keyword>
    <keyword>depression</keyword>
    <keyword>anthrax-vaccine-immunization-program</keyword>
    <keyword>eczema</keyword>
    <keyword>tendon-rupture</keyword>
    <keyword>amyotrophic-lateral-sclerosis</keyword>
    <keyword>department-of-defense</keyword>
    <keyword>surgeon-general</keyword>
    <keyword>baghdad</keyword>
    <keyword>als</keyword>
    <keyword>gulf-war-syndrome</keyword>
    <keyword>adverse-reaction</keyword>
    <keyword>depleted-uranium</keyword>
    <keyword>birth-defects</keyword>
    <keyword>squalene</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">20 April 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">110</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Null, Gary</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Loudon, Manette</producer>
    <producer>Polonetsky, Richard</producer>
    <producer>Slater, David (V)</producer>
    <producer>Null, Gary</producer>
    <producer>Florosz, Zoi</producer>
    <producer>Lang, Kevin C.</producer>
    <producer>Loudon, Manette</producer>
    <producer>Muschamp, Tom</producer>
    <producer>Polonetsky, Richard</producer>
    <producer>Slater, David (V)</producer>
    <producer>Spratt, Rachel (II)</producer>
    <producer>Cooper, Sloane</producer>
    <producer>Goldman, Melissa</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Null, Gary</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bush, George W.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rokke, Doug</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>After the Vietnam War, hundreds of thousands of U.S. veterans suffered toxic reactions, neurological damage, and rare cancers due to exposure to 2,4,5,-D and 2,4,5-T dioxin that was used in the form of the defoliant Agent Orange. Unfortunately, the U.S. military denied the problem and failed to heed any of the lessons of this chemical butchery. Instead, it expanded its harmful legacy to the current generation of soldiers and civilians exposed to new, more deadly chemical toxins in the Persian Gulf. Join accomplished filmmaker Gary Null, PhD, as he explores the real truth about Gulf War Syndrome and the secrets about chemical and germ warfare that the U.S. government is hiding from its veterans and the public. Dr. Null uncovers the hidden truths about Gulf War Syndrome, including the deadly and toxic effects of armor-piercing radioactive depleted uranium, the use of experimental and risky vaccines on over 1,100,000 U.S. troops, and the indescribable chemical contamination and environmental devastation that the military caused during the Persian Gulf Wars. In this film, Dr. Null relies on compelling testimony from eyewitnesses who served in the military, leading doctors and scientists who specialize in chemical exposure, and those veterans still suffering from the effects of their tours of duty. Dr. Null goes further than ever before to explain the illnesses of Gulf veterans, including their rare cancers, neurological diseases, cardiac ailments, genetic mutations, and autoimmune conditions, ranging from chronic fatigue syndrome to lupus and scleroderma. "Post Traumatic Stress Syndrome" is the glib and demeaning explanation that the U.S. Government likes to give to injured veterans and their families. By revealing the truth about how and why American soldiers became ill while fighting overseas, this film sets the record straight and holds the government accountable for trivializing and covering up some of the major causes and consequences of Gulf War Syndrome. This film is also a scathing indictment of the practices and policies of modern warfare, and how they are causing massive illnesses that have never been seen before and which do not recognize political or geographic boundaries.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?224683</url></doc>
