<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="226651">
  <docid>226651</docid>
  <title>Haathon Ki Lakeeren</title>
  <year>1986</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Musical</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="UK">PG</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">139</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Anand, Chetan</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Anand, Chetan</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Singh, Veera</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Mohan, Pyare</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Aman, Zeenat</actor>
      <role>Geeta L. Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dalvi, Sudhir</actor>
      <role>Singing Fakeer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Bharat</actor>
      <role>Lalit's lawyer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Kamal</actor>
      <role>Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khote, Shubha</actor>
      <role>Leela B. Pratap</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Sanjeev (I)</actor>
      <role>Dr. Bhanu Pratap</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lal, Ram</actor>
      <role>Lalit's servant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mathur, Arun</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pandit, Yashodhan</actor>
      <role>Yashodhan 'Bantu' R. Singh Yadav</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sharma, P.K.</actor>
      <role>Major Ranvir Singh Yadav</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shroff, Jackie</actor>
      <role>Lalit Mohan Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Srivastav, Anjan</actor>
      <role>Doctor</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Geeta lives a poor lifestyle with her widowed mother in Bhavnagar, Gujarat, who works as a Nurse in a hospital run by Dr. Bhanu Pratap, while she herself sings and dances in a hotel. She is in love with wealthy Lalit Mohan Singh, who lives with his widower dad in a mansion. When Lalit informs his dad that he wants to marry Geeta, he is told to go abroad and forget about Geeta, which he does, leaving behind a pregnant Geeta, who gives birth, but is subsequently told by her mother that the child, a son, was born lifeless. Six years later Lalit returns home, cremates his dad, locates Geeta, they meet, patch-up, re-kindle their romance and get married. Geeta gets pregnant but the child is born lifeless, and the doctor tells Lalit that Geeta will not be able to conceive again. With her marriage on the rocks, her mother tells them that her son was very much alive, but she gave him up in order to prevent a stigma being cast on her daughter. They meet with Dr. Bhanu Pratap, who refuses to tell them who adopted the child. Subsequently, Lalit finds out that his son is living with a widow named Mala Singh Yadav. They confront Bhanu Pratap, and together attempt to convince Mala to release the child to them, but she refuses. Lalit takes the matter to Court, where the Judge appears to be convinced by Mala, but Lalit's wily lawyer has a surprise witness - who will eventually turn the entire case around - changing everyone's lives forever.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?226651</url></doc>
