<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="228115">
  <docid>228115</docid>
  <title>Hamba Kahle - Go Well</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Worden, Zachary</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>disabled</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Zulu</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">71</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Shepherd, John R.</director>
    <director>Worden, Zachary</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Shepherd, John R.</producer>
    <producer>Worden, Zach</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>Dube, Nkululeko, and Next are disabled young men struggling to live independently in their impoverished South African communities. Their path to success is hindered by prevalent social prejudices against persons with disabilities and a troubled South African job market where work is hard to find even for the able-bodied. Fifty percent of South Africans live below the poverty line and an estimated 95% of persons with disabilities are unemployed. The Achilles Track Club and Achilles South Africa sponsored these three athletes' journey to New York City and their participation in the 2007 ING New York City Marathon. Traveling overseas and competing in the marathon afforded them a unique opportunity to challenge conceptions of their abilities. Dube and Nkululeko both have cerebral palsy, are 18 years old, and graduated from the Ethembeni School for the Physically Disabled and Visually Impaired three weeks after the marathon. Dube grew up on a remote and meager subsistence farm, and Nkululeko in the impoverished township of Madadeni. More often than not in South Africa, black children with disabilities do not attend school as most schools are incapable of meeting their needs. The Ethembeni School provides its students with an education and opportunities to develop life skills and confidence. Ethembeni's mission is to help its students to reach their highest potential and to become independent and responsible citizens of the community. Next is a 28 year old man from the violent Johannesburg township of Alexandra. Six years ago he was shot in the head; an accident leaving him hemiplegic, brain-damaged, unemployed, and almost completely dependent on his destitute family for survival. Hamba Kahle is the story of three young men and their adventure to New York City; and how the experience impacts their attempts at independence. Can this journey help them escape the poverty that traps much of South Africa's disabled population?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?228115</url></doc>
