<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="228820">
  <docid>228820</docid>
  <title>Handyman Superstar Challenge</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Wright, George L.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Reality-TV</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>tv-mini-series</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">6 April 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">22</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Dolin, John</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Makepeace, Chris</producer>
    <producer>Dunlop, Kari</producer>
    <producer>Blasioli, Joseph</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kane, Allan</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bertelsen, Karen</actor>
      <role>Host</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Caruk, Jim</actor>
      <role>Judge</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Holmes, Mike (II)</actor>
      <role>Judge</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lutz, Shasta</actor>
      <role>Judge</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zwic, Richard</actor>
      <role>Contestant</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Building, renovating or repairing a home is an experience like no other. While it demands our precious time and finances it often shakes the very foundations of our instincts, emotions and patience. With so much on the line it's hardly surprising good contractors and handymen are universally coveted while the vast majority face suspicion or distrust. Even less surprising is how perfectly suited and increasingly popular this "good guys/bad guys" industry is for television - particularly shows that hinge on a handyman's craft or character, a homeowners money (or dreams) or - most importantly it seems - a credible and charismatic hosts' ability to help the viewer sift through it all. These days the best of them are a triple-threat package: on-camera guide, story protagonist and series defining character or "brand". In this, HGTV's inaugural HANDYMAN SUPERSTAR CHALLENGE, our goal is to find Canada's next great home reno or repair show "package" - a real handyman with real skill, real integrity and real enough star potential to host their very own show. Over the course of seven action-packed, half-hour episodes the HANDYMAN SUPERSTAR CHALLENGE will be a fun and revealing look at both what it takes and who it takes to "make it" in this unique television genre. To help us decide popular HGTV hosts Mike Holmes and Jim Caruk will form two-thirds of our judging panel. Judge number three will be a top Toronto- based female casting agent.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?228820</url></doc>
