<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="229271">
  <docid>229271</docid>
  <title>Hanste Zakhm</title>
  <year>1973</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Musical</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Anand, Chetan</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Anand, Chetan</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Mohan, Madan (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gopal, V.</actor>
      <role>Brahmswaroop (Taxi owner)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jeevan (I)</actor>
      <role>Kunan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Bharat</actor>
      <role>Somesh's friend</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Col.</actor>
      <role>DIG of Police</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Kamal</actor>
      <role>Daulat Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Satyendra</actor>
      <role>Inspector Kumar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mohan, Mac</actor>
      <role>Braganza</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Murad</actor>
      <role>DIG of Police</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nischol, Navin</actor>
      <role>Somesh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Parvez, Yunus</actor>
      <role>Hari/Dhoban's dad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Randhir</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sahni, Balraj</actor>
      <role>SP Dinanath Mahendru</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sapru, D.K.</actor>
      <role>Banwari</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sethi, Ram P.</actor>
      <role>Ganesh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Singh, K.N.</actor>
      <role>Chanda's patron</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Somesh lives a very wealthy lifestyle with businessman dad, Banwari, and housewife mom. His dad runs a bank, Canara Bank, and wants Somesh to take an active interest in helping him, Somesh spends all his time drinking alcohol, womanizing, and at the races. When Banwari asks Somesh to marry Rekha Mahendru, his friend's, Superintendent of Police, Dinanath's daughter, Somesh not only refuses but quarrels and leaves. Several weeks later, Somesh is apprehended by the police smoking cocaine and is brought back home. His father apologizes to him, and tells him that he will not force him to marry Rekha. Banwari wants to throw a big party on the bank's anniversary, and asks Somesh to invite all his new-found friends and taxi-drivers from the slums, who he had been living with when he ran away from home. That night a number of well-dressed dignitaries arrive for the party, so do Somesh's poor friends. His father wants to make an announcement about Somesh's forthcoming engagement to Rekha until a woman named Chanda shows up. Somesh is in with love with Chanda and will not marry anyone else but her. The only problem is that Chanda is a highly paid prostitute and may have snared Somesh with her charms merely to get to his wealth. Watch what happens when Banwari decides to disown Somesh, leaving him penniless.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?229271</url></doc>
