<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="229762">
  <docid>229762</docid>
  <title>Happy Valley</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Unguren, Ben</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>utah</keyword>
    <keyword>drug-abuse</keyword>
    <keyword>happy-valley</keyword>
    <keyword>prescription-drug-abuse</keyword>
    <keyword>heroin</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">PG-13</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">28 March 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Williams, R.K.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Smith, Craig (XXXIV)</producer>
    <producer>William, R.K.</producer>
    <producer>Fifield, Joe</producer>
    <producer>Barnett, Dan (IV)</producer>
    <producer>Williams, R.K.</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Gileadi, Yoni</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Allen, Danny (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Williams, R.K.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Deep in the heart of Utah, commonly referred to as "Happy Valley," residents enjoy one of the lowest crime rates, highest literacy and language fluency - even the most jello consumption - across the nation. Yet under the glossy exterior of this beautiful community, there are less popular categories that Happy Valley contends in but doesn't advertise, including prescription drug abuse, double the national average of anti-depressant drugs, even suicide. In Happy Valley at least one teen per week dies from drug overdose. The real-life true story, Happy Valley, sheds light on the growing problem of prescription drug abuse in Utah County and, as importantly, the associated issues of denial, conformity, social pressure and guilt. The film intimately follows several lives and families that have been dramatically affected by prescription drug abuse leading to street drug abuse and addiction. From these stories and a single father's journey to reunite a family emerge unconditional love, forgiveness, acceptance... even transformation.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?229762</url></doc>
