<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="229974">
  <docid>229974</docid>
  <title>Hard Choices: Counting the Days</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Australia">2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Australia">26</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Mullins, Anthony (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Mayfield, Nathan</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Mullins, Anthony (II)</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>When Michael Bleathman found out that the bowel cancer he'd been fighting would soon take his life, he dealt with it in the down-to-earth way he'd approached the rest of his life; he made a plan. Michael decided he wants to travel to Tasmania to show his only daughter Nicole his hometown as well as revisit where he and his wife Bonnie shared their honeymoon. Unfortunately, because of his condition, Michael can't fly from where he lives in Hervey Bay, Queensland. The family will have to drive the 3,000 kilometres to Tasmania. Despite Michael's determination Bonnie is worried the trip will exhaust him and threaten to cut down the time he has left. But Michael is determined to choose 'quality over quantity'. Bonnie with all her courage and strength rallies behind him even though she'd rather stay at home and make the most of it. But Michael has another reason to head south. On the way to Tasmania he hopes to visit his four sons from a previous marriage. They live in Canberra with their mother. There hasn't been much contact between Michael and his sons for some years now. This will be an opportunity to say goodbye. Within a few weeks however it is apparent that Michael is declining rapidly and Bonnie is increasingly anxious. They'll have to leave soon if Michael is to see through his plans.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?229974</url></doc>
