<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="229976">
  <docid>229976</docid>
  <title>Hard Choices: Little Sister</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Australia">2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Australia">26</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Mayfield, Nathan</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>Most people are flat out formulating a five-year plan, at twenty-two, Melissa Dwyer is about to make a decision which could give her a plan for life. A bit of a rough diamond, Melissa does not fit the typical "nun in the making stereotype". In fact, if she does join the Conassian Daughters of Charity she'll be the first ever PE teaching nun. For the last two years, Melissa has been living in a convent. Recently she wrote the letter that would facilitate the next stage of her journey into holy life. The fact that Sister Rosa, her formator, had to chase her for it several times is a telling illustration of Melissa's constant struggle with the decision making process involved in giving her life to Christ. Over the coming days, Melissa must decide whether she will renounce all her worldly goods. She is about to cut up her credit cards, shut down her bank accounts and is struggling with the idea that she will have no money of her own for the rest of her life. Melissa needs to move to a new convent to complete the next part of her religious journey. Although she has lived in an environment of diversity - the convent she lives in now has nuns from East Timor, Vietnam and Italy, Melissa finds the prospect of starting over at a new convent, with nine new nuns, extremely daunting, especially since it will coincide with further restrictions to her life. Up until now Melissa has maintained an active life, if she moves to the new convent she will not be allowed to go out when she chooses. While her friends can visit her, she worries that they won't. Many of Melissa's friends have found it hard to understand why she'd want to become a nun. She has already lost many friends from her days as an athlete. So far Melissa's life has been very exciting # working with the poor, attending international conferences, finishing her degree, enjoying life with the Sisters she's come to know and love. But things are about to change. Melissa's life at the new convent will be one of study and isolation. Will an extroverted 22-year old handle being locked away? Meet Melissa and decide for yourself.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?229976</url></doc>
