<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="231362">
  <docid>231362</docid>
  <title>Haste Hasate</title>
  <year>1998</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">18 October 1998</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="India">140</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Kalidas (IV)</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Kalidas (IV)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Lahiri, Bappi</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Asrani</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gokhale, Vikram</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hattangadi, Rohini</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Shehzad</actor>
      <role>Prince</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Riten</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sharma, Sanjay (VIII)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This is the story of a retired P.T. teacher (Vikram Gokhale) who wants to make an Olympic Champion for his country. On the course, he finds five boys each of them having some speciality. He starts training them. On the other hand, each boy falls in love with a girl. The teacher thinks that their friendship with the girls will affect their training, so he takes them to the house of his old student (Varsha Usgaonkar). They get the upper floor of her house on rent. During the same peroid, the teacher's relations with his wife get bad. On the next day, one of the five girls happens to be the sister of Varsha and she takes all her four friends to her home where their lovers were already present. Varsha decides that the girls will live with her on the ground floor. Then the training of the boys start. On the other hand, Prince, a gangster warns Varsha to give him her home because their was a treasure saved in the ground of her house. Varsha rejects and all the boys make an assault on Prince. In the neighbourhood of Varsha, there was an old lover of her living. The relations between him and her were bad. The five boys and girls try to get them united again. In the course, the training becomes side-lined and Vikram decides to leave the training. But after leaving, he does not go to his home and roams here and there. After some years, when he goes back to his home and thinks that what will be the condition of his wife for so many years. So he goes to his home and is surprised to find that all the five couples are living in his house and they are married and more surprisingly all of them have one child each. Then a new thought comes in his mind that why not he should train their children. So then, he decides to train the children and at the moment the movie ends.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?231362</url></doc>
