<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="231580">
  <docid>231580</docid>
  <title>Hatyara</title>
  <year>1998</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">A</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">1998</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Prasad, T.L.V.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Dhariwal, Mahendra</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Sen, Dilip</composer>
    <composer>Sen, Sameer</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhanushali, Kishore Anand</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chakraborty, Mithun</actor>
      <role>Advocate Mahendra/Surya</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dhawan, Anil (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Paintal</actor>
      <role>Pandey</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rami Reddy</actor>
      <role>Shishupal Singhania</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rishi, Mukesh</actor>
      <role>Singhania</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Kajal is a professor in a college. One day she witnesses the rape and subsequent death of a female student. She reports it to the police, and even identifies the killer, Shishupal. But the police are reluctant to take any action as the killer is the younger and pet brother of the city's most powerful and influential industrialist and gangster, Singhania. When she organizes a student and teacher protest, Shishupal is arrested and held in prison. This angers Sinhangia, who approached Kajal and asks her to refuse to testify against his brother, and for that he will give her a lot of money, but Kajal refuses to do so. When Kajal informs her advocate husband, Mahendra, who is handicapped and walks with a help of a crutch, she finds him supporting and encouraging. Singhania has Kajal raped and killed in front of Mahendra's eyes, and as a result with the only witness killed, Shishupal is released from prison. Mahendra, devastated and humiliated sets about to avenge the killing of his wife by taking Singhania to court, only to have the case dismissed. Mahendra sets upon to avenge his wife's death by deciding to kill the Singhania brothers and his gang one by one - but how is a handicapped person, who is unable to defend himself, carry out such a mammoth task on his own?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?231580</url></doc>
