<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="231883">
  <docid>231883</docid>
  <title>Have You Ever Heard About Vukovar?</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Guerif, Julien</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>War</genre>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>ptsd</keyword>
    <keyword>question-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>place-name-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>former-yugoslavia</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Egypt">October 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Russia">September 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Italy">20 September 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">April 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Borraccetti, Paolo</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Dalton, Seth</producer>
    <producer>Dornstreich, Elijah</producer>
    <producer>Lynch, Annie</producer>
    <producer>Mechanic, Zak</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Borraccetti, Paolo</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kirst, Patrick</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kuchan, Josip</actor>
      <role>Davor Skalko</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mayberry, Ash</actor>
      <role>Tim Davis</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Tim Davis, an American soldier from San Pedro (CA), has recently returned home from the war in Iraq. He is set to deliver a motivational speech for recruiting purposes at a career day in his old high school. However, there is a conflict of conscious: diagnosed with post-traumatic stress disorder, Tim struggles with the reality of integrating with civilian life as much as with returning to the war zone. Davor Skalko, a Croatian refuge from the city of Vukovar, which was under siege for months during the Yugoslavia war, is running late. He is the driver who is supposed to take Tim to the ceremony. Before Davor's arrival, Tim receives a letter from the Army headquarters that announces his call back to duty. The two are opposites: Davor is laid-back and cynical, while Tim is sensitive and intensely self-critical. It's the wrong day for Davor to display his proverbial sense of humor. While trying to get to the school in time for the ceremony, his sarcasm targets Tim's uniform, soda flavors and the cult of celebrity that permeates L.A. Tim takes him too seriously from the very first moment and every beat of their journey displays the clash of personalities. "Have you ever heard about Vukovar?" takes the audience into the car with these two characters through the alienation of present day Los Angeles and into the emotional rollercoaster that Tim and Davor are forced to take together. They will learn that, even if they come from opposite ends of the world, they have a life-changing experience in common: war and its aftermath. Through their struggle to get to the ceremony Tim and Davor will form an unexpected bond that will change their lives.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?231883</url></doc>
