<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="232102">
  <docid>232102</docid>
  <title>Hawas</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Verma, Sanjay (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>marriage</keyword>
    <keyword>murder</keyword>
    <keyword>lust</keyword>
    <keyword>affair</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>DTS</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">A</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">26 March 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Razdan, Karan</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Malik, Daboo</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ali, Shawar</actor>
      <role>Raj Mittal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arora, Tarun</actor>
      <role>Ajay Rastogi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Madina</actor>
      <role>Dancer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shaq, Vivek</actor>
      <role>Dubai Police Constable Hassan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tiwari, Mukesh</actor>
      <role>Dubai Police Inspector Rashid</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Indian Nationals, Raj Mittal and his beautiful wife, Sapna, reside in Dubai, United Arab Emirates, where Raj works for a British firm. Raj plans to accumulate enough money so that he and Sapna can re-locate to the United States, buy their own property and live the good life. In order to make money, he works day and night, leaving Sapna alone, without any company. Sapna usually ends up going shopping on her own or having coffee with some girlfriends (Rita &amp; Ramona). One day Sapna meets with an accident, a kindly passerby, Ajay Rastogi, offers help, even lends her a book. Attracted by Ajay, Sapna meets him again, and soon finds herself getting intimate with him. When Raj hints that he knows something is going on behind his back, Sapna immediately calls off the affair. Raj gets suspicious so much so that he hires a private detective to trail Sapna. Then both Raj's and Sapna's lives are turned upside down when the police find Ajay's dead body, and assign Inspector Rashid and Constable Hassan from Bushera Police Station to investigate his death. Watch as events unfold with this investigation, with the climax centering around the killer and the breakdown of the marriage of the Mittals.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?232102</url></doc>
