<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="233133">
  <docid>233133</docid>
  <title>Heart Attack</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Pearson, A.D.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Sport</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>new-york-city</keyword>
    <keyword>athlete</keyword>
    <keyword>runner</keyword>
    <keyword>death</keyword>
    <keyword>narration</keyword>
    <keyword>addiction</keyword>
    <keyword>running</keyword>
    <keyword>blind-date</keyword>
    <keyword>health</keyword>
    <keyword>college-student</keyword>
    <keyword>male-female-relationship</keyword>
    <keyword>love</keyword>
    <keyword>heart-attack</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">18 November 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">10</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Harris, David (XXIX)</director>
    <director>Pearson, A.D.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Harris, David (XXIX)</producer>
    <producer>Pearson, A.D.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Harris, David (XXIX)</writer>
    <writer>Pearson, A.D.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Beasley, Kenyatta (II)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bennett, Rachel Darden</actor>
      <role>Leslie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Claus, Andrew</actor>
      <role>A-hole Date</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cooper, Marcus Allen</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ealer, Rob</actor>
      <role>Mark</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fischer, Henning</actor>
      <role>Leslie's Ex</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gorton, Ryan</actor>
      <role>Ray - Shallow Date</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mikell, Gregory</actor>
      <role>Gay Date</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Reyes, Mikey</actor>
      <role>Rat Guy Date</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Selinger, Ari</actor>
      <role>Hotdog Man</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sokoloff, Jason</actor>
      <role>Bobby Kay</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sparrow, Abraham</actor>
      <role>Taxi Driver Date</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Taylor, Jeffrey (XI)</actor>
      <role>Track Coach</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zeins, Claude</actor>
      <role>Young Date</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Leslie stands in front of a white wall, smiling. She's a pretty girl, happily gazing at us. A narration ensues. This gentle voice describes Leslie's kind attributes and her most basic, yet great, goal: to find her true love. The narrator introduces us to Leslie's boyfriend. We are now in a park, and the narrator describes the scene: Leslie's boyfriend becomes Leslie's ex-boyfriend. Unfortunately, we next look at a moping, tearful Leslie blowing her nose, reading relationship books, and eating ice cream in her bed. She sobs profusely as the narrator informs us that this continues for two months, until miraculously Leslie conquers her depression and turns to the ritual of online-dating. She sits at her computer and discovers a match from the site blinddate.com, a "fun, handsome" man named Bobby Kay "looking for the one." Leslie accepts. She meets Bobby Kay, who quickly reveals that he has been married three times, and carries seven kids of baggage along with him. Leslie gazes at him in confusion and shock. We are next introduced to another man who explains he is in search of a physical relationship, who is then replaced by a third New Yorker explaining that he "kills rats." A fourth man appears, explaining his plan to remain a taxi driver for life. On a fifth date Leslie meets a man who has never "been with a woman before." Finally, she meets a man who brags of his ripe old age of seventeen. Leslie asks him to leave. A strong man approaches. The narrator describes his offer to take Leslie on a date to Central Park and she accepts. Alas, she is running late for the date. Leslie jumps from a cab, and is struck by a hot dog heavily topped with ketchup and mustard that spills all over her dress. Stunned, Leslie continues running only to be hit on the head by a soccer ball. When a disheveled Leslie finally shows up to the date, the man dismisses himself after seeing that she is utterly disgusting. From the distance another man approaches, offering to take his place. His gentle tone reveals that he is our narrator. To close the film, he recites, "And that was the day we met. I guess it was just meant to be."</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?233133</url></doc>
