<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="233658">
  <docid>233658</docid>
  <title>Heaven Is Empty</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Beckwith, Shawn</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">22 September 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">10</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="default">04</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Scaravelli, Darren</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Blackie, Patrick</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Scaravelli, Darren</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Reynolds, Christopher (III)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bennett, Nigel (I)</actor>
      <role>Doctor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Levert, Gary</actor>
      <role>Franklin</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Franklin has been institutionalized most of his life, Doctor Murray has been treating Franklin for more than 35 years. Dr. Murray having developed a fatherly relationship with Franklin decides to release him to have the chance to experience some quality of life outside the Asylum walls. The Doctor does not realize the gravity of his decision. Heaven is Empty is a film about an insane man's struggle with reality. We follow Franklin as he tries to grasp his own version of the truth and are given access to his twisted views and skewed perceptions. This film is touches on the consequences of a Doctor decisions when he let's his relationship with his patient dictate a grave decision. This film gives the audience a front row seat to the climatic insanity of a Doctor and patient as their relationship evolves into the chaotic fulcrum of their actions. In order to accomplish the story of Franklin's fall from reality, Heaven is Empty employs alternate visual styles as the audience is pulled through different perception of reality. Together with an astonishing use of color and sound to magnify the weight of the story, the audience will be met on sensory fronts throughout the journey.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?233658</url></doc>
