<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="234609">
  <docid>234609</docid>
  <title>Helden von heute</title>
  <year>1984</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Hundsbichler, Klaus</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>airplane</keyword>
    <keyword>movie-theater</keyword>
    <keyword>dance</keyword>
    <keyword>music-video</keyword>
    <keyword>big-city</keyword>
    <keyword>press-conference</keyword>
    <keyword>topless-woman</keyword>
    <keyword>telephone</keyword>
    <keyword>new-wave-music</keyword>
    <keyword>pop-star</keyword>
    <keyword>costume</keyword>
    <keyword>gang-war</keyword>
    <keyword>new-wave</keyword>
    <keyword>travel</keyword>
    <keyword>tribute</keyword>
    <keyword>hotel-room</keyword>
    <keyword>private-club</keyword>
    <keyword>new-romantic</keyword>
    <keyword>family-dinner</keyword>
    <keyword>castle</keyword>
    <keyword>erotica</keyword>
    <keyword>ballroom</keyword>
    <keyword>love-sick</keyword>
    <keyword>choreography</keyword>
    <keyword>female-nudity</keyword>
    <keyword>prison-escape</keyword>
    <keyword>pirate-ship</keyword>
    <keyword>limousine</keyword>
    <keyword>convertible</keyword>
    <keyword>ancient-egypt</keyword>
    <keyword>desert</keyword>
    <keyword>sphynx-cat</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>German</language>
    <language>Italian</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>West Germany</country>
    <country>Austria</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Austria">20 October 1984</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">49</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Dolezal, Rudi</director>
    <director>Rossacher, Hannes</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Dolezal, Rudi</producer>
    <producer>Rossacher, Hannes</producer>
    <producer>Zupan, Gebhard</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Dolezal, Rudi</writer>
    <writer>Rossacher, Hannes</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cimarolli, Brigitta</actor>
      <role>Falco's girlfriend</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Falco (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Heidinger, Johann</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ponger, Robert</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Thill, Marcus</actor>
      <role>Interviewer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Thomas, Henry (V)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Falco dreams of driving a convertible and performing in front of a jubilant audience. But then he wakes up in a prison cell in Chicago, United States. He breaks out and witnesses a turf war between a black gang and a white gang. After that, Falco visits his girlfriend. They go to a movie theater and watch a black-and-white romance film, that shows Falco as the leading actor. Afterwards Falco rambles about the city. He sees a strip club and decides to enter. There he meets several semi-nude female dancers. Falco rams against the wall. He winds up in the recording studio of his producer Robert Ponger. Change of scene: An aircraft cemetery in the near of Tucson, Arizona. Suddenly Falco appears. He is singing and dancing. The camera films the aircraft wrecks. A mechanic (also played by Falco) takes a rest, he looks out of the window and sees Falco. Then the mechanic plays with the one-armed bandit at his workshop. At the end, he had the right combination (three sailing ships). Change of scene: Falco performs on a pirate ship (the back-up dancers are dressed up as pirates). Change of scene: Falco holds a press conference, where he "explains his concrete attitude as a post-feministic man". Change of scene: Falco has dinner with a family. The atmosphere is quite boring. Falco grimaces and thus he makes the young daughter of the family laugh. The parents tell a joke, but Falco just rolls his eyes. He leaves the dinner to look around the house. Falco finds a roll of film and plays it back. This film is about some weird figures who dance in a ballroom. Falco appears in this movie and becomes part of it. Falco comes out of the castle. Then he goes by limousine. It brings him to Egypt, where he sees the pyramids.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?234609</url></doc>
