<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="234872">
  <docid>234872</docid>
  <title>Hell's Chain</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Glennon, Eamon</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>cage-fighting</keyword>
    <keyword>mixed-martial-arts</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">10 August 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Echavarria, Hector</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Arico, Alejandro</producer>
    <producer>Echavarria, Hector</producer>
    <producer>Petersen, Curtis</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Echavarria, Hector</writer>
    <writer>Johnson, Patrick (XXI)</writer>
    <writer>Toledo, Rafael Alfonso</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Echavarria, Hector</actor>
      <role>Robert Santos</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Herring, Heath</actor>
      <role>Lucas Owens</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jackson, Quinton 'Rampage'</actor>
      <role>Jackson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mir, Frank</actor>
      <role>Destroyer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nogueira, Antonio Rodrigo</actor>
      <role>Renegado</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Silva, Anderson</actor>
      <role>Sandro</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>St. Pierre, Georges</actor>
      <role>Stone</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>After killing a man in the ring, mixed martial arts champion Robert Santos struggles to cope with the guilt and bad fame that goes along with such an incident. His beautiful wife Melanie assures him that he is certainly a good man and he should not be affected by what apparently was an accident. Meanwhile Richard Wallace and Adam Corona, two detectives for the L.A.P.D, investigate a series of murders which all resemble satanic rituals, as well as Robert's murder case. Lucas Owens, the next contender to the title that Robert still holds happens to be the dead fighter's brother, he is torn between the consequences of the sport, the violent death of his brother, and the upcoming fight with his brothers killer Robert. A series of kidnappings and murders by a mysterious killer make these characters turn against each other and loose their real selves. Mors, the serial killer who has named himself after an ancient Greek demon, lives his life targeting sinners on the verge of redemption. Along side Millita, his lover and partner in crime, Mors performs gore filled rituals and dis figuration on his victims who are delivered to the next life by his trademark torture chains. Roberto hunts his nemesis to a lavish estate which quickly turns into a bloody battle ground. The action is non-stop as Roberto painfully learns how deep his wife's devotion truly is while going toe to toe with his greatest adversary, fear.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?234872</url></doc>
