<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="234853">
  <docid>234853</docid>
  <title>Hell to Pay</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Hovmand, Brian</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>acquitted-of-murder</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>DTS</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="UK">18</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">31 October 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">93</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Gomez Martin, Roberto</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Vernon, Austin</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Jones, Ryan S.</composer>
    <composer>Tricky (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Altman, John (II)</actor>
      <role>Policeman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bateman, Nicholas</actor>
      <role>Police officer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Beckwith, Andy</actor>
      <role>Detective Inspector Beek</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bushell, Garry</actor>
      <role>One of larry's goons</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Conway, Pete</actor>
      <role>Police man</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Courtney, Dave (I)</actor>
      <role>Dave Malone</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Freeman, Ian (II)</actor>
      <role>Cellmate</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Guest, Joanne</actor>
      <role>Police woman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hancock, Martin (I)</actor>
      <role>Martin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Keating, Helen (II)</actor>
      <role>Helen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Legeno, Dave</actor>
      <role>Big Vic</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lewis, Francine</actor>
      <role>Gangsters wife</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mac, J.C.</actor>
      <role>Mike-stripper</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mailey, Trevor</actor>
      <role>Hood</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Murray, Billy (I)</actor>
      <role>Larry Malone</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Saint, Adam</actor>
      <role>Adam</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Slimani, Chico</actor>
      <role>Stripper</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stone, Terry (IV)</actor>
      <role>Johnny Murphy</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Larry Malone sets up his brother Dave to get rid of Murphy, a rival gang leader, and then informs on Dave to have him convicted of murder. In one simple act of double-dealing he, consequently, removes both his main rivals and clears the way for expansive future plans for his crime family. After a few months on remand, Dave is acquitted at the Old Bailey after producing a fake videotape showing him entering a club on the night of the murders. Suspicious of his brother, Dave starts to question some of Larry's activities: especially his use of guns and his movement into the more lucrative drug scene. Larry, meanwhile, picks up Johnny, Murphy's son, when he is released from prison and using Johnny's need to revenge his father's death, employs him to track down and kill Dave, hence aiming to give himself total control of their crime family. Dave employs Freddie, the son of one of the gang who's died 'in service', to drop £100,000 off in order to buy a painting by Ronnie Kray which is being auctioned. Freddie hands the money to Barry, another member of the gang, who's promptly shot by Johnny. The money is Johnny's payment for the contract killing of Dave, and Dave is, in effect, inadvertently paying for his own execution. Larry has set up the snatch all along, but Freddie is blamed and goes to ground. Dave becomes increasingly suspicious of Larry: finding out, at first, that Barry has been shot and the money is missing; then that Johnny has been released from prison and is out to get him. Determined to strike first, Dave finds out where Johnny is and shoots him while he lies on a sun bed. Jim, one of Dave's oldest and most trusted sidekicks, has thrown his lot in with Larry. Jim's wife, still loyal to Dave, finds out about Jim's betrayal and tells Dave. With Freddie back on board, Dave confronts Jim and uses him to set up a meeting with Larry at an out-of-the-way breaker's yard. At the yard, both brothers confront each other with their rival halves of the gang, and a large-scale shootout takes place in which Dave's men finally win out. Dave, eventually, chases after Larry and regretfully shoots his brother with the handgun Larry had originally given him to protect himself.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?234853</url></doc>
