<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="235011">
  <docid>235011</docid>
  <title>Hellfire Society</title>
  <year>1992</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adult</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>sex</keyword>
    <keyword>beautiful-woman</keyword>
    <keyword>fetish</keyword>
    <keyword>bondage</keyword>
    <keyword>hardcore</keyword>
    <keyword>lesbianism</keyword>
    <keyword>female-nudity</keyword>
    <keyword>sadomasochism</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">X</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Comshaw, Lisa (I)</actor>
      <role>Cindy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kennedy, Patricia (II)</actor>
      <role>Nancy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lynn, Porsche</actor>
      <role>Mistress Mabel</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Bondage and discipline video from HOM, Inc. Kelly Nichols and Porsche Lynn are dominatrixes who belong to the Hellfire Club and who delight in welcoming slaves into the club. Those slaves include Fawna (Lisa Comshaw), Star Chandler, Trish Adams, and Patricia Kennedy, an assistant mistress who wants to be punished like a slave. Porsche brings her new slave Fawna over for Kelly's approval. When Cindy fails to impress Kelly, she is punished. Next, Porsche and Kelly inspect Kelly's new slave, Trish, who makes an impression on Porsche during her punishment. The mistresses leave Trish hanging while they proceed onward to put Star through her paces as Fawna watches sullenly. When tempers flare between Star and Fawna, they are strapped together and punished. Following this, Patricia announces her desire to be punished, and the two mistresses oblige her. When the two doms make their rounds on Fawna, Star, and Nancy, Porsche sneaks off for an illicit rendezvous with Trish. Naturally, Kelly discovers them, and Porsche is duly punished for breaking the rules of the Hellfire Club.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?235011</url></doc>
