<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="236153">
  <docid>236153</docid>
  <title>Her Indian Mother</title>
  <year>1910</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Western</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">16 December 1910</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Olcott, Sidney</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Olcott, Sidney</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Conway, Jack (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Joyce, Alice</actor>
      <role>Daughter</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In the wilds of the Hudson Bay region in the late 19th century, a young Hudson Bay Co. factor buys a young woman from a First Nations tribe from her father. His wife gives birth to a girl before he is unexpectedly ordered back to Montreal, after two years with his new family. The factor works his way up to company manager over the years, and he forgets his first family. Not hearing from her white husband, the woman eventually returns to her father with her child. On her sixteenth birthday, their grown-up daughter is presented with her late mother's armlet by her grandfather. On an inspection trip of the area, the man happens upon his own daughter by chance. He recognizes her by the armlet he had given her mother, and impressed with her beauty and her resemblance to himself, he gains permission from her grandfather to take her back to Montreal. She leaves her tribe, and her lover, behind and goes off with her father. In Montreal, she is educated and trained to be a "white" girl. Though she makes the transition to her new culture fairly well, one day, memories of her old life are rekindled by the reminiscences of an old trapper, just returned from the region. She finds her old buckskin dress, and jarred by her remembrances of the past, she returns to the people who raised her, clothed in her buckskin. Her heartbroken father returns to the Hudson Bay country to find her, but she is living with as the wife of a young brave, the lover she had left behind. The father resigns himself to his fate, that he has lost his daughter forever.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?236153</url></doc>
