<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="238254">
  <docid>238254</docid>
  <title>Heylaa</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Shifau, Ali</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <directors>
    <director>Fuad, Moomin</director>
    <director>Shifau, Ali</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Samee, Mohamed</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Fuad, Moomin</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Saeed, Shaaz</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Abbas, Zeenath</actor>
      <role>Shahulaa</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mauroof, Ahmed</actor>
      <role>Shuhaadh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Muaz, Abdulla</actor>
      <role>Supporting</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rasheed, Ismail</actor>
      <role>Ahammaa</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Shuhaadh is a fourteen year old boy whose parents are drug addicts. When the movie begins Shuhaadh's father Ahamma, who is also involved in petty drug deals, is brought from police custody to house arrest. Shuhaadh's mother is said to be in drug rehabilitation center. Ahamma is shown as a vicious man, who abuses Shuhaadh's physically and verbally. While Shuhaadh is portrayed as a self respecting, responsible and ambitious who wants to take care of his family and is ready to do any work which comes his way. Shuhaadh was dependent on some good neighbors until he comes across a mysterious man who entices him with high hopes getting out of the miserable situation and to become self sufficient. This man assigns Shuhaadh some work and even pays him before hand. Little did Shuhaadh realize that he was getting into more and more troubles? In the course of time Shuhaadh finds out that what he had got involved in was smuggling of a revolver. He gets totally confused. Just like any other boy of his age Shuhaadh gets curious and learns to fire it. How ever this dangerous weapon keeps haunting Shuhaadh and finally confides the secret to Ashraf, a neighbor who had always helped him. Ashraf advices Shuhaadh to call the police home and to hand over the weapon to them. Mean while Ahamma arranges a drug deal of drugs at home. When Shuhaadh gets to know about this he tries to save his father from police by pleading him to at least hold the deal. The ever vile Ahamma suspects Shuhaadh of conspiring against him and starts beating him violently. Shuhaadh looks him mind and gets into a whirlpool of disturbing thoughts. When he comes back to his senses he finds out that he had shot his father to death whom he loved despite all.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?238254</url></doc>
