<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="239161">
  <docid>239161</docid>
  <title>Higher Power</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kesler, Joel</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">22</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Weis, Eugene</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Weis, Eugene</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gallay, Daniel</actor>
      <role>Mike</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Milani, Dina</actor>
      <role>Nicole</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nelson, Peter (VII)</actor>
      <role>Dr. Conrad</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Higher Power follows the story of Mike, a young man who finds himself waking up in a Drug and Alcohol rehabilitation center. He is sick, worn out, and needs help. Mike is hesitant to the rules and regulations that he is subjected to conform to. He doesn't find any comfort or stability in the help or people offered to him. During his time at the treatment center, Mike meets and falls in love with Nicole, a female patient at the center; which is strictly against the rules. Through his new found friend, Mike finds himself in a safe and comforting place with her. Together they fall for one and other in a very carnal and passionate way. They depend on one and other in the same way that they depended on drugs. Mike is convinced that Nicole can be his 'road to salvation'. Mike feels that this new passionate and powerful love has filled the void in his life and he believes that Nicole is everything he needs to survive; but he not only brings himself down crashing but Nicole is there for the long road ahead which ends up hitting a dead end. Together the pair form an addiction to each other and a dependence that leads them into toxic circumstances.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?239161</url></doc>
