<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="239522">
  <docid>239522</docid>
  <title>Hiljainen tila</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kuittinen, Tuuli</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Finnish</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Finland</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Finland">13 February 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Finland">52</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Junkkonen, Mervi</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Paananen, Kimmo</producer>
    <producer>Ronkainen, Mika</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Junkkonen, Mervi</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Baars, Girilal</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Junkkonen, Maija</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Junkkonen, Pentti</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In the Autumn of 2002 the cows of the Junkkonen farm are taken to the slaughterhouse. The wheels of progress roll onwards, but two middle-aged people get left behind, Maija and Pentti Junkkonen. The small municipality of Oulunsalo is planning factories, business parks, and a new 4-lane road which would cut through the farmers' fields. The old ways of making a living are dying. The oldest daughter, director Mervi Junkkonen, realizes that she herself is part of the reason why her parents decided to give up their livelihood-there is no one to take over the farm. Through her father's 8mm films, she catches glimpses of the farm's history and a time when it was full of life. Now, Pentti (60), spends his time with his collection of tractors and some small-scale farming, but Maija (55) doesn't know what to do. Yet, life keeps taking tragic turns and old worries do not seem so important any more. About a Farm is the director's personal inquiry into a vanishing life-style and a history of which she is the last link. It is a story about the period of mourning people who give up their livelihoods go through and about the things that really matter in the end.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?239522</url></doc>
