<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="239681">
  <docid>239681</docid>
  <title>Himmatwala</title>
  <year>1983</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kotagiri, V.R.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>remake</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">25 February 1983</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">179</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Raghavendra Rao, K.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ghattamaneni, Hanumantha Rao</producer>
    <producer>Rao, G.A. Sheshagiri</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Khan, Kader (I)</writer>
    <writer>Raghavendra Rao, K.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Lahiri, Bappi</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anand, Shoma</actor>
      <role>Champa</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Asrani</actor>
      <role>Bhushan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Govil, Arun</actor>
      <role>Govind</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jeetendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Ravi D. Murti</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Satyendra</actor>
      <role>Dharam Murti (Ravi's father)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Shakti (I)</actor>
      <role>Shakti N. Gopaldas</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Amjad (I)</actor>
      <role>Sher Singh Bandookwala</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Kader (I)</actor>
      <role>Narayandas Gopaldas (Munimji)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Latkar, Sulochana</actor>
      <role>Govind's Grandmother</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Dharam Murti is a much respected school master in Shaktinagar in India, where he lives with his young son, Ravi, daughter, Padma, and wife, Savitri. One day he witnesses a man being being killed at the hands of Sher Singh Bandookwala, the Zamindar. He reports this matter to the police and Sher is arrested and prosecuted. Sher uses all his financial might to convince the courts of his innocence, and is set free. Then a few days later, Dharam is found in a compromising position with a new lady school-teacher, Menaka, is summoned by the local Panchayat, and asked to leave Shaktinagar for 30 days. Dharam leaves and does not return, leaving his wife and children alone and destitute. Savitri toils hard to provide education for Ravi, and for this she scarifies everything she has owned, and sends Ravi to her brother's place. Years later, Ravi is now an Engineer and returns home to Shaktinagar, is appalled to learn of his mom's and sister's destitute condition and vows to avenge this humiliation, and get the family decent accommodation. He sets his plan in motion to clear his father's name by openly challenging Sher. Before the plan could proceed further, Ravi finds out that Padma is pregnant and is in love with Shakti, the son of Sher's Munim, Narayandas Gopaldas, who agrees to this marriage at Sher's insistent - not because the couple love each other - but to torture Padma and keep Ravi subdued. With Ravi reined in, how will he be able to clear his father's name?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?239681</url></doc>
