<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="239832">
  <docid>239832</docid>
  <title>Hindukusch - Portrait eines Soldaten</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>von Boehm, Felix</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>War</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>wwii</keyword>
    <keyword>portrait</keyword>
    <keyword>soldier</keyword>
    <keyword>germany</keyword>
    <keyword>mission</keyword>
    <keyword>afghanistan</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>German</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Germany">12 November 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">28</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>von Boehm, Felix</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bertram, Ingmar</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>von Boehm, Felix</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Todsharow, Martin</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Since January 2002 German troops have been based in Afghanistan. "HINDU KUSH" portrays Marcel P., a young German army officer, who will begin his mission at the Hindu Kush in September 2008. The audience learns about his motives, thoughts and fears. The viewers also get to know Marcel's grandmother, who does not understand her grandson's decision to go to Afghanistan at all. The film "HINDU KUSH" quickly develops into a double portrait of two different generations, whose stances over war strongly diverge: on the one hand the generation of the grandmother that has been traumatized by World War II and on the other hand today's generation of a youth that doesn't know war but instead has been experiencing the international fight against terrorism. In intense and dramatic conversations Felix von Boehm tries to reflect the conflict between generations and the abstraction "HINDU KUSH": Who are these soldiers that "defend Germany at the Hindu Kush"? What's their motivation? Deliberately not showing scenes from the army barracks and military practices, the film attempts to get as close to its protagonists as possible and rather wants to avoid the stereotype picture of a soldier's everyday life.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?239832</url></doc>
