<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="240052">
  <docid>240052</docid>
  <title>Hiram na mukha</title>
  <year>1992</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>based-on-comic</keyword>
    <keyword>medical-doctor</keyword>
    <keyword>plastic-surgeon</keyword>
    <keyword>freak</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Tagalog</language>
    <language>Filipino</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Philippines</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Lamangan, Joel</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>del Rosario Jr., Vic</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Gomez, Pablo S.</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>De Leon, Christopher</actor>
      <role>Dr. Hugo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fernandez, Maritoni</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gil, Rosemarie</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Medved, Nanette</actor>
      <role>Carissa/Alicia</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Montano, Cesar</actor>
      <role>Mendez</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rivero, Dante</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Famous plastic surgeon Dr. Hugo (Christopher de Leon) worships the ground his fiancée Alicia (Nanette Medved) walks on. That is because he feels Alicia is his creation. From a monstrous carnivals freak attraction he has transformed her into a beautiful and glamorous woman. But Alicia learns that beauty is not everything. She finds it hard to discern if people like her for herself or for being a beautiful and rich woman. She yearns to be her former self, Carissa. As the ugly Carissa, she was sure that people who liked her really liked her. People like her former neighbor and lover, Mendez (Cesar Montano). So when it turns out that Mendez is Dr. Hugo's grandson, the former lovers take up where they let off and plan a scam to get Dr. Hugo's money. Alicia will wed Dr. Hugo and get him to transfer his properties in her name. Mendez will then kill his grandfather and the lovers will live happily ever after. That is, if the good doctor does not have a plan of his own. In fact, it might even be a plan as diabolical as their own.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?240052</url></doc>
