<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="241788">
  <docid>241788</docid>
  <title>Hitler</title>
  <year>1998</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">1998</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Canada">1998</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Prasad, T.L.V.</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Sen, Dilip</composer>
    <composer>Sen, Sameer</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anand, Vikas</actor>
      <role>IPS Officer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bahl, Mohnish</actor>
      <role>Monty Bhalla</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bakshi, Arun</actor>
      <role>Inspector Bakshi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Birje, Hemant</actor>
      <role>Vicky</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chakraborty, Mithun</actor>
      <role>Jailor Siddhant Kumar Sharma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dhawan, Anil (I)</actor>
      <role>Kishorilal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dhillon, Mangal</actor>
      <role>Dy. Jailor Sewak</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Satyendra</actor>
      <role>Daulatram</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lever, Johnny</actor>
      <role>O Men</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Nicknamed as "Hitler", Jailer Siddhanth Kumar Sharma is feared and respected at work as well as at home where he lives with his wife, a former lawyer, Sheila; younger brother, Amar; two younger sisters and his son. He would like Amar to find employment for himself on his merit rather than use his contacts, but Amar is unable to secure any employment. Then wealthy Daulatram insults Siddhanth, accuses him of using Amar as a ploy to fall in love with his daughter, Priya, so that the Sharma family can inherit his wealth. An angered Siddhanth confronts Amar, and is told that he has fallen in love with Priya and would like to marry her. Amar is angry with Daulatram and wants him to apologize to Siddhanth, an argument ensues between them, Amar grabs a knife and warns Daulatram. Shortly thereafter, the police arrest Amar for killing Daulatram. Siddhant disbelieves him, but Sheila decides to don her black gown and represent her brother-in-law, against the overwhelming evidence that has surfaced against him. It is now up to Sheila to not only defend Amar but also attempt to find out the reason behind Daulatram's death.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?241788</url></doc>
