<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="242162">
  <docid>242162</docid>
  <title>Ho Ho Nooooooo!!! It's Mr. Bill's Christmas Special!</title>
  <year>1996</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">16 July 1996</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Williams, Walter (IV)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Jansen, Jude</producer>
    <producer>Williams, Walter (IV)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Williams, Walter (IV)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Angelo, Hilary</actor>
      <role>Older Sister</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Novello, Don</actor>
      <role>Father Guido Sarducci</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Salvatore Jr., Jack</actor>
      <role>Little Brother</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>For longtime fans of Saturday Night Live, nothing says "Christmas" like clay, and the hapless hero of Walter Williams's sadistic skits brings it all back in this half-hour 1996 special. Those who can't stand watching the torture of static, crudely sculpted Play-Doh people might not see the humor as Mr. Bill's whole family is subjected to a wide array of holiday abuse--from the festive blendering of the egg dog to the explosive arrival of the sinister Santa Sluggo. Things are livened up by spiritual guest Father Guido Sarducci and his quest to find a real Christmas in sunny L.A., home of many former SNL actors and writers. Mr. Bill also takes a technological leap forward as a reluctant Scrooge in a computer-animated version of Dickens's A Christmas Carol. Humorous ads for some very simple toys also add to the fun and festivity. And when you think it's all over, keep watching--the real gem of the package is slipped in after the credits. It's an example of the real thing, a Mr. Bill SNL Christmas spot from the 1970s. Done on film rather than video, the old Mr. Bill seems much cruder but much, much funnier. In all, this video is worth a few laughs, and would make an ideal gift for fans and collectors.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?242162</url></doc>
