<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="242483">
  <docid>242483</docid>
  <title>Hogi Pyaar Ki Jeet</title>
  <year>1999</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">7 May 1999</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Vasu, P.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Sharma, Anil (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Chitragupth, Anand</composer>
    <composer>Chitragupth, Milind</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chouhan, Gajendra</actor>
      <role>Arjun Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dave, Ketki</actor>
      <role>Shalini</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Devgan, Ajay</actor>
      <role>Raju</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dhawan, Anil (I)</actor>
      <role>Surjit</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Joshi, Mohan</actor>
      <role>Thakur Gajendra Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kango, Mayuri</actor>
      <role>Preeti Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Murad, Raza</actor>
      <role>Minister Khurana</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Prithvi</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, Rajesh</actor>
      <role>Pandit</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Talsania, Tiku</actor>
      <role>Truck driver</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Warsi, Arshad</actor>
      <role>Kishan</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Surjit finds out that his sister is in love with Manjit Singh, the younger brother of Thakur Gajendra Singh. When his sister gets pregnant, Surjit goes to Thakur's house in order to get Manjit to marry his sister. The Thakur humiliates him, making him, a vegetarian, eat dog-food, and beg on his knees. Surjit does so, and is told to go home and make wedding preparations. The next day, Thakur visits Surjit and kills him and his wife in broad daylight. Surjit's last dying wish is that his two sons, Raju and Kishan, must get married to Thakur's two daughters, Megha and Preeti, and they must have the Thakur come begging to their doorstep for this marriage alliance. Surjit's sister agrees to this, and accordingly brings up the two children. Unfortunately, Raju decides to move away, leaving her alone to bring up Kishan. Years later, they are re-united when Raju returns home, and they join together to fulfill Surjit's last wish. What they do not know is Megha and Preeti are to be married to Minister Khurana's two sons, and nothing in the world is going to make the Thakur change his mind.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?242483</url></doc>
