<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="243101">
  <docid>243101</docid>
  <title>Hollywood</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Babu, Dinesh (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Musical</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>comic-hero</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Kannada</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">3 January 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="India">130</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Babu, D. Rajendra</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Babu, Dinesh (I)</writer>
    <writer>Upendra (III)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kiran, Guru</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dean, Emma (I)</actor>
      <role>Manisha's best friend</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mason, Felicity (II)</actor>
      <role>Manisha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nag, Anant</actor>
      <role>Professor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Upendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Sudeendra</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Surendra and Upi are identical twins. Surendra is a research scientist in Los Angeles working with professor. Upendra, a filmmaker from India, moves to L.A to live with his twin brother Surendra. Upendra's aim to is make an Oscar winning Hollywood film. A love triangle complicates the lot. Surendra is in love with the beautiful blond neighbor Manisha. Surendra is shy and Upendra is dashing. Surendra admires Manisha, but Manisha likes Upendra for his vigor. Surendra and the professor create a robot to fool Manisha into thinking it's Surendra with added charm. The professor's idea is to destroy the robot once Manisha falls in love with Surendra (the robot). In the process, the robot develops human emotions (a love for Manisha) and with superhuman strengths, the robot can not be stopped. To counter the robot, the professor creates a look-alike robot of Manisha. The USA mafia plots to kidnap the powerful human-like robots for their own use. The climax deals with putting an end to this troublesome triplet.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?243101</url></doc>
