<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="243688">
  <docid>243688</docid>
  <title>Holy for Me</title>
  <year>1995</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>fake-documentary</keyword>
    <keyword>israel</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hebrew</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Israel</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">34</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Bernstein, Assaf</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Rosenblum, Amalia</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Baruch, Adam</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bernstein, Ory</actor>
      <role>Elias Siman-Tov</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Keren, Dror</actor>
      <role>Jonah Sidas</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Weiss, Ilan (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>For Jonah Sidas Tel Aviv is not just another busy and sticky Mediterranean beach town. Where other people see sweat and traffic jams, Jonah, a secular-Jew-turned-priest but otherwise your average Israeli, sees holiness and the cross. Where most see a plain and crowded humus joint, Jonah sees a time-travel shuttle to the last supper; where most see a narrow beach decorated with jellyfish, cigarette butts and broken glass bottles he sees holy water and the footsteps of the Lord. Believing himself to be on a mission from God, and equipped with army jargon and the infamously poor Israeli street manners, Jonah is trying to make other people see Jesus' miracles and majesty where they are not commonly believed to reside. And what could be a better vehicle for promoting his cause than a job as a tour guide? A documentary crew follows Jonah and his pilgrims through the streets of Tel Aviv, as the filmmakers try to answer such questions as: Who is Jonah Sidas? Why did he convert from Judaism to Catholicism? Do people see him as a con man? And of course - is he out of his bloody mind ?!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?243688</url></doc>
