<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="243826">
  <docid>243826</docid>
  <title>Home Alone 2: Lost in New York</title>
  <year>1992</year>
  <type>VideoGame</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>elevator</keyword>
    <keyword>park</keyword>
    <keyword>based-on-film</keyword>
    <keyword>tree</keyword>
    <keyword>pigeon</keyword>
    <keyword>surrealism</keyword>
    <keyword>video-game</keyword>
    <keyword>vacuum-cleaner</keyword>
    <keyword>staff</keyword>
    <keyword>lost-family</keyword>
    <keyword>friendship</keyword>
    <keyword>trap</keyword>
    <keyword>burglary</keyword>
    <keyword>dove</keyword>
    <keyword>family-relationships</keyword>
    <keyword>christmas-tree</keyword>
    <keyword>home-alone</keyword>
    <keyword>new-york</keyword>
    <keyword>child</keyword>
    <keyword>hotel</keyword>
    <keyword>maid</keyword>
    <keyword>kid-outsmarts-adult</keyword>
    <keyword>christmas</keyword>
    <keyword>townhouse</keyword>
    <keyword>roof</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Unrated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <composers>
    <composer>Van Hecke, Mark</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Look out New York, Kevin's back and this time he's lost in the Big Apple! Here's the scoop: The nosey staff at the Plaza Hotel know that Kevin has used a stolen credit card and they are all after him, but they're not the only ones: Harry Lime and Marv Merchants, who've escaped from prison, travel to New York and get wind that Kevin's around so they round up a few of their "friends". Kevin must get through the Plaza Hotel while avoiding: bellhops, bellboys, maids, guests, suitcases, even vacuum cleaners! Travel up five floors of fury then take the elevator down to the Kitchen. Watch out for the chefs, and the Head Chef who will have a bone to pick with you. After you escape, Harry and Marv greet you, but you escape and end up in Central Park which is packed with criminals, even angry pigeons in the sewer. Avoid them and head to Uncle Rob's townhouse! Now the townhouse is under renovation so there are holes in the floor and plaster falling from the ceiling. Harry and Marv also await you, so watch out! Complete the three floors then escape from Harry and Marv from the roof into downtown, then race to the top of the Christmas tree in Rockafellar Plaza, there the Bird Woman will have her pigeons defeat Harry and Marv, so Kevin can get home to his family for a Christmas they'll never forget, and Harry and Marv can spend some quality time in county lock-up.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?243826</url></doc>
