<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="244136">
  <docid>244136</docid>
  <title>HomeGrown: HipLife in Ghana</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Ghana</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">58</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Jacobs-Fantauzzi, Eli</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Panji</actor>
      <role>Panji</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rockstone, Reggie</actor>
      <role>Reggie Rockstone</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tac, Tic</actor>
      <role>Tic Tac</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tinny</actor>
      <role>Tinny</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vip</actor>
      <role>Vision In Progress</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>West Africa has a long-standing tradition of traveling storytellers known as Griots (pronounced GREE oh), who combine poetry, music, and oral history. In Ghana, a group of young Africans are continuing this legacy and have captured the attention of international audiences. Over the past decade, Hip-Hop music has merged with High-Life, the traditional music of West Africa, and this fusion has led to the birth of a new musical genre called HipLife. HomeGrown: HipLife in Ghana, is a feature-length documentary about V.I.P. (Vision In Progress). The film documents ten years of their journey from the ghetto in Accra to their first international tour. They grow from being teenagers with a shared dream to musicians with fans around the world. The tension between traditional values and international stardom unfolds in the film's dynamic story-line. The final footage shows V.I.P. on tour in Europe, South African, and the United States, being received by enormous crowds. The viewer is given an intense experience of the excitement surrounding the group's success and from witnessing the international explosion of HipLife music.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?244136</url></doc>
