<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="245364">
  <docid>245364</docid>
  <title>Hope Not Lost</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Aguirre, Jeffery (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>News</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">17 October 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">27</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Rem, Jason</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Aguirre, Margaret (I)</producer>
    <producer>Fitzgerald, Melissa (I)</producer>
    <producer>Rem, Heather Mara</producer>
    <producer>Rem, Jason</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Rem, Jason</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Aguirre, Jeffery (II)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fitzgerald, Melissa (I)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sheen, Martin</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>It has been called one of the most under-reported humanitarian crises in the world today. Uganda has suffered through decades of civil war. While parts of the country emerged from conflict and established some sort of peace, an ongoing rebellion in the north by the Lord's Resistance Army killed tens of thousands of innocent civilians and forced nearly two million others to flee from their homes. In the documentary "Hope Not Lost," Melissa Fitzgerald journeys to Uganda with International Medical Corps to bear witness to this crisis first-hand and give voice to those who for years have suffered in silence. "Hope Not Lost", which was recently screened at Warner Bros. Studios, provides a rare, unflinching look at the impact of war in Uganda - on the health, the livelihoods, the culture and the future of its people. "Hope Not Lost," featuring actress and activist Melissa Fitzgerald. Narrated by Martin Sheen. Synopsis It has been called one of the most under-reported humanitarian crises in the world today. Uganda has suffered through decades of civil war. While parts of the country emerged from conflict and established some sort of peace, an ongoing rebellion in the north by the Lord's Resistance Army killed tens of thousands of innocent civilians and forced nearly two million others to flee from their homes. In the documentary "Hope Not Lost," Melissa Fitzgerald journeys to Uganda with International Medical Corps to bear witness to this crisis first-hand and give voice to those who for years have suffered in silence. "Hope Not Lost", which was recently screened at Warner Bros. Studios, provides a rare, unflinching look at the impact of war in Uganda - on the health, the livelihoods, the culture and the future of its people.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?245364</url></doc>
