<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="246751">
  <docid>246751</docid>
  <title>Hot Streak</title>
  <year>1986</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Game-Show</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>non-fiction</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">6 January 1986</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Marcione, James</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Lucas, Caryn</producer>
    <producer>Speakman, Roger</producer>
    <producer>Noah, Robert</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Ellis, Marc (I)</composer>
    <composer>Ellis, Ray (III)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Forsyth, Bruce</actor>
      <role>Himself - Host</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Plendl, Mat</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Roddy, Rod</actor>
      <role>Announcer (pilot only)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Summers, Marc</actor>
      <role>Announcer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Winters, Anthony</actor>
      <role>Himself - Contestant (1986)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wood, Gene (I)</actor>
      <role>Announcer (1986)</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Unique, but short-lived game on ABC daytime. Two teams of 5 players, men vs. women, competed. In the main game, one member of the team would be given a secret word and would give a description of the word to the next teammate. Once he/she guessed it correctly, s/he would give the next teammate a description of the word, and so forth. This continued down the line, with 40 seconds given for all 4 "guessers" to name the secret word. The catch was, no "key words" could be duplicated in the various descriptions of the word or else scoring for that secret word would stop. Adding to the difficulty of this task was the fact that the guessers wore headphones that prevented them from hearing how the secret word was described by teammates earlier in the round. Each team had a chance to guess 3 words, and the team with the highest score at the end of the 3 rounds played the bonus round, which was an inverse of the main game. The bonus round was played in 3 rounds. In each round, a team captain was designated and given a word or topic. S/he would then pick 4 words/phrases s/he thought were most associated with the word. The other 4 members of the team wore headphones while the captain picked her 4 clues. The team would hear the topic and then have 20 seconds (5 seconds each) to try to guess the 4 clues that the captain had picked. The first two rounds earned money for a bonus bank each time one of the clues was guessed, while the final round was an all or nothing round that, if won, multiplied the bank earnings by five.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?246751</url></doc>
