<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="248494">
  <docid>248494</docid>
  <title>How to Boil a Frog</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Grave, David (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>collapse</keyword>
    <keyword>overpopulation</keyword>
    <keyword>peak-oil</keyword>
    <keyword>revolution</keyword>
    <keyword>climate-change</keyword>
    <keyword>global-warming</keyword>
    <keyword>economics</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Cooksey, Jon</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Cooksey, Jon</producer>
    <producer>Woods-McArter, Teri</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Cooksey, Jon</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cooksey, Jon</actor>
      <role>Conductor</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>How to Boil a Frog is an eco-comedy that gives an overview of the Big Mess We're In - environment, energy, economic - and lays out a set of personal solutions that will make your life better and save civilization as a by-product. HTBAF chronicles Jon Cooksey's personal, three-year adventure as a filmmaker, activist and, above all, a father driven to make sure his daughter would have a future beyond living on a raft with the last polar bear. HTBAF mixes humor, facts and a sprinkling of experts (in tiny doses) to show how climate change is just one symptom of an even messier problem: overshoot. "Overshoot means too many people using up too little planet," says Cooksey, "so in the end, we either need fewer people, more planets, or we're going to have use less stuff. Or all three. I dib Mars." With its Everyman approach in the style of "Supersize Me", interviews with scientists, journalists and energy experts across North America, HTBAF takes the kind of information that makes most people want to jump off a bridge and makes it into entertainment that just might save your life, and everybody else's too.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?248494</url></doc>
