<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="248625">
  <docid>248625</docid>
  <title>How to Kill Your Girlfriend's Cat</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Munster, Bobby</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>cat</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">18</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Hall, Kevin (IV)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Munster, Bobby</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Fair, Allan</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Berke, Johanna</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Honeycutt</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brown, Craig A.</actor>
      <role>Brent</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bulla, Burt</actor>
      <role>Little ol Lady</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dolce, Katie</actor>
      <role>Lindsey Honeycutt</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McBrien, Susan</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Smith</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Schwarz, Ken</actor>
      <role>Sherman Honeycutt</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wann, Keith</actor>
      <role>Moses</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Woertendyke, Max</actor>
      <role>Myles Cooley</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zahn, Rick</actor>
      <role>Mr. Smith</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Hapless teenager Myles Cooley has all the hopes and dreams of an average young man. To be successful in school, to be loved by his girlfriend and to win the approval of her father. Unfortunately for Myles, Melinda's father has dreams and aspirations of his own and none of them include Myles. After several aggravating confrontations with the family cat, Mr. Honeycutt decides to eliminate the boyfriend and the cat problem all at once. While preparing to leave on a week long vacation, Mr. Honeycutt secretly instructs Myles to 'take care' of the family cat, Uncle Fugly, while they are away. Not wanting to disappoint Mr. Honeycutt, a reluctant Myles embarks on a series of misadventures that take him deep into the strange and esoteric world of cat killing consultants. During his journey he learns not only how to get rid of a pesky feline, but in a strange way, also how to become a man. But when the time comes can he do it? Even if he does eliminate Uncle Fugly, will Mr. Honeycutt ever truly accept him? There's only one way to know for sure, Myles will have to learn, How to Kill your Girlfriend's Cat.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?248625</url></doc>
