<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="249368">
  <docid>249368</docid>
  <title>Huanglian houpu</title>
  <year>2000</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>custom</keyword>
    <keyword>doctor</keyword>
    <keyword>female-doctor</keyword>
    <keyword>abortion-scene</keyword>
    <keyword>cross-cultural</keyword>
    <keyword>based-on-novel</keyword>
    <keyword>ex-daughter-in-law</keyword>
    <keyword>herbs</keyword>
    <keyword>tradition</keyword>
    <keyword>cultural-conflict</keyword>
    <keyword>flashback-sequence</keyword>
    <keyword>divorce</keyword>
    <keyword>medical</keyword>
    <keyword>intellectual</keyword>
    <keyword>interracial-relationship</keyword>
    <keyword>christmas</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Mandarin</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Singapore">PG</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Singapore">20 September 2000</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Ding, Yinnan</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zhu, Xu</actor>
      <role>Guan Juchen</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This family tale spans three generations of Chinese trying to understand and come to terms with life's changes. Middlesome relatives stir up a storm. The old and the young find themselves and their values developing and evolving, and new relationships come and go. The eldest family member, Guan, the son of a royal physician of the former Qing Dynasty, has also become a great physician who is able to predict the exact time of a patient's death. His ex-daughter-in-law, Yu, trained by him to be a physician, still stays with the family as his assistant. Her ex-husband, Jin, comes back from the USA with his new girlfriend, Jenny, a beautiful American who is doing a research on the death of Guangxu, the second last Emperor of Qing Dynasty who is Guan's father's patient. Jenny speaks fluent Mandarin, but she has a long way to go before understanding and getting accustomed to the Chinese tradition and mindset. On the other hand, Yu falls in love with her old friend who is a married man. Jin takes the opportunity to send an anonymous letter to the man's wife which results in a mess in the family. Mr. &amp; Mrs. Guan and Jenny strongly disapprove of Jin's "face-saving" revenge. Jenny decides to break up with Jin, although her friendship with the rest of the family members remains...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?249368</url></doc>
