<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="249872">
  <docid>249872</docid>
  <title>Hum To Chale Pardes</title>
  <year>1988</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">29 July 1988</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Peepat, Ravindra</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Peepat, Ravindra</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Rajiv</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Shashi (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kharbanda, Kulbhushan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mahendru, Anju</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mandakini</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mittal, Mehar</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pandey, Sudhir</actor>
      <role>Doctor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rindani, Shiva</actor>
      <role>Kashmir Eve-teaser</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sethi, Ram P.</actor>
      <role>Dr. Sethi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shankar, Girja</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Kumar and Suman have been married for many years, but do not have any children. When Suman does get pregnant, gives birth to a baby girl, but is not expected to live, on her deathbed she asks Kumar to promise that he will take good care of their daughter, never re-marry, and after Kumar promises, she passes away. Kumar names his daughter Priya and grows very attached to her. Years later, Priya has grown up and there is a strong bond between father and daughter. She is now of marriageable age, and her marriage is arranged to London-based Ajay Mehra, her childhood sweetheart. The marriage is only allowed to take place after Ajay and his mom, Anu, promise to re-locate and settle in India. After the marriage takes place, neither Priya and Kumar are able to stay away from each other, leading to bitterness in the Mehra family, which results in Kumar asking Priya not to come to his house anymore. Hurt and heartbroken, a pregnant Priya agrees to move to London, and does not communicate with her dad at all. Then several months later, they find out that Kumar has had a heart attack and the family returns to India. The shock of seeing her ill dad has a negative effect on Priya's pregnancy, and the doctor asks Ajay to make a choice whether to save Priya or their child. While Anu wants the child, Kumar wants his daughter - and Ajay is the only one who has to decide. The question is what will Ajay decide under these circumstances, especially after being told that Priya will never be able to have children again.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?249872</url></doc>
