<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="250601">
  <docid>250601</docid>
  <title>Hurenkarussell</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Jacob, Cajetan</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>German</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Austria</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Austria">11 April 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">4 June 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">85</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="Austria">85</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Jacob, Cajetan</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hutterer, Bettina</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Jacob, Cajetan</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bonn, Georg</actor>
      <role>erster Freier</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Halus, Rebeka</actor>
      <role>Dienstmädchen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kaim, Magdalena</actor>
      <role>Marie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kotsios, Heike</actor>
      <role>Anna - Tochter des Grafen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Liebmann, Hannes</actor>
      <role>Fahrgast</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lieder, Günter (I)</actor>
      <role>Freier mit Kuchen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Makowski, Maja</actor>
      <role>Grete</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wittmann, Kilian</actor>
      <role>Straßenjunge</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Öttl, Andreas</actor>
      <role>Polizist</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>1905: Syphilis and prostitution flourish in a small town somewhere in the Danube monarchy. Though prostitution is officially prohibited, the panderers have found a way to bypass the law. Children run through the streets and do the pimping. In the midst of the night stands Marie, a young prostitute, who has learned how to live in this shady environment. She dwells together with Grete, her pregnant colleague, and some other whores at the brothel on the outskirts of town. Marie's encounters with johns have many faces; notorious bon vivants, an old man who brings cake from his wife, and Count Albin, a lofty gentleman whose behavior is very strange. Before Marie sleeps with him, she must tie a blue band with white dots around her thigh. The next day she encounters the Count shopping with his twelve year old daughter, Anna. It's apparent that Anna who wears a blue band with white dots in her hair is afraid of her father. Marie is deeply touched by Anna's emotional state which provokes her curiosity about the child. As she investigates Anna's situation Marie's humanity is revealed. It's ironic that a girl, Anna, of noble origins finds a motherly role model in Marie the prostitute. Because of this relationship the brothel is transformed into a nursery and Marie's bed becomes a safe haven from a pedophile father. Marie herself is also transformed into a loving, motherly individual.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?250601</url></doc>
