<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="253243">
  <docid>253243</docid>
  <title>I Wanna Play House</title>
  <year>1936</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Brown, Treg</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>merrie-melodies</keyword>
    <keyword>bear</keyword>
    <keyword>cartoon</keyword>
    <keyword>turtle</keyword>
    <keyword>hide-and-seek</keyword>
    <keyword>house-trailer</keyword>
    <keyword>drunk-scene</keyword>
    <keyword>kids-and-family</keyword>
    <keyword>spanking</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">11 January 1936</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">7</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Freleng, Friz</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Schlesinger, Leon</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Brown, Bernard B.</composer>
    <composer>Spencer, Norman (IV)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hansen, Bernice</actor>
      <role>Little Bears</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Two bear cubs, one black, one brown, frolic near their sleeping father. The black one chases a turtle, who turns around and nips him on the nose. The brown one laughs at this; the black one throws a rock, but he ducks and it hits papa's head. When each blames the other, he arbitrarily spanks the brown one. The black one next suggests they play hide-and-seek. He runs off and hides in a trailer, where he makes a sandwich and washes it down with cider. Feeling tipsy, he puts on a hat in front of a mirror and sings. The brown cub, having counted to a million, finds him. They fight, and in the process, release the brakes, sending the trailer careening down a narrow mountain road. It crashes into a tree, sending the cubs and the contents flying. The cider jug hits the brown bear on the head, making him woozy. Papa comes running, but seeing the jug and his son's actions, comes to the wrong conclusion and paddles him again. The black one thinks he's gotten away scot-free, but the brown one throws another rock at him.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?253243</url></doc>
