<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="253221">
  <docid>253221</docid>
  <title>I Wanna Be a Republican</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bielenberg, Ken</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>drag</keyword>
    <keyword>concert</keyword>
    <keyword>gay</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">21 June 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">84</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Bielenberg, Ken</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ruvalcaba, Alonzo</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Dilley, Chris</writer>
    <writer>Keller, Irwin</writer>
    <writer>Manabat, Jeff</writer>
    <writer>Schatz, Ben</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dilley, Chris</actor>
      <role>Trampolina</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Keller, Irwin</actor>
      <role>Winnie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Manabat, Jeff</actor>
      <role>Trixie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Schatz, Ben</actor>
      <role>Rachel</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In their first live concert film, the Kinsey Sicks -- America's Favorite Dragapella Beautyshop Quartet -- reveal the shocking news: they have gone Republican. In this mock GOP fund-raiser, Rachel, Winnie, Trixie and Trampolina, the four gifted singers and comedians who comprise the quartet, defend their conversion to conservatism. They sing -- literally! -- the praises of corruption, tokenism, greed and all things nuclear (both families and bombs). The Kinsey Sicks have been a cult phenomenon for over a decade. From Off-Broadway to Vegas and beyond, the larger-than-life Kinsey Sicks have developed a loyal following among comedy fans, music aficionados and lovers of biting political satire. Their hilarious, intelligent writing and their finely spiced menu of thought-provoking original songs and wicked parodies have won them a Lucille Lortel Award nomination for Best Musical and a Drama Desk Award nomination for Best Lyrics. They have won numerous a cappella awards and the New York Times has praised their "voices sweet as birdsong."</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?253221</url></doc>
