<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="255672">
  <docid>255672</docid>
  <title>Ice Girls</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Harkema, Reginald</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>ice-skating</keyword>
    <keyword>ice-rink</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>ice</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">9 January 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Dolman, Trish</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hamilton, Brian (II)</producer>
    <producer>Mallen, Leah</producer>
    <producer>Dolman, Trish</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Dolman, Trish</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Malcomson, Hettie</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hodges, Vikki</actor>
      <role>Subject of Film</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Holmes, Jennifer (II)</actor>
      <role>Subject of Film</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>5:00 am practices. Tutors. Weight training. Injuries. Dedication to a single cause since the time they could walk. All for a career that can peak at age fifteen. For the three teenage girls whose lives are chronicled in the feature length documentary Ice Girls, this is the reality behind "the most glamorous sport in the world" - international women's figure skating. Ice Girls is the story of three elite young figure skaters - the UK's Jennifer Holmes and Vikki Hodges and Canada's Keyla Ohs - as they pursue their dreams of one day picking roses off the ice and ascending the Olympic podium. Shot over three years, Ice Girls provides a behind-the-scenes look at these girls' lives and their dedication to a sport that demands tremendous physical power and psychological strength. In a world where the cost of competing can eat up a family's savings, winning is a matter of national pride, and anything less than perfect performance doesn't make the grade, Ice Girls celebrates the dedication and courage of three young women as they pursue their dreams of figure skating stardom.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?255672</url></doc>
