<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="257714">
  <docid>257714</docid>
  <title>Il cembalo della luna</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Di Franco, Linda</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Italian</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby SR</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Italy">2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Italy">85</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Ricagni, Leonardo</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>McVicar, Daniel</producer>
    <producer>Tosi, Davide</producer>
    <producer>Campanile, Luigi</producer>
    <producer>Campanile, Luigi</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>De Bellis, Fabiana</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Angelo, a young teacher of Anthropology, has returned to Salento after a six-year absence. His homecoming, however, has a few surprises in store. Angelo must again face his past and a homeland which reveals itself to be ambiguous and hostile. The places that were, until only a few years previously, familiar and recognizable, now manipulate him, attracting him and repulsing him, sending him mysterious messages that Angelo struggles to comprehend. The protagonist is catapulted almost blindly into a world somewhere between dream and reality. The sting of a scorpion (the tarantula), metaphorically marks the beginning of his journey: deep in the ancient culture of a Salento full of emotion, in its legends, superstitions, pagan rituals that Angelo relives, being bewitched by the notes of tarantula; In the arc of a couple of months, Angelo sees the crumbling of his emotions. His one-time friend, Totò, has become a small-time crook who pushes his young daughter Giada into a life of prostitution. The women he comes into contact with force him to confront an uncomfortable past. His meeting with Shaula, a sensual, liberal woman, helps release him from an oppressive situation. Having become so detached from a world of poison, but not so much from himself, Angelo has no choice but to assert himself and maintain his own integrity in an extreme act of liberation.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?257714</url></doc>
