<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="259827">
  <docid>259827</docid>
  <title>Ilan the Security Guard</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Berkovich, Itay</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hebrew</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>International Recording Engineers System</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Israel</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Israel">14 September 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Kamer, Nimrod</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kamer, Nimrod</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Lonai, Ilan</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kamer, Nimrod</actor>
      <role>The Interrogator\Director</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lonai, Ilan</actor>
      <role>Lead role</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This is the story of Ilan, a lonely student in Jerusalem, who one day realizes that only the security guards in the city really care for him, as they keep on asking him for his well being as a part of their job. Thrilled by these findings Ilan decides to become a security guard himself. He sews himself an outfit and starts touring the city with his "Protector" - an apparent metal detector made out of corrugated cardboard. In the film accompanies him Nimrod, an acquaintance. Together they try to get to the true bottom of Ilan. Background: In the year of 2005 almost 70,000 security guards are being employed in Israel. They are considered to be about 4.7% of the total work force. Roughly a quarter is being employed in the city of Jerusalem, from which around one third is used for securing the public transport system; mainly the buses in the city center. One of the instructions given to those security guards is to ask pedestrians questions that would make sure that they speak Hebrew in a non-suspicious manner. The most frequent of questions is "How are you? ". Any attempt, by the pedestrian, not to answer the question is considered to be an unusual reaction, intended to outsmart the security guard.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?259827</url></doc>
