<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="261032">
  <docid>261032</docid>
  <title>Imperfect</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Lewis, Carey</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>one-word-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">6 August 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">13</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Lewis, Carey</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Lewis, Carey</producer>
    <producer>Stevens, Susan (III)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Lewis, Carey</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>DiFrancesco, Ryan</actor>
      <role>Gavin</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Imperfect tells the story of how guilt rots away at you. Perfection is an impossible end to meet and if you focus on it for long enough, it will eventually destroy you from the inside- out. Always striving for, but never achieving the goal, it is an unfair thing to ask of anyone, least of all yourself. Gavin hasn't led a very good life and doesn't feel he deserves much of anything. When something good does come his way, he questions it over and over again, wondering why he's lucky enough to have it and what he's done to deserve it. Because he doesn't feel good enough to have anything of value, he subconsciously sabotages himself into losing it. Camden is somewhat blinded by her dreams for the future. She is so steadfast to achieve her plans, that she doesn't see the reality that is occurring around her. Sheltered all her life, Camden always finds a bright side to everything and chooses to ignore the things that contradict her goals. When she is forced to face what is really happening and her dream fall apart around her, it shatters her.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?261032</url></doc>
