<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="261852">
  <docid>261852</docid>
  <title>In Men We Trust</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Puchkoff, Carrie</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">7</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Pilieva, Tatia</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Amato, Jay</producer>
    <producer>Salort, Michael</producer>
    <producer>Schweitzer, Jenny</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Brogan, Maureen</writer>
    <writer>Salort, Michael</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Belardinelli, Daniel</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brady, Kelly</actor>
      <role>Emma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cash, Aya</actor>
      <role>Liza</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Coker, Tug</actor>
      <role>Chuck (2006)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cranmer, Alex</actor>
      <role>Peter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Francesca, Pierra</actor>
      <role>Candy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jonas, Phoebe</actor>
      <role>Mariel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kahn, Ian</actor>
      <role>Everett</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Larrabee, Adam</actor>
      <role>Restaurant Patron (2006)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Liotti, Frank</actor>
      <role>Sleazy Guy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Litman, Jody Kay</actor>
      <role>Joan (2006)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Webber, Nicholas</actor>
      <role>Jack</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zeller, Patrick</actor>
      <role>Harry</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>How does a smart, accomplished woman find a "good" man? As any woman knows, it's not easy. In fact, it's downright disturbing, disheartening and disabling. This core mission is the central plot line of IN MEN WE TRUST. When Liza, 26, Emma, 25, and Grace, 33, find themselves on a string of horrific dates, they turn to relationship guru, Mariel Cushing, to steer them to the promised land of worthwhile men. It would seem that Mariel's got the goods - she's a well-studied expert on the subject and she seems to have found the perfect man in handsome Everett Greer. So the ladies enroll in Mariel's relationship seminar: "DATING BOOT CAMP: FIND THE MAN YOU'RE SEARCHING FOR." But "tragedy" looms... after the class proceeds through a hilarious dating exercise, it's turned upside down when Mariel herself makes a shocking discovery: she uncovers Everett under covers with a gorgeous young blonde! Outraged and incensed, Mariel uses a pair of handcuffs to keep Everett hostage. After all, she wants answers! Why do men act this way? Then, Everett tells her why men do it - a revelation that shocks her theory on relationships to its very core. Miraculously, Everett insists on a second chance with Mariel, professing his love. Mariel agrees to a second chance, only if Everett submits to becoming her class 'guinea pig.' In the episodes that follow, the class and Mariel are rocked by Everett's insights on why men behave the way they do. In the end, the women are forever changed but Mariel must make a choice of whether to forgive Everett, choose a handsome suitor named Jack, or go it alone.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?261852</url></doc>
