<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="263142">
  <docid>263142</docid>
  <title>In the Heart of Gold Country</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">16 September 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">48</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Memisevic, Aida</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Memisevic, Aida</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Memisevic, Aida</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>In the Heart of Gold Country reveals the unusual character and life of a tiny Croatian-dominated mining community in of one of North America's largest gold producing areas. From the early 1900's the little town of Schumacher Ontario emanated a unique spirit and heart, nurtured through a close knit Croatian-Canadian community. This wonderful and distinct place reveals it's unique character through the stories of the residents. Schumacher is an extraordinary community that defies time and geographic barriers - past and current residents maintain a special bond; every five years, former residents (of varying cultures) return from all over Ontario, Canada and beyond, for a town reunion. Stories are recounted , memories shared and the connection that each resident felt as a member of this special town, is remembered and restored. In the center of the town is the Croatian Hall, the heart and soul of the community where social gatherings, weddings, christening and even funerals all took place. In this Croatian-Canadian community, babysitters were rarely considered; children attended events with their parents. It was truly a family based town. For many of the Croatian families, the Croatian Hall was not just a social gathering center, it was the heart beat; it was a second home. The tales are of community closeness, where Croatian families bonded as they adapted to their life in Canada while maintaining the essence of their European culture; stories that are heart warming and heartbreaking; memories of happiness and hardship and of near death experiences working in the gold mines of Ontario; memories of a very unique community. That sense of extended family closeness is a memory that Ed Mavrinac holds with him today. Ed lived his childhood in Schumacher, Ontario. Today at 53 he has had a significant career as a musician, teacher and ambassador of the Croatian community; an accomplishment recognized by the Governor General of Canada when he was awarded the 125th Anniversary Commemorative Medal. In the Heart of Gold Country takes us through Schumacher's present and past including a look a back through Ed Mavrinac's eyes; stories of his grandfather who worked in the gold mines for forty years; a man who was politically active becoming President of the "Croatian Peasant Society" a group promoting social justices. We visit with his and other families as they share their memories of working in the gold mines. In the early days with little equipment and meager safety gear, hard working immigrants forged the landscape for one of North America's largest gold producing areas. Schumacher, a small town, once having a population of 4000 (people) boasted one of the highest percentage of Croats in Canada from 1940 to 1960. The Croatian community of Schumacher was then called "Mali Zagreb" translated as "Little Zagreb" - referring to the capital city of Croatia. Today the town of Schumacher has a declining Croatian population and the once vibrant Croatian Hall is a little worse for wear. The once grand hall is having a hard time keeping financially afloat and is at risk of closing it's doors. Frank Sebalj, the hall president hopes the former residents can assist in some way. Frank is looking forward to the upcoming town reunion where he hopes to generate some revenue and a plan to keep the Croatian hall doors open; or this reunion, with functions at the historical Croatian Hall, may be one of the last.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?263142</url></doc>
