<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="263287">
  <docid>263287</docid>
  <title>In the Mix: 25 Days and Not a Minute More</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Goldberg, Mark Lee</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 March 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Lieberman, Jeff L.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hurwitz, Sam</producer>
    <producer>Lieberman, Jeff L.</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chriqui, Emmanuelle</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Palminteri, Chazz</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Raymond, Usher</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>4 Mini Documentaries on the making of the feature film "In The Mix". 25 Days and Not a Minute More It's renegade filmmaking when a director has only 25 days to make a Feature Length Film and loses the star to a concert in Paris on the 26th. Director Ron Underwood and the rest of the filmmaking team share insights on the 3 1/2 weeks of shooting in Los Angeles, from a mansion on Mullholland to the Downtown rooftops and all the action in-between. Bridging The Gaps From Romeo and Juliet to Jungle Fever, the topic of intermarriage and inter-racial relationships have been a hot topic from the Jews to the Japanese. Filmmakers and cast share thoughts on the unique angle of this story and why it's important to tell. Usher: Singer, Dancer, Actor Today's hottest young star is making waves on the radio, TV, sold out concerts, the red carpet and now in movies. The film crew and cast members share anecdotes about working with the media sensation. Emmanuelle Chirqui talks about dancing with the master, Chazz Palminteri recalls teaching the kid a thing or two and learning some things himself, and Producer Holly Carter Davis describes Usher's non-stop enthusiasm to good work, little sleep and a schedule that never stops. The 3 Maestros Palminteri, Davi and Costanzo: The three longtime Italian Actors have appeared in countless films and have defined Italian American Culture through generations of filmmaking. They share thoughts on In The Mix, how to create characters without relying on stereotypes, and a few anecdotes about Sinatra, the man who started it all.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?263287</url></doc>
