<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="264682">
  <docid>264682</docid>
  <title>Inertia</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Garrett, Kyle</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>hvx</keyword>
    <keyword>inertia</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">29 March 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">27</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Garrett, Kyle</director>
    <director>Seamer, George</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Garrett, Kyle</producer>
    <producer>Heimlich, Bo</producer>
    <producer>Seamer, George</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Seamer, George</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Harris, Matthew (XVI)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bochenek, Amy</actor>
      <role>Sexual Deviant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Boisselle, Jen</actor>
      <role>Nothing</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Crosby, Amber</actor>
      <role>Eve</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Floros, Laura</actor>
      <role>Eve</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Garrett, Haley</actor>
      <role>Telemarketer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Garrett, Kyle</actor>
      <role>Ever #2</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gundry-Monji, Danielle</actor>
      <role>Ricky's Girlfriend</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harrigan, Brian</actor>
      <role>Ever #1</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Heimlich, Bo</actor>
      <role>Sunglass Store Employee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kimbrough, Matt (II)</actor>
      <role>Ex-Boyfriend</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mesa, Frances</actor>
      <role>Bum</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Purnell, Geoff</actor>
      <role>Drug Dealer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rutsch, Doug</actor>
      <role>Chad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Seamer, George</actor>
      <role>Ricky</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Slatkin, Eric</actor>
      <role>Mange</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sperling, Perry</actor>
      <role>Dr. Cox</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zapasnik, David</actor>
      <role>Chad's Boss</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The bleak outskirts of San Francisco act as the backdrop for this view into a jaded generation. Floating through their mid-twenties, four strangers interweave on one fateful day none of them are prepared for. Chad is a telemarketer, obsessed with living up to his idols: Bill Gates, Alexander the Great - his father - but he is the constant butt of his supervisor's mockery. When he is evicted from his apartment he is forced to examine how different he is from those he idolizes. Eve is homeless, controlled by her addictions, crushed under the accusatory eyes of passersby on the street. Out of money, out of drugs, out of self respect, she grows more and more desperate, finally pawning everything she owns for a knife: her last chance to get some respect. Jane has never stayed in one city for longer than a few months, but when she finds out she is pregnant she sees her freedom slipping away forever. They are all waiting for how their envisioned lives were supposed to turn out. As they realize their lives have become something completely different, their bad choices pull them closer to a tragic meeting that will touch them all. Their only hope is prophetic Ricky, a bookish retail clerk who feels his life is an endlessly repeating loop in which he has no volition. Even when his girlfriend walks out on him he is unable to take action, or to even say a word. He goes about his day as if he is merely a character in a story that was written long ago and can never be changed. He is living the same day, over and over . . . As the actions of the four strangers lead them to race towards the same deserted intersection, Ricky has flashes of the tragic collision that will soon unfold. It too seems like something he has experienced over and over . . . when will it end?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?264682</url></doc>
