<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="264675">
  <docid>264675</docid>
  <title>Inebriatus Rex</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Patel, Sharad Kant</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Mystery</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>drunk</keyword>
    <keyword>ghost</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>new-wave</keyword>
    <keyword>jazz-music</keyword>
    <keyword>cinema-verite</keyword>
    <keyword>dinosaur</keyword>
    <keyword>hi-def</keyword>
    <keyword>neo-noir</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">3 January 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">5</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Patel, Sharad Kant</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Patel, Sharad Kant</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Patel, Sharad Kant</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Muskratch</composer>
    <composer>Particle (II)</composer>
    <composer>Particle (III)</composer>
    <composer>Webb, Chris (XVII)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tramel, Matt</actor>
      <role>Drunken Man</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Within a paranoid psychogenic midnight episode, a young, drunk professional stumbles out into a back alley. He flails around in anger, cursing those who have jettisoned him. He seems like a solitary scarecrow caught in a muffled desperate nightmare. His only sense of calm comes when he sits and meditates over a tiny photo he produces from his wallet. The image appears to calm him, in an almost longing but weary way. Of course, this fleeting spell of rest is broken by a backwards-cap, t-shirt wearing instigator who snatches the beloved photo and wanders away into the empty city. A chase follows. One filled with surreal twists and visions. His tormentor is always ahead, always out of reach, always eluding him. His sense of reality lapses... "I'd catch that thief but there's a freakin' dinosaur in the middle of the street!" Finally, sick from the chase, our hero sulks back to his car only to find the thief inside, sleeping in the driver's seat. In a last twist, and apparent awakening, the hero seems to be caught in an eternal mental loop where he has chased his own lost idealism.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?264675</url></doc>
