<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="265894">
  <docid>265894</docid>
  <title>Inside America's Executive Mansions</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Fernando, Joel</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>History</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">16 September 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">22</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Padgett, Kelly</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Mosher, Matt</producer>
    <producer>Hunt, Thomas (V)</producer>
    <producer>Blischok, Troy</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Schifter, David</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Inside America's Executive Mansions is a series of one-hour mini-documentaries that highlight the homes of each State's Chief Executive. Each mansion is a treasure chest of history and style as unique as each state. From the type of marble used on the floor, the type of wood paneling, the portraits hanging in the foyer, to even the selection for the State china pattern, each mansion, each detail tells a story of great historical importance. We are here to tell this story. This program will look to see how the house is used both as a private residence and a showcase for state events. We will look at the Executive Chef and cuisine that is served in the Mansion. We will highlight many of the gifts that have been given to each state that turn many of the Executive Mansions into mini-museums of history and culture. Many of our Nations Executive Mansions also have extensive gardens, this program will highlight everything the Grounds and Mansion has to offer. Shot in High Definition (HDTV), the shooting style has a documentary feel - focusing on the house, it's furnishings - including the special items of historical significance, the décor, and the history of the house - including how it was built and how it came to be the official Governor's residence. We will include Interviews with mansion employees as well as both former and current residents of the mansion when possible - we will include videotape from local stock footage when available to create a unique program.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?265894</url></doc>
