<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="265993">
  <docid>265993</docid>
  <title>Inside Hana's Suitcase</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>New, David (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Czech Republic</country>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">88</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Weinstein, Larry</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Biermann, Rudolf</producer>
    <producer>Daniel, Jessica</producer>
    <producer>Weinstein, Larry</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Wallner, Thomas</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Louie, Alexina</composer>
    <composer>Pauk, Alex</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brady, George (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brady, Lara</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ishioka, Fumiko</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>INSIDE HANA'S SUITCASE A Theatrical Documentary Synopsis "Inside Hana's Suitcase", is the poignant story of two young children who grew up in pre-WWII Czechoslovakia and the terrible events that they endured just because they happened to be born Jewish. Based on the internationally acclaimed book "Hana's Suitcase" which has been translated into 40 languages, the film is an effective blend of documentary and dramatic techniques. In addition to tracing the lives of George and Hana Brady in the 1930's and 40's, "Inside Hana's Suitcase" tells the present-day story of "The Small Wings", a group of Japanese children, and how their passionate and tenacious teacher, Fumiko Ishioka, helped them solve the mystery of Hana Brady, whose name was painted on an old battered suitcase that they received from Auschwitz, the notorious Nazi death camp built in Poland. The film's plot unfolds as told through contemporary young storytellers who act as the omniscient narrators. They seamlessly transport us through 70 years of history and back and forth across three continents, and relate to us a story of unspeakable sadness and also of shining hope. For this is a Holocaust story unlike others. It provides a contemporary global perspective and lessons to be learned for a better future. Directed by award-winning filmmaker, Larry Weinstein, "Inside Hana's Suitcase" is a powerful journey full of mystery and memories, brought to life through the first-hand perspectives of Fumiko, Hana's brother George, and of Hana herself.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?265993</url></doc>
