<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="266211">
  <docid>266211</docid>
  <title>Inside the Butterfly Net</title>
  <year>2010</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>animal-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>insect-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <directors>
    <director>Spohr, Ian</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Connolly, Scott (I)</producer>
    <producer>Lloyd, Doug</producer>
    <producer>Menides, Georgia</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Menides, Georgia</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>A renowned scientist discovers a gene in a rare butterfly that could cure his daughter's leukemia. Fourteen, spirited, and determined to live a normal teenage life; Allison finds a shocking way to escape the disease on her own. James Nagle is one of the top geneticists in the country who lectures about scientific responsibility based on his own mistakes in the past. His 14-year-old daughter Allison suffers from acute leukemia. Although James has tapped every connection to get her the best drugs for her condition, her body is not responding. A chance meeting with an old colleague leads James and his brother Reid to Brazil, in search of a butterfly said to promote an almost miraculous healing. A series of complex genetic screenings reveal a sequence in the butterfly's DNA that seems to reverse cell growth in malignant blood tissue. Unlike most drugs, this sequence binds solely with the carcinogenic cells leaving the healthy cells in the body unscathed. An unfortunate accident with a colleague's research leaves James hesitant. He fears his daughter's diminished immune system cannot handle this new serum, and gives up hope on what he has discovered. Secretly, Reid brings the butterflies home, using his own scientific background to continue testing. He is convinced that if the serum works on infected blood tissue, James will change his mind. At home, James' marriage is falling apart. Often left alone to deal with her daughter and the realities of her illness, his wife Jessica is sinking into anger and depression. As things get worse with Allison, and her husband becomes more distant, Jessica's isolation consumes her. Allison's aunt, Nettie, leads her through a series of spells and meditations that keep Allison excited and positive. Allison's faith in these rituals is constantly disrupted by her parents' adherence to traditional medicine. But In the end, Nettie has to come to terms with the limits of her religion. Allison is a lovable and spirited girl determined to live a normal high school life, despite her illness. She is convinced that between her father's science and her aunt's religion, she will get better. She is also very much the average high school girl, "in love" with a basketball player in her school and constantly thinking of ways of ways to attract him. But when she finally confronts her father and learns that he is unsure of how to treat her, Allison is forced to face that science, religion, and her own family have failed her. Now Allison must find her own spiritual and physical liberation.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?266211</url></doc>
