<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="266678">
  <docid>266678</docid>
  <title>Intelligent Life: Change Your Mind, Change Your World</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Malone, Brian (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>environmental</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Thailand">21 February 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">73</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Malone, Brian (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Nemeth, Stephen</producer>
    <producer>Malone, Brian (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Malone, Brian (II)</writer>
    <writer>Malone, Cindy (III)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Gilmer, Jerome</composer>
    <composer>Lamu, Yangjin</composer>
    <composer>Malone, Brian (II)</composer>
    <composer>Manring, Michael</composer>
    <composer>McCandless, Paul (II)</composer>
    <composer>Nakai, R. Carlos</composer>
    <composer>Pole</composer>
    <composer>Winter, Paul (VII)</composer>
    <composer>de Grassi, Alex</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Through a series of meditative music/video vignettes, the film connects the "cause and effect" on our unintentional impact to the world around us. Intelligent Life forces us to face the unpleasant truths behind our treatment of factory farm animals, electricity generation, auto emissions, trash, obsessive consumerism and more. A casual fast food burger is directly tied to the horrific and inhumane treatment of feedlot cattle. An impulse for instant material gratification leads to the filthy and inevitable end of a product's life in a landfill, where it will take thousands of years to decompose. The simple convenience of turning on a light bulb is bound to the environmental catastrophe of stripping away layers of the Earth. These images are contrast against a world without man; a world of rare beauty and wonder. Vivid colors, massive natural landscapes and moving music transcend the viewer to an entirely beautiful world without human influence. Finally, Intelligent Life offers practical solutions; how mankind can sustain life within its natural and finite world. The solutions are simple everyday adjustments that are easily adoptable by most everyone. And they can make a significant impact. They answer problems presented at the beginning of the film including: humanely/organically raised animals, renewable energy choices for business and home, alternative modes of transportation... even pollution-free recreation.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?266678</url></doc>
