<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="266720">
  <docid>266720</docid>
  <title>Inteqam</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Choudhary, Harish</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Azmi, Aslam</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Goswami, A.M.</producer>
    <producer>Jethwani, Sugnu</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Azmi, Aslam</writer>
    <writer>Lucknowi, Suroor</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Shyam, Jitin</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anand, Akshay</actor>
      <role>Rajan Sahay</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anand, Tinnu</actor>
      <role>Neighbour</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dadwal, Pooja</actor>
      <role>Shoma Kapoor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harish (I)</actor>
      <role>Vijay Kumar Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Shakti (I)</actor>
      <role>Mohan Seth</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Kiran (I)</actor>
      <role>Inspector Madhukar Shende</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Sujit (I)</actor>
      <role>Dilip Navin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Parvez, Yunus</actor>
      <role>D.I.G. R.P. Srivastava</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Saraf, Ashok</actor>
      <role>Mulri (Watchman)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sheikh, Aashif</actor>
      <role>Rocky</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tiwari, Brijesh</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Upendra, Jeet</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Verma, Arun</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Vijay Kumar Singh lives in a big apartment building with his parents. He and his three male friends are thrilled and intrigued by the arrival of a new family in their neighborhood, especially by a young and attractive Shoma Kapoor. To add to this, she also gets admitted in the same college as they, and all four males attempt to romance her in their own way - and each one believes that he has succeeded. Rumours abound, and Shoma's mom comes to know about them, resulting in Shoma having a open and public forthright talk with alleged suitors. Humiliated and dejected, the three plot to avenge this, and meet with a gangster named Mohan Seth, who they hire to rape and assault Shoma during the ensuing Navratri Festival. But when Shoma extends her hand in friendship, and admits her love for Vijay - they quickly try to contact Mohan and cancel the contract. But Mohan wants to have his way with Shoma at any cost - and he refuses to take any instructions from the three young friends. Fisticuffs follow, Vijay also gets involved, Mohan is beaten and believed to be dead. The friends hide his body in an abandoned garage and agree to dispose it off early next morning. The next morning they arrive at the location and find that the body is missing. A few days later, Mohan's dead body is found and the police come across evidence that the crime was committed by four males and a female. Vijay, Shoma, Rajan, and their two friends are arrested and held in prison. With the odds stacked against them - the four may face life in prison - unless a miracle takes place - which seems very unlikely.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?266720</url></doc>
