<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="266776">
  <docid>266776</docid>
  <title>Interference</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kavanagh, Natalie</editor>
    <editor>Lloyd, Toby</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">19 August 2005</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="France">17 May 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">20</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Dayle, Kimberley</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Clarke, Phil (V)</writer>
    <writer>Dayle, Kimberley</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Banks, Tash</actor>
      <role>Additional Caller</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Belander, Jennifer</actor>
      <role>Sam</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brown, Stewart (II)</actor>
      <role>Eagle</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chhabu, Arif</actor>
      <role>Jay</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Clyde, Duncan</actor>
      <role>Additional Caller</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hale, David (V)</actor>
      <role>Jeff</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kavaz, James</actor>
      <role>Voice</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Knight, Mark J.</actor>
      <role>Dave</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Neill, Matthew</actor>
      <role>Chad</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>It is 2020 New York. The growing concern over the greenhouse effect has escalated. The world is hopeful for redemption in the form of an ambitious project which will see a nuclear device detonated on Mars, which will, over a few hundred years, create a breathable atmosphere in which civilisation can 'begin again'. Sam is a DJ, working the graveyard shift at Sound-City FM, a run-down, stuck-in-the-past radio station. Bored with herself and her seemingly endless drizzle of nutcase callers, the nights drag by as does her uneventful life. Bombarding those around her with dry sarcasm and wit, her long-suffering colleagues are surprisingly tolerant. Chad is one of those who 'never quite made it' to college, but still acts like he belongs there...and Dave, a rather uptight executive/boss, whose actual purpose is somewhat of a mystery to his counterparts. Late one night, amongst the usual tirade of callers, Sam receives a mysterious call from someone, or 'something' who claims to be the intelligence behind the Mars bomb. It says it has been reprogrammed...and is now to explode within the Earth's atmosphere. At first, Sam is unbelieving, but she slowly begins to realise that all is not as it seems, and the world does not have very long to contemplate what makes us human.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?266776</url></doc>
