<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="267584">
  <docid>267584</docid>
  <title>Into the Unknown</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Al-Matrouk, Fawaz</editor>
    <editor>Frost, Ryan (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">27 June 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">13</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Dion, John</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Eskreis, Rebecca</producer>
    <producer>Snyder, Mallory (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Swanson, Joe (IV)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kim, Brian H.</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Connell, Kelly</actor>
      <role>Gus</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harper, James (I)</actor>
      <role>Al</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McIntyre, Marilyn</actor>
      <role>Fern</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>For many couples, retirement provides the opportunity to explore new hobbies and perhaps rekindle their romance. At least that's what Fern had in mind when she and her husband, Al, retired to a secluded lakeside cabin. Fern wants Al to try rowing and hiking and "experiment" in ways they haven't in years. Al, on the other hand, is content to spend hours alone in his workshop perfecting his wicker weaving techniques. Our story begins on a day like any other - Fern brings Al his breakfast and encourages him to get some fresh air. Unsuccessful as always, she leaves him to his work. Later that day, while sudsing up, Al discovers a most uncanny occurrence - a black hole seems to be forming in his shower.  Plumber Gus arrives to check out the situation. With his knowledge of astrophysics and ancient cultures, Gus is far from the typical pipe cleaner. And while his interpretation of the black hole excites Fern, Al can't wait to get rid of it. Gus suggests that the black hole is not just a scientific anomaly; it's a sign of a relationship gone sour. But can Fern and Al mend the growing rift between them or will the black hole get between them first?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?267584</url></doc>
