<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="268169">
  <docid>268169</docid>
  <title>Io non sono un moderato</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Ciacci, Andrea (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Italian</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Argentina">9 April 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="France">November 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Mexico">October 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Switzerland">4 August 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Italy">November 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Denmark">13 March 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">70</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Nobile, Andrea (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Nobile, Andrea (II)</producer>
    <producer>Borrelli, Alessandro (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Nobile, Andrea (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fo, Dario</actor>
      <role>Himself - Nobel Prize in Literature</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fuksas, Massimiliano</actor>
      <role>Himself - architect</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Livingstone, Ken (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself - Mayor of London</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Prodi, Romano</actor>
      <role>Himself - Italian Prime Minister</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>October 16, 2005: for the first time ever in Italy, were held primary elections to choose Berlusconi's antagonist in the upcoming political elections in 2006. The extraordinary popular participation, far beyond all expectations, urged Literature Nobel Prize Dario Fo to invoke primary elections for Mayor elections in his city, Milan, and to propose himself as a candidate. His candidacy has a terrific symbolic value. Milan itself is a symbol: the economic engine of the country, the "moral capital" of Italy - as it defines itself. Milan has a symbolic value for Italian politics as well: it has witnessed Silvio Berlusconi's entrepreneurial and political rise and embodies his characteristics. But it's not an easy way for Dario Fo. Despite the warm acceptance by the Milanese people, most of the left-wing parties decide not to support him and to candidate the former prefect of the city. The documentary follows all the Fo's campaign, from the preliminary meetings to the public speakings, from the very intimate confessions to the theatre shows made for the campaign. The strength of Dario Fo's candidacy is to bring passion back into politics, to put into the spotlight whole parts of the population which had been forgotten and disillusioned by politics, to try to find a new political space to civil society. But the documentary is also a way to discover the connections between artistic works and public life of one of the most influential Italian intellectual, a myth for the left-wing radicals of all Europe.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?268169</url></doc>
