<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="269028">
  <docid>269028</docid>
  <title>Isang sulok ng mga pangarap</title>
  <year>1994</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Tagalog</language>
    <language>Filipino</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Philippines</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Philippines">1994</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Guillen, Laurice</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>del Rosario Jr., Vic</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dixson, Alice</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rivera, Ariel (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Nimfa is a poor, good hearted street vendor with a deformity on her face who wishes for a man who will love her despite her looks and Alissa is a rich beautiful woman who hides her evil ways with her beauty and charms. Nimfa meets a guy who wooed her despite the way she looks. He taught her lots of stuff including things that you'll learn in a finishing school (like proper posture). Then he convinces her to have plastic surgery to make her beautiful. At first, she is hesitant but because of an accident, she said yes. When the operation is over, his true nature comes out and the truth about this fairy tale life that she's having now is just a plan of another person, ALISSA! She now looks like her, moves like her and she will become her! While Alissa is away with her lover (Gutierrez) in Vegas, (Through blackmail of Alissa and her lover) Nimfa will pose as Alissa in her household and must fool Alissa's husband, daughter and everyone else that they're just the same person. Nimfa found it hard at first but she caught the sympathy of all the people she's fooling. She is now living the perfect life of another person who doesn't appreciate it. All is well until Alissa suddenly shows up again and wants her life back! Will Nimfa give up this perfect life? Especially now all the people she fooled is now dear to her and she's starting to fall in love with Walter (Alissa's husband).</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?269028</url></doc>
