<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="269344">
  <docid>269344</docid>
  <title>Island of the Great White Shark</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>nature-documentary</keyword>
    <keyword>great-white-shark</keyword>
    <keyword>shark-diving</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby SR</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 January 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">43</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Theiss, Richard (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Theiss, Richard (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Theiss, Richard (II)</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Off the coast of Baja, Mexico, 210 miles south of San Diego, California, a remote island serves as one of nature's dwindling sanctuaries to a fearsome ocean predator - the Great White Shark. In a race against time, eco-tourists and marine researchers from the United States and Mexico have forged a unique alliance to gather scientific data in the hopes of protecting these animals from potential slaughter. This is a countdown, a countdown to survival at Isla Guadalupe - the Island of the Great White Shark. With these opening words, RTSea Productions' documentary, Island of the Great White Shark, begins the first comprehensive examination of Isla Guadalupe, its population of great white sharks, and the ongoing scientific research taking place there. Several compelling concepts are brought together in this production: the wide range of research techniques being employed, the kinds of data being gathered, the unusual working relationship between shark researchers and eco-tourism operations, and of course the sharks - both feared and misunderstood by the general public while also highly vulnerable and threatened with possible extinction.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?269344</url></doc>
