<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="270723">
  <docid>270723</docid>
  <title>Italian Americans and Federal Hill</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Gulino, John</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>food</keyword>
    <keyword>italian-heritage</keyword>
    <keyword>pasta</keyword>
    <keyword>italian-music</keyword>
    <keyword>organized-crime</keyword>
    <keyword>providence</keyword>
    <keyword>descrimination</keyword>
    <keyword>padrone</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>italian-immigrant</keyword>
    <keyword>rhode-island</keyword>
    <keyword>immigration</keyword>
    <keyword>italian-food</keyword>
    <keyword>american-studies</keyword>
    <keyword>little-italy</keyword>
    <keyword>italian-american</keyword>
    <keyword>italian</keyword>
    <keyword>discrimination</keyword>
    <keyword>italian-culture</keyword>
    <keyword>federal-hill</keyword>
    <keyword>italian-immigration</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">11 August 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">89</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="USA">89</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Raben, Jon</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Votolato, Max</producer>
    <producer>Raben, Jon</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>Federal Hill, Providence, Rhode Island's "Little Italy," is one of America's most storied neighborhoods. Relive the traditions and challenges of Italian Americans whose ancestors immigrated for a better future. Once a bustling Italian enclave of cold-water flats and peddlers, Federal Hill now features upscale restaurants and markets known throughout the world. For immigrants challenged by poverty, the language barrier and discrimination, hard work and education became the path to a better life. Today, Italian Americans from Federal Hill are among the mainstream and elite of society. Italian Americans and Federal Hill, produced and directed by Jon Raben, features personalities with ties to Federal Hill including three former Providence mayors, a Rhode Island lieutenant governor and a Providence City Council president. Also included are an historian, a judge and a U.S. ambassador, as well as priests, artisans, entrepreneurs and other Italian Americans from Federal Hill. Attacking stereotypes, this moving and lively depiction of the Italian American experience was filmed on location in historic Federal Hill. The soundtrack features traditional Italian folk and classical music recorded live.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?270723</url></doc>
