<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="271947">
  <docid>271947</docid>
  <title>Jack Says</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Baker, Paula</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>jack-says</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>paris</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="UK">18</certificate>
    <certificate country="Australia">MA</certificate>
    <certificate country="New Zealand">R16</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">22 September 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">85</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Phillips, Bob (XI)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bis, An u</producer>
    <producer>Bishton, Matthew</producer>
    <producer>Burgess, Nic Sara</producer>
    <producer>Gill, James (II)</producer>
    <producer>Grobler, Craig</producer>
    <producer>Halliday, Mike</producer>
    <producer>Mackenzie, Steve</producer>
    <producer>McMahon, Jason (IV)</producer>
    <producer>Searle, Geoff (II)</producer>
    <producer>Talliss, Russ</producer>
    <producer>Wilkinson, Graham (V)</producer>
    <producer>Wilson, Robbie (II)</producer>
    <producer>Mashadi, Miran</producer>
    <producer>Brickwood, Neale</producer>
    <producer>Davies, Oliver (II)</producer>
    <producer>Loades, Luke</producer>
    <producer>McAlingdon, Fintan</producer>
    <producer>Stewart, Garry (II)</producer>
    <producer>Villiers, William</producer>
    <producer>White, Phil (VII)</producer>
    <producer>de Silva, Roy (II)</producer>
    <producer>Davey, Mark (III)</producer>
    <producer>Hamilton, Eva (II)</producer>
    <producer>Meredith, Toby</producer>
    <producer>Phillips, Simon (IV)</producer>
    <producer>Sayers, Aaron</producer>
    <producer>Stewart, Garry (II)</producer>
    <producer>Themistocli, Rick</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Pereira, Piers</writer>
    <writer>Ronald, Alan</writer>
    <writer>Tanter, Paul</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Beard, David (III)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Allwood, Robert</actor>
      <role>Sleazy Bar Creep 3</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Aloneftis, Marianna</actor>
      <role>Cafe Waitress</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Amblard, Aurélie</actor>
      <role>Girl X</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bender, Michelle</actor>
      <role>French Waitress</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cantona, Eric</actor>
      <role>Man At Bar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carpentier, Nicolas</actor>
      <role>Taxi driver</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fosh, Christopher</actor>
      <role>Heavy 2</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Frail, James</actor>
      <role>Detective Edwards</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Idollor, Danny</actor>
      <role>Twinkle</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>James, Alexia</actor>
      <role>Serenity</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>KB, Forbes</actor>
      <role>Heavy 1</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kazan, Alexandra</actor>
      <role>Woman with Dog</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Layer, Jean-Marc</actor>
      <role>Mugger</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lee, Julian (IV)</actor>
      <role>Dominique</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lenska, Rula</actor>
      <role>Garvey</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Masquelier, Géraldine</actor>
      <role>Victim</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mehelleb, Sidney</actor>
      <role>Shop Keeper</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Palmer, Charlie (II)</actor>
      <role>Dr. Matt Poulton</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Phillips, Simon (IV)</actor>
      <role>Jack</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pinheiro, Miguel</actor>
      <role>Barman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pritchard, Phil (I)</actor>
      <role>French Detective</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Reid, Mike (I)</actor>
      <role>The Guv'nor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Roberts, Daniel (III)</actor>
      <role>Messenger</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rueller, Ralf</actor>
      <role>Club Host</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sandhu, Steven</actor>
      <role>Sleazy Bar Creep 2</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stone, Robert (IX)</actor>
      <role>Heavy 3</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Talbot, Rob</actor>
      <role>Heavy 4</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tanter, Paul</actor>
      <role>Sleazy Bar Creep 1</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The film opens with Jack tied to a chair in a warehouse, guarded by heavies. He seems to have evoked the wrath of the Guv'nor, who lectures him about 'losing respect'. A girl called Natalie is present, and is clearly not in the Guvnor's good books. As one of the heavies removes Jacks gag, the Guvnor points a gun at his head. The scene fades to black, followed by two gunshots. The scene opens in a lively Paris bar, where the Messenger pushes his way through the vibrant crowd and into the dressing room area out back. He walks in on Girl X as she is changing. He is here to deliver a message and some flowers from Garvey, making clear that she is not pleased with Girl X fraternizing with men in the bar. To really make a point, he leaves a packet with her, which she discovers contains a ring and some teeth. Jack awakens in a bathroom in London next to the corpse of the Guvnor. Having been hit around the head, Jack is suffering from amnesia and cannot remember who he is or how he or the body got there. He searches his pockets and finds a Polaroid of a pair of breasts with the name 'Erin' and a Paris address written on the other side. Hearing police sirens, he decides to leave, figuring Paris is good place to lie low. He finds some I.D that confirms his name and address, so quickly heads there to get changes and dispose of his blood-soaked clothes. Meanwhile, the police begin investigating the Guvnor's death. They find a piece of Jack's I.D and seem to recognize him. Jack arrives in Paris and, via encounters with a talkative taxi driver and a philosophical barfly, and an attempted mugging at gunpoint; he calls at Erin's. Erin, Jack's ex-girlfriend, agrees to take him in. Back in London, the police are discussing Jack's criminal past and wondering if he's progressed to murder. The news comes through that Jack's credit card has been used in Paris. In a flashback scene, we see Jack reluctantly agreeing to help Natalie rip off the Guvnor. The next day, Jack heads out to explore Paris. He happens upon a bar, where he sees Girl X's show. Enamoured with her, he heads backstage, and interrupts the Messenger delivering another 'message' from Garvey. Jack swiftly and violently dispatches with the Messenger, taking his gun. Seeing Jack's usefulness, Girl X offers Jack payment to permanently dispose of Garvey, who is in love with her, and has been making threats against those close to her. Jack declines the offer; due to his amnesia, he is still unsure of whether he is capable of killing, and wants to keep a low profile for a while. The British police are now on their way to Paris. Natalie and her heavies are in hiding, and anonymously tip off the police information about where Jack may have headed. Semi-drunk, Jack returns to Erin's apartment, where he falls asleep in the doorway, as Erin is still at work. Erin returns, and has bought Jack a new suit. They scrub up and head out for a night on the town. Walking back along the Paris riverside, they flirt and discuss their previous relationship. Jack still cannot remember what happened, so Erin fills him in, explaining how much he hurt her. Jack wants to make it up to her. The sexual tension between them crescendos, and they head home to bed. In the morning, Jack discovers a positive pregnancy test kit in the bathroom. As it has only been a few months since they split, and Erin has been single since, he knows the child is his. As Jack heads out, Erin declares her love for him; he doesn't respond. Meanwhile, the police appear to have received some useful information. Jack mulls things over and returns, where he discovers that Erin has been brutally murdered. A bloody warning, "Leave X alone" has been daubed on the wall. Narrowly escaping the police, Jack heads to see Girl X, and tells her he will deal with Garvey in exchange for the payment she offered. He takes the money and heads to a restaurant where Girl X is acting as bait to lure Garvey. Jack threatens Garvey, but is talked out of killing her due to the possibility of immediate reprisals from her henchmen. When Girl X re-enters the restaurant and sees Jack, Garvey realizes the two are colluding. They run, but Jack is struck around the head by the heavies and captured. The blow to Jacks head frees up his memories. He remembers what happened in the warehouse; Natalie killed the Guvnor, who was her father. She then knocked Jack out and dumped him next to the body to try to frame him. Jack wakes, tied to a chair in a warehouse. This time he is at the mercy of Garvey, who begins cutting chunks of flesh off Jack and eating them. She is interrupted by a call from Girl X, and leaves. Jack escapes from the warehouse by overpowering Twinkle, one of Garvey's heavies. The police have found Erin's body and are closing in on Natalie in London. Jack heads to the bar to kill Garvey, but discovers Girl X has already killed her. Girl X accidentally reveals that she killed Erin to dupe Jack into going after Garvey. Jack attacks Girl X, who staggers out to the bar and dies spectacularly on stage. Jack takes the package with his payment, which contains a picture of Serenity, Girl X's daughter. Jack realizes that this is the person she was trying to protect, and is now in danger from Garvey's men. At Garvey's restaurant, Jack kills the Messenger and rescues Serenity. Seeing a chance to try to make things right and be the father he wanted to be to Erin's unborn child, he takes Serenity with him. Just as he is about to leave Paris, the police finally catch up with him, revealing that he was deep undercover for the police, but is now quitting. He leaves with Serenity for an unknown destination.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?271947</url></doc>
