<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="272810">
  <docid>272810</docid>
  <title>Jai Shakumbhari Maa</title>
  <year>2000</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Saluja, Ballu</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">2000</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Kumar, Shiv (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Goyal, K.C.</producer>
    <producer>Goyal, Mukesh</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Rajda, Mulraj</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Jain, Ravindra</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Agarwal, Mamta</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Agarwal, Pooja</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Eisshan</actor>
      <role>Abhishek 'Abhi'</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ghosh, Poorva</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gupta, Sharda</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jain, Neha (I)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kaul, Ashish</actor>
      <role>Balmukand</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Master Zahir</actor>
      <role>Young Alok</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Shahid Wahid</actor>
      <role>Baburam 'Bob'</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kiran, Raj</actor>
      <role>Jaikishan 'Jai' 'Jackson'</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Baby Mantoska</actor>
      <role>Young Mona</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Master Rachit</actor>
      <role>Young Abhishek</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mohan, Mac</actor>
      <role>Kaal Bhairav</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sagar, Aman</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sehgal, Vishal</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sharma, Shrestha</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Singh, Dara (I)</actor>
      <role>Fakeer Baba</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Balmukand lives a poor lifestyle in a village in India along with his wife, Sharda, and son, Alok. They share their house with his brother, Jaikishan, his wife, Urmila, their son, Abhishek, and daughter, Mona. Jaikishan gets an offer to work in America and with Sharda's financial help re-locates there along with his family. Balmukand, a devotee of Devi Shakumbhari Maa, manages to acquire a factory and run it quite successfully until his partner embezzles money and vanishes. He asks Jaikishan for help, who returns to India along with his now grown children and a thoroughly modern Urmila to try and assist Balmukand. Jaikishan does assist his brother, but Urmila takes over the factory as well as the house and all belongings, compelling Balmukand and Sharda to re-locate to serve and live in Devi Maa Shakumbhari's Mandir. Jaikishan wants Abhishek to get married to Pooja, the daughter of a poor Poojary, initially Abhishek refuses as he loves another girl, but when he sees her he realizes that it is the same girl. Despite strong protests from Urmila, the marriage does take place with financial assistance from none other than Shakumbhari Maa herself. Shortly thereafter the young couple decide to go on a combo business and honeymoon, but Pooja decides to remain behind to look after an ailing Urmila. Several days later Abhishek returns home to find everything changed. His father has left home to live at the Shakumbhari Maa Mandir, while Pooja has eloped with his cousin, Alok!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?272810</url></doc>
