<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="273152">
  <docid>273152</docid>
  <title>Jallaad</title>
  <year>1995</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anand, Vikas</actor>
      <role>Prasad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arya, Sulabha</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Gopinath</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chakraborty, Mithun</actor>
      <role>Amavas/Vijay Bahadur Kunwar/Police Inspector</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chatterjee, Moushumi</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chopra, Prem</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gill, Avtar</actor>
      <role>Gopinath (Koyal's dad)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Issar, Puneet</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Shakti (I)</actor>
      <role>Shakti Jackson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Kader (I)</actor>
      <role>K.K.</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Madhoo</actor>
      <role>Gayetri</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Packard, Gavin</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Parvez, Yunus</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Singh, Gurbachchan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Talsania, Tiku</actor>
      <role>Police Inspector</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A young, dashing, and honest Police Inspector, who lives with Mr. and Mrs. Prasad, goes to a small town in Southern India to be introduced to a prospective bride, Koyal, the daughter of Gopinath. The Police Inspector falls head over heels in love with Koyal and wants to marry her. Koyal too falls in love with him. When the time comes for finalizing their marriage, a man comes forward alleging that the Police Inspector is not who he claims to be, but a man who is a bastard, born out of an unknown biological father. This leads to the postponement of the marriage, and the Inspector questioning Prasad and his wife as to who he really is and who his father was. Prasad starts recounting his mother, Gayetri's, life, the fact that she married an obnoxious man named Amavas - a man who was selected by a shady politician to lure the innocent public to vote for him - so that he can plunder the nation to no end. Watch as this story takes you back in time, showing the greed and avarice that can encompass even the simplest of men - making him turn into a demon.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?273152</url></doc>
