<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="274311">
  <docid>274311</docid>
  <title>Jawaani</title>
  <year>1984</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">160</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Behl, Ramesh</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Behl, Ramesh</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Burman, Rahul Dev</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Amrapurkar, Sadashiv</actor>
      <role>Joe</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Birbal</actor>
      <role>Babubhai (Real Estate Agent)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chatterjee, Moushumi</actor>
      <role>Prema Mohan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Huma</actor>
      <role>Jatin's girlfriend</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kher, Anupam</actor>
      <role>Surendra Malhotra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khote, Viju</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Malhotra, Jatin</actor>
      <role>Jatin S. Malhotra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nath, Narendra</actor>
      <role>Vishnu Dada</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nischol, Navin</actor>
      <role>Amar Nath</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shah, Karan (I)</actor>
      <role>Karan A. Nath</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Singh, Gurbachchan</actor>
      <role>Johnny</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Sanam Malhotra studies in a hostel, while her parents, Surendra and Sushma, and brother, Jatin, live in Bombay in a small flat. Things change for the Malhotras when they are able to sell a large plot to the builders of a five star hotel. They move up in life and buy a bungalow and several cars and arrange for Sanam to stay with them. But these material possessions does make them a little snobbish, as Jatin cannot hear of his friend, Karan, the son of Bank Manager, Amar Nath, for falling in love with his sister. Surendra has Karan arrested for being near Sanam. Independent minded Sanam has also fallen in love with Karan, and when she is imprisoned by Surendra, both elope, much to chagrin of Surendra, who is aware that widowed Amar is having an affair with a woman named Prema Mohan. Surendra &amp; Jatin with the help of Vishnu Dada and his goons hunt them down, but the lovebirds are rescued by Uncle Joe, a friend of Karan. After being rescued, they are asked by Joe to take a holiday. What Sanam does not know is that Karan has taken to smuggling so that he can rich as the Malhotras. The question remains will Sanam join forces with Karan as his crime partner, or will she oppose him, and thereby end their short-lived romance.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?274311</url></doc>
