<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="274375">
  <docid>274375</docid>
  <title>Jay Cutler All Access</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>bodybuilding-competition</keyword>
    <keyword>performer-name-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>bodybuilding</keyword>
    <keyword>weight-training</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>weightlifting</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">76</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Alvarez, Chris (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Smith, Larry (XXV)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Garner, Sage (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cutler, Jay (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>IFFB professional Jay Cutler invites you to join him on his journey to the 2008 Mr. Olympia. After dethroning the legendary Ronnie Coleman in 2006, he won the title again in a controversial battle against Victor Martinez the following year. Now, reigning champion Jay Cutler works harder than ever before to create the best physique to defend his title! With time running out, he must eat, sleep and train around the clock, monitoring his progress along the way. But will his goals and destiny cross paths once more? Follow the Massachusetts native into his Las Vegas home and discover how to live like a champion. Join him in the original Gold's Gym in Venice, "Muscle Beach," California and experience a mind-blowing workout regime alongside the sport's greatest ambassador. Spend the weekend backstage at the world famous Joe Weider's Mr. Olympia Championship and catch a glimpse of the moments before game-time. With absolutely NO restrictions, watch Jay Cutler prepare for the most anticipated moment of his career.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?274375</url></doc>
