<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="275136">
  <docid>275136</docid>
  <title>Jeene Ki Sazaa</title>
  <year>1991</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bhushan, Bibhuti (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">1991</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Herekar, Nazir</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Herekar, Nazir</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Herekar, Nazir</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Qureshi, Iqbal</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhattacharya, Abhi</actor>
      <role>Swami</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chandran, Sudha</actor>
      <role>Sheetal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chopra, Anita</actor>
      <role>Chameli</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cola, Coca</actor>
      <role>Chanchal Paldru</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dongre, Daya</actor>
      <role>Abhijeet's mom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mohan, Mac</actor>
      <role>Prof. Chowdhury</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Oberoi, Suresh</actor>
      <role>Dr. Santosh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shukla, Rishabh</actor>
      <role>Abhijeet</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Abhijeet wants to finds a cure for people addicted to brown sugar and for this purpose works day and night. Although his widowed mom would like him to get married to Reena Chowdhury, who is the only daughter of Prof. Chowdhury, his boss, Abhijeet pleads that he is not yet ready for marriage. Nevertheless an engagement party is arranged, however, Abhijeet leaves abruptly. A furious Reena sets his laboratory on fire, leaving Abhijeet devastated and shattered so much so that he himself becomes addicted to brown sugar. No longer able to walk, confined to a wheelchair, his mom admits him in a recovery clinic run by Dr. Santosh. Here Abhijeet meets an attractive nurse, Sheetal, and falls in love with her. Sheetal helps him to recover and soon Abhijeet gets discharged. He would like to marry Sheetal, as his mom also approves of her. Then Abhijeet gets the shock of his life when he finds out that Sheetal is already married. Watch whether this discovery will cause a relapse in Abhijeet's health, and the reason why Sheetal chose to betray him in this manner.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?275136</url></doc>
