<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="276066">
  <docid>276066</docid>
  <title>Jesse's Story</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Jacobs, Mark S.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">25 September 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">73</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Jacobs, Mark (VII)</director>
    <director>Jacobs, Mark S.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Billauer, Josh</producer>
    <producer>Jacobs, Mark (VII)</producer>
    <producer>Jacobs, Mark S.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Jacobs, Mark (VII)</writer>
    <writer>Jacobs, Mark S.</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Billauer, Cecile</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Billauer, Engelina</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Billauer, George</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Billauer, Jesse Brad</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Billauer, Josh</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dorian, Shane</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harper, Ben (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hearne, Brendan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hearne, John (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hurley, Bob</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Johnson, Jack (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Machado, Rob</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rabuchin, Beny</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Reeve, Christopher</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sanson, Brett</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Slater, Kelly</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stanley, Brad (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Following a childhood as a gifted, multi-sport athlete, Jesse Billauer developed into an up-and-coming professional surfer with unlimited promise. Word traveled fast around his hometown of Pacific Palisades, California: there was a new light in the water. Sponsored almost immediately by Billabong and Hurley International founder Bob Hurley, Jesse was signed for the Hurley Team. One early morning, when conditions were best, Jesse was at Zuma Beach, riding the inside of a massive, barreling wave. It would close out on Jesse's back, sending him head first into a sand bar just inches below the water's surface. So powerful was the wave that Jesse was unable to brace for impact with his hands. He hit the sand bar head first, snapping his neck and severing his spinal cord at the C6 level. Jesse Billauer was now a quadriplegic, his life changed forever. But Jesse would never stop living. As news spread through the surfing community of the accident, many of Jesse's would-be competitors came to his aid. With the help of six-time World Champion Kelly Slater and Hurley team member Rob Machado, Jesse devised a way to get back where he belonged: in the water. "Jesse's Story" chronicles the life of a determined young man who succeeds where others might fail. It features captivating childhood footage taken by his parents; an emotional, minute-by-minute account of that fateful day at Zuma Beach by the surfers who saved his life; Jesse's return to surfing -- and his ride in the barrel of the second most dangerous wave in the world, Cloudbreak, in Fiji; and, Jesse diving among one of the ocean's most feared predators, the great white shark. "Jesse's Story" is not a surf film, but one of inspiration, and how to win when they change the rules.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?276066</url></doc>
