<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="276881">
  <docid>276881</docid>
  <title>Jihad!</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Garber, Nara</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Arabic</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">June 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">110</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Rum, Muhammed</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Castro, Sonia</producer>
    <producer>Rum, Muhammed</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Rum, Muhammed</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Bratslavsky, Jan</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arnold, James (V)</actor>
      <role>Harold</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Goodstein, Gerry</actor>
      <role>Lawyer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hamadeh, Hussam</actor>
      <role>Ed</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kay, Bianca</actor>
      <role>Miya</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Oliver, Edgar</actor>
      <role>The Jinn</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Poli, Rick</actor>
      <role>Teacher</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Riccardo, Erik</actor>
      <role>Fidel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Robins, Jeff (III)</actor>
      <role>Matt</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rum, Muhammed</actor>
      <role>Kamis</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zuaiter, Waleed</actor>
      <role>Salaam</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>JIHAD! In Arabic, translates as striving, struggling, a zeal or effort and has two connotations: A lesser Jihad and a greater Jihad. This movie focuses on the later through the personal struggles of its main character Ed, a Palestinian-American living in a pre-911 New York City, and as reflected in the lives of his friends and family. Cousin Salaam's unanticipated visit to New York City, which is precipitated by a close friends death in Ramallah (Palestine) brings up repressed conflicts for Ed as he pursues an affair with Hanna, a married American women. Ed's romantic fixation for Hanna belies a greater more cultural relationship between the mid-east's attraction for the west and its struggle to come to terms with its limitations. Hanna holds the promise of a new romantic life yet one which is hopelessly wedded to it's own contradictions. Salaam at first is representative of many Arab stereotypes, but surprisingly reveals a more accurate portrayal of Palestinians in general. His visit triggers haunting memories for Ed of a past-repressed life under occupation. Their discussions highlight differences in political, cultural, as well as ideological definitions about freedom, Islam and of course the meaning of Jihad. Harold, a University Dean of Theology, tries to shed light on the definition of Jihad with the two, and later exposes a perdition that exposes his own Jihadic conflict. Harold expresses a darker more obsessive reaction to the temptations of the west. JIHAD! Cries out for a greater definition then the one we have come to understand post 911. Through the lens of its writer/director Muhammed Rum it becomes a prism by which we can discover the striving, struggles and zeal of the lives of those caught between worlds.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?276881</url></doc>
