<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="276846">
  <docid>276846</docid>
  <title>Jigoku sensei Nube</title>
  <year>1996</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>teacher</keyword>
    <keyword>anime</keyword>
    <keyword>exorcist</keyword>
    <keyword>ghosts-japan</keyword>
    <keyword>japanese-schools</keyword>
    <keyword>japan</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Japanese</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Japan</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Japan">13 April 1996</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Japan">24</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Kaizawa, Yukio</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fujita, Toshiko</actor>
      <role>Hiroshi Tateno</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kanemaru, Jun'ichi</actor>
      <role>Shuichi Shirato</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kasahara, Rumi</actor>
      <role>Kyoko Inaba</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Matsuo, Ginzô</actor>
      <role>Masaru Kaneda</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Midorikawa, Hikaru</actor>
      <role>Zekki</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Morikawa, Toshiyuki</actor>
      <role>Kyosuke Tamamo/Tamamo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Okiayu, Ryôtarô</actor>
      <role>Meisuke Nueno/Nube</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tanaka, Kazunari (I)</actor>
      <role>Katsuya Kimura</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Nueno Meisuke, known to his students as "Nube" is a teacher/exorcist who finds that his new school is home to a huge variety of supernatural disturbances. Nube has a demon he trapped in his hand from a battle when he was younger. This demon hand allows him to communicate with ghosts and spirits and dispatch them if necessary. However, there are risks, as Nube must balance using the power of the demon but not being consumed by it. Some of these "yokai" (spirits, demons, etc., many of which are taken from Japanese folklore or urban legend) are drawn to the school by him, as he has crossed paths with many spirits and demons in his career as an exorcist. Among them is Yukime, a snow/cold spirit who has an unrequited love for Nube, which leads to many comedic and touching moments. This show has many comedic elements, as the students and staff of the school are a quite a bunch of varied characters, and Nube himself is sort of a good-natured, clownish klutz when not fighting demons and so forth, and his interactions provide many humorous moments. He is something of a lecher towards his co-worker Ruriko, who is afraid of all things supernatural. This leads to many classic comedic slapstick situations or misunderstandings. However, the show is equally, if not more so, horror-related, as many demons, ghosts, spirits, etc. cross paths with Nube, the staff, and children, some friendly, well-meaning, or otherwise harmless, but many malicious and evil; Nube must dispatch these threats to himself, his students, and others.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?276846</url></doc>
