<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="277722">
  <docid>277722</docid>
  <title>Jo-Jo at the Gate of the Lions</title>
  <year>1992</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <editors>
    <editor>Sjogren, Britta</editor>
  </editors>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Sjogren, Britta</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Sjogren, Britta</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Sjogren, Britta</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Sampson, Jonathan (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Griba, Kate</actor>
      <role>Katie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hayes, Beatrice</actor>
      <role>Old Woman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Marino, Lorie</actor>
      <role>Jo-Jo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Schultz, David 'Dutch'</actor>
      <role>Luke</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shearer, Chris (I)</actor>
      <role>Jon</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zahedi, Caveh</actor>
      <role>Phone Rapist</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Jo-Jo is a young woman who hears voices. She meets and falls in love with Jon, an astronomer with whom she feels a strange affinity. For Jon, life is complete once he has found Jo-Jo; his destiny is achieved. However, Jo-Jo's voices tell her that she must sacrifice her desire for a simple happiness with Jon if she is to fulfill the strange and elusive destiny in store for her. She believes that by resisting what she wants, or by embracing pain, she may be able in some mysterious and mystical way to prevent nuclear war. The voices compel her to accept as part of her fate a relationship with Luke, a shadowy phone-sex entrepreneur who persuades her to come work for him. He too imagines that Jo-Jo belongs with him, and she is drawn to his very violence. Caught between these two men, her destiny and her desires, Jo-Jo withdraws from the demands and joys of the real world. She focuses her mind inward, in a kind of apotheosis, to understand the message her voices bring her, a message of passion, fear and spiritual transfiguration.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?277722</url></doc>
