<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="277996">
  <docid>277996</docid>
  <title>Joe Longthorne: If I Never Sing Another Song</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Iacovou, Paul</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>entertainer</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="UK">Approved</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">30 May 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">64</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Iacovou, Paul</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Iacovou, Paul</producer>
    <producer>Iacovou, Paul</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Iacovou, Paul</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Longthorne, Joe</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Capturing Joe Longthorne on and off stage, the documentary follows Joe through his 2004 Spring Tour and his 9 week Summer Spectacular in Blackpool cataloging the highs and lows in what turned out to be an incredible series of events. As we began filming in March 2004 Joe was put on a 12 week experimental course of treatment to combat his 17 year battle against cancer. Electing not to cancel the spring tour Joe granted us unfettered access as we followed him on a roller coaster of a ride which saw him returning to Blackpool 3 times a week whilst desperately trying to accommodate the grueling schedule of 37 dates in just 50 days all over the UK. The Summer Season in Blackpool proved to be just as dramatic as the Spring Tour and this film managed to capture many great and often touching moments. If I Never Sing Another Song pays testament to Joe's courageous struggle with his illness and his consummate passion to carry on performing in the face of so many obstacles.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?277996</url></doc>
