<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="277938">
  <docid>277938</docid>
  <title>Joe Blade 3</title>
  <year>1989</year>
  <type>VideoGame</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">1989</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <producers>
    <producer>Prosser, Tom (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Severn, Andrew</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>In a daring raid disreputable master criminal Crax Bloodfinger kidnapped six world leaders, demanding a thirty billion-dollar pay-off for their safe release. Unfortunately for Crax, Joe foiled his evil plans. During the rescue Joe Blade single handedly eradicated his private army of underworld henchmen, and in the process leveled Bloodfinger's fortified base. After the wholesale demolition of his jungle fortress, Crax went into hiding, Under the bizarre alias of Quentin Bloodfinger he created Crax Industries as a front organization for his flourishing narcotics empire. Bloodfinger himself moved into the top floor penthouse suite of his recently constructed thirty floor high rise The Crax Plaza. Soon after the completion of the building Crax had his happy band of Libyan electricians install a myriad of electronic counter measures and state of the art security systems. The ground floor was fortified and most of the upper level windows replaced with two meters of reinforced concrete. Once the Plaza's impenetrable defenses were complete. Crax put his most diabolical plan into operation. He knew that kidnapping officials would be futile, the governments concerned would never give in to terrorist demands. A squad of Bloodfinger's most loyal men kidnapped six of the worlds best loved music and television celebrities and secured them within the massive concrete stronghold. Crax knew that the fans would give literally anything to see their heroes released. Within days of issuing a demand for 100 billion dollars, huge amounts of untraceable bank notes started flooding into Crax Industries Swiss bank accounts. The Mission: The authorities are powerless to act, finding themselves in a no win situation, knowing that if any of the celebrities are harmed they'll face riots on a horrifying scale. They have only one option left to them; they know what they have to do. ONLY ONE MAN IS CAPABLE OF BRINGING OUT THE HOSTAGES ALIVE THAT MAN IS JOE BLADE.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?277938</url></doc>
