<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="278375">
  <docid>278375</docid>
  <title>John E. Loskot - Der verschwundene Held</title>
  <year>1997</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Arnold, Thomas (IV)</editor>
    <editor>Kutschker, Thomas</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>research</keyword>
    <keyword>experimental</keyword>
    <keyword>california</keyword>
    <keyword>usa</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Germany">5 November 1997</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Germany">82</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Arnold, Thomas (IV)</director>
    <director>Kutschker, Thomas</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Arnold, Thomas (IV)</producer>
    <producer>Arnold, Thomas (IV)</producer>
    <producer>Kutschker, Thomas</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Arnold, Thomas (IV)</writer>
    <writer>Kutschker, Thomas</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Friedman, Burnt</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>During the late 1950's John E. Loskot has a vision of urbanizing the desert and living there self-sufficiently. At the end of the 60's he buys a piece of land at the south end of Death Valley. 1972 he retires and moves to the desert in a self built trailer along with his wife Mildred. He constructs greenhouses, workshops, uses solar energy and digs for gold. Until today you can see the abandoned trailer withering next to the Death Valley Star Route in California, 50 kilometres away from the nearest populated area. There were about 3000 fragments of bank-statements, checks, receipes, photographs and letters dated between 1944 and 1983 scattered by the wind on the sandy ground around the dwelling. By looking through the check books - places and dates of issue, which amounts were spent and what they were spent for - you can roughly trace journeys, personal habits and the circumstances of the lives of John and Mildred Loskot. 1978 the name of John E. Loskots wife disappears from all documents. He writes a book on the theorie that the mountains were created by meteors that hit the land. Apparently Mildred had revealed this to him after her death. 1981 he draws maps of the ?Mildred L. Loskot Meteorite Memorial Park? including parking lots, buildings, a cinema and hiking paths. In the summer of 1983 John E. Loskot disappears. Written information and interviews do not add up to a clear picture - neither regarding his lifetime, nor his disappearance. It is still a mistery.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?278375</url></doc>
