<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="278469">
  <docid>278469</docid>
  <title>John Mellencamp Live at Walter Reed Hospital</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Volkema, Ray</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <directors>
    <director>Lucas, Mark (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Iversen, Sarah</producer>
    <producer>Haiman, Evan (I)</producer>
    <producer>Hoffman, Randy (I)</producer>
    <producer>Seda, Angela</producer>
    <producer>Cotter, Dominick</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Clark, Dane (III)</actor>
      <role>Guitar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gunnell, John (I)</actor>
      <role>Bass</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kinnett, Troye</actor>
      <role>Keyboards</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mellencamp, John</actor>
      <role>Lead Vocal, Guitar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wanchic, Mike</actor>
      <role>Guitar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>York, Andy (II)</actor>
      <role>Guitar</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Washington Post - Walter Reed Concert Article/Review At Walter Reed, Mellencamp Shuts His Mouth and Sings By J. Freedom du Lac Washington Post Staff Writer Saturday, April 28, 2007 A funny thing happened on John Mellencamp's way to Walter Reed Army Medical Center: He stuck a muzzle on himself. John Mellencamp is going to perform an historic concert inside the Walter Reed Army Medical Center for the wounded men and women of America's Armed Forces. The concert will be on Friday, April 27th at 8 PM ET. This full-band concert will repeat on July 4th Weekend as well. Washington Post - Walter Reed Concert Article/Review At Walter Reed, Mellencamp Shuts His Mouth and Sings By J. Freedom du Lac Washington Post Staff Writer Saturday, April 28, 2007 Article includes photo - Click HERE to read the article online. A funny thing happened on John Mellencamp's way to Walter Reed Army Medical Center: He stuck a muzzle on himself. Mellencamp has been a vocal critic of the war in Iraq and the Bush administration. But last night, the outspoken singer checked his politics -- or at least his polemic -- at Walter Reed's guarded front gate. During a superlative hour-long concert on the beleaguered military hospital campus, Mellencamp avoided turning the stage into a soapbox, opting instead to simply entertain a group of soldiers wounded fighting a war that the rock star doesn't support.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?278469</url></doc>
