<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="278574">
  <docid>278574</docid>
  <title>John the Baptist</title>
  <year>1990</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Koford, James</editor>
    <editor>Paton, Randy</editor>
    <editor>Tobin, Thomas J.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>bible</keyword>
    <keyword>cartoon</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>christian</keyword>
    <keyword>christianity</keyword>
    <keyword>kids-and-family</keyword>
    <keyword>jesus-christ</keyword>
    <keyword>answer-to-prayer</keyword>
    <keyword>new-testament</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 June 1990</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Rich, Richard</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Noss, Terry L.</producer>
    <producer>Brown, Jared F.</producer>
    <producer>Rich, Richard</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Nissen, Brian (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>de Azevedo, Lex</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Crosland, Ivan</actor>
      <role>Jesus</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Doupé, Susan</actor>
      <role>Judean Woman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grey, David (IX)</actor>
      <role>Shem</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jackson, Pat (VII)</actor>
      <role>Mary</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Johnson, Donna K.W.</actor>
      <role>Herodias</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Keeler, Daniel A.</actor>
      <role>God the Father</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Luther, Dion</actor>
      <role>Pharisee #1</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maxfield, Nelden</actor>
      <role>Angel Gabriel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nash, Alan (I)</actor>
      <role>Uncle Jasher</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nichols, Paul (VIII)</actor>
      <role>Herod Antipas</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nissen, Brian (II)</actor>
      <role>Pharisee #2</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Porter, Ray (I)</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Snegoff, Gregory</actor>
      <role>John the Baptist/Caiaphas</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Whitaker, Jack</actor>
      <role>Zachary</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Winant, Bruce</actor>
      <role>Andrew</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>John the Baptist, born to an elderly couple in answer to their prayers and a promise from God, grows up to be a prophet, preaching of the coming of the messiah. He fulfills Biblical prophecy by recognizing Jesus as the promised Savior and baptizing Him going before the Lord. The moving story of John the Baptist begins as Elizabeth, a virtuous older woman who longs for a child, delights in watching a young boy playing outside her window. Her husband Zacharias, chosen to offer incense to God at the temple, is visited there by the Angel Gabriel who tells him that his wife is to bear a son. Zacharias can't believe this miracle but the angels assures him," All things are possible with the Lord." Because of his disbelief, Zacharias suddenly falls deaf and mute, unable to tell his family and neighbors what happened to him. When Elizabeth's son is born and family members ask his name, she answers " John " a name they refuse to accept since none among them share it. The family asks Zacharias his son's name and as he writes "John" on a tablet, his hearing and speech are restored, and he shares with them prophecy of the role his son is to play. John grows up to be strong in both body and spirit, living a humble life on the banks of the River Jordan. He preaches of the imminent coming of a savior, and baptizes people in the river in the name of the messiah, preparing the way for Jesus. All of this proves disturbing to the Pharisees and their leader, Caiaphas, who tries to convince King Herod*. The King is reluctant but not his wife, Herodias. Even when Pharisee spies question John as he preaches of the repentance, he does not temper his word, calling Herod a sinner for taking his brother's wife. This accusation drives Herodias to demand John's capture and death but before this happens, Jesus approaches the place where John is preaching. "Behold, the lamb of God", John cries out, recognizing the savior about whom he has been preaching. Jesus asks John to Baptize him and when that happens, the heavens open and the Holy Spirit appears in the form of a dove. Even though his life is in danger from Herodias and Herod, John refuses to flee, declaring," My work is done".</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?278574</url></doc>
