<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="279912">
  <docid>279912</docid>
  <title>Journey of the Heart</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Crawford, Adrian</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>heart</keyword>
    <keyword>journey</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Australia">19</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Crawford, Adrian</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Leader, Chad</producer>
    <producer>Crawford, Adrian</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Crawford, Adrian</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Mitchell, Alexander (II)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Boyd, Whitney</actor>
      <role>Skye Western</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Frost, Patrick</actor>
      <role>David Chamberlain</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hermann, Leona</actor>
      <role>Helen Chamberlain</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lee, Tamara (IV)</actor>
      <role>Jenny Falcone</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Willson, Adam</actor>
      <role>Brett Davidson</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Should a still grieving heart risk all for a new and dangerous love affair? Fifty year old Helen Chamberlain, Principal of a Catholic Girls High School recalls the devastating loss of her beloved husband, David, from his fateful departure to her final granting permission for his organs to be removed. And on her desk, a romantic gift and card from a would-be lover. Who could this be from? All-too-charming young Adonis and drama teacher, Brett Davidson is later caught guiltily leaving an absent Helen's office by attractive Head of Drama, Jenny Falcone. Helen had sent Jenny to her office while she retrieves young trouble-maker, Skye Western. But first, Helen rings 'Donor Organs Australia' attempting to contact David's heart recipient - but to no avail. But is that the case..? Unable to wait, Jenny finds Helen outside Brett's classroom transfixed by Brett as he discourses on Shakespeare to his class of enthralled sixteen year-olds - and a bored Skye. What prompts Helen to suspend Skye, when they reach Helen's office despite Jenny's vigorous protest? Is it an internal mail envelope with the self-same sketched promise of romance that now secretly confronts Helen, an envelope not there before? Finally alone, Helen pulls from this envelope a typed offer of first time romance that night. Dare Helen risk all for this? Helen writes a letter in her car pleading for more time. But when Helen, heading to the staffroom, catches out Skye with her punk boyfriend, Helen drops her reply and Skye snatches it up. Is the truth out as Skye now believes? Is Helen about to have an affair with a much younger work colleague? And is Helen really ready for this and all its perilous consequences?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?279912</url></doc>
