<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="281058">
  <docid>281058</docid>
  <title>Juko's Time Machine</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>punctuation-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>best-friend</keyword>
    <keyword>time-machine</keyword>
    <keyword>apostrophe-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>time-travel</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Barry, Kai</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Struck, Lauren</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Barry, Kai</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Allen, Zibby</actor>
      <role>Rory</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cozzolino, Nathan</actor>
      <role>Juko</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moggridge, Alex</actor>
      <role>Jed</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Jed and Juko have been best friends since the third grade. After a childhood spent crashing teacher's cars and building crazy mechanical contraptions, they find themselves all grown up. While Jed has matured into a functioning adult, married with a baby on the way, Juko lives in Jed's garage. Nina, Jed's husband is growing less sympathetic to Juko's situation and wants him out of the house. Jed is convinced that if Juko can fall in love, the way that he has, Juko will be able to move forward with his life. Juko does have a crush, in fact it's the same one he has had since grade school, Rory. But there's one obstacle - she's already married. In response, Jed and Juko go about solving the husband problem in the only way they know how, by building the most complicated machine of their career: a time machine. Hoping to capture Rory's heart before she gets engaged, Juko and Jed travel back in time, running into a myriad of problems along the way, not the least of which is, what happens when you see yourself in the past?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?281058</url></doc>
