<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="281817">
  <docid>281817</docid>
  <title>Junglee</title>
  <year>1961</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Naik, V.K.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Musical</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="India">139</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="default">161</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Mukherji, Subodh</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Mukerji, Probodh</producer>
    <producer>Mukherji, Subodh</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Kashmiri, Agha Jani</writer>
    <writer>Mukherji, Subodh</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Pankal, Jaikishan Dayabhai</composer>
    <composer>Raghuwanshi, Shankarsinh</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Azra (I)</actor>
      <role>Rajkumari the Princess</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Banu, Saira</actor>
      <role>Rajkumari 'Raj'</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chatterjee, Moni</actor>
      <role>Doctor (Raj's Father)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Goyle, O.P.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Haksar, Rajan</actor>
      <role>The Princess' Brother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hameeda</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Helen (I)</actor>
      <role>Miss Suku</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Shammi</actor>
      <role>Chandra Shekhar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Bazid</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Anoop</actor>
      <role>Jeevan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moolchand</actor>
      <role>Creditor with red turban</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sen, Asit (I)</actor>
      <role>Doctor Uncle</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shivraj (I)</actor>
      <role>Manager</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Chandrashekhar (Shammi Kapoor) or Shekhar as he is called now, belongs to an aristrocratic family, who believe laughter is a sign of belonging to the lower class, and as a result laughter is not encouraged in the household, run by Shekhar's domineering mom (Lalita Pawar). In this household the only one who dares to laugh and enjoy life is Shekhar's sister Mala (Shashikala), who also dares to love Jeevan (Anoop Kumar). Things change when their mom finds out about Mala's indiscretions, and she asks Shekhar to take her away from their home, to distant and scenic Kashmir, for awhile. She also instructs Shekhar to arrange to get married to a girl from a princely family. When Shekhar escorts Mala out of town, and on reaching Kashmir, he meets up with beautiful Rajkumari (Saira Banoo), and after being stranded with her for a night during a snowstorm, he realizes what he has been missing, and becomes a care-free man in love. This change is welcomed by Mala, but not by his mother. To make matters worse, Rajkumari does not belong to a princely family, and Shekhar knows that his mom will never approve of his marriage with Rajkumari. This movie is known as the first movie of Saira Banoo. And is also known for its songs: "Chahey koi mujhey junglee kahey..."; "Nain tumhare mazedar o janabewali..."; "Ja ja ja mere bachpan kahi jakhe chup nadaan..."; "Din sara guzara tohre angana ab jane de mujhe mohre sajna, mere yaar shaba kher...."; "Ai ai ya karo me kya sooku sooku..."; "Ehsaan tera hoga mujpar dil chahta hai woh kahene do mujhey tumse mohobat ho gai hai mujhey palkon ki chaon me rehne do...".</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?281817</url></doc>
