<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="283517">
  <docid>283517</docid>
  <title>Kaanoon Ki Awaaz</title>
  <year>1989</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Kumar, R.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Murali, Krishna</producer>
    <producer>Reddy, P. Chandrasekhara</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Singh, Jagjit (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Asrani</actor>
      <role>Havaldar Bhoja Banarasi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Babbar, Menaka</actor>
      <role>Advocate Reshmi Mishra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chopra, Prem</actor>
      <role>Darshan Lall</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Christo, Bob</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Das, Leena</actor>
      <role>Dancer/Singer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Irani, Aruna</actor>
      <role>Havaldar Mrs. Banarasi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Irani, Manik</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jayapradha</actor>
      <role>Advocate/Judge Janki Rai</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Manmauji</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rajababu</actor>
      <role>Ram Manohar Tripathi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Singh, Gurbachchan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sinha, Shatrughan</actor>
      <role>Raghunath Prasad Rai</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Suman, Shekhar</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Darshall Lall is a gangster with many political connections. And it is for this reason that no police officer has dared to arrest Lall or any of his men. But when Public Prosecutor, Janki Rai's rickshaw-driver husband, Raghunath Prasad Rai, witnesses Lall's son, Surendra Pal, kill Ram Mohan Tripathi, Lall's son is arrested and brought before the court. Lall's offer to bribe Janki are in vain, and as a result Surendra is convicted and sentenced to die. Lall swears to break up the Rai to avenge the death of his son, and finds out that Raghunath could be brought with money, and he induces him as such, and inducts him in a life of crime. Money and an easy life corrupt Raghunath and he takes to coming home late, and drinking alcohol. One day Raghunath is arrested by the police and held for a court hearing. During that night Lall arranges his escape, however, Raghunath's car meets with an accident, and he dies, leaving Janki widowed and to single-handedly bring up Raghunath's younger brother, Sunil. She ensures Sunil gets a good education and after several years he becomes a police officer. His superiors are impressed with his performance and assign him a special case of stopping smuggling activities, which Sunil accepts with great pride. What Sunil does not know that the smugglers he is attempting to arrest are headed by none other than Darshal Lall, who also has an unpleasant surprise awaiting him.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?283517</url></doc>
