<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="283872">
  <docid>283872</docid>
  <title>Kadhalan</title>
  <year>1994</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Lenin, B.</editor>
    <editor>Vijayan, V.T.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Telugu</language>
    <language>Hindi</language>
    <language>Tamil</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">U</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">168</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Shankar, S. (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kunjumon, K.T.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Balakumaran</writer>
    <writer>Shankar, S. (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Rahman, A.R.</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deva, Prabhu</actor>
      <role>Prabhu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Karnad, Girish</actor>
      <role>Kakarla</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Madhoo</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Manorama (II)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Raghuvaran</actor>
      <role>Malli</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>S.P., Balasubramaniam</actor>
      <role>Prabhu's Father</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vadivelu</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Student leader in his South Indian (Tamil Nadu) college, popular collegian, Prabhu, is asked by the Principal to invite the Governor of the state, Ranjit Singh Rathore, to be the chief guest on the annual day of the college. When he goes to invite Ranjit, he meets his lovely daughter, Shruthi, and instantly falls in love with her. She too subsequently gets to meet him, and falls in love with him. Since there is considerable fear of terrorism in the state, Ranjit does not permit his daughter to travel anywhere without bodyguards. On one occasion, she does manage to give them the slip and runs away with Prabhu at a dance festival in Chidambaram. Shortly thereafter there is a threat of a bomb being planted there, Shruthi is immediately returned home, and Prabhu is arrested. Shruthi is forbidden to see Prabhu again, while Prabhu is released from police custody, albeit after a severe beating. Prabhu then goes to meet Shruthi, unaware of the changed circumstances, and this is where he will find evidence that will lead him to a hideout of a daredevil terrorist who is responsible for planting bombs and killing people. The question is, will Prabhu be able to get out alive and tell this tale, or will he end up as another victim?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?283872</url></doc>
