<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="286147">
  <docid>286147</docid>
  <title>Kannathil Muthamittal</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Prasad, A. Sreekar</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>War</genre>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>kamalahasan</keyword>
    <keyword>civil-war</keyword>
    <keyword>terrorism</keyword>
    <keyword>snorricam</keyword>
    <keyword>suicide-bomber</keyword>
    <keyword>sri-lanka</keyword>
    <keyword>search-for-parent</keyword>
    <keyword>writer</keyword>
    <keyword>adopted-daughter</keyword>
    <keyword>violence</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Sinhala</language>
    <language>Tamil</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>DTS-Stereo</soundmix>
    <soundmix>DTS</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">U</certificate>
    <certificate country="Switzerland">12</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Japan">27 November 2005</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="India">14 February 2002</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Switzerland">14 August 2003</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Canada">8 September 2002</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">24 April 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">123</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Ratnam, Mani</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ratnam, Mani</producer>
    <producer>Srinivasan, G.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Ratnam, Mani</writer>
    <writer>Sujatha (III)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Rahman, A.R.</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chakravarthi, J.D.</actor>
      <role>Dhileepan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chowdhury, Shefali</actor>
      <role>Refugee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Das, Nandita</actor>
      <role>Shyama</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Keerthana, P.S.</actor>
      <role>Amudha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kethan, Master</actor>
      <role>Akhilan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Delhi</actor>
      <role>Ganesan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Madhavan (I)</actor>
      <role>G. Thiruchelvan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Raj, Prakash</actor>
      <role>Dr. Herold Vikramsinghe</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Suraj, Master (II)</actor>
      <role>Vinayan</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Dhileepan and Shyama are Tamil-speaking residents of Mankulam, Sri Lanka, who get married with the blessings of their respective families. After the marriage, Shyama confides that she would like to be a mother of 8 children, but is stunned when her husband tells her that he cannot father any children until there is peace between the mainstream and the Tamils in this country. Nevertheless, they do get intimate, resulting in Shyama getting pregnant. Dhileepan goes into hiding because of his connections with the Tamil Tigers, while Shyama returns to her dad, Devanathan's house. A storm threatens their village, and they are forced to flee to a Refugee Camp in Rameswaram, India. Alone, without any support, Shyama gives birth to a girl, leaves her, and returns to Sri Lanka to be with her husband. This child gets noticed by noted Tamil author Thiruchelvan, who lives with his sister, Kamalee, her husband, and their son, and authors books under the pen-name of 'Indra', who is actually an attractive TV news-woman who lives next door. When he comes forward to adopt her, he is initially refused, as he must be married in order to adopt any child. He accordingly gets married to Indra, and they adopt the child and name her Amudha. Subsequently, they become parents of two sons, Vinayan and Akhilan. After Amudha completes her 9th year, she is told that she has been adopted, compelling her to start searching for her biological mother. She initially runs aways to Rameswaram, but is unable to locate her, continues to be distraught, until Thiruchelvan promises to take her to Mankulam. They do come across a woman named Shyama, but she denies having any children, and it is then that they find out that there is another Mankulam to the north of Sri Lanka. They travel there, amongst almost war-like conditions, and it is here that Thiruchelvan and his guide, Dr. Herold Vikramsinghe, will be abducted by Tamil Tigers, who in turn, will arrange for a meeting with Shyama. Watch what happens when Amudha finally gets to meet her birth-mother - who may outrightly disown her or induct her as one of the many child warriors amongst the Tamil Tigers.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?286147</url></doc>
