<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="286885">
  <docid>286885</docid>
  <title>Karate Kallie</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>van der Merwe, Wimpie</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Afrikaans</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby SR</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>South Africa</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="South Africa">18 September 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="South Africa">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>van der Merwe, Wimpie</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Joubert, Pieter</producer>
    <producer>Groenewald, Charl</producer>
    <producer>Van Rensburg, Pia</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>van der Merwe, Wimpie</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Staaldraad</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cupido, Solomon</actor>
      <role>Errol</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gryffenberg, Henrietta</actor>
      <role>Mevrou Kotzé</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harmse, Petrus</actor>
      <role>Fritz Kotzé</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kruger, Ben (I)</actor>
      <role>Meneer Lessing</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lerm, Leani</actor>
      <role>Annetjie Kotzé</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pretorius, Soon</actor>
      <role>Soon Pretorius</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Smuts, Mike</actor>
      <role>Mike Haasbroek</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>van Vollenstee, Wynand</actor>
      <role>Kallie Haasbroek</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>van der Westhuizen, Richard</actor>
      <role>Meneer Kotzé</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The traditional tale about the new kid on the block. Karate Kallie is the story about a chubby 17 year old school boy, Kallie. From the get go in the new town, Kallie realizes that he, and most certainly his family, don't really fit in all that well. Without a father figure around, and Kallie's low self-esteem, it is inevitable that trouble will arise in his new school. At least Kallie quickly establishes a friendship bond with a colored boy. Unfortunately this bond is not powerful enough to stop Kallie from being bullied by a fairly smaller, arrogant scholar, Frits. To make matters worse, Kallie falls in love with Frits's sister Annetjie, but will never have a taste of sweet love if he can't defend himself against Frits. Luckily for Kallie, his tow-truck driving older brother, Mike, whom is hooked on Kung-Fu movies, comes to the rescue. Mike is a bit of a racist, but the unthinkable happens and he also falls in love. With Kallie's new friend's sister! It might merely be the fact that she drives a pimped up car, shooting flames out the exhaust and you name it, but it might also be the age old saying that true love has no boundaries. This is also then truer in Kallie's case, stating that he will stop at nothing to get to Annetjie. This is where the make or break period starts, as Mike decides to give Kallie a few pointers in the art of Karate. They even go in search of extra professional mentorship from the Weekend Assassins, but soon realize that these guys are also wannabes and in dire need of help, maybe more so than Kallie. Kallie's mother on the other hand, keeps a firm eye on the two of them and wants to take Kallie to professional Karate lessons from the master, Soon Pretorius. This sets off to become a hilarious adventure for Kallie in the quest of getting to know himself somewhat better and to win the girl. In the meanwhile, Mike, is constantly on the run from the police for being a "creative" tow-trucker, rigging his own accident scenes. A great team effort evolves between Mike and Kallie. With the upcoming talent show at school, Kallie realizes that this might be the opportunity he has been waiting for. Luckily the competition isn't really that strong. Kallie knows there is only way he will woo Annetjie... This also leads to a final showdown between Kallie and Frits... A true Afrikaans Comedy in the making.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?286885</url></doc>
