<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="287100">
  <docid>287100</docid>
  <title>Karishma Kali Kaa</title>
  <year>1990</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Punjabi, Ashok</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Punjabi, Ashok</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Lahiri, Bappi</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhatt, Urmila</actor>
      <role>Shiv's mom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dhawan, Anil (I)</actor>
      <role>Police Commissioner</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dubey, C.S.</actor>
      <role>Parvati's Advocate</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gokhale, Vikram</actor>
      <role>Sadhu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jadhwani, Kamal</actor>
      <role>Advocate Daruwala</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Roopesh</actor>
      <role>Inspector Ganpat Godbole</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Murad, Raza</actor>
      <role>Ghanshyam Dhabaria</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Muthu, Pramod</actor>
      <role>Mantri Sampoorna Anand</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ranjeet</actor>
      <role>Dr. Ajay Ganotra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sinha, Shatrughan</actor>
      <role>CID Inspector Shiv 'Shiva' Kumar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Subbiraj</actor>
      <role>2nd Police Commissioner</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Parvati is a devotee of Devi Maa Kali and lives a poor lifestyle in a village in India. One night after offering prayers to Devi Maa Kali, the Poojari asks Parvati to take care of the jewelry and deposit it in the bank the next day. Before Parvati could do so, she is sexually assaulted by four men namely Mantri Sampoorna Anand, Ghanshyam Dhabaria, Advocate Daruwala, and Dr. Ajay Ganotra, who subsequently kill the Poojari and abscond with the jewelry. Inspector Ganpat Godbole blames the death and the theft on Parvati and arrests her, but she manages to escape with the help of a Sadhu, who entrusts her with heavenly powers and asks her to apprehend and kill her assailants, bring back the jewelry, and offer herself as a sacrifice to Devi Maa Kali. Parvati sets about this task, rescues a young boy named Pappu, whose brother is CID Inspector Shiv Kumar, who she falls in love with. But when Shiv finds out that Parvati is wanted for theft and murder, he arrests her, has her tried in Court, where she is found guilty and sentenced to be hanged. The question remains: how will Parvati avenge her humiliation and retrieve the stolen jewelry?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?287100</url></doc>
