<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="287579">
  <docid>287579</docid>
  <title>Kash... Aap Hamare Hote</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Ali, Akiv</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Musical</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">14 February 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Peepat, Ravindra</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Shah, Beena</producer>
    <producer>Nankoosingh, Ganesh</producer>
    <producer>Shah, Rajesh (I)</producer>
    <producer>Babbar, Nadira</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Peepat, Ravindra</writer>
    <writer>Tiwari, Atul</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Shrivastava, Adesh</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ahmed, Riyaz</actor>
      <role>Jay's friend</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Babbar, Juhi</actor>
      <role>Amrita</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Babbar, Raj</actor>
      <role>Sardar Teja Singh Brar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gupta, Raavee</actor>
      <role>Daljit Brar (Dolly)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Sharad S.</actor>
      <role>Randeep Raj Mankotia</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lever, Johnny</actor>
      <role>Native Indian Black face</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nigam, Sonu</actor>
      <role>Jay Kumar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Patni, Hanif</actor>
      <role>Jay's friend</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, Om</actor>
      <role>Yashwant Raj Mankotia</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shaq, Vivek</actor>
      <role>Jay's friend</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tate, Prashant</actor>
      <role>Jay's friend</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Yashwantraj Mankotia (Om Puri) has brought up the daughter of his late friend, Amrita (Juhi Babbar) with love and affection as his own daughter. He plans to marry her to his only son, Randeep (Sharad Kapoor), who is settled in Canada. Randeep is reluctant to visit India to see his father, but does so when his father feigns heart trouble. Randeep is upset that he has to leave his business. He gets even more upset when his father proposes marriage with Amrita. Randeep reluctantly agrees to marry Amrita in order to get his father's inheritance. After the marriage, Randeep and Amrita travel to Canada, where Amrita finds that Randeep has a live-in girlfriend/spouse/business partner by the name of Simone (Saadhika). Simone and Randeep humilate her and she runs away. She hides in the garage of Jay Kumar (Sonu Nigam) and both eventually fall in love. Daljit "Dolly" Brar (Ravee Gupta) is the daughter of Jay's boss, and is jealous of the relationship developing between Amrita and Jay, so she fires him. Randeep has engaged some men and asked them to hunt down Amrita and kill her. Fearing for the well-being of Amrita, Yeshwantraj journeys to Canada, only to find her missing. Randeep attempts to somehow convince his dad that Amrita has eloped with some unknown man. Yeshwantraj continues looking for Amrita, not knowing that the results will change his life forever.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?287579</url></doc>
