<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="290257">
  <docid>290257</docid>
  <title>Khandan</title>
  <year>1965</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Singham, A. Paul Durai</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Musical</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">U</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <directors>
    <director>Bhimsingh, A.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Menon, Vasu</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bhimsingh, A.</writer>
    <writer>Krishan, Rajendra</writer>
    <writer>Solaimalai, M.S.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Ravi (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arundev</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Behl, Nutan</actor>
      <role>Radha G. Lal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chatterjee, Sulochana</actor>
      <role>Parvati Shankar. Lal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Choti, Mohan</actor>
      <role>Manmauji</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dutt, Sunil</actor>
      <role>Govind S. Lal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Helen (I)</actor>
      <role>Jati (Dancer)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kala, Jeevan</actor>
      <role>Sati (Dancer)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Krishna, Manmohan</actor>
      <role>Shankar Ramswaroop Lal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Sudesh (I)</actor>
      <role>Shyam S. Lal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Prakash, Om (I)</actor>
      <role>Jeevandas Ramswaroop Lal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pran (I)</actor>
      <role>Navrangi Lal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ravikant</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>After the passing of Ramswaroop Lal, his two sons, Jeevandas and Shankar take over the control of their farmland. Jeevandas marries Bhagvanti and has no children, while Shankar marries Parvati and has two sons, Govind and Shyam. Due to an accident with an electric pole, Govind's right side gets paralyzed. Years later, Shyam has gone for further studies to the big city, while the only relatives of Bhagvanti, Navrangi Lal and his sister, Neelima, have moved in with the Lal family. When Shyam returns, he falls in love with Neelima, and then begin a series of misunderstandings and disagreements which result in the house being divided in two - with Jeevandas, Bhagvanti, Shyam, Navrangi, and Neelima on one side, and Govind, his wife, Radha, Shankar, and Parvati on the other. Navrangi borrows money from Bhagvanti and invests it in a Carnival, however, most of his earnings are stolen by two dancers, Jati and Sati. He then borrows more money, this time from Shyam, and purchases an elephant. Govind and Radha rejoice when they give birth to normal son, Navjeevandas Lal. Weeks later, Navrangi plans a novel move with his carnival, that is to have the elephant throw a child from it's trunk - and the child he plans to use is none other than Govind's son. Watch what impact this has on the entire family when they find out that Navjeevandas has been abducted.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?290257</url></doc>
