<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="291572">
  <docid>291572</docid>
  <title>Kill Time</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Aschmann, Carsten</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>hate</keyword>
    <keyword>sex</keyword>
    <keyword>boredom</keyword>
    <keyword>isolation</keyword>
    <keyword>urban-paranoia</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Germany">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Germany">15 November 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">18</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Aschmann, Carsten</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Nilsen, Bj</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sigmarsson, Sigtryggur</actor>
      <role>Icelandic Guest</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A short film about metropolitan boredom. Space is controlled by isolation and paranoia. Some guy (the Icelandic artist Sigtryggur Berg Sigmarsson) chases his demons and analyzes his environment with a misanthropic view. He directly speaks into the camera, sketching out a hopeless conception of the world: "I tell you people are no good, they are cheap. I hate people." No one is innocent; the whole world is on the list, even the fat guy next door. Carsten Aschmann brilliantly translates Sigmarsson's text into moving picture. He makes the leading character wander around in urban sediment (backed by the dark soundtrack of Stilluppsteypa and the Swedish BJ Nilsen) and captures his undifferentiated attacks on film. With dark sunglasses, unshaved, and dressed in a parka, on a feedlot outside the city. In search of cocaine and sex, in front of shop windows in the red light district. There is this unpleasant constraint, to constantly place something between himself and the environment. He finally finds relaxation in brutal union with a rubber-doll, resembling old Ed Gein in his hut.He said: i would prefer being a doll in this world; I think I'd be better off as a doll. All emotions and fears are switch off. The last goal is to switch off the torture of boredom.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?291572</url></doc>
