<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="292067">
  <docid>292067</docid>
  <title>Kimchi Warrior</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
    <language>Korean</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>South Korea</country>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="South Korea">2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Kang, Young Man</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kelley, Jin</producer>
    <producer>Kang, Young Man</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Brody, Dylan</writer>
    <writer>Kang, Young Man</writer>
    <writer>Kelley, Jin</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Colceri, Tim</actor>
      <role>Evil Lord of Disease</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Coughlin, James (II)</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Coughlin, Jim</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Johnson, Kim Marie</actor>
      <role>Cop</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mamoun, Monir</actor>
      <role>Curry Warrior</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Michaels, Jessica</actor>
      <role>Gochu Warrioress</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Phillips Jr., Rick</actor>
      <role>Mad Cow</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Ancient Asia. A world governed by rules like honor, family, and tradition. Three great civilizations were ruled this way for centuries. Long ago the greatest battles were not for land, or tyranic rule... but rather, a recipe. A recipe shrouded in legend. A recipe... for Kimchi. After the great wars, Korea would claim the book for itself... and it's power. Since, in attempt to restore family honor, the rival contries have tried to regain the book and gain its power for themselves. Each generation has brought forth a single champion to protect the potent magic, the KIMCHI WARRIOR. Receiving supernatural fighting abilities and astounding martial arts skills from a magical Kimchi recipe hidden within the book, the warrior takes on the burden of protecting the book and passing its secrets down to his descendants. The next in line for this responsibility is a young man named Dongsik Cho. The son of an immigrant shopkeeper in Los Angeles, he knows only the drudgery of work in a small supermarket and the kimchi kitchen in back. But when a brutal warlord who killed Dongsik's father, comes to the U.S. and searches for the book, Dongsik's time has come to lear the truth. The clumsy, cabbage scented young man must defend the secret of his family, protect the spirit of his people, and try to win the heart of a beautiful American cop. THE MASK meets RUMBLE IN THE BRONX in this martial arts comedy about a lovable loser who becomes a superhero.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?292067</url></doc>
