<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="292789">
  <docid>292789</docid>
  <title>Kingdom of Women</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Ng, Benson (II)</editor>
    <editor>Wu, Cynthia (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>china</keyword>
    <keyword>matriarchy</keyword>
    <keyword>kingdom</keyword>
    <keyword>matriarchal-society</keyword>
    <keyword>women</keyword>
    <keyword>amazon</keyword>
    <keyword>marriage</keyword>
    <keyword>walking</keyword>
    <keyword>lama</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">15 January 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">56</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Flander, Elizabeth Dukal</director>
    <director>Zou, Roger J.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Tang, Bin</producer>
    <producer>Chang, Kenneth (IV)</producer>
    <producer>Chang, William</producer>
    <producer>Hill, Lynne</producer>
    <producer>Wu, Cynthia (I)</producer>
    <producer>Zou, Roger J.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Zou, Roger J.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Zhang, Yi Cheng</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chou, Wah-Shan</actor>
      <role>Himself - Anthropologist</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Eckhart, George</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zhang, Yi Cheng</actor>
      <role>Flute Player</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In a remote corner of Southwestern China, at the border of Yunnan and Sichuan provinces, lies a body of water called Lugu Lake. Nestled against a backdrop of snow-capped mountains, nearly nine thousand feet above sea level, the 30 square-mile lake and its surrounding countryside form an isolated and independent world called the Mosuo society. After nearly three thousand years of isolation, Mosuo society remains the most complete and intact matriarchal society. Like most tribal cultures, the Mosuo regard religion as a major part of their life. In particular, the people of Lugu Lake revere two types of spiritual guides: the Buddhist Lamas and the Daba. These spiritual guides are leaders of the local religion. Tibetan Buddhism was brought to the Yong Ning region in 1276. Since then, Tibetan Buddhism has become the primary religion of the Mosuo people, and they have adapted it to fit their culture. Every year on July 25th of the lunar calendar, a Mountain Festival is dedicated to the most celebrated deity - the mountain goddess Ga Mu. Families gather at Ga Mu's temple high up on the mountain to pay their respects. Mosuo culture has served the interests of its people for centuries. Families care for the sick and the elderly. Conflicts over property are unusual and easily resolved. There are no records of sexual assault, and there are no conflicts between men over women. Unlike western households, the Mosuo women rule the home. All property and assets are transferred to the female side of the family. Even the surname is passed down from mother to daughter.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?292789</url></doc>
