<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="293818">
  <docid>293818</docid>
  <title>Kitewallah</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Dhruvo, Moin Hassan</editor>
    <editor>Guha, Paramita</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>kite-song</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="UK">R</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">28 February 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">29</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Venkat, Kiran Valipa</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Parigi, Sudarshan Reddy</producer>
    <producer>Venkat, Kiran Valipa</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Venkat, Kiran Valipa</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Bhanot, Upamanyu</composer>
    <composer>Sharma, Jon Curtis</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Agarwal, Mohinder</actor>
      <role>Babban Mia</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arora, Bhanu</actor>
      <role>Afroz</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mogha, Alka</actor>
      <role>Razia</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Prasad, Mohit Kishore</actor>
      <role>School Teacher</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tabir</actor>
      <role>Abu</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Tragedy strikes Razia and her eight year old Abu, when her kite-maker husband dies. They migrate to her brother's place Rohru near the foot hills of Himalayas. Her brother Babban Mia is an apple farmer and a fruit &amp; Vegetable seller in Rohru. Abu joins the local school where Babban Mia's children Afroz and Arshiya go. Life is not easy for Abu and Razia as they have to cope with the new place and people. Razia decides to make a living by selling kites like they used to do in Hyderabad. Meanwhile, Abu is trying hard to make friends and find company at the kite games. All his attempts at winning friends are faltered by Bashir. Abu decides to lure them to playing kites but it doesn't seem to be easy. Abu resorts to playing marbles, one of the many ideas he uses to make friends at the kite games. The kites are not selling at the shop and are ready to be thrown out. Abu needs to support his mother and he hasn't much time and chances. Until one fateful day, when he meets an opponent at fighter kiting in the blue skies. All the while Abu tried and tried, he never gave up.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?293818</url></doc>
