<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="294743">
  <docid>294743</docid>
  <title>Knock Out Bondage #9</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adult</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>sex</keyword>
    <keyword>bondage</keyword>
    <keyword>hardcore</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">82</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Anton, J.</director>
    <director>Chance, Loren</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Anton, J.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Anton, J.</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chance, Loren</actor>
      <role>Loren</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chance, Sasha</actor>
      <role>Sasha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Flame, Penny</actor>
      <role>Penny</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Green, Mary Jane (II)</actor>
      <role>Mary Jane</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Laine, Charlie</actor>
      <role>Charlie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Marceau, Jewel</actor>
      <role>Jewel</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In the 9th installment of the Knock Out Bondage series, we follow a series of white-slavery tales. In the first story, Mary Jane and Charlie look luscious in lingerie as they prepare to model in a fashion show. But, it's all a trap, set by white slavers and knock out gas fills the room. They try to escape by crawling up some stairs, but they pass out before they get too far. They wake up bound in one of Loren's stringent positions, gagged with tape. In story 2, Jewell and Anastasia apply for a job...but, guess what? the job is slavery and the girls pass out after drinking drugged drinks. They wake up, now in lingerie, tied in another cruel position. In our third story, it's just another day at the office for Sinn and Penny...until a male intruder shows up and chloroforms both girls at once. When co-worker Mary Jane enters, she meets the same fate. The trio awakens securely bound and gagged. New model Sasha looks hot as a waitress in orange shorts and white top. Boss Loren knocks her out with chloroform and ties her in a very uncomfortable position before pulling up her top and fondling her tits. Sasha is chloroformed again while still bound. In the final story, Jewell is alone at work when an intruder enters and knocks her out with a blow to the head. Jewell is then bound and cloth-gagged.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?294743</url></doc>
