<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="298499">
  <docid>298499</docid>
  <title>Kuch Dil Ne Kaha</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Urdu</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Pakistan</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Pakistan">8 December 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">35</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Suleman, S.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Suleman, S.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Ansari, Bushra</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ansari, Bushra</actor>
      <role>Shaista</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Masood, Nouman</actor>
      <role>Kabeer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sheikh, Javed (I)</actor>
      <role>Ahsan</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Kuch Dil Ne Kaha is the story of Kabeer, Shaista &amp; Savera. Kabeer &amp; Savera have two grown - up sons. Savera, a typical housewife, is no longer valued by her husband and has been reduced to no more than an old piece of furniture kept in the house. She longs for attention from her husband and lives a dreary existence. Her life changes however when she leaves for London to visit her ailing brother. While she is away she tells Shaista to take care of her house and sons. During Shaista and Kabeers interaction and attachments grows and develops between them. On the way back from London, Savera's flight is delayed and she is stranded in Bangkok for a few days where she meets Ahsan an Indian Muslim who is also stranded because of flight delays. Ahsan and Savera strike up an immediate friendship and the three days they spend together are her happiest of their lives. Savera comes back home but does not know about Kabeer and Shaista's affair. When Kabeer gets to know about his wife's attraction to another man, he throws her out. Savera then moves to Bangkok with her older son. Shaista meets her own end and Savera faces Ahsan in an earth shattering climax.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?298499</url></doc>
