<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="298555">
  <docid>298555</docid>
  <title>Kudiyon Ka Hai Zamaana</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Mengle, Vijay</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Butala, Amar</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Butala, Amar</producer>
    <producer>Khan, Mejoo</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Butala, Amar</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Darbar, Iqbal</composer>
    <composer>Darbar, Yasin</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chaudhry, Mahima</actor>
      <role>Anjali</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chinappa, Nikhil</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Das, Vasundhara</actor>
      <role>Natasha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Gaurav (I)</actor>
      <role>Rahul</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khedekar, Sachin</actor>
      <role>Akash</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mushran, Ashwin</actor>
      <role>Cyrus</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Patel, Ashmit</actor>
      <role>Amar Khanna</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sadanand, Kabir</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Mayuri, Kanika, Natasha, and Anjali have been friends for many years. All of them come from very wealthy families. While Mayuri has been married 4 times, she still has feelings for her first husband, Girish, and keeps aloof from her current spouse, Akash; Natasha is married to Punit, and is expecting a child; Kanika is in the process of getting married to Rahul; while Anjali, who is 24 years of age, is unmarried. All four constantly bet large sums of money on trivial issues, mostly involving men, but only Anjali keeps winning. On the eve of Kanika's marriage, she, Mayuri and Natasha get Anjali to commit in writing that she will only get married after she turns 25, to which she agrees. Now her three friends get together and resolve to find men, who will woo, win her heart, and get married to her before she turns 25. Accordingly 4 men attempt to woo Anjali and try to win her heart. Karan is a stock-broker, wealthy and handsome; Rocky is a wannabe WWF wrestler, wealthy, and handsome; Cyrus is a bit of a child-man, but is rich; and Amar Khanna is a wealthy singer. Anjali is all set to give her heart to one of these men - but just before she says yes - she finds out about the bet - and refuses to marry any one of the men. Does this mean that Anjali stands to win this bet also?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?298555</url></doc>
