<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="298510">
  <docid>298510</docid>
  <title>Kuchhe Dhaage</title>
  <year>1973</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">A</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <directors>
    <director>Khosla, Raj</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Khosla, Raj</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kudalkar, Laxmikant Shantaram</composer>
    <composer>Sharma, Pyarelal Ramprasad</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bedi, Kabir</actor>
      <role>Roopa/Pandit Tulsiram</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhagwan, Master</actor>
      <role>Ram Bharose</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chatterjee, Moushumi</actor>
      <role>Sona</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Trilok (I)</actor>
      <role>Subedar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khanna, Vinod</actor>
      <role>Thakur Lakhan Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Dev (I)</actor>
      <role>Thakur Bahadur Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Murad</actor>
      <role>Judge</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Raj, Jagdish</actor>
      <role>Amrutlal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Randhir</actor>
      <role>Balwant's father</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ritesh (I)</actor>
      <role>Bhola</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Singh, K.N.</actor>
      <role>Sona's Father</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In the state of Madhya Pradesh, India, particularly in the Chambal Ravine there are abundance of bandit gangs, chiefly consisting of Brahmans and Thakurs, both carrying on their age-old rivalry and hatred for each other from generation to generation. Our story revolves around Brahman Pandit Tulsiram who betrays Thakur Bahadur Singh to the police, and as a result Bahadur is sentenced to be hanged. Widowed, pregnant and devastated, Bahadur's wife swears that she will raise her child to hunt down and kill Tulsiram at any cost. She gives birth to a son, names him Lakhan, and lets the bandits teach their way of life. As soon as Lakhan grows up, he kills Tulsiram. Hearing of his father's death, army-man, Roopa, resigns and openly swears to kill Lakhan. Unknown to both of them, a beautiful young woman named Sona enters their lives, making them wish that they were living a honest life instead, and both fall head over heels in love with her. Both are on the verge of changing their lives when they find out that the other also has fallen in love for Sona, and they return back to their bitter oaths - kill or be killed.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?298510</url></doc>
