<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="301532">
  <docid>301532</docid>
  <title>L'amore proibito dell'eroe</title>
  <year>1995</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>loss-of-lover</keyword>
    <keyword>gay-soldier</keyword>
    <keyword>gay-interest</keyword>
    <keyword>israel</keyword>
    <keyword>gay-rights</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Italian</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">26 June 1997</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Italy">36</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Minerba, Giovanni</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Steiner, Adir</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Doron Maizel is not an ordinary soldier, but a respected and esteemed colonel and doctor, who has been having a love affair over the past seven years with a handsome young man, Adir Steiner. In this way, he challenges the rules and conventions and risks compromising his own chances at a career. The army understands and tolerates a strange and contradictory relationship like this, where the being of one part of the couple the soldier walks the line between duty and passion every day. The relationship goes on until disease enters the scene . A malignant melanoma brings Doron to his death in a span of a few months. Adir has survived, but slowly, tenaciously and, above all, in extreme solitude, he decides to remember and bear witness, Re any jew, by conducting his personal battle. He himself becomes a "soldier" in order to get the army and the state to recognize him officially as a widower. In this way he could use some of the social services that are guaranteed to those who normally find themselves in this status, such as the transferral of the pension.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?301532</url></doc>
