<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="304896">
  <docid>304896</docid>
  <title>L.A. Blues</title>
  <year>1995</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <editors>
    <editor>Möller, Ralf (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Lohner, Henning</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bernheim, Chantal</producer>
    <producer>Lohner, Henning</producer>
    <producer>Lohner, Peter</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Lohner, Henning</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Lohner, Henning</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hopper, Dennis</actor>
      <role>Host</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>World famous director and actor Dennis Hopper is one of the few great figures of the American "Author's Cinema". As a photographer and painter he has exhibited throughout America and Europe. We join Hopper on one of his regular excursions to the backlands of the greater Los Angeles area to discover through his photographic eye the city he has been living in for most of his life. Our film essay is a document to portray Hopper's artistic aesthetic and how the barren walls of the city of Los Angeles inspires the artist. We experience Hopper seclusively, when he goes to work alone, just with a photo camera; himself commenting on what he is seeing within the obvious, commonly known aspects of one of the world's great cities. Hopper takes us to the backstreets of Los Angeles, reveals to us the hidden language of graffitti, and of the cover-up "art" on the walls of his city. Images from "past encounters", news reel footage relating to the gang wars, riots, and the homeless in Los Angeles are inserted into the film narrative like flashbacks of sudden dream-like memories, embellishing Hopper's discourse.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?304896</url></doc>
