<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="305824">
  <docid>305824</docid>
  <title>La bella Lola</title>
  <year>1962</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Alcocer, Teresa</editor>
  </editors>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>based-on-novel</keyword>
    <keyword>beautiful-woman</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>melodrama</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>France</country>
    <country>Spain</country>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="France">8 May 1963</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Spain">6 September 1962</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Italy">22 December 1962</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="France">88</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="Spain">111</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Balcázar, Alfonso</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Arozamena, Jesús María de</writer>
    <writer>Cussó, Miguel</writer>
    <writer>Palacio, José María</writer>
    <writer>Dumas fils, Alexandre</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>García Segura, Gregorio</composer>
    <composer>Lecuona, Ernesto</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Angelat, Josep Maria</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Caffarel, José María</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cifariello, Antonio</actor>
      <role>Armand</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cobos, Germán</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Israel, Víctor</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Martín, Roberto (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mattioli, Luisa</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Montiel, Sara</actor>
      <role>Lola</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puche, Jesús</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Re, Gustavo</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sanz, Santiago (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ulloa, Fernando (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vega, Vicente</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Villard, Franck</actor>
      <role>Edmond</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>de Armenteras, Antonio</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"La Bella Lola" (Sara Montiel) is a struggling singer trying to make a living for herself and her sister Ana (Luisa Mattioli) in late 19th Century Spain. Lola is having an affair with Gabriel (Frank Villard), a rich and influential older man who gives her jewelry and supports her singing career. Things change rapidly when Lola meets and falls in love with young playboy Javier (Antonio Cifariello), although the romance is doomed from the start. Javier belongs to an aristocratic family and has a bright future as a politician. Lola is just a singer with a dubious past. As La Bella Lola's fame and fortune increases, the affair grows to proportions that become alarming to Gabriel, to Javier's relatives and to society in general. Lola and Javier run off to a deserted beach where they live days of great happiness away from the influences that are conspiring to separate them. Soon they must face reality: Lola decides to drop Gabriel and her career while Javier decides to forgo his family and future. The decision is not very well received or accepted specially by Javier's mother, who manages a secret meeting with Lola and persuades her to sacrifice her love to save Javier's life. Under false pretenses Javier is sent away and upon return finds Lola singing and back with Gabriel. When he confronts Lola, she tells him she doesn't care for him any longer. Heartbroken, Javier goes back to his family and obligations while Lola tries to forget by drinking and partying hard. Eventually such living takes its toll and she ends up destitute and with heart disease. Meanwhile, Javier has not found happiness in his social status and his mother confesses the truth. He searches for Lola and finds she is trying to make a come back singing at a local Casino. He shows up at the performance and Lola spots him in the crowd. Their eyes meet briefly but after the show Lola runs away and collapses on the street. Later, Javier makes his way to her home where he finds her laying in bed. Again Lola tries to send him away but now he is wise to her intentions. Javier embraces her and promises never to leave her. Lola remembers their happy days at the beach long ago... It seems they are happy at last but, suddenly, Javier realizes she has died in his arms.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?305824</url></doc>
