<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="309318">
  <docid>309318</docid>
  <title>La fisica dell'acqua</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Calabria, Esmeralda</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Mystery</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Italian</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Czech Republic">July 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Canada">August 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Italy">1 January 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Farina, Felice</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Casiraghi, Mauro</writer>
    <writer>Farina, Felice</writer>
    <writer>Fiorini, Eleonora</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Piersanti, Franco (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Amendola, Claudio</actor>
      <role>Claudio</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brizzolara, Francesca</actor>
      <role>Maestra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Calamari, Ferruccio</actor>
      <role>Agente immobiliare</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cardaci, Giorgia</actor>
      <role>Poliziotta</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cortellesi, Paola</actor>
      <role>Giulia</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dionisi, Stefano</actor>
      <role>Daniele</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ferrari, Fabio</actor>
      <role>Manfredi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Frontini, Camilla</actor>
      <role>Invitata</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Longhi, Samuele</actor>
      <role>Alessandro ad 1 anno</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Negro, Davide (I)</actor>
      <role>Poliziotto</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pavanello, Lorenzo</actor>
      <role>Filippo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Valvassori, Lorenzo</actor>
      <role>Alessandro</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Alessandro, the young protagonist of this story, lost his father when he was very little. He lives with his mother, Giulia, a swimming teacher, in a nice house in the hills just outside of town. It's a bright day. He is awakened by a car's engine noise. Something is wrong: he sees his mother leaving with his uncle Claudio and starts running after them, terrified, screaming. He can't stop her. The car is in a terrible collision and Alessandro gets to the accident scene only to see the ambulance leaving with its siren full on. Alessandro is taken to the police station. He's in a state of shock. An inspector looks after him. Crying, Alessandro confesses to sabotaging the car brakes and causing the accident. The inspector is a special guy. He manages to calm him down and makes him tell his story, starting from the day uncle Claudio came back to their home. Claudio is his father's brother and had not seen him since he was two years old. That is when Alessandro's life began to fill with confused shadows from the past, with fears and troublesome "visions", and begins sharing his worries with his best friend Edo. The arrival of Claudio brought big changes to Alessandro's life. Not only did the man begin courting his mother, who never re-married after her husband's death, but the old house Alessandro is very attached to had been put on sale. During the interrogation Alessandro grows more and more uneasy: like a young detective he is forced to dig into his past, deep into the blocks of his memory, until the true tragic motives of his dislike for his uncle are unveiled.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?309318</url></doc>
