<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="311577">
  <docid>311577</docid>
  <title>La marmite diabolique</title>
  <year>1903</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>French</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">6 February 1904</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
<plot>A cook and his assistant are seen preparing dinner. While cook leaves the room he cautions his assistant to watch the pot so that it will not boil over. The assistant proceeds to pick the feathers from a chicken. Meanwhile the pot boils over and Satan appears, surrounded by a cloud of steam. He alights and creeps over to within a few feet of the bench on which the assistant is sitting. Suddenly the chicken takes life and Satan stands out in the centre of the floor. He seizes the assistant and, after wrestling with him, throws him bodily into the large pot, the chicken meanwhile hops away. Satan disappears and the cook returns. Missing his assistant, he looks into the pot and tastes the contents thereof with a large ladle. The soup not being to his taste, he digs into it with a large spit, when out comes one of the legs of his assistant. He dips in again and repeats until the entire body, in small pieces, lies on the floor before him. Fishing for the head, he finally pulls out the head of an ass. Throwing it on the floor, the pieces come slowly together, but the head of the assistant is still missing. He returns to the cauldron and finally fishes out the head, which, together with an arm that had been overlooked, he throws at his assistant, and he is again restored to his natural shape. He relates his experience to the cook, who listens with mouth wide open. In the meantime the cauldron takes the shape of a huge devil head, and in their excitement to run away the bench is overturned and the cook is precipitated to the floor with great force. Extraordinarily funny.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?311577</url></doc>
