<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="317615">
  <docid>317615</docid>
  <title>Ladies as Gentleman: Drag Kings on Tour</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Japan">21 July 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Canada">27 June 2004</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">23 July 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Slutsky, Sonia</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Itkoff, Sandra</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kat, Johnny</actor>
      <role>Johnny Kat</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In Drag Kings on Tour, a feature documentary in the spirit of "Priscilla, Queen of the Desert," we tour North America in a motor home with a lively ensemble of drag kings (women who take on male personae) as they perform a politically charged burlesque in cities as diverse as Biloxi, Mississippi; St. Louis, Missouri; and Toronto, Ontario. This cinema vérité road movie is the first feature length film to focus exclusively on the lives of drag kings. Drag Kings on Tour has had sold out, enthusiastic screenings at virtually every major gay &amp; lesbian film festival across North America. Drag Kings on Tour features the popular music of Annie Lennox; David Bowie; Teddy Pendergrass; and Boys Don't Cry. The Kings-alternately hilarious and profound-sing, flirt, and inspire their audiences to understand complexities surrounding gender. Drag Kings on Tour fits into a growing, national trend. Drag Kings have begun to gain prominence, a sizable following and fan base, and mainstream recognition in popular culture with appearances on The L-Word, Sex in the City, and daytime talk shows. Drag Kings on Tour goes beyond mere fascination with an underground scene, appealing to a wide audience with a telling portrait of attitudes about sex, tolerance, gender, family, and identity. The drama of the film lies between the kings' interpersonal relationships and their interaction with audience members across the country. The Kings confront traditional definitions of masculinity and femininity, as both men and women learn about themselves their attractions, and identities regardless of their sexual orientation.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?317615</url></doc>
