<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="318703">
  <docid>318703</docid>
  <title>Land</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">22 September 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Pinder, Julian T.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Flahive, Gerry</producer>
    <producer>Scherzer, Paul</producer>
    <producer>Pinder, Julian T.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Pinder, Julian T.</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ortega, Daniel (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The most important election in Nicaragua's history looms on the horizon. Daniel Ortega, leader of the Sandinista revolutionaries, is ahead in the polls. At the same time, the southern coast of the country is being transformed from primitive fishing villages into the next Dominican Republic, due to monied foreigners. America warns the Nicaraguan people against voting in the former Socialist president -the last time it happened America financed the Contras, and it became a decade long civil war. Drawing from a wealth of intriguing characters -politicians, American expatriots, former soldiers, land developers, and tourists- the film weaves among the worlds of corrupt politics, American interventionism, American expatriots, gated communities, reclusive cowboys, and real estate moguls in this wild west frontier country where the gun is mightier than the law. Will Ortega and the Sandinistas re-gain Nicaragua, taking land away from the foreign developers, drawing American retribution, but ultimately reviving the dignity of the Nicaraguan people? Land delves headlong into the world that is contemporary Nicaragua, and the outcome borders on the carnivalesque.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?318703</url></doc>
