<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="320624">
  <docid>320624</docid>
  <title>Last Rights: Facing End-of-Life Choices</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Gavin, Chris (III)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>death</keyword>
    <keyword>hastened-death</keyword>
    <keyword>rationed-care</keyword>
    <keyword>life-choices</keyword>
    <keyword>assisted-suicide</keyword>
    <keyword>aid-in-dying</keyword>
    <keyword>patient-rights</keyword>
    <keyword>civil-rights</keyword>
    <keyword>hospice</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">10 October 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">57</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Cantor, Karen</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Gavin, Chris (III)</producer>
    <producer>Cantor, Karen</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Cantor, Karen</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Stephàn, Harold</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Who decides how life ends? The patient? The family? The physician? The health care system? This film looks at the choices available to four dying people. The intent is to introduce viewers to the complexity of end-of life choices. The four terminally ill patients featured in "Last Rights" come from across the United States. Each was determined to confront his/her illness and plan his/her final days on earth according to his/her own desires and sense of dignity. These patients and their families turned to clergy, the medical profession and, in some cases, the government in order to access information and answers to matters practical and spiritual. Their decisions have profoundly impacted their families. The desire to hasten the death of a terminally ill patient brings up a multitude of issues - medical, ethical, religious, political. Viewers will be introduced to some of these dilemmas inherent to end-of-live choices: What role does society have in preserving life? What is society's obligation to relieve suffering? How do religious and legal institutions deal with these responsibilities?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?320624</url></doc>
