<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="321173">
  <docid>321173</docid>
  <title>Latter-Day Saint Leaders: Past and Present</title>
  <year>1948</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Wise, Frank S.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>History</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>latter-day-saints</keyword>
    <keyword>missionary</keyword>
    <keyword>religion</keyword>
    <keyword>lds-film</keyword>
    <keyword>mormon</keyword>
    <keyword>mormonism</keyword>
    <keyword>voice-over-narration</keyword>
    <keyword>church-history</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1948</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">21</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Clawson, Shirley Young</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Clawson, Chester</producer>
    <producer>Clawson, Shirley Young</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Wise, Frank S.</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grant, Heber J.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McKay, David O.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Richards, Wayne (IV)</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Smith, George Albert (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Smith, Joseph F.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Talmage, James E.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Widtsoe, John A.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This is a compilation of some historically important films which were crumbling to dust (on nitrate stock) when discovered in a basement during the late 1940's. In scenes that survived, many General Authorities (senior leaders) of the Mormon church were photographed in Salt Lake City, usually on the grounds near the temple. The earliest shows The First Presidency (Joseph F. Smith, Anton H. Lund, &amp; John Henry Smith) during the time of the General Conference of the church in April, 1910. Much of the remainder of the film was taken at the time of the General Conference of April, 1916. However, some footage up through the 1920's is also included. Members of The Quorum of the Twelve and others are shown in groups or standing alone, including Heber J. Grant, George Albert Smith, James E. Talmage, Stephen L. Richards, Melvin J. Ballard, John A. Widtsoe, Reed Smoot, J. Golden Kimball, David O. McKay, Francis M. Lyman, George F. Richards, Anthon W. Ivins, Presiding Patriarch Hyrum G. Smith, Joseph Fielding Smith, Charles W. Penrose, Charles W. Nibley, and B.H. Roberts. President Smith is even shown entering a Packard touring car in front of the Church Office Building. Originally shot at 16 frames per second, the scenes were converted to 24 fps for sound projection by printing every other frame twice. Biographical information is given in narration, with some leaders still living at the time this film was released.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?321173</url></doc>
