<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="321867">
  <docid>321867</docid>
  <title>Lazarus Lives</title>
  <year>2000</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 June 2000</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Rich, Richard</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Noss, Terry L.</producer>
    <producer>Tobin, Thomas J.</producer>
    <producer>Brown, Jared F.</producer>
    <producer>Young, Seldon</producer>
    <producer>Brown, Jared F.</producer>
    <producer>Rich, Richard</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Nissen, Brian (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Bestor, Kurt</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>The story opens in a cave - a Leper colony. One of its members, Simon, has a daughter, Sarah, who is also afflicted and gravely ill. Simon is a friend of Lazarus and was his previous business partner before he took ill. Meanwhile, Lazarus and his sister, Mary, prepare care packages for Simon and the others at the Leper colony. Mary has made a special doll for Sarah. They go to visit the Leper colony to deliver the care packages, including the doll. When they arrive, they receive the news that Sarah has died from her leprosy. Stricken with grief, Lazarus and Mary return to their home. Lazarus then goes to town and delivers letters from the Lepers to their families and friends who are not afflicted. While in town, Lazarus witnesses Jesus healing a sick woman. Moved by the experience, Lazarus rushes home to tell his two sisters. He gathers his belongings and goes to his friend, Simon, at the Leper colony. He finds Simon and then takes him to town to see Jesus. Christ heals the afflicted Simon of his leprosy. In thanksgiving and appreciation, Mary invites Jesus back to their home for dinner and rest. When Jesus leaves, he asks if He may return and visit some day. On one trip to Lazarus's house, Jesus visits with Mary and Martha as Lazarus is in Jerusalem with Simon. Mary kneels at Jesus' feet to listen to His words while Martha serves. Jesus encourages Martha to join them and partake of what is more important fellowship and a lesson about God's glory through victory over death. In Jerusalem, Lazarus takes ill and Simon brings him home to his sisters. Martha beckons Simon to go and bring Jesus back. The story cuts to a scene where Jesus and some of His disciples are met on the streets by some skeptics. They inquire whether or not He is truly God's son. They want Him to prove it. Jesus responds by sharing the story of Jonah who lay three days in the belly of a whale and then was set free. The disciples are confused about the story of Jonah and ask Jesus to explain further. He foretells of His own crucifixion, death, and resurrection on the third day. Peter challenges Jesus -- not understanding the necessity of Jesus' own death and resurrection for the salvation of mankind. Jesus' power over death is the ultimate glory to God. Simon finds Jesus and the disciples and beckons Jesus to come to His friend, Lazarus, who is gravely ill. Jesus explains that Lazarus is already dead but goes to him in order to show the disciples and the others of His power over death. When Jesus arrives, Martha explains that Lazarus has been dead for four days. He instructs Martha to get Mary and come to Lazarus' tomb. When they arrive at the tomb, He directs that the stone should be removed from the tomb much to the astonishment of Lazarus' sisters and His own disciples. As the stone is removed, Jesus calls out "Lazarus come forth." Jesus explains that He has done this so that all may truly believe that He, the son of God, has power over death.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?321867</url></doc>
