<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="324286">
  <docid>324286</docid>
  <title>Le grand cahier</title>
  <year>2011</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>wwii</keyword>
    <keyword>twin</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Germany">12</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Germany">2011</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <producers>
    <producer>Sándor, Pál</producer>
    <producer>Söth, Sándor</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Kristof, Agota</writer>
    <writer>Szekér, András</writer>
    <writer>Szász, János</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Towards the end of World War II, people living in big cities are at the mercy of bombing raids and death from starvation. In her desperation a young mother deposits her twin sons at their grandmother's house in the country - despite the fact that she is a filthy, cruel, bestial alcoholic. The villagers only call her the Witch, because it is rumored, she poisened her husband many years earlier. Previously pampered, the twins must learn how to survive alone in the threatening wilderness. They realize that the only way to survive is to become completely unfeeling and merciless, that unless they are free from hunger, pain and emotion, they will be unable to endure what is in store for them. They fortify their spirits by reading the Bible and learning foreign languages. They practice everyday to harden their bodies and minds. They hold their hands over flames, they cut their legs, arms and chests with a knife and pour alcohol on their wounds. They injure themselves to insults and invective, and they train themselves to ignore the more insidious appeals of sentiment and love. In order to be prepared for the insanity of war and the perversions of humans the twins alter their personalities. The twins keep a written record of all they've witnessed during the war - the notebook. Their narrative style does not allow them to express any kind of emotions and that is why they concentrate on keeping their notes precise and objective. Worse, they are initiated into the corruptions and horrors of a war-torn world. They have to listen to a lecherous priest's hypocritical avowals of faith; they watch soldiers herd refugees to their death, and selfish cruelties their neighbors inflict on one another. Liberation at war's end brings the worst moments of all: rape, suicides, a brief, but grisly reunion with their mother and a vivid final tableau involving parricide, opportunism, and the twins ultimate separation. The Notebook is a fascinating and at the same time horrible story about innocent but cruel children who will resist any morale.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?324286</url></doc>
