<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="328325">
  <docid>328325</docid>
  <title>Left Lane: On the Road with Folk Poet Alix Olson</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Campbell, Sean (III)</editor>
    <editor>Sanchez, Larilyn</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>lesbian</keyword>
    <keyword>lesbian-interest</keyword>
    <keyword>poetess</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="France">29 October 2006</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">5 June 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Farinella, Samantha</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Farinella, Samantha</producer>
    <producer>Olson, Alix</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Farinella, Samantha</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Means, Pamela</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Montgomery, Lyndell</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A year in the making, Left Lane chronicles life on the road with Alix and her road manager/filmmaker Samantha Farinella as they tour the country connecting the dots from a high school visit in Lincoln, Nebraska to a CD release party in New York City. Alix Olson is an internationally touring folk poet and progressive queer artist-activist. One part peace vigil, one part protest rally, and one part joyful raucous concert, Alix ignites audiences everywhere as she performs. A self-defined global patriot, Alix emboldens audiences with her quick wit and powerful humanitarian voice. This documentary highlights spoken-word performances from around the country and a plethora of behind the scenes glimpses at the search for independent thought, grassroots defiance, passionate connection, organic food and clean laundry. Accompanied by the music of Pamela Means, Melissa Ferrick, Ember Swift, Lyndell Montgomery, Chris Pureka, and Peter Mulvey, Left Lane offers a few more untethered voices to the nucleus of grassroots progressive struggle and the future of laughter, rage, and optimism.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?328325</url></doc>
