<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="331993">
  <docid>331993</docid>
  <title>Les palais des chaussures</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Sauvage, Benoît</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="France">5 February 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="France">17</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Leddon, Michelle</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Leddon, Michelle</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Leddon, Michelle</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Keegin, Hillary</actor>
      <role>Jennifer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>de Crayencour, Amaury</actor>
      <role>Vincent</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Talking on his phone, Vincent, a twenty-something French man, explains to a friend that he is worried that Jennifer, his American friend, who will arrive to meet him soon, is going tell him that she loves him. Jennifer, an attractive thirty-something, arrives carrying a suitcase. She is taking a plane that evening to go on vacation. In a window she notices a pair of Italian heels. Vincent encourages her to buy them, but she reminds him that she is a working American girl not a bourgeois French boy like him. Vincent takes Jennifer out for a cheap lunch where he, protecting himself, starts to takes jabs at her and her insecurities. The date ends abruptly when Jennifer hints that she has feelings for Vincent. He gets up and walks off. Jennifer chases him. They fight. She starts to leave when Vincent admits that he has taken a job in New York and that when she returns from her vacation he will be gone. He convinces her to have one last coffee with him. In the café, Vincent, reminds Jennifer that she is a little too old, doesn't really have the right color of hair, and doesn't walk like he thinks a girl should walk. Jennifer endures each slight until Vincent gets up and starts hitting on a lost tourist, at which point Jennifer storms off. Vincent chases her and finds her in front of a shoe store window. "Vincent?" "Tell me?" "I don't think I'll ever find anyone to buy me a pair of shoes." Vincent drags her to the Palais Royal where, in one of Paris' most magical places, they have one last chance to reach out for each other.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?331993</url></doc>
