<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="333417">
  <docid>333417</docid>
  <title>Let's Dance!</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Adult</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>dancing</keyword>
    <keyword>teenage-boy</keyword>
    <keyword>title-based-on-song</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Ukrainian</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Ukraine</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">63</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Kostenyuk, Igor</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Eisenlohr, David</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Stephens, Guy Russ</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sergey (IV)</actor>
      <role>Himself (age 14)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vitalik</actor>
      <role>Himself (age 14)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vuychislavovitch, Schuken Roman</actor>
      <role>Himself (age 14)</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>It's springtime in the picturesque Ukrainian city of Chernivtsi. On the sun-dappled lake, ducks glide effortlessly beside bobbing boats tied-up at dockside while on a nearby street, best buddies Sergey and Vitalik are enjoying the morning sunshine and each other by pushing, shoving, and clowning around - as boys that age are known to do. But these seemingly typical fourteen-year-olds are about to defy a boyhood stereotype by sharing their passion for, of all things, ballroom dancing. That's right, in "Let's Dance" you'll meet dozens of handsome, talented and happy lads who approach their fancy footwork as they would any other athletic event in the Promin Sportdance Club ("Promin" means "sunray" in Ukrainian). In fact, many have already achieved the designation of Master of Sport and have the medals to prove it. But all's not strictly ballroom here either. For boys will be boys, and that means they can't go too long without a rollicking game of basketball or kick-the-can. So get ready to meet the charming guys (and gals) of the Promin Sportdance Club as they prepare to do battle on the dance floors of Europe, while at the same time spinning, stepping, and twirling their way right into your hearts!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?333417</url></doc>
