<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="333611">
  <docid>333611</docid>
  <title>Let's Start a Revolution</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Catalano, Kristin</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>music</keyword>
    <keyword>rockumentary</keyword>
    <keyword>milwaukee</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">5 January 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">26</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Catalano, Kristin</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Catalano, Kristin</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Catalano, Kristin</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Heathrow</composer>
    <composer>Nice Outfit, The</composer>
    <composer>Trolley</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wall, Paul J.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>White, Eric A.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Documentary that tracks two Milwaukee-based roommates who battle the music industry, as they try to break in, or at least get recognized. Paul Wall of the power-pop band, Trolley, locally large over the past ten years, is 34-years old and waiting tables. He recently stepped up to the ageist industry, and formed a garage-rock band with younger musicians called, The Nice Outfit. Eric White, 33, of the six-year and rising Brit-pop band, Heathrow, has a more pessimistic, or perhaps a more realistic view than his dream-determined roommate. After Eric's last band, The Virgins, broke up, his faith in the whole music charade nudged him back into college, where, in 2004, he received his Master's Degree in History. While Eric's backup plan of becoming a teacher is rushing to the front, Paul keeps at his stagnant server job, with his thoughts afloat, never stepping foot into a university. But, at the end of the day, these two roommates have dissimilarly similar dreams; they're marching to the same song, just at a different beat.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?333611</url></doc>
