<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="335704">
  <docid>335704</docid>
  <title>Life at the End of the Rainbow</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Coles-Janess, Wayne</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>drought</keyword>
    <keyword>australia</keyword>
    <keyword>social-justice</keyword>
    <keyword>family-relationships</keyword>
    <keyword>community</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Australia">1 November 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Australia">55</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Coles-Janess, Wayne</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Coles-Janess, Wayne</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Coles-Janess, Wayne</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Mountfort, Helen</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Rainbow is a small farming community of five hundred existing on the edge of the Australian desert. It is best known for its dust storms and beautiful sunsets. Using 1940's home movies, Life at the end of the Rainbow gives an insight into what life is and once was like for the people of Rainbow. The Rainbow community lies on the edge of the Big Desert, North Western Victoria, Australia. The area was originally considered worthless and was fenced off and abandoned. The town was established around the turn of the century, with German settlers. It then boomed with the soldier settler policies after the first and second World Wars. From its inception, Rainbow and its people have struggled to eke out an existence for more than three generations. Like so many other small towns around Australia, Rainbow is fighting to survive. For the past 100 years the Rainbow community has battled on against adversity with varying degrees of success and prosperity . Global economics and government policy are now compounding the difficulties of marginal farming, to the extent that small communities such as these are now facing an increasingly arduous and uncertain future. Life at the end of the Rainbow provides viewers with a window into the changing world of rural communities. Through the use of home movies shot from the 40's, the evolution of farming and the community is vividly depicted. Each character has their own perceptions of life on the land. They all share one thing - they make up the small country town of Rainbow.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?335704</url></doc>
