<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="335818">
  <docid>335818</docid>
  <title>Life of an American Fireman</title>
  <year>1904</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1904</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
<plot>This beautiful subject, so dear to the life of every American man, woman and child, will create enthusiasm unbounded and an encore will positively result from the exhibition thereof. The picture is made in 10 scenes, showing the Fireman's dream, the view of sleeping quarters of the brave fire laddies, the interior of the engine house, the apparatus leaving the house, the fire run and the arrival at the fire and the rescue of woman and innocent children, etc., etc. No more touching scene could be enacted than this, and none is more ready to do homage to the Firemen than the American who justly places the value of life above riches. Unlike any other position in the City Government's service, the firemen are considered in a class wholly by themselves. Great latitude is allowed them, and where one is seen, especially in a crowded building, no matter where, one feels that he is protected and that the danger has been reduced to a minimum. Note the fireman dozing in his armchair in the fire house, and one sees the dream depicted on the wall over his head. He dreams that his wife and child are probably in danger, and in fancy he sees his wife placing the child in its crib for the night. Disturbed by the dream, he awakens and paces the floor nervously until an alarm is sounded and the scene changes to the sleeping quarters of the men. They jump out of their cots, hastily don some of their clothing and slide down the pole erected in the centre of the room and which leads to the main floor below. Meanwhile the horses bound out of their stalls, place themselves in front of the apparatus and are secured thereto by the men who have reached the ground. The doors are opened and out they dash at breakneck speed, threatening danger to whoever may place himself in their way. Then note the fire run, the greatest ever yet produced. One after another they dash by with almost lightning rapidity, until the very earth trembles with vibration from the iron hoofs of the grand horses, who appear to know that they are on an errand of mercy. They arrive at the fire, and immediately is seen the hook and ladder being placed in position, the firemen mounting the ladder, carrying the hose with which they finally extinguish the blaze, but not before they rescue several inmates of the burning dwelling, including a number of children. No more realistic picture could be imagined or offered to the public, who, without exception, praise the heroic efforts of the fire fighters, and applaud again and again. No picture show is complete without one of these marvelous life motion headliners.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?335818</url></doc>
