<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="337261">
  <docid>337261</docid>
  <title>Links</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Markus, Albert</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>black-comedy</keyword>
    <keyword>neglect</keyword>
    <keyword>rotterdam-netherlands</keyword>
    <keyword>brain</keyword>
    <keyword>agnosia</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Dutch</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Netherlands">AL</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Netherlands">22 January 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Greece">25 September 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Netherlands">83</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Tan, Froukje</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>van der Leeden, Maarten</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Tan, Froukje</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Easy Aloha's</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ben Horsting, Ali</actor>
      <role>Henry/Revalidation Nurse</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Blanken, Nettie</actor>
      <role>Shoplady/Nurse/Mother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dam, Guus</actor>
      <role>Boss / Surgeon / Father</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dchar, Nasrdin</actor>
      <role>Police officer 1-2 &amp; 3</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>van Koningsbrugge, Jeroen</actor>
      <role>Dexter</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Dexter's controlled life gets thrown into confusion when a girl appears on his work that looks exactly like his girlfriend Stella. At home his beloved Stella doesn't understand what's going on and she starts questioning their relationship. Dexter's life deteriorates furthermore: traffic bills keep coming in, he is banned from his trusted working place, Stella breaks up with him, and his boss sends him on an immediate leave. When Dexter has crashed several cars, he is arrested by the police and taken to hospital. There he is told that a stroke has caused him a brain damage in his right hemisphere. Consequently he doesn't see left anymore and his sense of reality has been affected: he sees the same people everywhere. Dexter has to learn to live in a world wherein people look alike. Initially he reacts rather indifferent. Then, in the hospital he meets another girl who looks like Stella. She is of little words and has a minimal appetite. As she has to regain her taste for life, Dexter has to discover that from all Stella's, there's only one he really cares about. LEFT is a tragicomedy wherein Dexter is forced to look into his other side. The film treats this subject subtly and considerate: everything gets twisted a little bit, but never falls apart completely.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?337261</url></doc>
