<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="337850">
  <docid>337850</docid>
  <title>Little Beaux Pink</title>
  <year>1968</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Gunther, Lee</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>pink-panther</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">G</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2 October 1968</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">6</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Pratt, Hawley</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>DePatie, David H.</producer>
    <producer>Freleng, Friz</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Dunn, John W.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Greene, Walter (II)</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>The Pink Panther had a little lamb, whose fleece was white as snow, and wherever the lamb went to graze, the panther had to go. The panther and his lamb cross a boundary into Cattle County, Texas, and when the lamb begins eating the grass of a hot-headed Texan rancher, the Pink Panther must defend himself and his lamb from the Texan's wrath. The panther plants stakes and builds a fence around his lamb's grazing territory, and the Texan, rapidly riding a horse, pounds the stakes - and the Pink Panther - almost entirely into the ground. Undaunted, the Pink Panther establishes his own ranch, and the Texan tries to flatten panther and lamb with a huge, rolling stone, which the Pink Panther guides through a barn so that it hits a tree branch which recoils it on top of the Texan. The Texan telegrams some hired gunslingers, asking them to eliminate someone who is pink, and when a bucket of the Pink Panther's pink paint falls onto the Texan, rendering him pink, the gunslingers arrive and blast him with bullets.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?337850</url></doc>
