<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="337974">
  <docid>337974</docid>
  <title>Little Claus &amp; Big Claus</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Doucet, Robert (III)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>fairy-tale</keyword>
    <keyword>19th-century</keyword>
    <keyword>hans-christian-andersen</keyword>
    <keyword>period-piece</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">26 December 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">22</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Ricker, James</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Jestdadt, Torrance Garret</producer>
    <producer>MacDonald, Michael (VII)</producer>
    <producer>McNeill, Paul (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>McNeill, Paul (I)</writer>
    <writer>Ricker, James</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Fung, Darren</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anderson, Blaine</actor>
      <role>Little Claus</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ash, Paul (I)</actor>
      <role>Inn Keeper</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Beale, John</actor>
      <role>Hans Christian Andersen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chandler, Leslie</actor>
      <role>Farmer's Wife</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Collette, Dave</actor>
      <role>Big Claus</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Feron, John</actor>
      <role>Pharmacist</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Flemming, David</actor>
      <role>Hooligan</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Hans Christian Anderson was only seventeen years old when he began publishing his many collections of endearing children's stories. Of the many books he eventually wrote, one of his more popular tales was woven around two men who lived in the same town and shared the same name - Claus. But, as the title asserts, that was where the similarities ended; for one was little in stature and clever of mind, and the other as big as an Ox - and just as dumb. The story of Anderson's life is one of grinding poverty in his youth, unhappiness in his romantic life and restless traveling. He was, he informs us, the ugly duckling, the lowest in the town's pecking order, the brunt of crude jokes and coarse criticism. Little Claus and Big Claus is a dark tale, riddled with Anderson's comic vision of the struggle of humanity. It is the tale of David vs. Goliath, Brains vs. Brawn, and in an ominous way, it is the story of overcoming our sinister demons Little Claus and Big Claus will be an adaptation of Anderson's original short tale into a visually stunning half-hour television piece. Hans Christian Anderson himself will be as a character. This addition was inspired by the following Anderson quote. "Ideas for tales, lie in my mind like seeds and only need the kiss of a sunbeam or a drop of malice to flower."</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?337974</url></doc>
