<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="338517">
  <docid>338517</docid>
  <title>Little Steps... Walk with Jesus</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Reilly, Timothy (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>religion</keyword>
    <keyword>children</keyword>
    <keyword>christian</keyword>
    <keyword>family-relationships</keyword>
    <keyword>jesus-christ</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Approved</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">21 January 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>King, Kandra</director>
    <director>Shell, Marlena</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Shell, Marlena</producer>
    <producer>King, Kandra</producer>
    <producer>Shell, Marlena</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>King, Kandra</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>King, Kandra</actor>
      <role>Narrator/Mary</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Have you ever dreamed of taking them to the Holy Land? A trip to Israel would allow you to show your children the holy sites that they read about in the Bible. Little Steps... Walk With Jesus takes you on this incredible journey without having to leave your home. This three disc DVD series was filmed entirely on location and at some sites not accessible to the general public. This trip is very special because you will actually be following in the footsteps of Jesus Christ. You could show them the actual places where Christ traveled, performed miracles, was crucified and even the tomb from which He arose. Rebecca &amp; Rachel are two adorable twin girls and they will be your tour guides throughout this series. Through our voyage on Disc 1, you will be able to visit the actual places where Jesus Christ was born and played as a child. You will walk with these cherished children on the path that Joseph and Mary took on their way to Bethlehem, leading to the Church of the Nativity to see where Christ was born. You will also visit a period village to explore what life was like 2000 years ago during Christ's childhood. In Disc 2, you will witness where He performed His most famous miracles. Follow our twins to the Wedding Church at Cana where Jesus performed His first miracle, then on to Holy Sites where He fed the 5000 and delivered His Sermon on the Mount. Next you are on to Galilee where He lived with His disciples and taught us through His ministry. In part three, you will accompany Rachel and Rebecca to the Garden where Jesus was betrayed, travel with them to Jerusalem where Christ was condemned and tortured. You will witness Christ's Passion, where He was crucified, the tomb in which He was laid and from which He rose to meet His disciples on the road to Emmaus. You will visit the Church of the Primacy of Peter where Jesus instructed Peter to throw His net on the other side of the boat after His resurrection. You will see the place where the disciples witnessed the ascension of Jesus into Heaven. These three beautiful 30 minute DVD's will take your children to the places of wonderment and miracles they read about in the Bible are real and exist even today in the Holy Sites of Israel. What better way to help strengthen their faith and help them understand the Love that Jesus Christ has for each of us?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?338517</url></doc>
