<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="339120">
  <docid>339120</docid>
  <title>Livicated</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>musician</keyword>
    <keyword>singing</keyword>
    <keyword>revolution</keyword>
    <keyword>reggae</keyword>
    <keyword>singer</keyword>
    <keyword>africa</keyword>
    <keyword>song</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">82</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Madelenat, Paul</producer>
    <producer>Raji, Samira</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jobson, Wayne</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"Everywhere I go in the world today, Bob Marley is the symbol of freedom," says Jack Healy, president of Amnesty International. Marley is a particular hero to young people. "If you enter college without knowing Bob," said a student recently, "By the end of your first week, everyone will have shared his albums with you and made you an instant fan." His is one of the two most ubiquitous images of rebellion today, alongside Ché Guevara, found from Australia to Alaska, from the bottom of the Grand Canyon to the heights of the Himalayas. Marley's music stands for something, and he transcends mere pop stardom to have become a moral figure, particularly to those in the third world. Last year, Acording to Forbe's Magazine, Bob Marley is the 7th-biggest-earning dead artist. Each year, Bob Marley Festivals, honoring him at the time of his birth in February, draw sold-out crowds in Long Beach, California, in Miami, Florida, and all over the world (300,000 people at the last commemoration in Ethiopia). In the week of April 9th, 2005, Billboard magazine's Top Pop Album Charts listed Marley's album "Exodus" as the 6th best sales as of mid-April 2005 and after being a presence on the chart for a whopping 808 weeks. Reggae Festival Guide, An annual free magazine with a six-figure circulation, contains more than a hundred pages of ads for reggae festivals in his honor all over the country. Roger Steffens knew Marley personally, and traveled with him on his last tour of the United States. He has been collecting his works for 32 years, and his Reggae Archives are acknowledged universally as the world's largest body of work about the roots reggae prophet and the culture that spawned him. He has searched the far corners of the globe for thousands of unique items that illuminate reggae's spread, and the influence of Marley himself. Along the way, he has encountered many of the biggest names in reggae and world music and interviewed them for his various radio and TV programs. Thousands of people visited an eight-month-long exhibit of Steffens' archives at the Queen Mary in 2001.   Today, this massive collection, which fills six rooms of his home in Los Angeles, California, is in the process of being transferred to Jamaica to become the National Museum of Jamaican Music. "Livicated" tells the story of that unprecedented journey.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?339120</url></doc>
