<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="339182">
  <docid>339182</docid>
  <title>Living Is Winning</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Williams, Richard (XXXIII)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Sport</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>na-sports</keyword>
    <keyword>athlete</keyword>
    <keyword>lake-placid</keyword>
    <keyword>houston</keyword>
    <keyword>swim</keyword>
    <keyword>bike</keyword>
    <keyword>leukemia</keyword>
    <keyword>ironman-triathlon</keyword>
    <keyword>triathlete</keyword>
    <keyword>andrew-johnston</keyword>
    <keyword>cyclist</keyword>
    <keyword>tnt</keyword>
    <keyword>elite</keyword>
    <keyword>triathlon</keyword>
    <keyword>cancer</keyword>
    <keyword>training</keyword>
    <keyword>run</keyword>
    <keyword>multi-sport</keyword>
    <keyword>sports-champion</keyword>
    <keyword>family-relationships</keyword>
    <keyword>spirit</keyword>
    <keyword>team</keyword>
    <keyword>competition</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">5 September 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">107</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Burns, Linda (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bartlett, Ruth</producer>
    <producer>Burns, Diane (II)</producer>
    <producer>Burns, Larry (VII)</producer>
    <producer>Harris, Andrew (XV)</producer>
    <producer>Melgaard, Megan</producer>
    <producer>Hutcheson, Sandra</producer>
    <producer>Keating, Jeff</producer>
    <producer>Willingham, Deborah</producer>
    <producer>Burns, Linda (I)</producer>
    <producer>Keating, Jeff</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Burns, Linda (I)</writer>
    <writer>Johnston, Andrew (XVI)</writer>
    <writer>Keating, Jeff</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Johnston, Andrew (XVI)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Johnston, Diana (II)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Melgaard, Megan</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In the calm, cold water of Mirror Lake, the starting gun for Ironman Lake Placid is ready to fire. Andrew 'Drew' Johnston floats, waiting to battle competitors from all over the world as they swim over, under, and around each other on a quest to qualify for the Ford Ironman World Championship. But for Drew, a different struggle weighs heavily on his mind and in his heart. In 2004, a recurring leg injury forced his withdrawal with 10 miles left in this race, something he never imagined possible. This injury led to a frightening diagnosis of Leukemia (CML). One year later, after the oral chemo Gleevac put his disease in remission, Drew began competing at an elite level again, and winning. But he had unfinished business, and his emotional return to Lake Placid serves as the backbone of this film. Throughout the grueling 2.4 mile swim, 112 mile bike, and 26.2 mile run, Drew retells his inspirational life story. From his introduction to cycling and early struggles with triathlon to his diagnosis and successful comeback at the famous Ford Ironman World Championship in Kailua-Kona, Drew's story is one of strength, determination, love, family and friendship. Surprisingly funny interviews with family and friends provide more than the usual glimpse into the world of an elite athlete. And with every stroke, pedal, and step Drew takes, you not only root for him, you cheer for what he believes in - a nothing is impossible attitude and a day-to-day appreciation of life. Andrew Johnston overcomes the odds to challenge himself and to inspire others to live life to its fullest. He proves that our only limitations are the ones we set for ourselves.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?339182</url></doc>
