<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="339238">
  <docid>339238</docid>
  <title>Living Warbirds: Steel Warriors</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Hans, Iqbal</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">14 July 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">103</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Hans, Iqbal</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hans, Iqbal</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>No Music - No Distracting Narration Just screaming pistons in full stereo sound Living Warbirds: Steel Warriors puts you on the tarmac so you can see, hear, and feel the fierce power of these magnificent warbirds: the roar of the engines starting, closeups of the beautifully restored aircraft, takeoffs, multiple flybys, and landings. From World War I and World War II, to every other major conflict of the 20th century, victory would not have been possible without the most advanced fighting machines of their time. In battles over Europe, African, Asia, and the Pacific, fighter planes like the P-51 Mustang and bombers like the B-29 Superfortress carried and protected our brave men and women. After their missions were complete, most of these warbirds were neglected and abandoned. A few survived, lovingly restored by warbird enthusiasts around the world. Living Warbirds: Steel Warriors features these historic airplanes in all of their glory, reminding us of the critical roles they played in the greatest wars of our time. Airplanes included on this DVD: Chance Vought F4U Corsair, Curtiss P-40N Warhawk, Douglas C-53D Skytrooper, SBD-5 Dauntless, Fairchild PT-19A Cornell, Grumman F3F, F4F Wildcat, F6F Hellcat, F7F Tigercat, F8F Bearcat, TBM Avenger, Hawker Sea Fury FB-11, Lockheed P-38 Lightning, Mitsubishi A6M Zero, Nanchang China CJ-6A, North American Aviation AT-6B, P-51 Mustang, SNJ-4, SNJ-5, T-6 Texan, T-28, TB25N Mitchell, Ryan PT-22 Recruit, and many more.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?339238</url></doc>
