<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="339654">
  <docid>339654</docid>
  <title>Llorona Gone Wild</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Williams, Terrence (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>la-llorona</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">13 March 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">220</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Williams, Terrence (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Williams, Terrence (I)</producer>
    <producer>Williams, Nicole (VI)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Williams, Terrence (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>QDC</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Andrews, Jim (IV)</actor>
      <role>Royce</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Castillo, Carlos Javier</actor>
      <role>Jacob</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Curitore, Tom</actor>
      <role>Jay</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Morales, Will (I)</actor>
      <role>Miguel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Royuela, Antonio</actor>
      <role>Daniel/Eduardo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ryan, Mitch (I)</actor>
      <role>Doug</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Williams, Terrence (I)</actor>
      <role>Thug 1</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>THE RIVER: LEGEND OF LA LLORONA The urban legend of La Llorona (Spanish for The Weeping Lady), comes to life in this morbid tale about the monstrous, vengeful boogie woman who wanders near bodies of water and wails into the night for her lost children, who she drowned after being spurned and deserted by their father. Miguel, a mercenary, soon learns that La Llorona is anything but a legend, when he is commissioned to locate and return a young runaway to a sleepy riverside town in order to rid it of La Lloronas curse. Miguel is successful in recovering the young girl; however as he is nearing the town he swerves to avoid a figure standing in the road and crashes his car. Awakening, he finds that the young girl is missing and heads towards the town to find her. There he discovers that cashing in might mean cashing out, in a story filled with Latin mythology, irony, and deception. REVENGE OF LA LLORONA An arrogant television tabloid host that is trying to get big ratings decides to take his crew through a haunted house. The house is rumored to be haunted by La Llorona (the Weeping Lady), a white-garbed specter who is believed to have killed numerous residents of the house. Soon strange things start happening and the TV host begins to realize that these ratings could take him to the top or straight to the bottom...of hell! CURSE OF LA LLORONA A troubled family must unite to save their young niece from the sinister forces of La Llorona, an evil spirit that inhabits an abandoned house.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?339654</url></doc>
