<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="340177">
  <docid>340177</docid>
  <title>Locked Out</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Takahashi, Yasunobu</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Japanese</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Japan</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">September 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Japan">82</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Takahashi, Yasunobu</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Usui, Masaaki (II)</producer>
    <producer>Takahashi, Yasunobu</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Akima, Noboru</actor>
      <role>Kazuhiro</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kimura, Keisaku</actor>
      <role>Officer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Miyashita, Tomomi</actor>
      <role>Yuri</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ohnuki, Yutaka</actor>
      <role>Nagata</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shimada, Takeru</actor>
      <role>Keita</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sonobe, Kiichi</actor>
      <role>Hiroshi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Takahashi, Yasunobu</actor>
      <role>Clurk</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Hiroshi is lost, on the road, driving aimlessly by himself, radio blaring, when he slowly realizes he is nowhere. He doesn't know exactly where he is, and reflects that he doesn't even have a specific destination. The feeling of loss lingers around him. On the way, he encounters a projection of a more violent self, seething with hatred and viciousness. A hurried mother busy with a million things at once, Shoko is trying to cope with her six-year-old son Keita at the supermarket. She tells him to stay put in the car while she goes back to pick something up; he secretly slips out, however, stealing some change from the car to get a snack expressly forbidden to him earlier. Prize in hand, he rushes back before mom returns. He manages to get back just in time, and hides the snack in the glove compartment as he spies Shoko approaching some ways off. However, she passes him by without noticing. Keita starts to see that something is wrong. At that moment, Hiroshi, having stopped off, walks up to the car and motions to open the door. Keita has made a mistake: his mother's car and Hiroshi's are exactly the same... This chance encounter unfolds into a journey, and begins to bring Hiroshi back from his dry emotionalism's, triggering fragmented flashbacks of his shocking past; it also heralds a little change in himself.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?340177</url></doc>
