<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="342393">
  <docid>342393</docid>
  <title>Los electroduendes</title>
  <year>1986</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Spain">1986</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Conesa, Matilde</actor>
      <role>Bruja Avería (1986-1988)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Egido, Ángel</actor>
      <role>Maese Sonoro (1986-1988)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pérezagua, Luis</actor>
      <role>Maese Cámara (1986-1988)</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>After the huge success that the characters of the first section of the famous show "La bola de cristal" had, they finally got their own show for the evenings from Monday to Friday evening, while they still appeared in "La bola de cristal" on Saturday morning. The scheme of this show is not very much different from the section of the same title, "Los electroduendes" from "La bola de cristal". The Witch Avería (Breakdown) still wants to blow and break down the Electroduendes (Electro-elfs), Maese Sonoro (Mister Sound), Maese Cámara (Mister Camera), Fairy Video and Truca Witch. Each electro-elf represent a main element of audiovisuals. Maese Sonoro represents the Microphone and he hears very well, Maese Cámara represents the Camera, and nothing gets out of his sight, the Fairy Video represents the Videocassette, and she remembers all that has been heard and watched by his friends, and the Witch Truca is a fan of cinema and always remembers the seventh art. These five characters (which are puppets sometimes joined by real actors) live many adventures with ironic humor for all the family.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?342393</url></doc>
