<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="343300">
  <docid>343300</docid>
  <title>Los victorero</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Batalla, Adela</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
    <language>Bable</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Spain">1 October 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Spain">55</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Tapia, Gonzalo (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Tapia, Gonzalo (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Tapia, Gonzalo (I)</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Lastres is an isolated fishermen village in northern Spain, by the Atlantic coast. There lived between centuries the Victorero family. They were the wealthiest in the county and the religious and political caciques. It was form by three brothers and three sisters that live together their entire live without marring any of them. Their fortune came from the cotton business in Mexico during the First World War. Afterwards they started a factory in their village to produce one of their inventions: a semiautomatic cigarette rolling machine. The inventor was the second brother, Antonio. He was a very creative person he invented also a machine to generate light effects for the local nativity that has a curious witty touch. It is still mounted in the village church every year for Christmas by some local volunteers since the 1920's. The other passion Antonio had to fulfill his lonely and long days was filmmaking. He did many shots and sequences that show common live in the forties and fifties in Lastres: sailors, fishermen, children, the family gardens and forests. Our documentary makes a panoramic over this family. An aquarelle of their live through interviews of their fellow villagers and illustrated by the footage Antonio rolled.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?343300</url></doc>
