<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="343438">
  <docid>343438</docid>
  <title>Losing a Highway</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>experimental-film</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Germany">30 June 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">52</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Kubein, Mirko</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Kubein, Mirko</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Schütz, Peter (II)</actor>
      <role>The man</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The film tries to measure the narrative, esthetical and technical possibilities, and most of all impossibilities, of "streaming" over the internet as a medium. On the background of a reflection about media theory, techniques and history, we follow a man who has to achieve something he is not able to, but he still tries and fails. Nevertheless he won't give up and his obsession will lead, or rather pull him into an endless loop, where he will finally be dissolved. This is the story of a man who has to achieve something he is not able to. He still tries until he realizes that he won't succeed and goes back, before he will try again. He is moving in a loop but not in a real circle, since the endless repetition of the apparently same action slightly modifies its course each time. This repeated trial and error turns the man's wish to reach his goal into an obsession, which will eventually make him forget his initial objective. He is loosing himself in this swirl and will finally be dissolved. All what's left is his obsession. This process gets accelerated in LOSING A HIGHWAY, since the failure is already included in each new attempt, which means that the man is at once constantly trying and constantly failing. He is in contradiction to his own words and action - a repeatedly double tragedy. LOSING A HIGHWAY is 52 min long. The viewer can sort of follow the man's way, go it himself, become weak and be dissolved; in order to see where he arrives at the very end, which is actually not a real end.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?343438</url></doc>
