<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="344332">
  <docid>344332</docid>
  <title>Love 10 to 1</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Le, Christine (I)</director>
    <director>Rodriguez, Lucy (II)</director>
    <director>Somers, Laura (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Le, Christine (I)</writer>
    <writer>Rodriguez, Lucy (II)</writer>
    <writer>Somers, Laura (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Alonso, Daniella</actor>
      <role>Cali</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Coccoli, Jessica</actor>
      <role>GG</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dyke, Ashley</actor>
      <role>Layla</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Eldridge, Chance</actor>
      <role>Young Guy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fischer, Takayo</actor>
      <role>Grandma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Golomb, Cazzy</actor>
      <role>Domino</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hernke, Hans</actor>
      <role>Grandma Lover</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hoang, Bach</actor>
      <role>Jackie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hsu, Art</actor>
      <role>Tim</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Klosky, Justin</actor>
      <role>Jim</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kuroda, Emily</actor>
      <role>Ma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Marks, Mari</actor>
      <role>Sonny</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maxwell, Jordan T.</actor>
      <role>Cup Envy Guy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mui, Eddie</actor>
      <role>Francis</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ritchey, Matt</actor>
      <role>Hot Actor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Villar, David</actor>
      <role>Dustin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vongtama, Roy</actor>
      <role>Married Man</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Three stories, interwoven, each exploring a different aspect of searching for love in the city of Los Angeles. The lead characters are interconnected, but not necessarily related, and each thread operates more or less independently. The first story explores the life of a 29-year-old virgin, Jenny, who desperately wants to lose her virginity before her 30th birthday. As she encounters one loser after another on dates, Jenny pines after her boss, Dustin. While at her grandmother's retirement home, Jenny learns a powerful lesson from her grandmother about sex and the meaning of life. The second explores two days in the life of Shane, the lead singer of the L.A. rock band Dirty Virgin. Shane has her pick of admirers but it's her roommate Dustin she wants to be with. Shane confesses having feelings for a "mystery man" on a radio show but when Dustin meets Cali, Shane's shot at love starts to dwindle. With Dirty Virgin about to embark on a world tour, will Dustin realize that he's the object of Shane's affections? Will they risk their friendship to give this Love Song a chance? The final story picks up where Love 10 to 1 left off, but from the perspective of Jim, the guitarist of Dirty Virgin. Jim sees Jenny at a swimming pool, trying desperately to overcome her fear of diving. In fact, he finds out that she's making a list of everything that she's afraid of and trying to overcome them, one by one. He is instantly smitten and tries to convince her that he's not just a rock star who 'loves 'em and leaves 'em'. Can a rock star find love with a virgin?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?344332</url></doc>
