<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="344571">
  <docid>344571</docid>
  <title>Love Inn Exile</title>
  <year>2000</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>palm-springs</keyword>
    <keyword>erotic</keyword>
    <keyword>threesome</keyword>
    <keyword>gay</keyword>
    <keyword>sex</keyword>
    <keyword>homosexual</keyword>
    <keyword>soft-core</keyword>
    <keyword>gay-love</keyword>
    <keyword>orgy</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">25 July 2000</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">70</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
<plot>Shy bookworm Tommy vacations in Palm Springs, never expecting an amorous adventure. But once he spots Brendan, he can't stop fantasizing about being with the sensuous, dark-haired man. However, Brendan's friends have their own ideas, and continue to pull him into their orgy of alcohol and sex. Finally alone at the pool, Brendan approaches Tommy and they spend an afternoon exploring the desert town and each other. Just as Tommy saves Brendan from a poolside accident, Brendan's friends come back - and try to force the two apart. True love conquers all, as Tommy's vacation climaxes in a passionate declaration of love and desire. LOVE INN EXILE boasts several unforgettable erotic scenes - including the strangely tender, drunken ménage a trois between Brendan's friends, a spicy tequila shot off Brendan's shoulder, and, of course, Tommy's ultimate fulfillment by his ideal man. LOVE INN EXILE is filmed entirely on location at Inn Exile in Palm Springs. With music by adult film star Sharon Kane, this video makes exile seem like a perfectly good punishment!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?344571</url></doc>
