<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="344694">
  <docid>344694</docid>
  <title>Love Letter</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Korean</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>South Korea</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="South Korea">10 February 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="South Korea">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Oh, Gyung-hoon</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Oh, Su-yeon</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ji, Jin-hee</actor>
      <role>Jung Woo-jin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jo, Hyeon-jae</actor>
      <role>Andrea, Lee Woo-jin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ju, Hyeon</actor>
      <role>Dr. Jung Myeong-woo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kim, Yeong-ae</actor>
      <role>Dr. Yim Gyung-eun</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kweon, Min-jung</actor>
      <role>Sister Esther</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Son, Hyeon-ju</actor>
      <role>Father Peter</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Lee Woo-Jin, also known as Andrew (Jo Hyeon-Jae), became an orphan at a young age and ended up living with his abusive aunt. He faithfully prays that one day God will save him from his hardships. His prayers are answered when his uncle, Father Pedro (Son Hyun-Joo), comes to rescue him from his dismal environment. Father Peter raises Andrew into a promising young man. As a gentle and optimistic high school kid, Andrew meets Jo Eun-Ha (Soo-ae) and sympathizes with her as both of them share the common experience of losing their parents. Andrew's genuine and delicate concern for Eun-Ha brings their friendship to the brink of love. However, they must remain only friends as Andrew reveals to her his wish to become a priest. Upon graduating from high school, both Andrew and Eun-Ha are accepted into medical school in Seoul. Andrew meets Jung Woo-Jin (Ji Jin-Hee). Both of them have the same given name and soon become great friends. Meanwhile, Jung Woo-Jin starts to have feelings for Eun-Ha and tries his best to charm her. As Andrew's two best friends gradually become closer and closer, he feels an emptiness and realizes for the first time that he has lost his heart to Eun-Ha...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?344694</url></doc>
