<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="345074">
  <docid>345074</docid>
  <title>Love Without Mercy: Slavoj Zizek</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Torella, Chris</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2 January 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">137</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Abreu, Miguel (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Abreu, Miguel (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zizek, Slavoj</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>LECTURE Slavoj Zizek "Love without Mercy" Monday March 10 2003, 7:00pm Deitch Projects, 18 Wooster Street, New York, NY 10013 Presented by Foundation 20 21 Slavoj Zizek, the world-renowned philosopher and cultural theorist, held an exciting town meeting in New York City on March 10th at Deitch Projects (18 Wooster Street) in conjunction with the publication of Lacanian Ink 21. The subject of his lecture was "Love without Mercy." There were more than 600 people from all over the world packing the huge, cavernous gallery space. The police intervened to disperse the overcapacity crowd, a portion of which, unfortunately, was left outside. "The thrill of reading Zizek," says Robert Boynton in Lingua Franca, "arises in part from the collision between the insanity he finds everywhere in our psychic and social lives and the rigorous clarity with which he anatomizes its workings." Slavoj Zizek is Senior Researcher at the Institute of Social Studies, University of Ljubljana. Some of his recent books include, The Fragile Absolute - or, why is the Christian legacy worth fighting for? (2000), On Belief (2001), and Welcome to the Desert of the Real: Five Essays on September 11th and Releated Dates (2002). Lacanian Ink is a cultural magazine which focuses on the teachings of French psychoanalyst, Jacques Lacan. It is published biannually in New York.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?345074</url></doc>
