<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="345159">
  <docid>345159</docid>
  <title>Love and Jealousy Behind the Scenes</title>
  <year>1904</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">January 1904</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
<plot>This is a dramatic subject giving insight to that mystery of behind the scenes so interesting to the uninitiated. In the first two scenes a number of girls are shown in a manager's office undergoing a trial of their voices and of their dancing ability. One of the young girls, particularly a winsome girl is accepted and in the next scene she is shown in the dressing room where several girls of the company are ready to go on the stage. In the following scene the young girl who is the heroine, is introduced to the young man who plays the part of the clown in the pantomime and a pretty love scene between the two ensues. The next scene shows the betrothal of the two and the culmination of the romance when the clown slips a diamond ring on the girl's engagement finger. A disturbing element appears however in the shape of a swell who has been introduced to the girl back of the scenes by the manager. He becomes charmed with the girl and proceeds to make himself as agreeable as possible and she apparently does not disdain his attentions. The clown watches the proceedings from behind the wings. The last scene shows that the young girl has broken her troth to the clown and is giving her affections to the young swell. Finally the clown cannot stand it any longer and hurrying to his dressing room, secures a revolver and shoots the young swell as he is bending over to kiss the girl, making a most dramatic final to a most interesting scene.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?345159</url></doc>
