<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="346705">
  <docid>346705</docid>
  <title>Lucky Sevens</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">5 April 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">15</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Nicholson, Zac (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Barber, Jeromy</producer>
    <producer>Nicholson, Zac (I)</producer>
    <producer>Sibble, Sam</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Nicholson, Zac (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Pitts, Will</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mertz, Jack</actor>
      <role>Walter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Swansen, Larry</actor>
      <role>Marvin</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Lucky Sevens is a film about one man's reckless attempt to make sense of his existence in the twilight of his life. Marvin Zigglebaum, a failed gambler, is a borderline recluse who has all but given up on life. When he wakes up from nostalgic dreams on his 70th birthday to find an eviction notice on his door, he intends to let nature take its course and to go on with his day as if nothing is wrong. This all changes, however, when a random glimpse in the daily newspaper leads him to the horse race section. Specifically, Marvin notices a certain horse in a certain race with whom he makes a cosmic connection and a seed is planted towards a last ditch attempt to save himself from his current situation. Interrupting his plan, however, is Marvin's longtime friend, the caring and cautious Walter, whom Marvin has grown to see as nothing more than a happy-go-lucky nuisance. Walter arrives to celebrate his dear friend's birthday and instead finds himself being whisked away to the racetrack, a place he has vowed never to return to after past experiences and hard luck. Despite Walter's best efforts, Marvin's stubbornness is too strong and he bets his petty savings on his special horse. What actually takes place at the racetrack is very different from what either man could have expected and Marvin ends up realizing much more about himself, his friendship, and the world than he could have ever intended.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?346705</url></doc>
