<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="348856">
  <docid>348856</docid>
  <title>M.O.V.I.E.</title>
  <year>1986</year>
  <type>VideoGame</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Mystery</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>acronym-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>puzzle</keyword>
    <keyword>detective</keyword>
    <keyword>gumshoe</keyword>
    <keyword>collection</keyword>
    <keyword>movie-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>pulp-adventure</keyword>
    <keyword>entire-title-is-capitalized-acronym</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <producers>
    <producer>Dimitrijevic, Dusko</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Dimitrijevic, Dusko</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Ocean productions presents M.O.V.I.E., a 1986 AD release on the Imagine label by Yugoslav Dusko Dimitrijevic. After programming two freebies for Ocean, Dusko returned to Yugoslavia to program M.O.V.I.E. for the VX Spectrum and Amstrad CPC systems. Praised by critics for its concept, playability, and graphics, the monochromatic plunge into the Big Apple and its pulp fiction world of Marlowean detectives, gangsters, and molls fit the bill for Londoner gamers thirsty for a taste of stateside noir action. Out to extract a cassette recording from a mobster's lair, you play the gumshoe PI lone-stepping through the underworld of passwords and iconic interaction. Unapologetically borrowing from Marlowe, The Thin Man, and 1930's film palates, the game plays like a movie. Hence the title. The mysterious acronym of the title aside, the plot unfolds satisfyingly, with no wait between room screens. Comparable in theme but not in execution to "Mugsy," the game was a real triumph for programmer and player alike. As always, there's a girl involved. But this dame's got a twist: she's a twin. But who's the evil twin? One will guide you to the hideout, the other will take you on a darker path. Once you figure out the right sister, you're walking right, mister. Don't forget to treat her like a lady. Classic adventure in the noir vein expands from the PI's office into the underworld, just as you'd expect. And, as one would likewise expect, the more business-as-usual the better. This film-noir gumshoe detective mystery won't disappoint with it's one-two punch of action adventure and puzzle solving.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?348856</url></doc>
