<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="349753">
  <docid>349753</docid>
  <title>Maa Ki Mamta</title>
  <year>1995</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Shetty, Sunder</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">1995</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Asrani, Manju (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bhansali, Sukh Sampat</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Vyas, Gaurang (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhaduri, Rita</actor>
      <role>Shanti</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brahmachari</actor>
      <role>Dharam's brother-in-law</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kharbanda, Kulbhushan</actor>
      <role>Thakur Dharam Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khare, Preeti</actor>
      <role>Sunita Veer Singh/Sunita S. Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mehta, Priti</actor>
      <role>Jhoothi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mukherjee, Babloo (I)</actor>
      <role>Jhootha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Upendra, Jeet</actor>
      <role>Suraj D. Singh</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Thakur Dharam Singh and his wife, Thakurain, are devotees of Devi Maa Ambe, and they believe that it is through her blessings that they gave birth to a son, Suraj. But shortly after doing so, the Thakurain passes away, leaving Dharam in a dilemma as to who is going to breast-feed Suraj. He comes across one of his farm laborer, Someshwar, whose wife, Shanti, is nursing her very own child, and asks them to help, to which they agree. Shanti is so caught up in nursing Suraj that she neglects her son, who tragically passes away. When Suraj grows up, he is asked to attend a hostel away from home. When he returns he has matured, but is very affectionate towards Shanti and his dad, much to the chagrin of Dharam's sister, who would like the entire estate and property be under her and her son, Jhootha's control. Suraj meets and falls in love with wealthy Sunita, who is the daughter of Thakur Veer Singh, bitter enemy of Dharam Singh. Veer would like his daughter to get married to Zohravar, but both Thakurs overcome their hatred and get their children married. An enraged Zohravar kills Someshwar. After the marriage Sunita finds out about Shanti's status, her low Caste, instigates Suraj against her, makes her face abuse - and leaves Shanti with no option but to run away and live a life of beggary and destitution.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?349753</url></doc>
