<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="349824">
  <docid>349824</docid>
  <title>Maan Abhiman</title>
  <year>1980</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Nag, Hiren</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Barjatya, Tarachand</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Jain, Ravindra</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dubey, C.S.</actor>
      <role>Munim</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Iftekhar</actor>
      <role>Thakur Sumer Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jagirdar, Gajanan</actor>
      <role>Money-lender Prabhu Dayal Gupta</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kiran, Kavita</actor>
      <role>Rekha Choudhary/Mrs. Ravikant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kiran, Raj</actor>
      <role>Ajay Mathuraprasad Choudhary</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Latkar, Sulochana</actor>
      <role>School Headmistress</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Parvez, Yunus</actor>
      <role>Hari Kaka</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, Amrish</actor>
      <role>Mathuraprasad Choudhary</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, Shashi</actor>
      <role>Dr. Ravikant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sunder (I)</actor>
      <role>Lalbhai</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Young and enthusiastic Ajay Choudhary returns home to his widowed father, Mathuraprasad, sister, Rekha, and her fiancé, Dr. Ravikant. His father instructs him to take over the business as he no longer keeps good health. Ajay is overwhelmed by this but agrees to look after all affairs. One of his first assignment is to secure a palatial house in a remote rural community. He travels there, and meets with his father's Munim, and they visit the said house. It is here that Ajay first sets his eyes on a young, embittered woman named Mallika Singh, the daughter of Mathura's deceased partner Thakur Sumer Singh. Ajay is attracted to her, but she shuns him at every meeting. Ajay gets friendly with her brother, Sumo, but this does not auger well her either, and she forbids him from seeing Ajay. It is then Ajay decides to find out why she is so bitter and angry with him, and he will soon find out that it was his dad who embezzled monies and properties from a trusting Sumer Singh, leaving the later penniless, with a house that is heavily mortgaged. Sumer and Mallika had both sworn to distrust the evil Mathura and his kin throughout their lives. The question remains what will Ajay do to make amends, especially when their Munim has already filed papers in the local Courthouse seeking possession of the house that Mallika and her live brother live in.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?349824</url></doc>
