<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="350467">
  <docid>350467</docid>
  <title>Mad Love: V.J. Smith and Mad Dads</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">10 April 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>McKeever, Kevin (VI)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>McKeever, Kevin (VI)</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>V.J. Smith came from a childhood of abandonment and juvenile incarceration, and in early adulthood was lured into drug dealing in the black mafia. But he always knew he was meant for better things. Smith then let religion into his life, and he credits God for his redemption and making him who he is today: a respected leader of MAD DADS, a nationwide group of men dedicated to reaching out to gang members and at-risk youth and helping them turn their lives around. This film is not only the story of Smith's life and work, but also an examination of the growing crisis of juvenile crime. Through interviews with Smith, young men he has helped, probation officers, juvenile detention workers, politicians, and a ride-along with a juvenile task force comprised of police officers and U.S. Marshals, a well-rounded picture is presented of just how difficult the juvenile crime situation is - and how heroes like Smith make a very real difference. The filmmaker follows Smith as he walks streets in "Murderapolis" that even policemen are wary of, offering encouragement, prayers, and programs of assistance to those who need it most. Watching this gifted and exciting personality, it's easy to see why he is one of the most respected leaders in the African-American community - and of any race - in Minneapolis.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?350467</url></doc>
