<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="352270">
  <docid>352270</docid>
  <title>Mahaguru</title>
  <year>1985</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>K., Gopal Rao</editor>
  </editors>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">26 April 1985</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Ravichandra, S.S.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kannaiah, Y.</producer>
    <producer>Babu, U.S.N.</producer>
    <producer>Chandrasekhar, K.C.N.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Agnihotri, Gyandev</writer>
    <writer>Khan, Kader (I)</writer>
    <writer>Ravi (V)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Lahiri, Bappi</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grover, Gulshan</actor>
      <role>Girikar (Darbari's nephew)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Inamdar, Shafi</actor>
      <role>Shyam Kumar Talwari</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jeetendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself (in the song "Pyar Ka Khel" from a movie)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Kader (I)</actor>
      <role>Naag Raj Darbari</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khote, Shubha</actor>
      <role>Chanda (Talwari's wife)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kishore, Raj</actor>
      <role>Bijli</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rajnikanth (I)</actor>
      <role>Vijay (Maha Guru)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Roshan, Rakesh</actor>
      <role>Subhash</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Naag Raj Darbari and his associate Shyam Kumar Talwari rule over a small community in India with an iron hand. When former military officer, Subhash, comes home to his mother and sister, he is appalled at the conditions that the community is living in, and decides to do everything possible to improve their lot. This gets him in the bad books of Darbari and Talwari, who recruit a hit-man named Mahaguru to deal with Subhash. Mahaguru confronts Subhash, and severely beats him up, resulting in Subhash being crippled for life. Shortly thereafter, Mahaguru rescues Subhash's sister from some men who were molesting her. Village belle Basanti, a close friend of Subhash, decides to have a go at turning Mahaguru around. She starts a friendship with him, finds out his name is really Vijay, and he does respond positively and becomes attracted to her. This leaves Subhash free to assist the community, thus angering Darbari and Talwari all the more. They abduct Subhash and hold him prisoner, and then instruct Mahaguru to do away with him. Will Basanti's influence change Mahaguru? Or will he just act for anyone who gives him money?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?352270</url></doc>
