<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="352463">
  <docid>352463</docid>
  <title>Mahlen</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Durban, Justin R.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>science</keyword>
    <keyword>nanotechnology</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">6</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="USA">7</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Durban, Justin R.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Durban, Justin R.</producer>
    <producer>Durban, Justin R.</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Durban, Justin R.</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hafner, John</actor>
      <role>Robert Cristo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maccarni, Bob</actor>
      <role>Dr. William Mahlen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ramsaur, Matthew</actor>
      <role>Soldier 2</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Walton, Nicholle</actor>
      <role>Elizabeth Cristo</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Elizabeth Cristo has been suffering from migraine headaches for the past few years with a diagnosis of an extremely rare bone disease. Scientists and doctors around the world have been unsuccessful in treating her rare and dangerous illness. One thing that is certain... She is dying. Years ago Elizabeth's husband, Robert Cristo, partnered with the renown scientist and humanitarian, Dr. William Mahlen in hopes to aid and finance his research and development of biometrics to ultimately find a cure for Elizabeth's terminal illness. When Robert discovers that Dr. Mahlen's intentions are vastly different than his own, Robert leaves the foundation to seek the necessary means to continue his research and to find a cure. Robert and Elizabeth have been hiding from Dr. Mahlen for months, each time narrowly evading capture. An few hours ago, Dr. Mahlen's team found a security breach in their computer mainframe which has lead them to Robert and Elizabeth's current location. A strike force has been dispatched to intercept and regain his intellectual property.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?352463</url></doc>
