<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="352762">
  <docid>352762</docid>
  <title>Main Chup Rahungi</title>
  <year>1962</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>remake</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Bhimsingh, A.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Meiyappan, A.V.</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Gupta, Chitra</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Babloo (I)</actor>
      <role>Shyam</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Choti, Mohan</actor>
      <role>Madhav</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dutt, Sunil</actor>
      <role>Kamal Kumar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Helen (I)</actor>
      <role>Menka</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jagirdar, Gajanan</actor>
      <role>Ratan Kumar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumari, Meena (I)</actor>
      <role>Gayetri</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mehra, Raj</actor>
      <role>Thekedaar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Palsikar, Nana</actor>
      <role>Narayan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sharma, Umesh</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Narayan works as a laborer on the farmland owned by businessman, Ratan Kumar, in Ramnagar, who also has a rubber estate in Singapore. Although Narayan was an ex-convict, Ratan had assisted him getting a job, some land, and a small house where he now lives with his grown daughter, Gayetri, who used to work as a tutor/teacher. While bringing him his lunch one afternoon, Gayetri faints, and a woman tells him that she is pregnant. A shocked Narayan tries to find out who the father is, but Gayetri refuses to answer. He is all ready to beat the truth out, when Ratan intervenes, asks Narayan to take some money and re-locate, which Narayan gratefully does. They do re-locate and Gayetri gives birth to a baby boy, Narayan takes him to an orphanage donated by Ratan himself, and leaves him there, he returns home and lets Gayetri know that her child was still-born. Gayetri and Narayan eventually return to Ramnagar where Gayetri finds a job as a teacher in the very orphanage that her son (now named Shyam) lives in. When Ratan's son, Kamal, returns from Singapore, he meets with Shyam and likes him, but when he finds out that his school-teacher is Gayetri, he informs the Manager to fire her as she is not of good character. The question remains, who is Shyam's father, why does Gayetri remain silent about his identity, and what does Kamal know about Gayetri's sordid background?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?352762</url></doc>
