<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="352818">
  <docid>352818</docid>
  <title>Maine Dil Tujhko Diya</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="UK">PG</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">23 August 2002</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="UK">23 August 2002</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Kuwait">10 September 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">154</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Khan, Sohail</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Khan, Sohail</producer>
    <producer>Walia, Bunty</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Malik, Daboo</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bedi, Kabir</actor>
      <role>Mr. Varma (Ayesha's father)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dutt, Sanjay</actor>
      <role>Bhai-Jaan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Eijaz</actor>
      <role>Ejaz</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Sarfaraz</actor>
      <role>Chotte (Bhaijaan's henchman)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Sohail</actor>
      <role>Ajay</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sheikh, Aashif</actor>
      <role>Raman Chopra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tahil, Dalip</actor>
      <role>Chopra (Varma's associate)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vora, Neeraj</actor>
      <role>Principal/Pandit</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Yadav, Rajpal</actor>
      <role>Munna (Bhaijaan's henchman)</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A prominent and very wealthy businessman named Mr. Varma lives a middle class life with his two daughters. The eldest one named Ayesha Verma is expected to marry Varma's friend and right-hand named Mr. Chopra's son, Raman. Soon after Ayesha started to go to college and is attracted to Ajay. The two lovers spend beautiful moments together in college and elsewhere, one day Raman spot Ayesha and Ajay together at a rose day party and is jealous and so he complaints to Mr. Varma thereafter Mr. Varma decides to tests Ajay and see if he is ready to become his future son-in-law. But Ajay proves to be hot headed and so he and Mr. Varma became sworn enemies and he asks Ajay to move away from his daughter's life but Ajay does not obey and continues to reach Ayesha, Varma contact a notorious underworld Don, named Bhai-Jaan and Ajay is told that after the 30 days of Ramadan, he is suppose to meet a violent death, and so Ajay is badly beaten up by his goons and is left virtually for dead on the outskirts of Bombay, but Ajay recovers and swear that he will marry Ayesha. Verma contacted the police and Ajay also receives another trashing from them but Ajay escapes and throws a challenge to Chopra and Verma that he will make Ayesha become his bride within 24 hours and will strive hard to fulfill his promise. Along with the help of the college principal and students Ajay and Ayesha is finally married after a big blast with the enemies.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?352818</url></doc>
