<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="353322">
  <docid>353322</docid>
  <title>Make a Wish</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>nudity</keyword>
    <keyword>twist-in-the-end</keyword>
    <keyword>throat-slitting</keyword>
    <keyword>lesbian</keyword>
    <keyword>neck-breaking-scene</keyword>
    <keyword>lesbian-kiss</keyword>
    <keyword>murder</keyword>
    <keyword>lesbian-interest</keyword>
    <keyword>camping-trip</keyword>
    <keyword>arrow</keyword>
    <keyword>birthday</keyword>
    <keyword>title-spoken-by-character</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="UK">15</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="France">19 October 2005</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">August 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">96</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Ferranti, Sharon</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Silverstein, Lawrence</producer>
    <producer>Johnson, Lauren (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Johnson, Lauren (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Ferranti, Jay</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Alapai, Lava</actor>
      <role>Chloe</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Baeta, Virginia</actor>
      <role>Monica</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Durham, Susan</actor>
      <role>Ranger</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Flynn, Melenie Freedom</actor>
      <role>Linda</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>King, Moynan</actor>
      <role>Susan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Peterson, Bob (V)</actor>
      <role>Zeke</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vichi, Eric</actor>
      <role>Steve</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wilson, Neil (IV)</actor>
      <role>CK McFarland</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"Make A Wish" In the tradition of Friday the 13th and other classic horror films, Make A Wish tells the story of a group of women who get together once again for an annual birthday camping trip. The common denominator in this group of gay and straight girls is Susan: all of the campers are exes of hers. All except Andrea, who is Monica's new girlfriend, and not very pleased to be dragged along on this ridiculous outing. Linda, now straight, left her boyfriend Steve pouting at home, annoyed that she wanted to leave him for the weekend for a romp in the woods with the girls. Chloe, the aggressive vegetarian, and Dawn, whom Susan recently dumped, complete the group. Linda and Monica suspect that Susan's been cheating on Dawn, and they're surprised when Dawn opts to come on the trip in the first place. Before the rest of the group arrives, Susan has a run in with Steve, who shows up looking for Linda. Zeke, a rough-looking outdoorsman, convinces Steve with a little physical violence to leave Susan alone, but Steve doesn't go far. Also looking for someone is Detective C.K. McFarland # but for whom-or for what-is he looking? By the time the girls set up camp, tensions between Andrea and Susan are running high, and Linda has her eye on Monica, who doesn't mind looking back. Chloe is mad because there is no vegan food, and Dawn is performing healing rituals that look a lot like witchcraft. Michelle, the final camper, is supposed to be arriving any minute, but god knows she's always late. So when Chloe takes off on her bike to go to shopping,, nobody thinks much of it, And when Andrea disappears with the car, well, it's just because she's angry because Monica kissed Linda by the fire isn't it? But how come Chloe isn't back? And how come Michelle never showed up? And how come people keep disappearing?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?353322</url></doc>
