<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="353859">
  <docid>353859</docid>
  <title>Making the Monster: Special Makeup Effects Frankenstein Monster Makeup</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Essman, Scott</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>frankenstein's-monster</keyword>
    <keyword>frankenstein</keyword>
    <keyword>glenn-strange</keyword>
    <keyword>makeup</keyword>
    <keyword>monster</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">PG-13</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">20 September 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">9</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Essman, Scott</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Essman, Scott</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Essman, Scott</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Thompson, Matthew (III)</actor>
      <role>Frankenstein Monster</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>From the original JACK PIERCE TRIBUTE, this short production features a nine-minute step-by-step Glenn Strange FRANKENSTEIN MONSTER likeness makeup created by Kevin Haney in 1999 and applied only once at the Pasadena, CA convention center. The prosthetic Glenn Strange Frankenstein Monster likeness makeup was designed and created by Haney for the 1999 Jack Pierce Tribute intended for the Alex Theater in Glendale, CA but never staged. Instead, Haney, with assistance from Kenny Myers and Bill Corso, only applied this makeup once - on July 25, 1999. Haney designed and created a completely new Boris Karloff Frankenstein Monster makeup which was applied by Haney for the Jack Pierce tribute in 2000 and again in 2001 (for the 70th anniversary film screening of Frankenstein at the Alex Theater) and applied by Barry Koper in 2003 (for the Hollywood Makeup Awards - Jack Pierce Lifetime Achievement Award) and then by Rob Burman (75th Anniversary of Frankenstein in 2006). The costume was made from scratch by Jennifer McManus and used each of these applications. Enjoy the entire process for this once-in-a-lifetime Glenn Strange likeness makeup as the Frankenstein Monster, which Strange performed in three films - House of Frankenstein (1944), House of Dracula (1945) and Abbott and Costello Meet Frankenstein (1948, with makeup by Jack Kevan).</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?353859</url></doc>
