<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="354653">
  <docid>354653</docid>
  <title>Malvinas: La guerra intima</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Zunino, Andres</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>War</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>argentina</keyword>
    <keyword>military</keyword>
    <keyword>great-britain</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Argentina</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Argentina">27 April 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Argentina">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Molinero, Cune</producer>
    <producer>Guebel, Diego</producer>
    <producer>Pergolini, Mario</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>Malvinas - The Intimate War On April 2, 1982 nearly five thousand Argentinean soldiers set foot on the Malvinas Islands, claiming sovereignty, and setting forth an armed conflict against Great Britain. The Military Junta planned the invasion of the archipelago at a time when the population's discontent was increasing as a result of a deteriorating economy and violations of human rights. Three months later, the end of the war would bring forth the fall of the military dictatorship and the beginning of a nightmare for the ex combatants doomed to live in oblivion. Six hundred soldiers died in the battlefield, but more than three hundred fifty decided to put an end to their lives once they returned to their country. Malvinas, the intimate war is a documentary which reviews the facts through the eyes and descriptions of the survivors. A return to the experiences of the real protagonists of the war, capturing the human face of each story. Through the narrations of friends and relatives, documentation, photographs, recreations and resources taken from the actual places of battle, we reconstruct the lives of those that were called to be a part of Argentina's martial history.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?354653</url></doc>
