<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="355673">
  <docid>355673</docid>
  <title>Manacha Kunku</title>
  <year>1981</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Ved, N.S.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Marathi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">1981</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Kulkarni, Govind</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kulkarni, Govind</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Shinde, Datta (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Raj, Rishi (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deshpande, Suhasini</actor>
      <role>Rukmani D. Deshmukh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Disa, Ravindra</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dutt, Yashwant</actor>
      <role>Daulatrao Deshmukh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gandhi, Leela</actor>
      <role>Manjula D. Deshmukh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gosavi, Raja</actor>
      <role>Narayan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Madhu (XIII)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mokasi, Gulab</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Patil, Ganpat</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Suryakant (I)</actor>
      <role>Madhavrao 'Madhya' D. Deshmukh</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Manjula lives a poor lifestyle in rural Maharashtra, India. She is befriended by wealthy Daulatrao Deshmukh, married to Rukmani, who is unable to bear him children. Both Manjula and Daulatrao get intimate, and soon she gives birth to a son, Madhavrao. When villagers, led by Rukmani's brother, Narayan, find out that she has given birth out of wedlock, they humiliate and force her to leave the district. Manjula brings up Madhavrao on her son, making a living as a dancer/singer. Years pass by, Madhavrao has grown up, is in love with a dancer/singer, Bakula, and works in the theatre troupe run by his mother. An ailing Daulatrao manages to convince Rukmani to accept Manjula and her son as the sole heir to his estate, and she agrees. Manjula and Madhavrao re-locate to live with the Deshmukhs, much to the chagrin of Narayan. Many problems arise after Daulatrao passes away, namely, Madhavrao is not permitted to see Bakula anymore nor meet anyone from the troupe; Manjula detests the old way of life and wants Madhavrao to marry a decent girl; and Narayan gathers together some hoodlums and forcibly takes over the house and property of the Deshmukhs.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?355673</url></doc>
