<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="355620">
  <docid>355620</docid>
  <title>Man-Mauji</title>
  <year>1962</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Panjabi, S.</editor>
    <editor>Vittal, R.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Musical</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">U</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <directors>
    <director>Krishnan, R.</director>
    <director>Panju, S.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Meiyappan, A.V.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>D., Madhusudhana Rao</writer>
    <writer>D.V., Narasa Raju</writer>
    <writer>Krishan, Rajendra</writer>
    <writer>Reddy, Kadri Venkata</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Mohan, Madan (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Baby Farida</actor>
      <role>Advocate's Daughter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chatterjee, Sulochana</actor>
      <role>Bhola Ram's wife</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chitnis, Leela</actor>
      <role>Bhagwanti</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Choti, Mohan</actor>
      <role>Sitaram</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Devika (I)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Haksar, Som</actor>
      <role>Daroga</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hussain, Anwar (I)</actor>
      <role>Advocate</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jayalalitha</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khote, Durga</actor>
      <role>Dr. Mohan's mom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Ashim</actor>
      <role>Dr. Mohan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Kishore</actor>
      <role>Raja/Raja Lal Bahadur</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mukri</actor>
      <role>Darbari Lal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Narayan, S.L.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Prakash, Om (I)</actor>
      <role>Rai Saheb Bhola Ram</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pran (I)</actor>
      <role>Jagga</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sarosh (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shahid, Master</actor>
      <role>Advocate's Son</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sharma, Umesh</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shyamlal</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sunder (I)</actor>
      <role>Schoolmaster</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Whisky, Johnny</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Raja has a vivid imagination since childhood, used to frequently lie and gamble, which did lead him to considerable trouble with his schoolmaster, mom, Bhagwanti, and sister, Rani. When Raja is accused of stealing medication, he is arrested, leading to the death of his ailing mother, and Rani being taken to an orphanage run by Kamlabai. Years later, Raja re-enters Rani's life and claims to be a very wealthy businessman with contacts all over the world. A few days later, Rani comes to know that Raja has been lying and the wealth that her brother had acquired was by robbing his employer, Rai Saheb Bhola Ram. Raja gets arrested and sent to prison. Ashamed by her brother's wrong-doing Rani leaves the orphanage and goes to work in the household of Dr. Mohan by looking after his ailing mom. Shortly thereafter she finds out that Raja, too, has got a job as a chauffeur with this family - only to be dismissed for stealing a wrist-watch of Mohan's advocate brother. Rani continues to work for Mohan and his family, without letting anyone know that Raja is really her brother, and soon wins everyone's heart, gets engaged to Mohan, much to the chagrin of Bhola Ram, who wants his daughter, Sarangi, to get married to Mohan, and wants to expose Rani's background. Shortly after Rani marriage to Mohan, the Police are informed that Bhola Ram has been killed and in his dying declaration had named Raja as his killer. Watch what happens when Mohan and his family find out that Raja is really Rani's brother - and the impact this has on the entire family - and Raja, who may well face the gallows, after being convicted. (Includes the popular song: "Jaroorat Hai Jaroorat Hai, Ik Shrimati Ki, Kalavati Ki, Seva Karey Jo Pati Ki...").</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?355620</url></doc>
