<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="356226">
  <docid>356226</docid>
  <title>Manhattan Rendez-vous</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Durga, Speedy</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Swedish</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Finland</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">4 October 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">5 October 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">40</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Finn, Kim</director>
    <director>Hakalax, John</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hakalax, John</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Finn, Kim</writer>
    <writer>Hakalax, John</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Bartholomew, Simon</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dennis, Harry</actor>
      <role>Harry Dennis</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fox, Judy (II)</actor>
      <role>Judy Fox</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kuchta, Ron</actor>
      <role>Ron Kuchta</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Simonsson, Kim</actor>
      <role>Kim Simonsson</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A Woody Allen &amp; Spike Lee inspired documentary following the underground porcelain sculptor Kim Simonsson as he lands on The Big Apple to meet some of the leading American players of the art business since the 1960's. The curator and museum director Ron Kuchta (Chrysler collection among others), American Ceramics publisher Harry Dennis and the critic Cynthia Nadelman all operate daily in Chelsea - the center of the art world - which has fifty times more galleries than during Andy Warhol's time. The gallery owner Nancy Margolis explains why she fell for Simonsson's weird porcelain sculptures and why she represents him in New York City. Together with Simonsson we visit also his favorite artist Judy Fox, who has become known worldwide for her provocative child sculptures. Simonsson's own art is depicted in form of dramatic installations that visually remind us of the stylistic introduction of the murdered bodies in Henry - A Serial Killer. The documentary ends up in a humorous dinner in which our protagonists discuss among others subjects like the mad mind of the artist and during which interesting sides in Simonsson's background are revealed. A musical score by Brand New Heavies' guitarist Simon Bartholomew rhythms this peculiar road movie with funky New Yorkers and challenging ceramics.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?356226</url></doc>
