<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="356753">
  <docid>356753</docid>
  <title>Manorama Six Feet Under</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Merchant, Jabeen</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Mystery</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>estrangement</keyword>
    <keyword>small-town</keyword>
    <keyword>neo-noir</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">21 September 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="India">135</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Singh, Navdeep</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Gada, Hiren</producer>
    <producer>Maroo, Mansi</producer>
    <producer>Maroo, Smita</producer>
    <producer>Maru, Ketan</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bhagat, Devika</writer>
    <writer>Kashyap, Abhinav</writer>
    <writer>Singh, Navdeep</writer>
    <writer>Tapadia, Manoj</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Mirza, Raiomond</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deol, Abhay</actor>
      <role>Satyaveer Randhawa</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gupta, Yana</actor>
      <role>Herself (Illusion)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jogiji</actor>
      <role>Fauji</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kale, Brijendra</actor>
      <role>Bihari Lal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kharbanda, Kulbhushan</actor>
      <role>Minister P.P. Rathore</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pathak, Vinay</actor>
      <role>Brij Mohan</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Rajasthan-based Satyaveer Singh Randhawa works as a Junior Engineer with Lahkot Municipality's Public Works Department and lives a middle-class lifestyle with his wife, Nimmi, and son, Raju. The region faces drought and extreme temperatures, with the local Irrigation Minister, P.P. Rathore, making tall promises of diverting water from Haryana and Punjab via a canal that is being constructed on a controversial site. Satyeveer also authored a fictional novel 'Manorama' that sold only about 200 copies. So dismayed was he with this that he decided to not even keep a copy for his private library. To make matters worse he accepts a motorbike from Seema Constructions as a bribe, is apprehended, and suspended pending an inquiry. Now out of a job, he is approached by Manorama Rathore, the wife of the Irrigation Minister, to collect evidence that her husband is having an extra-marital affair for a fee of Twenty thousand rupees. Satyaveer accepts this offer little knowing that he will soon be thrust into a web of lies and deceit, which will not only get him in the bad books of Rathore, assaulted by his goons, but also implicate him in the murder of two lovers, Sameera, and Dr. Anil Poddar, compounded all the more by the sudden death of Manorama and the disappearance of an orphan named Deepti.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?356753</url></doc>
