<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="358491">
  <docid>358491</docid>
  <title>Mario's Time Machine</title>
  <year>1993</year>
  <type>VideoGame</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>item</keyword>
    <keyword>super-mario</keyword>
    <keyword>video-game</keyword>
    <keyword>william-shakespeare</keyword>
    <keyword>wright-brothers</keyword>
    <keyword>time-machine</keyword>
    <keyword>sequel</keyword>
    <keyword>dinosaur</keyword>
    <keyword>historical-fiction</keyword>
    <keyword>first-olympics</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>mario</keyword>
    <keyword>samurai</keyword>
    <keyword>time-travel</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">E</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <directors>
    <director>Markarian, Henrik</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Iverson, Andrew</writer>
    <writer>Jenkins, Wes (II)</writer>
    <writer>Koretsky, Rachel</writer>
    <writer>Pearson, Jim (II)</writer>
    <writer>Singer, Valerie</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Knight, Mark (III)</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>The evil Bowser is at it again. This time he's kidnapped Yoshi and locked him in his museum of ancient artifacts, which are actually stolen artifacts, items used by famous people centuries ago and now that they're stolen they can't use them and that could rewrite history in a bad way. So Mario hops in Bowser's time machine and travels back to historical years and returns all the historical items, like in 1192 he returns a sword to a Samurai; in 80,000,000 BC he returns a dinosaur egg; in 1969 he returns the American flag onto the moon Lander; in 1903 he gives Orville and Wilbur Wright back the propeller to their plane; in 1686 he places the apple back on the tree that will help Isaac Newton discover gravity; In 1905 he returns the E=MC2 equation to Albert Einstein; In 1602 he returns ink and a quill to William Shakespeare so he can write his famous sonnets; In 1862 he returns Abraham Lincoln's stove pipe hat so he can make the Gettysberg Address; and so on. Finally when all the items are returned, Mario must use all his knowledge of historical events to battle Koopa, destroy him, and rescue Yoshi. Mario will go down in history!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?358491</url></doc>
