<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="358705">
  <docid>358705</docid>
  <title>Mark(s)</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Deierling, Adam</editor>
    <editor>Lux Davis, Hannah</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 July 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Day, Josh</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Day, Josh</producer>
    <producer>Putnam, Ian J.</producer>
    <producer>Reising, Celina</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Day, Josh</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Marsh, Kerry (II)</composer>
    <composer>Rackley, Phillip</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>3 Nutz, Johnny</actor>
      <role>Bud</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Abiskaron, John</actor>
      <role>Hariff</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cruzado-Burge, Jesse</actor>
      <role>Ramirez</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Torres, William (IV)</actor>
      <role>Jairo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Whittaker, Lee</actor>
      <role>Mitch</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A convenience store robbery turns sour when two brothers, Jairo and Ramirez pick the wrong evening to rob a store by disrupting a record breaking arcade campaign played by Mitch. Police quickly arrive on the scene and discover the robbery to have turned into a double-crossed hold up with both Mitch and Rosemary stuck between the line of fire. The story jumps back in time when Rosemary receives terrible news regarding her failed cancer treatment. Dropped by health insurance and flirting with bankruptcy, Rosemary decides to fabricate a convenience store robbery in order to instigate a wrongful death suit to clear her from severe medical debt. But Rosemary's mark is anything but proficient, hiring Jairo after his failed attempt trying to steal her purse during the climax of a major panic attack. To make matters worse, Jairo just discovered that he is the paternal contributor of his brother's girlfriend's pregnancy, Maria, and must find enough money to pay for her abortion. The story further unfolds when Mitch, who has just found out he has testicular cancer, is taken out for an enjoyable evening with his best friend, Bub, only to be later beaten up by fraternity boys. While waiting in the convenience store, Mitch discovers the beating was planned by Bud right before Jairo and Ramirez enter the store with loaded weapons. Mitch decides he will not be another mark for the evening, wrongfully believing the robbery to be another orchestrated scam by Bud. Instead, Mitch pulls out his arsenal of manipulative and creative fabrications, refusing to stand down, jeopardizing Rosemary's wrongful death heist, and revealing a hysterical, climatic twist of last minute confessions mixed with armed and loaded panic attacks.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?358705</url></doc>
