<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="358846">
  <docid>358846</docid>
  <title>Marlon</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>court-case</keyword>
    <keyword>teenager</keyword>
    <keyword>aspiration</keyword>
    <keyword>blind-boy</keyword>
    <keyword>death-of-brother</keyword>
    <keyword>disability</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>one-word-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Tagalog</language>
    <language>Filipino</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Philippines</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Philippines">October 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">83</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Amparo, James</director>
    <director>Jover, Ralston</director>
  </directors>
<plot>Marlon is the iconic story of a 17-year-old blind teenager who looks like a 10-year-old boy. His blissful innocence brightens his bleak fate brought about by his disability and his family's miseries. The film starts with his great desire for knowledge. He wants to go to school despite the suspension of classes in all levels caused by a coup d'etat threat to the national government on February 24, 2005. Marlon's mother is subservient to her child's needs. She believes God is punishing her with his condition because she attempted to get rid of him in birth. She gives up her entire life taking care of him. Marlon's family is also grieving over the death of his eldest brother who gets killed by a bully, a son of a local official. His father continues to pursue the criminal case against the suspect despite the sluggishness and inanities of the rural court. At times, he could understand the proceedings which are usually conducted in the English language. Marlon's ultimate dream is to become a school teacher for the visually impaired. Nothing can stop him from pursuing this dream, not poverty, or his family's tragedies; and not even people's apathy. As he usually says, he is not blind, he just winks a lot. He may not see the world for all its beauty and its tragedy, but in his mind he vividly perceives the brightness of day with the sound of his infectious laughter. He can hear the weary mundane noises with his imminent sense of affect. His unwavering faith in the Divine through his resilient songs and prayers has clearly defined his undying hope and zest for life.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?358846</url></doc>
