<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="360573">
  <docid>360573</docid>
  <title>Masters of the Maze</title>
  <year>1994</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Game-Show</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>kids-and-family</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <producers>
    <producer>Dowaliby, James M.</producer>
    <producer>Kline, Richard S.</producer>
    <producer>Weydt, Mary</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>López, Mario (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself - Host</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maxwell-Smith, Mark</actor>
      <role>Mirror Man</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Roth, J.D.</actor>
      <role>Himself - Host</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Three contestants of three teams, all dressed up from the beginning of their powersuits, compete to win prizes. Host Roth shows an out of focus picture (e.g., person, place, thing or a T.V. show), every time the contestant buzzes in with the right identification to the picture will win 10 points and the same contestant will be asked a multiple-choice question about the picture (e.g., pop culture, storybook, spelling words, places, etc.), and if the contestant gets it right (again), then the contestant will get 5 points = 15 points. The first team who ended the game with 50 points will be able to run inside the maze with the help of his/her partner, after a decision has been made (whether if he/she will go first or second). Then, after the first team won, the two contestants will go right into the speed round where each correct picture is still 10 points and host Roth will no longer have to ask anymore questions. An incorrect picture on the contestant's meant that Roth would read a clue to what that picture is, but without any unveiling. The second team with 50 points goes right inside the maze. A rule added later that in season 1, that the 3 contestants have 10 seconds to buzz in and come up with the picture to win whatever point value was awarded on the clock, and then the contestant can answer the question correctly in order to double their points. If time runs out or if all 3 contestants gets the picture wrong, then no points was awarded at that time, and the 1st 2 teams who ended the game with more than 50 points will go into the maze. In the maze, after all the kids have been dressed up, the contestants' partner uses the joystick to connect with their partner (in any direction his/her partner chooses), before winning the game, in the fastest time. In the Mirror Maze, the contestants' partner must navigate the contestant to the Mirror-Man (who eventually take over his path), and the contestant must answer his question correctly in order to proceed. If at anytime, the contestant answers the Mirror-Man's question correctly, then he's free to go, but if he gets it wrong or pass, then host Roth will automatically ask another question, 3 incorrect answers and/or passes the contestant has already made will wait until the contestant is told to go. Then, after finding both powersticks, the contestants' partner will have the him/her go to the Honeycomb Maze, where the contestants' visor would have to come down and his/her partner would have to direct him in the appropriate area of the contestant of where he/she is supposed to go, into The Chamber of Knowledge. After the contestant is told to put his/her visor up, then he/she will enter into the chambers to answer all 3 true/false questions. If the contestant gets 1 right from a guardian, then the door will automatically open, if the contestant gets it wrong, then one of the 5 guardians will ask another question. 3 incorrect answers will automatically open the door with excessive time. If the contestant gets all 3 correct answers, then he/she will take a short trip to the jar to stop the contestants' time. Then, its team #2 turn to do the same, to see if the contestant can beat the contestants' time (e.g., 1:56 (best time ever), 1:57, 2:40, 4:30, etc.), and if the contestant does this even quicker, then the contestant will go on to the Prize Mountain, if not, then their opponents automatically go on to Prize Mountain. In Prize Mountain, there are 5 monitors, (e.g., both of them flashing PRIZE/NO PRIZE), after their partner locks in on the monitor, the contestants' job is to point their lazer, aim and (scream fire very often). If the contestant fires in on 3 "PRIZE" monitors before locking in on 3 "NO PRIZE" monitors, then the contestant will be going home with a grand prize (e.g., a $500 shopping spree at Sharper Image at Beverly Hills). In the fall of 1995, Roth was replaced by actor/heartthrob, Mario Lopez, and the rules stay the same, but there's a "Bonus Picture," for the contestant who buzzes in with the right picture, get 15 points, and once again, 2 teams who end the game with 50 points will go into the maze to see which teammates has the fastest time.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?360573</url></doc>
