<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="361292">
  <docid>361292</docid>
  <title>Matters of Consequence</title>
  <year>1999</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kashima, Kenn</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>the-little-prince</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">13 January 1999</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">97</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Night, Morgan Higby</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Glazen, Brian</producer>
    <producer>Falco, Tracy</producer>
    <producer>Night, Morgan Higby</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Night, Morgan Higby</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Antin, Robin</actor>
      <role>Josie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Buckman, Phil</actor>
      <role>Joe</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Coyle, Morty</actor>
      <role>Zack</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dante, Peter</actor>
      <role>Peter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Francis, Paul (II)</actor>
      <role>Drew</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Night, Morgan Higby</actor>
      <role>Billy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wiles, Jason</actor>
      <role>Jake</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Morgan Higby's "Matters of Consequence" is an edgy, deeply felt first feature centered on three young men who share a house and all work at the Opium Den in Hollywood. Higby wrote his film's pivotal role for himself: Billy, a reflective, fatalistic druggie deejay. Morty Coyle plays Zack, an ambitious self-absorbed singer eager to get a record deal for himself and his band (the Impostors, who provide a highly affecting soundtrack), and Paul Francis is Drew, the bartender, who sees himself as a detached Mr. Cool. Into the young men's lives come three women who may--or may not--change their perspectives in varying degrees: Devon Odessa's Blue, Zack's lovely younger sister, attracted to Billy; Meredith Salenger's Reiko, a classy call girl who would like to dent Drew's armor; and Robin Antin's Josie, a kinky club dancer who zeros in on Zack. Jason Wiles is Jake, Billy's volatile drug supplier. Sharply photographed by Thaddeus Wadleigh, "Matters of Consequence" has a great look and delves, amid easy humor, way beneath trendy surfaces to pose some of life's bigger questions.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?361292</url></doc>
