<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="362111">
  <docid>362111</docid>
  <title>Maya Bazaar</title>
  <year>1958</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Mistri, Babubhai</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Wadia, Homi (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Gupta, Chitra</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chatterjee, Sulochana</actor>
      <role>Subhadra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Guha, Anita</actor>
      <role>Rajkumari Surekha B. Yadav</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kanchanamala</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Raj (I)</actor>
      <role>Rajkumar Abhimanyu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mahipal</actor>
      <role>Bhagwan Shri Kishan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pahelwan, Vasantrao</actor>
      <role>Ghatotkach</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Raje, Babu</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shribhagwan (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ulhas (I)</actor>
      <role>Balram 'Baldev' Yadav</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vyas, B.M.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vyas, Kanta</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Ancient India has three prominent families living in Hastinapur, Indraprastha, and Dwarkapuri, namely the Pandavas, Kauravas, and the Yadavs respectively. Hastinapur is ruled by Yudhister, aided by his brothers: Arjun, Bhim, Nakul and Sahadev, their common wife, Draupadi, as well as Arjun's wife, Subhadra and their son, Abhimanyu; the Kauravas consists of Duryodhan, Dushashan, and 98 other brothers, their maternal uncle, Shakuni, their blind father, Dhirtharastra, and their mother; and finally the Yadavs who include Bhagwan Shri Kishan, his wife, Rukmani; Kishanji's brother, Balram, his wife, and daughter, Surekha. Surekha meets and falls in love with Abhimanyu, much to the delight of their respective families, especially as Draupadi is Kishanji's sister. At a Yagna in Indraprastha, Shishupal, as associate of Duryodhan, insults Kishanji, who had taken a vow to forgive 100 mistakes, and when Shishupal completes the 100 insult mark, Kishanji slays him with his Sudarshan Chakra. While Abhimanyu shows Duryodhan and some guests the mystical Maya Mahal, Duryodhan stumbles and falls down, Draupadi mocks and laughs at him calling him the 'son of a blind man', which enrages Duryodhan so much he vows to publicly humiliate Draupadi in the presence of her husbands. Much later at Hastinapur, Shakuni invites Yudhister to gamble, and the later ends up losing everything, including his wealth, title, Indraprastha, his brothers, and finally he even loses Draupadi. Dushashan attempts to disrobe Draupadi, who calls out for help from the Pandavas but they refuse to respond and Kishanji comes to her rescue. The Pandavas are then banished from their kingdom for 13 years. Balram changes his mind about getting Surekha married to Abhimanyu, and instead arranges her marriage to Lakshman, Duryodhan's son. A frantic Abhimanyu decides to travel to Dwarkapuri so that the two lovers could elope, but on the way is waylaid by a giant named Ghatotkach, a magician and illusionist, who first kills him, but later revives him when he finds out that Abhimanyu is his half-brother. The duo set out to Dwarkapuri with an attempt to meet Surekha and get her to elope. Little do they know that soon the two brothers will be pitted against the Yadavs, the Kauravas, as well as the master magician and illusionist - Bhagwan Shri Kishan himself.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?362111</url></doc>
