<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="365568">
  <docid>365568</docid>
  <title>Men in Court</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Norman, Matt (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>injustice</keyword>
    <keyword>murder</keyword>
    <keyword>corruption</keyword>
    <keyword>suicide</keyword>
    <keyword>family-court</keyword>
    <keyword>divorce</keyword>
    <keyword>family-relationships</keyword>
    <keyword>court</keyword>
    <keyword>child-custody</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby</soundmix>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Australia">1 October 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Australia">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Norman, Matt (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Favelle, Michael</producer>
    <producer>Pederson, Dave</producer>
    <producer>Norman, Matt (I)</producer>
    <producer>Norman, Rebecca (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Norman, Matt (I)</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Five men a day in Australia commit suicide because of child custody issues. We have a justice system that is considered a joke by society and the continued demand for change is laughed at by our government. The Family Court in Australia is a one stop money making shop for Lawyers and solicitors and judges spend more time enjoying their lunch than they do looking after the children who are being ignored. "MEN IN COURT" documents how the Family court are responsible for the upbringing of our children. The film examines the horrifying effects that losing a child has on a MAN and the burden that has on society. Suicide, murder, debt, depression, loneliness, deception, aggression, mental illness... Children see it too! With the tragic events of late not just here in Australia but around the World, where fathers have either taken their own life or that of their children shows that no-one is doing much about the problems faced in our society. This shouldn't be about Man Vs. Woman. It should be clearer than that. It should be purely related to the child. Unfortunately the Family court believe that they know better and the men that jump from buildings, hang themselves in the shed, take their head off with a shotgun and sometimes become so sad that nothing makes sense to them anymore and believe that their children would be better off dead with him than alone without him, tells me that there MUST be a better solution.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?365568</url></doc>
