<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="366377">
  <docid>366377</docid>
  <title>Mere Sartaj</title>
  <year>1975</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Kardar, Abdul Rashid</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Sharif, K. Usman</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Ravi (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Alka (I)</actor>
      <role>Sultana</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Helen (I)</actor>
      <role>Dancer/Singer at Angel Club</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hussain, Nasir (I)</actor>
      <role>Parveen's dad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jagdeep</actor>
      <role>Munir-Ul-Haq Qadri</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Trilok (I)</actor>
      <role>Thakur Kaka</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kaul, Satish</actor>
      <role>Javed Ahmed Gulrez</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khanna, Padma</actor>
      <role>Shabab Bano</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Roopesh</actor>
      <role>Asad</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Parveen lives a wealthy lifestyle in India with her widowed dad in India. She is of marriageable age and has three suitors, Munir-Ul-Haq Qadri - who wants to be a live-in son-in-law; equally wealthy Asad, who will do anything for her; and wealthy poet Javed Ahmed Gulrez. Parveen has her dad and gorgeous friend, Sultana, reject Munir and Asad and gets married to Javed. The two admirers get together and plot vengeance, and Asad gets busy to get Javed actively involved in a new nightclub, Angel Club, and introduces him to alcohol and gambling. Parveen and the loyal family servant, Thakur Kaka, attempt to dissuade Javed, but in vain. Javed comes to know that Parveen is having an affair with Munir, reprimands her, starts to frequent a brothel and falls in love with a Courtesan named Shabab Bano. He even goes to the extent of asking her to move into his house, and makes Parveen her servant. Then things spiral out of control when the police get involved in the theft of jewelry from Javed's house, and then Javed himself goes on the run, chased by the police - for murder!!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?366377</url></doc>
