<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="366355">
  <docid>366355</docid>
  <title>Mere Do Anmol Ratan</title>
  <year>1998</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">1998</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Shankar, K. Ravi</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Roshan, Rajesh</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Amrapurkar, Sadashiv</actor>
      <role>Mahesh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Banerjee, Beena</actor>
      <role>Bhagawat's sister</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhagwat, Suresh</actor>
      <role>Advocate Mathur</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dev, Mukul</actor>
      <role>Surinder (Suren)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hingoo, Dinesh</actor>
      <role>Raju Ishnani</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Kader (I)</actor>
      <role>Major Bhagawat Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lagoo, Reema</actor>
      <role>Suman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Muthu, Pramod</actor>
      <role>Sudhakar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Warsi, Arshad</actor>
      <role>Narinder (Naren)</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Suman and Mahesh have been married for several years but have not been blessed with any children. Suman prays in the temple frequently and hopes that her prayers will be answered. Her prayers are heard and she soon gets pregnant. During her delivery in the hospital, there is a power outage which sets off a fire, which is soon brought under control by the fire department. Two children, both boys, are saved by a nurse, who soon passes away due to extensive burns. One of the boys is of Suman, but no one knows which one, as the second boy's mother had died during delivery. So Suman and Mahesh take both, Suren and Naren, home in the hopes of solving this mystery. Major Bhagawat Singh comes to their home claiming that he is the father of one of the boys, but again no resolution is reached, and both the children grow up under the loving care of Suman, while Mahesh hopes to identify his son during his lifetime. Years pass by, both the boys are now handsome young men. Mahesh's friend, Sudhakar, asks his daughter, Kiran, to assist Mahesh in identifying his son, and she moves into their house. She starts taking notes and studying them in detail. She falls in love with one of them, and is unable to tell who is indeed Mahesh's son. To make matters worse both Suren and Naren are in love with her, and want to marry her, fully aware that she can only marry one. There is only person who knows this secret, and he/she may not come forward to reveal this - for she/he has a reason for this to be kept secret - forever.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?366355</url></doc>
