<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="366829">
  <docid>366829</docid>
  <title>Messengers</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Beckwith, Shawn</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">18 September 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">27</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="default">27</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Blackie, Rob</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Blackie, Rob</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barbati, Reno</actor>
      <role>Vito</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hebert, Janique</actor>
      <role>Angelique</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wendland, Steven (II)</actor>
      <role>Thor</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Vito (Reno Barbati) has been sentenced to 4 years in prison for a crime he insists he didn't commit, while his lover Angelique (Janique Hebert) promises to wait for him. They strive to keep their relationship alive despite their separation, but while Vito is in prison their love affair exists solely in written letters. Vito endures the brutality of prison life quietly, and hides from Angelique the harshness of his life behind bars. Angelique accidentally discovers money and documents that Vito has been hiding and she slowly unravels a series of clues that lead her to a grim discovery. Meanwhile, Vito is torn apart by guilt over his lies, and under the advice of his fellow inmate and friend 'Thor' (Steven Wendland) he makes the commitment to come clean with Angelique. But he's too late. She has discovered the truth - that Vito has lied about his involvement in his 'father's business'. He returns home after 4 years to discover that she has learned the truth and everything that is dear to him is in jeopardy.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?366829</url></doc>
