<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="368319">
  <docid>368319</docid>
  <title>Michael Carroll: King of Chavs</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Warburton, John (III)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>chav</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">22 April 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">48</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Allen, Keith (I)</director>
    <director>Parker, Ned</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Weller, Tom</producer>
    <producer>Lewis-Smith, Victor</producer>
    <producer>Parker, Ned</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Frodsham, Knowles</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Allen, Keith (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Aubrey, Anne (II)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carroll, Michael (IX)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Smith, Mark (XIII)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Michael Carroll was just 19 when he picked up a cheque from Camelot for £9.7 million. He was wearing an electronic tag at the time for a series of criminal offences. After celebrating his win with a bottle of vodka and a "spag bol", Michael promised to go straight. Sure. Two years, countless court appearances and a spell in jail later, KEITH ALLEN catches up with Michael, whose favourite hobbies are now consuming vast quantities of Stella Artois lager, annoying his neighbours by trashing vintage cars at night, and igniting enormous bonfires with anything from mobile homes to boats thrown on them. MARVEL at exclusive coverage of Carroll's rigorous training regime, interrupted only by drinking sessions and visits from the constabulary, as he prepares for a 'D' list celebrity boxing match with former Gladiator 'Rhino', bringing viewers all the glamour from this classic East End bout. ENJOY THE HOSPITALITY of "The King of Chavs" at his Norfolk home, and in one of the few London Hotels which allow him to book in - for one night at least. JOIN THE GANG with 'Mikey' and his posse as they invade a recording studio and step behind the microphone to record their very own rap song. Keith's hard-won access to gain insight into Carroll's life - unsurprisingly he is not a great fan of the media - goes some way to enlightening us as to WHY, if he has enough money never to have to work again, does he wish he'd never won it? WHY did he continue to re-offend, culminating in his imprisonment last month? WHY is he so obsessed with destroying valuable cars? What have they ever done to him? WHO is the real Michael Carroll? Is he portrayed as one- dimensional by the media? Continuing KEITH ALLEN's ground-breaking series of profiles of bizarre and larger-than-life icons of British society, including LAUREN formerly JAMES HARRIES (Little Lady Fauntleroy) and YOU'RE FAYED! on Egyptian entrepreneur MOHAMED AL FAYED, the presenter now alights on millionaire lottery winner Michael Carroll, creating KING OF CHAVS a fabulously watchable piece of television, a cross between Panorama and a riotous Carry-On movie.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?368319</url></doc>
