<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="369804">
  <docid>369804</docid>
  <title>Milap</title>
  <year>1972</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">12 September 1972</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Ishara, B.R.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kunnu, I.M.</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Sahni, Brij Bhushan</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Denzongpa, Danny</actor>
      <role>Raju</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fazlu (I)</actor>
      <role>Raghunath</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Krishna, Manmohan</actor>
      <role>Judge</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mazumdar, Fatik</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sinha, Shatrughan</actor>
      <role>Ravi/Raju</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Ravi lives a very wealthy lifestyle in India, and since he is the only child his parents grant his every wish. This leads him to every possible bad habit including drugs, alcohol and women. He eventually gets fed up of his lifestyle and re-locates to an isolated hilly region to try and put his life together. The room which he rents is looked after by a woman named Rani, both meet and soon fall in love with each other. Ravi comes to know that Rani is a Sapheran (Snake Charmer) who has been estranged from her lover, Raju, in an earlier life. In this lifetime she has an admirer, also named Raju, who has already asked for her hand from her widower dad, Raghunath, and who is quite displeased when he sees her mingling freely with Ravi. Ravi will also find out that Rani has another admirer, who is also named Raju, but this Raju is over a century old venomous shape-changing snake, who will soon acquire human form, get intimate with Rani and make her his own - and there is no known power on Earth that can stop him.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?369804</url></doc>
