<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="371116">
  <docid>371116</docid>
  <title>Minuscule</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>None</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="France">25 October 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">5</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Giraud, Hélène</director>
    <director>Szabo, Thomas</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Benhamou, Jean-Jacques</producer>
    <producer>Delarue, Philippe</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Giraud, Hélène</writer>
    <writer>Szabo, Thomas</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Although children aren't entomologists, when they take a trip to the country and start roaming through fields and meadows, they do spend an incredible amount of time observing insects. Unlike grownup specialists, our knee-high observers with scabby knees have a peculiar perception of these tiny creatures, readily imagining them in utterly weird, surrealistic situations. Such an offbeat, and often comic vision provides the basis for how MINUSCULE will be showing insects in their day-to-day existence, "at grassroots level," as if we were right there with them. So forget everything you've ever learned about segmented, winged or wingless little creatures, because you're about to discover bug reality. MINUSCULE revolves around the day-to-day existence of insects. Although the series calls to mind a wildlife documentary, it's a documentary in which the insects are presented in burlesque situations, with a fair amount of philosophical contemplation thrown in. You might call it a cross between Tex Avery and Microcosmos, or grassroots slapstick. Or a docu-cartoon series.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?371116</url></doc>
