<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="371137">
  <docid>371137</docid>
  <title>Minutiae of Light</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Gaoiran, Grace</editor>
    <editor>Van Sandt, Michelle (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">8 June 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">13</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Van Sandt, Michelle (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Van Sandt, Michelle (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Van Sandt, Michelle (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Bowsher, Patrick</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bischoff, Joel</actor>
      <role>Ray</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moses, Matthew (I)</actor>
      <role>Victor</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Violet, on a typical night out with Ray, playfully taunts her husband daring him to dare her to do it. He knows she can seduce any man she wants but tonight he is doubtful. Violet loves a challenge and when young, hot Victor walks in the adventure begins. What is supposed to be a night of brief excess creates a stirring in everyone. Ray, always a willing accomplice, wearies of their wild ways. Victor, against his better judgement, falls for a married woman. Something huge moves Violet and sets her off on a journey of self-discovery that could change her whole world. Fearing that which she desires most, she must choose between living on her own terms and the blithe concessions of marriage. Ray is forced to examine his own priorities when Violet leaves town with Victor. Mutual acceptance and understanding prevail when Violet returns to Ray, but are they denying themselves? Can Violet and Ray reconcile their individual longings without hurting each other? A unique perspective on sex, love and understanding.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?371137</url></doc>
