<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="372241">
  <docid>372241</docid>
  <title>Miss Representation</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Siebel Newsom, Jennifer</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Allbright, Taylor</producer>
    <producer>Dietrich, Claire</producer>
    <producer>Scully, Regina Kulik</producer>
    <producer>Brubaker, Debbie</producer>
    <producer>Siebel Newsom, Jennifer</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arcieri, Leila</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cho, Margaret</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Couric, Katie</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dawson, Rosario</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fonda, Jane</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Haggis, Paul</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Liu, Emily (II)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mix, Sheonna</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Newsom, Gavin</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Guess what, America? Sexism still exists in the U.S., despite the fact that women are a majority of our population. "Miss Representation" explores women's underrepresentation in positions of power and influence in America by challenging the limited portrayal of women as encouraged by the mainstream media. On a scale unprecedented in human history, the media communicates cultural values, dictates gender norms, and tells us who we can and cannot be. The collective message that seeps into our subconscious is that women's value lies primarily in youth, beauty and sexuality. As a result, both men and women have a limited understanding of who women are and what women can be, leading to the under-representation of women in key leadership roles and skyrocketing levels of eating disorders, sexual assault, cosmetic surgery, and exploitative pornography. In this climate of dangerous stereotypes and rigid gender roles, women are rarely seen as powerful figures, and it is difficult for the average woman to feel powerful herself. Accompanied by a collaborative social outreach campaign, "Miss Representation" will celebrate women's progress across America and empower our audience to take action for transformative social change.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?372241</url></doc>
