<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="374030">
  <docid>374030</docid>
  <title>Modern Greeks: Mikis Theodorakis</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Pappas, Daniela</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>French</language>
    <language>Greek</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Greece</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Greece">K</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Greece">52</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Anagnostopoulos, Demetres</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Cokinakis, Greg</producer>
    <producer>Georgiou, Vasso</producer>
    <producer>Anagnostopoulos, Demetres</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Carr, John (XVIII)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Theodorakis, Mikis</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Theodorakis' fascination with music began in early childhood; he taught himself to write his first songs without access to musical instruments. In Pyrgos and Patras he took his first music lessons, and in Tripolis, Peloponnese, he formed a choir and gave his first concert at the age of seventeen. On 21st April 1967 a fascist junta (the Regime of the Colonels) took power in putsch. Theodorakis went underground and founded the Patriotic Front. The Colonels published Army decree No 13, which banned playing, and even listening to his music. Theodorakis himself was arrested on 21 August 1967 and jailed for five months. Theodorakis has written more than 1,000 songs and song-cycles, whose melodies have become part of the heritage of Greek music. Theodorakis is well known for his left-wing views, which he has expressed openly (including, notably, during the junta dictatorship). He has campaigned for numerous human rights and peace causes Mikis Theodorakis was not merely a composer and conductor, although he has achieved world fame out of it. Such has been the man's energy that throughout his career he has delved into politics, sometimes radical, sometimes conservative, always controversial. Now, in his 80s, he is still bursting with the need to say and do things. Like a true Greek, his opinions emerge with an accompanying passion for action over thought.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?374030</url></doc>
