<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="374431">
  <docid>374431</docid>
  <title>Moira Orfei amore e fIori</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Zanoli, Luca</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Italian</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Italy">7 June 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Italy">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bevilacqua, Carlo</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bevilacqua, Carlo</writer>
    <writer>Di Loreto, Francesco</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>A documentary about the life of Moira Orfei, Circus Star, and Dolce Vita living legend the Callas of Circus, part of the Italian Iconography. By Moira's own words and her husband's narrative tale, this documentary film reveals the secrets behind the scene of Moira Orfei's 40-year-long success. A convoy of lorries and caravans is driving down a road towards southern Italy. The Moira Orfei circus travels from town to town, to amaze both the young and the old with her dazzling show. Traveling is the secret of circus life and our star is going to introduce us to her world of shimmering costumes, dangerous animals and acrobatics. As Moira reveals the secrets and tricks of the trade, the artists are all busy putting up the big top: a tangle of wires, poles, ropes and tent pegs. Walter Nones, Moira's husband, organizes the work of the others The star talking about her origins in Montenegro, with a gypsy tongue she enchants us with tales of her grandfather priest and of a life full of distant adventures. The Diva/image, created by Dino De' Laurentis, is still the same image that we see on the faded torn bills posted on the walls of our cities and also on the latest new printed ones. The last preparations: all the women are dressed in perfect costumes, the artists are all concentrated and relaxed; and our diva, Moira waits patiently in her stunning costume ready to make her entrance. Before Moira makes her entrance ten girls dressed up as Moira, just like in a film, illuminate the scene with their dresses covered with tiny lights.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?374431</url></doc>
