<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="374799">
  <docid>374799</docid>
  <title>Moment</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Fanara, Toti</editor>
    <editor>Lee, R. Songe</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>new-york-city</keyword>
    <keyword>transgender</keyword>
    <keyword>immigrant</keyword>
    <keyword>love</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">10</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Lee, R. Songe</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Yonder</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Elliott, Lawrence</actor>
      <role>Foreigner</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Three characters meet at a place in NYC by chance. An Asian female, trouble by her citizenship for staying in the US, wonders why and how she wants to leave the land where she was born and come to America. Her yearning to stay becomes her quest for opportunity. A struggling artist seeks for the means of survival. Living in her studio, without heat and comfort. All in the quest of fame one day. One Male, an European with an ugly past, a suffering soul who came to NY to seek his ideal soul mate whom he met on the internet. But She is not really a she, but a beautiful transvestite. He comes to NY in quest of love. They meet in a desolated area, over looking the Statue of Liberty. They all had encountered a dramatic experience in their journey. The artist is frustrated that she can't paint anymore after a rejection from an artist colony. The Asian woman is facing deportation and is ready to commit suicide. The European male met his ideal woman and realized She is a He. Three lives intertwine in a pivotal moment that changed the direction of their lives.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?374799</url></doc>
