<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="375036">
  <docid>375036</docid>
  <title>Momz Hot Rocks</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Perotti, Kate</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>mother</keyword>
    <keyword>rock-music</keyword>
    <keyword>rock-'n'-roll</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby SR</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Perotti, Kate</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Perotti, Kate</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Blades, Joan (I)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Davids, Judy</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fabisch, Sue</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kerrigan, Nancy</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Messner, Paula</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>MOMz HOT ROCKs is a feature length original music documentary on the emergence of mom rock bands, 2004-2007. Turning the rock genre on its belly, they are the first children of the rock and roll generation to be louder than their kids. Introducing Joy Rose, mother of 4, lead singer of Housewives on Prozac and founder of Mamapalooza Festivals, Frump from Texas, Placenta from California, the Mydols Detroit and a comic from Nashville. The concept and reality are humorous, fast paced and intense. Each of the bands is a completely different entity, each member with unique passions, duties and agendas. Being in a band is likened to being in a marriage and these groups of women formed during and after family life. Never mind the laundry, the balancing act only intensifies as tasks increase with both family and blossoming new musical careers. One thing that the documentary exposes is how hard working and dedicated these women are to playing music in order to inspire others to express themselves somehow, all the while maintaining enormous daily responsibility. MOMz HOT ROCKs is both a documentary and a music video, it combines the best of both of these genres and brings the audience an entertaining look into how women--MOMz, take on the world, manage their full lives and make music to rock your socks off.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?375036</url></doc>
