<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="375968">
  <docid>375968</docid>
  <title>Monsieur Truffaut Meets Mr. Hitchcock</title>
  <year>1999</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kurz, Natalie</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Germany">5 August 1999</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Fischer, Robert (IV)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Stewens, Simone</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Fischer, Robert (IV)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chabrol, Claude</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hitchcock, Patricia</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Richard, Jean-Louis</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>When Francois Truffaut approached Alfred Hitchcock in 1962 with the idea of having a long conversation with him about his work and publishing this in book form, he didn't imagine that more than four years would pass before Le Cinéma selon Hitchcock finally appeared in 1966. Not only in France but all over the world, Truffaut's Hitchcock interview developed over the years into a standard bible of film literature. In 1983, three years after Hitchcock's death, Truffaut decided to expand his by now legendary book to include a concluding chapter and have it published as the "Edition définitive". This film describes the genesis of the "Hitchbook" and throws light on the strange friendship between two completely different men. Robert Fischer - a friend of Truffaut and vice director of the Münchner Filmmuseum - spoke for his film with Claude Chabrol, Patricia Hitchcock, Madeleine Morgenstern, Jean-Louis Richard, and Laura Truffaut and came across some rare documents in both Los Angeles and Paris. The centrepieces are the extracts from the original sound recordings of the interview with the voices of Alfred Hitchcock, Francois Truffaut, and Helen Scott - recordings which have never been heard in public before.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?375968</url></doc>
