<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="376620">
  <docid>376620</docid>
  <title>Moonboy</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>surrealism</keyword>
    <keyword>student-film</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">December 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">4</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Calfee, Adam</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Calfee, Adam</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Calfee, Adam</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>A nameless, neglected child becomes increasingly agitated and upset while flipping through the television channels one evening. He is confronted by a seemingly endless barrage of depressing, negative and vile images and slogans. He is offered a glimmer of hope when he comes across what seems to be a home-movie, about a puppy playing in a park, and is devastated when it becomes apparent that it is a part of a larger and not-so-pleasant news item. The boy finally snaps. Pitching his half-drunk glass of milk into the television screen and running into the starlit night as his apathetic mother smokes nonchalantly in the dirty kitchen the news man cheerfully intones, "It's a shame about that cute little puppy." The boy runs frantically through the night, stumbling and crying, until he reaches the edge of a cliff and finds himself staring into the full, glowing, face of the moon, the moon which offers something more than the hurtful existence of this world... the moon which offers just that sort of something which the boy has been looking for.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?376620</url></doc>
