<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="377181">
  <docid>377181</docid>
  <title>More Than 100 Miles: Riding to Cure Diabetes</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kleinheksel, Karen</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>bicycle</keyword>
    <keyword>michigan</keyword>
    <keyword>diabetes</keyword>
    <keyword>ride</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">16 April 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">45</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Scheidel, Thomas</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Scheidel, Thomas</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>A century ride, riding a bicycle 100 miles in a single day, is an accomplishment for any cyclist. To complete a century through the mountains or the desert increases the level of difficulty. And when the people riding are doing it for a great cause you get an event of epic proportions. In 1998 the Juvenile Diabetes Research Foundation held their first Ride for a Cure in Death Valley, California. What started as a small group of committed individuals has swelled to thousands of people at ride sites across the country. Each year these events draw a diverse group of riders. Some people are serious cyclists. Some are the parents of children with diabetes. And some have Type 1 diabetes themselves. The goal of all these riders is to raise money to help find a cure for diabetes. The JDRF ride requires extensive training and on-going fund raising. This film follows cyclists from West Michigan as they prepare for the rides in Asheville, North Carolina and Death Valley, California. We will hear their stories, see their training and join them on Ride Day. We will find out how the Ride is helping to make a cure for diabetes a reality in the near future. For these people, the Ride to Cure Diabetes is more than 100 miles, it's a way to the cure.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?377181</url></doc>
