<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="377916">
  <docid>377916</docid>
  <title>Moscow Swing</title>
  <year>2010</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Slobtsov, Dmitri</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>city-name-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>place-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Russian</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Russia</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Russia">15 December 2010</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Russia">100</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Shmelev, Vadim</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Karyshev, Denis</writer>
    <writer>Shmelev, Vadim</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Dan'kov, Dmitry</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>A young couple (Patrick and Julie) come to Moscow from London. Their trip is connected with Patrick's work. He's being transferred to his company's Russian affiliate, and Julie, as a devoted wife, is prepared to follow her husband to the end of the earth. At first, Jason and Julie don't have any positive feelings about life in a new place. After London, everything seems boring and provincial. And then one day, our heroes meet a Russian couple in a nightclub. They quickly find they have a lot in common, and they have a great time together. They meet up, then again, then a third time. Between them, a strange friendship develops, out of which it's just a simple step to innocent experiments in sensuality... to swinging. Adrenalin, hooliganism, boredom, and alcohol all take their toll. And before you know it, and before they've even noticed themselves, Patrick and Julie cross that boundary, on the other side of which lies: betrayal, endless arguments, recriminations and even (though they couldn't yet imagine such a thing)... death. They still live each other. But will their love survive the coming trials? For what seemed at first like a casual adventure in sex stops becomes anything but casual, when strangers kidnap Julie and demand that Patrick meet a whole host of conditions. As it transpires, conditions which cannot BE met! And he has just three days to do it all.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?377916</url></doc>
