<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="379101">
  <docid>379101</docid>
  <title>Movievoyeur.com</title>
  <year>2000</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Mystery</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>internet-domain-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>sergeant</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">93</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Cook, Bob (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Cook, Bob (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Cook, Bob (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cook, Bob (I)</actor>
      <role>Neighbor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cook, Doris</actor>
      <role>Mrs. White</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Eberwine, Cat</actor>
      <role>Sgt. Kate Blanchard</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ferguson, J. Don</actor>
      <role>Sheriff Ames</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lord, Robyn</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Ames</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Johnny Blanchard (Tom Golden) is a California film maker relocated to the small town of Haynes City, Florida. Johnny has an unusual business. He videotapes people in the privacy of their own home and sells it on the Internet as pornography. Haynes City is run by Sheriff Jed Ames (J. Don Ferguson) and his deputy, Paul Higgins (Patrick Moore). When the Internet Voyeur is tied to a murder case and found dead with a gunshot wound to the head, the Sheriff sees it "as an obvious case of murder suicide." Kate Blanchard (Cathleen Louise), a detective in the Sacramento Children's Crime Unit and sister to the Movie Voyeur, visits Haynes City to claim her brother's body. During her trip, she finds a few holes in the sheriff's investigation. She believes her brother was killed by one of the victims videotaped by her brother, and then framed for the murder. Although Kate is no match for Jed physically, she has a decided advantage during a battle of the minds. Kate turns up several suspects including the town's Preacher and the beautiful Dana Anderson (Leslie Stevens), a nurse who claims to be an exhibitionist who had an unusual love affair with the Movie Voyeur. Comedy upstages this mystery, however, when Deputy Higgins views the voyeur's tapes and can't get the images of the townspeople out of his mind. "I'm not aroused but I'm definitely affected," he confides to Kate during a meeting.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?379101</url></doc>
