<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="379414">
  <docid>379414</docid>
  <title>Mr Ya Miss</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Shah, Vivek (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">U</certificate>
    <certificate country="UK">12</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">2 December 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">136</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Mali, Antara</director>
    <director>Puranik, Satchit</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Desai, Tejaswita</producer>
    <producer>Tevatia, Yogesh</producer>
    <producer>Chainani, Sunil</producer>
    <producer>Srivastava, Sameer</producer>
    <producer>Varma, Ram Gopal</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Mali, Antara</writer>
    <writer>Shekhawat, Raghuvir</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Raikwar, Nitin</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ali, Ishrat</actor>
      <role>Arvind Sen - Sanjay's boss</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dabholkar, Bharat</actor>
      <role>Prakash Malhotra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dabi, Snehal</actor>
      <role>Road Romeo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deo, Ajinkya</actor>
      <role>Bhagwan Shri Shivji</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deshmukh, Ritesh</actor>
      <role>Shekhar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dutta, Divya</actor>
      <role>Loveleen Kapoor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jalali, Faezeh</actor>
      <role>Suzy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mali, Antara</actor>
      <role>Sanjana Patel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puranik, Satchit</actor>
      <role>Police Inspector</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shivdasani, Aftab</actor>
      <role>Sanjay Patel</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Wealthy Gujarati-speaking Sanjay Patel is a self-styled Indian Casanova, who believes in dating and flirting with a wide assortment of young women, and breaking their hearts. He works as an Executive in an Advertisement Firm and is very friendly with a male co-worker, Shekhar, who is exactly Sanjay's opposite when it comes to females. Sanjay flirtatious actions land him in trouble with three women, Loveleen Kapoor, Seema and Rita, he is attacked and is killed. He appears before Bhagwan Shivji and Devi Maa Parvati and he pleads with them to let him return, he is asked to mend his ways before the next Shivratri, and is permitted to return. The next day Sanjay treats this as a bad dream and sets about his usual way. This does not auger well with Parvati and she recommends to Shivji that Sanjay's gender be changed to female in order to enable him to understand and appreciate the fairer sex. The transformation takes place and Sanjay, much to his horror, is transformed to a female. He sets about his normal lifestyle, but finds obstacles everywhere. He confides in Loveleen and Shekhar about his real identity, tells everyone that he is Sanjay's sister, re-names himself Sanjana, and let her take over his job and life - albeit hilariously. He is asked to secure a 3.5 Crore deal with Prakash Malhotra, who is all set to seduce her/him. Then the inevitable happens when alcohol-induced Shekhar and Sanjana get intimate, with Sanjana getting pregnant. Even while Sanjana is attempting to adjust his/her life to this challenge, the Police find the body of a dead male, identify it as that of Sanjay's, and arrest Sanjana for his death. Watch what happens in Court when a visibly pregnant Sanjana must now testify to a disbelieving world about his/her real identity, and may end up facing the death sentence.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?379414</url></doc>
