<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="379724">
  <docid>379724</docid>
  <title>Mr. Hood</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Reay, Richard</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>death</keyword>
    <keyword>revenge</keyword>
    <keyword>blood</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>kidnapping</keyword>
    <keyword>murder</keyword>
    <keyword>friendship</keyword>
    <keyword>violence</keyword>
    <keyword>gunshot</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">3 November 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">8</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>McMorine, David</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>McMorine, David</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>McMorine, David</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lake, Daniel James</actor>
      <role>Mr Hood</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McGowan, Peter Michael</actor>
      <role>The Old Boy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Orme, Philip</actor>
      <role>The young man</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Kidnapped in the dead of night as he walks home from an evening at the pub, Mr Hood finds himself sentenced to death and at the mercy of a professional killer. With no word from the cold hearted assassin and unable to determine what he's done wrong, Mr Hood pleads for his life while the dulcet thuds of his grave being dug by the hit man's assistant, mark the countdown of his last moments of life. While trying to appeal to the ice cold killers better nature to let him go, his pleas fall on deaf ears. His offers of money and anything else he can imagine don't seem to have any effect. The killer, a man who obviously enjoys his work and the power he gets from it seems reluctant to reveal the real reason as to why he is there. The assistant's past and his reason for being there also a mystery as he sits locked into his hood and his fate it seems. Can he bribe, beg and plead his way out, or is his death a prelude to something else? A battle for survival using wits alone, his only hope is to gain his freedom before his grave is finished.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?379724</url></doc>
