<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="380077">
  <docid>380077</docid>
  <title>Mr. Stern, Can I Have Your Autograph?</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bonk, Geoffrey Michel</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">31 July 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">88</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Bonk, Geoffrey Michel</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Grossmann, Amy</producer>
    <producer>Meade, Jaime</producer>
    <producer>Svoboda, Corinne Helene</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bonk, Geoffrey Michel</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bonk, Basil</actor>
      <role>Clayton Stern</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Crozier, Aaron</actor>
      <role>Pimp Daddy Slim</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Eren, Ayse</actor>
      <role>Carrie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Goldkamp, Megan</actor>
      <role>Marsha Zonk/Tiffany Tear</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Heuvelman, Charles</actor>
      <role>Cary Boyle</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Koller, Ian</actor>
      <role>Zonk Brother #1</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>La Fata, Giovanni</actor>
      <role>Jim - News Anchor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moses, Jonas</actor>
      <role>Mickey Donald</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Peterson, Charlie (I)</actor>
      <role>Valet</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Samul, Ryan</actor>
      <role>Frustrated Locker Guy</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Mr. Stern, Can I Have Your Autograph? is the story of Clayton Stern, a paparazzo/ journalist who is unwittingly thrown into a chaotic world of family mystery, deceit, and ill-fame. One day out on the town while looking for tabloid headlines, Clayton meets Marsha Zonk, who offers him some juicy information that sounds too good to be true. Taking a liking to the young woman, Clayton helps her out in covering up a nasty smear campaign against America's favorite teen pop icon. However, the question Clayton must ask himself is whether he is being used as a device to promote the luscious young star. Damon Sanders is the corrupt game show host America tunes into every night. When Damon becomes the subject of a nation-wide scandal, Clayton must fight Damon's attempt to drag Clayton down with him. Clayton becomes caught in a merry-go-round of fascinating characters with secrets and ulterior motives, when all he really wants to do is devote himself to his long-time girlfriend, Carrie. But Carrie, an up-and-coming artist, can't take his smut-filled lifestyle any longer and is threatening to end it all. We also meet Mickey Donald, Clayton's editor, who introduces the added pressure of a deadline. Not only must Clayton get the story to Mickey in time, but he must also make an important decision: should he turn in the sensationalistic story he knows the public wants to hear or the "safer" story that will be much easier to prove? Along the way Clayton encounters a trio of cross-dressing brothers, a large bunny rabbit, and somehow finds himself in jail. An adrenaline-filled story of turmoil and melodrama, Mr. Stern, Can I Have Your Autograph? takes a look at the underground world of celebrity's most famous star behind the stars.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?380077</url></doc>
