<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="380028">
  <docid>380028</docid>
  <title>Mr. Romeo</title>
  <year>1974</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">1974</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Mukherjee, Subhash</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Mukherji, Subodh</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Burman, Rahul Dev</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dutt, Utpal</actor>
      <role>Saxena</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Haksar, Rajan</actor>
      <role>Pal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jaiswal, Rinku</actor>
      <role>Sheetal Batra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Pinchoo</actor>
      <role>Police Commissioner</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Shashi (I)</actor>
      <role>Ramesh Saxena</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kishore, Raj</actor>
      <role>Ratra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Kiran (I)</actor>
      <role>Suresh Saxena</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumari, Lalita</actor>
      <role>Woman in hospital</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nath, Narendra</actor>
      <role>Prem Pal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ranjeet</actor>
      <role>Raja Dada</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>When Pal's son kills a police constable, his best friend, Saxena, the only witness to this murder, comes forward and as a result Pal's son is arrested and charged with murder. Pal pleads with Saxena to change his witness statement, but Saxena refuses to do so, and as a result Pal's son gets convicted and is sentenced to death. Pal swears to avenge his son's death. Years later, Saxena's sons, Ramesh and Suresh, have grown up. While Suresh, the younger son, is serious, studious, and business-minded, Ramesh is quite the opposite. Pal's son, Prem, befriends Suresh and gets him hooked-up with a gorgeous looking girl, and drugs his drinks, thus making him an addict. He falls in love with this girl and wants to get married to her. His parents and Ramesh are opposed to this, and Ramesh goes to the extent of threatening to kill her. Shortly thereafter, the girl is killed, and a drug-induced Suresh immediately believes that Ramesh is the killer. He abducts Ramesh's to-be bride, Sheetal Batra, and takes her with him to his hideout. Now the climax is set between the two brothers - with Pal and Prem watching delightedly - as they know only one will survive, and the other will be arrested by the police, and get the death sentence, thus leaving the Saxena family childless and without any heir.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?380028</url></doc>
