<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="380167">
  <docid>380167</docid>
  <title>Mr. X</title>
  <year>1957</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Bhatt, Nanabhai</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Dutta, N.</composer>
    <composer>Gupta, Chitra</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Agha</actor>
      <role>Murli</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chavan, Padma</actor>
      <role>Singh's assistant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Haksar, Rajan</actor>
      <role>Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Helen (I)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jankidas</actor>
      <role>Jamundas' advocate</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jaywant, Nalini</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Karnataki, Amirbai</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Ashok (I)</actor>
      <role>Ashok Kumar/Mr. X</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Sailesh</actor>
      <role>Detective</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Murad</actor>
      <role>Jamunadas</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pran (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sajjan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ulhas (I)</actor>
      <role>Jamunadas' brother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Walker, Johnny (III)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A wealthy businessman, Jamunadas, is killed by person(s) unknown. The police take up this investigation and are clearly baffled as the killer has left no clues for them to go on. Before they could any further action, Jamunadas' daughter, Nemo, is found dead in her bath-tub. The police suspect that this could be the work of the dreaded Mr. X, and want to question him. Their investigations take them to Rangoon where they are involved in a web of deceit and lies at the hands of one Ashok Kumar. Then they get a clue from a drunk, who claims he saw a woman floating and then being taken away in a driver-less convertible. The police do not know whether to believe this drunk or not. What they do not know is that the killer is in possession of a portion that turns him invisible, and this is not the first time that he has eluded the police through wild-goose chases. It looks like the police, who had nothing to go on in the first place, now are faced with a namely and unseen suspect, who may just be anyone known or unknown to them.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?380167</url></doc>
