<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="380486">
  <docid>380486</docid>
  <title>Mt. Baker's Legendary Banked Slalom</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Castner, Bernadette</editor>
    <editor>Chambers, Josh (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">7 May 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Castner, Bernadette</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Castner, Bernadette</producer>
    <producer>Lubetich, Matthew</producer>
    <producer>Merriman, Craig</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Castner, Bernadette</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Bowen, Grant (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Burt, Tom</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Christy, Barrett</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cummins, Temple</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Haakonsen, Terje</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jealouse, Victoria</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McGuire, Joey (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shackleton, York</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The Legendary Banked Slalom is the longest running snowboarding contest in history. Snowboarders come from around the world to race in this contest; and with an annual snowfall at Mt. Baker of over 1,000 inches per year, riders get a lot more than just a race. The remote location and infamous harsh weather conditions have kept the media from covering this race in any detail - until now. Covering all aspects of the legendary three-day weekend in January, this DVD includes race footage, interviews with highlighted pro riders, behind the scenes with Mt. Baker staff, mountain entertainment, and insane freeriding from Mt. Baker's infamous backcountry. Professional snowboarders showcased include: Terje Haakonsen, Barrett Christy, Temple Cummins, Victoria Jealouse, Joey McGuire, Tom Burt and more. Local musicians Miget Money, Chico's Paradise, and Panhandle Jumpers serve up live music all weekend. Featuring world-class riders with local flare, the Legendary Banked Slalom is the most rider driven, deep snow riding contest around.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?380486</url></doc>
