<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="381157">
  <docid>381157</docid>
  <title>Mulberry Park</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Canonico, Tony</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>street-gang</keyword>
    <keyword>rumble</keyword>
    <keyword>irish</keyword>
    <keyword>italian</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">16</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Canonico, Tony</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Canonico, Eric</producer>
    <producer>Galoob, Jeff</producer>
    <producer>Canonico, Carole</producer>
    <producer>Canonico, Lou</producer>
    <producer>Canonico, Tony</producer>
    <producer>Toland, Coby</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Canonico, Tony</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Andrade, Richard (I)</actor>
      <role>Italian Crew</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Back, Alex</actor>
      <role>Irish Crew</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Butler, Ken (I)</actor>
      <role>Father Corella</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Prinzo, Chris</actor>
      <role>Italian Crew</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Savani, Alex</actor>
      <role>Vinny</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stamboulis, Spero</actor>
      <role>Italian Crew</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Thorne, Rick</actor>
      <role>Mickey</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vallely, Mike</actor>
      <role>Danny</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wexler, Bruce</actor>
      <role>Irish Crew</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In the small town of Mulberry, traditional living takes on a whole new meaning. A town of blue-collar workers and street hoods make-up the neighborhood, split by the old park and connected by the Roman Catholic Church. The Italians inhabit the north and the Irish, the south. Control of the town has changed hands many times over the years but has gone to the Italians for the last half of the century. Power has been determined by a clash of the two gangs that represent both sides. The fight takes place every five years on November 1, All Saints Day, the Catholic holy day celebrating all the saints. Vinny Saciani and Danny O'Brian grew up together as friends through school, but in Mulberry any ties with those from the other side of the park is diminished by high school. Vinny and Danny were born leaders so when the time came, both were chosen to head up the two factions. The two had become sworn enemies, not by choice but by the duties given to them. Over the past hundred years this ritualistic brawl has taken place and been accepted by the town. Although times have changed both sides stick to the rules that have been laid down before them and avoid the use of knives or guns. This year things change when two of their guys take things to far. The town suffers a loss always feared but never expected and it's up to Vinny and Danny to decide where things go from here.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?381157</url></doc>
