<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="381644">
  <docid>381644</docid>
  <title>Muqaddar Ka Badshaah</title>
  <year>1990</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Tatineni, Rama Rao</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Shah, Viju</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anand, Suparna</actor>
      <role>Geeta</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Asrani</actor>
      <role>Dhamdilal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Azmi, Shabana</actor>
      <role>Advocate Sharda Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Choti, Mohan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ghanshyam</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Kader (I)</actor>
      <role>Inspector Gulshan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khanna, Vinod</actor>
      <role>Naresh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kher, Anupam</actor>
      <role>Vijay Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maruti, Guddi</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Gidwani</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nischol, Navin</actor>
      <role>DSP Rathod</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, Amrish</actor>
      <role>Vikral Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sapru, Tej</actor>
      <role>Manik Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sheikh, Aashif</actor>
      <role>Ashok Singh</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Naresh is union leader, and is felicitated for bravery shown in stopping an out of control bus, full of children. Naresh continues to struggle for the worker's rights, and soon becomes a thorn on the side of his employer, Vikral Singh, and is wrongfully accused of several crimes and produced before the courts. All the accusations are overturned by the courts due to his lawyer, Sharda, who is the wife of Public Prosecutor, Vijay Sing, a close friend of Vikral's. Naresh's sister falls in love with Vijay's son, Ashok, and both want to get married, but Vijay humiliates Naresh at the behest of Vikral, and asks him to be wealthy enough, and then bring this proposal. Naresh does so, however, he is again rejected, as Vikral would like Ashok to marry his daughter, Rajni. Things take an unexpected turn when the DSP Rathod's son is kidnapped by Naresh, and the police launch a manhunt for him, on one hand, and Ashok is accused of killing Rajni on the other. Will Sharda be able to assist Naresh and Ashok this time?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?381644</url></doc>
