<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="382263">
  <docid>382263</docid>
  <title>Mushka Water</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Lowe, Cameron (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">10 September 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Lowe, Cameron (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Wolf, Johann (V)</producer>
    <producer>McLaughlin-Strassman, Lisa</producer>
    <producer>More, Camilla</producer>
    <producer>Lowe, Cameron (I)</producer>
    <producer>Wolf, Johann (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Lowe, Cameron (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Clark, Bryan (VII)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bilenkij, Ljupka</actor>
      <role>Bosnian Girl</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brezina, Oto</actor>
      <role>Bosnian Shop Keeper</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Clark, Tara (III)</actor>
      <role>Boy's Mother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cohen, Noel (III)</actor>
      <role>Bosnian Child 3</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Frederick, Alison</actor>
      <role>Sutton's Blind Date</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hooey, Bill</actor>
      <role>Plumber</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kemp, Cameron</actor>
      <role>Bosnian Child 1</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kemp, Rhett</actor>
      <role>Bosnian Child 2</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kirshman, Armand</actor>
      <role>Young Boy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lowe, Hana</actor>
      <role>Girl on Beach</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mandrick, Natalie</actor>
      <role>Marina</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McAtee, Robert</actor>
      <role>Sutton</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tsacrios, Frank J.</actor>
      <role>Landlord</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vietor, Sananda</actor>
      <role>Fortimbras</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vietor, Sebastian</actor>
      <role>Boy on Beach</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wolf, Johann (V)</actor>
      <role>Bosnian Street Transient</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A mysterious spring is hidden deep in the mountains of Bosnia, named Mushka Voda, which translates as "Men's Water". Locals swear that when a man drinks from the spring he will become more virile. Director Cameron Lowe takes this Eastern European fable and weaves it into a unique and surprising story of a young man's rite of passage into the world of passion and love. The story starts in the local village of Brateljevici where an old man has been driven insane by his addiction to the famed water - and the lack of it. The spring, long dried up, is rumored to now be flowing again and old Ibrahim races maniacally to its source. Through a cosmic upheaval set off by Ibrahim this special water gushes deep through the center of the earth to appear in the bathroom pipes of one single apartment in Los Angeles, California. As the wisdom goes, 'the water always finds the man who needs it most'. The tenant of this apartment, Fortimbras Sangster, unwittingly gets a taste of the water and quickly becomes addicted to its properties. He feels more alive, more charismatic and attractive - this overrides the fact that he can only extract this intoxicating elixir from his toilet. Beautiful, exotic Marina is immediately attracted to Fortimbras, who is perplexed and confused by her attentions. Addicted to both the Mushka Water and Marina's beguiling sensual presence he opens up and allows himself to be led through the labyrinth of the heart. Clinging to obsessive love and in the grips of the water's addiction, Fortimbras is forced to make the most important choice of his life.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?382263</url></doc>
