<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="383194">
  <docid>383194</docid>
  <title>My 1st Time: Tribeca Film Festival</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <editors>
    <editor>Coda, Daniel</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Reality-TV</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">3 May 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <producers>
    <producer>Marton, John (II)</producer>
    <producer>Mann, Jesse Zook</producer>
    <producer>Gerstenbluth, Beth</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Elie, Lolis Eric</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Graves, Duane</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Meeks, Justin</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>We follow 3 first time filmmakers to the Tribeca Film Festival who are looking to break into the film business with their hearts on their sleeves. Our Characters Are: Justin Meeks from Austin Texas who shot his movie The WIldman of the Navidad for next to nothing stealing workers from his dads steel company to work on his film. He's out to break into the movie business with his homage to 70's horror flicks. Lolis Elie from New Orleans Louisiana who has a movie called Faubourg Treme about how the civil rights movement started in the 6th ward 100 years before Martin Luther King. Lolis is working to get the message to NY that New Orleans is irreplaceable and important... and is in dire need of help. Nina Paley - Who created a feature length animation over 5 years in her 350 square foot Hells Kitchen apartment. Her film Sita Sings the Blues is about an ancient Indian epic, and her own story about being dumped by her ex-husband over email. She's out to get her film out to her home town of NYC and to see what the box office gods have to say about her movie.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?383194</url></doc>
