<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="383389">
  <docid>383389</docid>
  <title>My Blood My Compromise</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>de Stani, Nuhi</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>kosova</keyword>
    <keyword>rape</keyword>
    <keyword>kosovo</keyword>
    <keyword>serbia</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Albanian</language>
    <language>Serbo-Croatian</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Hungary">19 April 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 June 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>de Stani, Nuhi</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>de Stani, Nuhi</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>de Stani, Nuhi</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Brennan, Michael (XIII)</composer>
    <composer>Trentacosta, Joe</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dellova, Kadri</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Demaçi, Adem</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ivanovich, Oliver</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kosumi, Bajram</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kurti, Albin</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Malcolm, Noel</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sava, Father</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sejdiu, Fatmir</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>My Blood My Compromise reveals the horror of President Slobodan Milosevic's pursuit of power during the 1998-99 Kosova war. Milosevic's strategic warfare includes cruel forms of physical abuse devised to ultimately destroy the mind, identity, and posterity of its victims. Torture, murder, rape and other atrocities, committed against women and children in particular, work within the design of a military strategy that fights its most lethal battles after the dust settles. This method deliberately strikes the family nucleus in order to systematically destroy the region's society and culture with centripetal force. My Blood My Compromise demystifies these gruesome tactics within the province of Kosova. Filmmaker Nuhi de Stani illuminates the immediacy of the peoples' suffering, and the ongoing nature of their struggles in Kosova. Eight years after UN's intervention, the women and children are still the ones suffering and Kosova's final status remains in question. The documentary's stark honesty results from de Stani's personal endeavor to find understanding in an area and situation riddled with the scars of political greed. The film unveils the continuing human rights violations evidenced from testimonials, key political figures, historians and activists. The failures and possible successes of the United Nations Mission in Kosova underscores a contemporary and universal relevance.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?383389</url></doc>
