<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="383446">
  <docid>383446</docid>
  <title>My Brother Called King</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Tvrdik, Jonathan</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 February 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Tvrdik, Jonathan</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Billings, Drew</producer>
    <producer>Purcell, Jon</producer>
    <producer>Tvrdik, Jonathan</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Purcell, Jon</writer>
    <writer>Tvrdik, Jonathan</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Bushon, Dustin</composer>
    <composer>Dapose (II)</composer>
    <composer>Tvrdik, Jonathan</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Aagesen, Kathryn</actor>
      <role>KP Wardyn</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Farrell, Michael (XI)</actor>
      <role>Dr. Saqueton</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hardie, Brian</actor>
      <role>Brandon Dominguez</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hutson, Bill</actor>
      <role>Mr. Willits</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Purcell, Jon</actor>
      <role>Thom Wardyn</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Thom is intensely arrogant; mysteriously driven. When shredding any number of his opponents in the advertising world, Thom will reveal nothing of his past and only the essentials of his future. Creative director. Screenwriter. Musician. Mover and shaker. He's hard-pressed to even let on that he has a wife and an older sister with severe learning disabilities who lives with him. It isn't until he is delivered the devastating news that he has pancreatic cancer that Thom is forced to slow down and take stock of his life. It is an uncomfortable and alien place for Thom and he finds that it couldn't come at a more inconvenient time: the night he is to escort his despised sister to her art class. At first brushing off his news and the introspection it brings, Thom fights hard to ignore his fears and mild hallucinations he suffers as a result of his condition. Unfortunately for Thom and his carefully crafted facade, the descent into mental collapse overtakes him and he is compelled to come to terms with 28 years of self-loathing in one night in front of a classroom full of strangers.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?383446</url></doc>
