<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="383732">
  <docid>383732</docid>
  <title>My Eyes Were Fresh: The Life and Photographs of John Gutmann</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Dorsky, Nathaniel</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby SR</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">2006</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Germany">2006</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Reed, Jane Levy</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Phillips, Sandra (VI)</producer>
    <producer>Reed, Jane Levy</producer>
    <producer>Reed, Jane Levy</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>My Eyes Were Fresh: The Life and Photographs of John Gutmann chronicles the life and work of one of the seminal figures of twentieth-century photography. Gutmann, who was part of the German Jewish diaspora that helped transform American intellectual and artistic life starting in the 1930s, had a singular gift for creating powerful and often iconic images with compelling emotional content. His visual embrace of the cultural and social landscape of his adopted country is richly detailed in his work and in this seductive film. The film allows Gutmann to present his own story as well as the context for his works through a series of six interviews that resonate with his personality. He narrates the story of his early fascination with art and his almost accidental introduction to photography as a powerful medium. He also outlines the many decades he spent practicing his craft as the stormy "American Century" unfolded and his new home emerged as a powerful center of culture. Gutmann served as a vibrant link between the European modernism of the early twentieth-century and the burgeoning artistic culture of the San Francisco Bay Area in the second half of the century. His influence can be seen today in the works of many celebrated photographs. My Eyes Were Fresh profiles an artist and teacher who made a lasting contribution to the history of modern photography. It is also a vivid portrait of the development of a unique artistic sensibility one born out of the distinctive milieu of modern German-Jewish culture in Breslau and Berlin and shaped by the politics, the popular culture, and the emerging native modernism of the United States.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?383732</url></doc>
