<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="384434">
  <docid>384434</docid>
  <title>My Martyrdom in Every Case</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>German</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Germany">35</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Wolfshohl, Jeff</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Sabellek, Susanna</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Wolfshohl, Jeff</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anderson, Kim (VIII)</actor>
      <role>Sid</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fischer, Nina (III)</actor>
      <role>Young Woman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wolfshohl, Jeff</actor>
      <role>Garv</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Garv and Sid are good friends meeting for coffee. Both in their twenties, Sid is soon returning to his hometown of Berlin, while Garv is staying in his new hometown Cologne. They discuss their male prowess and their experience in the dating world. Sid is concentrating his thoughts on a new co-worker, where Garv is concentrating on the image of a previous customer. Garv begins to have his first, in a continuation of flashbacks, which particularly visualizes a just-talked-about dating experience. As he misrepresents it to Sid, the waitress returns in pushing their exit. A previous fling of Sid, unknowingly to Garv, she is very rude to them both. They walk across the street to another café, which faces the previous one. The ex-fling waitress sees their move and turns in disgust to her co-worker, and begins ranting about Sid and men in general. A good-looking waiter takes their order for more coffee in the new café, igniting Garv into a brief complaining session about dating men. Sid tries to console him by sparking a conversation with the waiter, and advertising Garv as a personal trainer in English who offers private lessons. After getting the waiter's phone number, the ex-fling marches to the table of their new café and begins to yell at Sid. Stunned, moments of silence are attempted to be solved with Garv's unwanted interjection. Garv leaves them, walking over to the counter to get the good-looking waiter to agree to go out that night.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?384434</url></doc>
