<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="385498">
  <docid>385498</docid>
  <title>Mystery Mardi Gras Shipwreck</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>high-definition</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">31 July 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">52</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="USA">52</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <writers>
    <writer>Mooring, Robyn</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>A mysterious sinking, a group of dedicated scientists and technicians and a 200 year old shipwreck have all collided in the Gulf of Mexico. Four thousand feet below the choppy seas the remains of a 19th century shipwreck lie in wait and a month long expedition has been mounted to uncover her secrets. This is the deepest underwater archaeological project ever attempted in the Gulf of Mexico. And it's a race against time to uncover the Mardi Gras shipwreck and solve the mystery. The Department of Oceanography at Texas A&amp;M University has assembled a world class team of underwater archaeologists from A&amp;M and the Minerals Management Service and submersible pilots from Veolia ES Special Service to tease the secrets from a buried hulk lying deep in the Gulf of Mexico. The 4.8 million dollar expedition has been over 2 years in the making and the team has less than three weeks to recover as many artifacts as possible from the site. Using a state of the art remotely operated vehicle the pilots will retrieve items as small as Spanish coins and as large as a 950 pound cannon. All in hopes of putting a name to this shipwreck and writing a new chapter in the maritime history of the Gulf of Mexico.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?385498</url></doc>
