<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="386775">
  <docid>386775</docid>
  <title>NASCAR: Unauthorized</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Antonik, Michael</editor>
    <editor>Tweedie, Jared</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">15 October 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Bouson, Michael</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>McKenzie, David (III)</producer>
    <producer>Sharratt, Paul</producer>
    <producer>Thomas, Brad (II)</producer>
    <producer>Caligiuri, Patrick</producer>
    <producer>Aguilar, Carlos (VIII)</producer>
    <producer>Bouson, Michael</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bouson, Michael</writer>
    <writer>Caligiuri, Patrick</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Ross, John (XVIII)</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>NASCAR: Unauthorized takes you out of the bleachers and into the driver's seat in the fastest, most hair-raising sport in America. Stock-car racing was born on the dusty dirt tracks of North Carolina. It has become the new national pastime that has exploded into a multi-billion dollar industry. NASCAR: Unauthorized will showcase young drivers who risk everything, including their lives, in pursuit of the checkered flag. Ever wonder what is racing through the mind of a driver when he is at the helm of a 700 horsepower machine? This edge-of-your-seat documentary answers those questions. Race teams are always in hot pursuit to reach the winner's circle. A hand-picked team of automotive experts reveal the trade secrets of stock-car engineering that helps racers grasp the competitive edge on the track. Today's super-speedways are some of the most modern and technically advanced sporting arenas in the world. NASCAR: Unauthorized features every dangerous bend and so close to the cars that you can feel the heat off the hood. NASCAR: Unauthorized is an hour filled with heart-pounding, fender-rubbing action, using some of the most captivating imagery caught on camera and interviews with stock-car racing's leading experts!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?386775</url></doc>
