<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="387067">
  <docid>387067</docid>
  <title>NWF Kids Pro Wrestling: The Untold Story</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>wrestling</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">25 October 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">84</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Crossen, Shawn</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Crossen, Shawn</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ackermann, Michael</actor>
      <role>Interviewee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Clauson, Jason</actor>
      <role>Interviewee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Crossen, Shawn</actor>
      <role>Interviewee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hanson, Chris (XI)</actor>
      <role>Interviewee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hoffman, John (IX)</actor>
      <role>Interviewee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Johnson, Leslie (III)</actor>
      <role>Interviewee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kelsey, Matt</actor>
      <role>Interviewee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lane, Chuck</actor>
      <role>Interviewee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Travis (III)</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>NWF KIDS PRO WRESTLING - THE UNTOLD STORY is an in-depth look at the history of a league that actually existed during the 1980's. Learn how a very talented and ambitious 14-year-old kid did the impossible task of running his very own professional wrestling league during a time when doing such a thing was simply unheard of. Predating the emergence of "backyard wrestling", NWF Kids Pro Wrestling was a much different venture. These young kids not only got inside the ring and wrestled, but they actually produced their own cable TV shows, promoted their own "live" spectator events, and ran the league from behind the scenes. Now twenty years later, the kids who were the creative force behind the NWF have all come back together to share their amazing story. Witness the amazing footage from the leagues extensive video history, along with great stories and recollections from past NWF superstars. From the birth of it's creation in 1984 on bed mattresses, to the successful cable TV show and live events, to a final act of sheer betrayal.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?387067</url></doc>
