<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="388230">
  <docid>388230</docid>
  <title>Nagai sanpo</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Japanese</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Japan</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Japan">December 2006</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Canada">30 August 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Japan">136</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="Canada">136</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Okuda, Eiji</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Uono, Mark</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Momoyama, Sakura</writer>
    <writer>Okuda, Eiji</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Inamoto, Hibiki</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harada, Kiwako</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kiuchi, Midori</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Matsuda, Shota</actor>
      <role>Wataru</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ogata, Ken</actor>
      <role>Matsutaro Yasuda</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ohashi, Tomokazu</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Okuda, Eiji</actor>
      <role>Detective Iwai</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tsugawa, Masahiko</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Matsutaro Yasuda, a retired girl's High School Principal who has lost his wife to alcoholism and is forsaken by his Daughter, moves to an old apartment in a country town. Yasuda, at his new address, meets a little five years old girl who lives next door. Sachi, the little girl, clenches on an iron fence at the apartment. All alone, she is gazing into the distance. Angel's wings made of cardboard are on her back. She is barefoot and wears a summer dress in spite of it being winter. On her leg there are scratches and bruises. Yasuda speaks to Sachi but she does not smile or say a word. When night falls, violent voices can be heard from next door to the mother and her lover echoing in Yasuda's room almost every night. Yasuda blocked out his emotions. He didn't want to hear or see anything. However, little by little something moved his emotions we can call it passion. When he looked into the little girl's eyes, which are also lacking in emotion, something seemed to overlap his wounded heart. "Have you ever seen a blue sky? Where clouds appear like cotton candy and a white bird is flying high?" "Would you like to walk with me?" Yasuda and Sachi begin their long walk.... During their walk, the two meet a young boy named Wataru at a small desolate train station. Wataru seems to be easygoing. However, he is also lonely and holds an empty feeling in his heart. The passing Wataru joins the two on their journey but the trip goes in an unexpected direction when one day Sachi begins to open her heart to Yasuda and Wataru. Cardboard Angel wings begin to fly toward a real sky.......</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?388230</url></doc>
