<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="390986">
  <docid>390986</docid>
  <title>Naturally Intense</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>DeGennaro, Francis Xavier</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Sport</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 June 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>DeGennaro, Francis Xavier</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Richardson, Kevin D.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Richardson, Kevin D.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Sci, LaFrae Olivia</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Richardson, Kevin D.</actor>
      <role>Himself- Professional Bodybuilder</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Champion Natural Bodybuilder, Kevin Richardson's video, Naturally Intense, shows the high intensity workouts and principles that enabled him to transform himself from a 125lb teen into a 225lb ripped to shreds natural bodybuilding champion- without the use of steroids or drugs of any kind! Training only 20 minutes three times a week Kevin has been able to forge a world-class physique while still maintaining a balance in life. You don't need to spend countless hours in the gym, to achieve your goals, and Kevin's Naturally Intense approach allows for bodybuilding to truly be a healthy and wholesome pursuit. Having successfully trained hundreds over the past 16 years, he is truly the modern guru of natural bodybuilding. Along with his workout partner, future fitness sensation and drummer extraordinaire, LaFrae Sci, you will see exactly how Kevin trains. No camera tricks, no out takes, just pure hardcore training that show some pretty fantastic examples of pushing it to the limit and beyond. The incredible weights lifted and the phenomenal physiques prove without a doubt that you do not need drugs or special supplements to realize the upper levels of human physical development.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?390986</url></doc>
