<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="391593">
  <docid>391593</docid>
  <title>Naya Jigar</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Madhu, K.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Telugu</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Balasekaran</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ahmed, K.N. Altaf</producer>
    <producer>Basha, G. Jaffer</producer>
    <producer>Sheriff, A.S.</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Sharma, Shiv Kumar (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Akkineni, Nagarjuna</actor>
      <role>Arvind</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chawla, Bhoomika</actor>
      <role>Yuvrani Padmini</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rami Reddy</actor>
      <role>Pratap Singh</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Arvind lives a wealthy lifestyle in India along with his mom, dad, sister, Amritha, maternal grandma, an aunt, uncle, and cousin, Gautam. He has two very close friends, who he considers family, namely Chandrashekhar alias Chandru, the son of Judge Rajshekhar, and Krishnaprasad alias Krupa. Amritha and Chandru are in love with each other and are expected to get married soon. When a prank goes awry, the trio get into a dispute with Pratap Singh and his men, and must re-locate to Mussorie in order to avoid being arrested by the Police. It is here they work as apprentices with Krupa's brother-in-law, Bhawani Shankar, who gets a contract to paint and refurbish a palace in Pratapgarh. The crew attend there and this is where Arvind gets to meet Yuvrani Padmini. Circumstances force both of them to get married to each other, much to the chagrin of Chandru, who knows that Padmini does not love Arvind and is merely marrying him to avenge her family's humiliation and create a rift between the friends. Shortly after the marriage, Amritha's Saree is set aflame and Arvind is nearly killed in a bullock-cart race accident. Chandru blames Padmini and bitter acrimony results so much so that the past is re-visited and Arvind is blamed for killing Chandru's younger and mute brother, Chhotu. A confrontation ensues between Arvind and Chandru - and both men know that only one of them is fated to walk back home.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?391593</url></doc>
