<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="394127">
  <docid>394127</docid>
  <title>New Legends</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>VideoGame</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>video-game</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2 March 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Chin, Justin</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Chin, Justin</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Manthei, Kevin</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Auberjonois, Rene</actor>
      <role>Topo, Kang</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Boen, Earl</actor>
      <role>Boo, Tracker, Wounded Soldier</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chin, Feodor</actor>
      <role>Sun Soo, Flyer, Prison Guard #1</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Guest, Kim Mai</actor>
      <role>Mai Chan, Jen Chi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Horan, James</actor>
      <role>Talos, DS #2, Kuun</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jackson, Roger (VI)</actor>
      <role>Xao Gon, Zhang</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>James, Charity</actor>
      <role>Chen, Launch Voice</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McGaharn, Michael</actor>
      <role>Tao Soo, SW #1, Yang</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tabori, Kristoffer</actor>
      <role>Roa Khan, Prison Captain, Medic</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Towles, Tom</actor>
      <role>Bradley</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>West, Don (III)</actor>
      <role>Yen Soo, Farmer, Gate Guard</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>For more than a century, the great kingdom of China had been under siege. Torn apart by skirmishes and feuds between warring clans and two-faced bureaucrats reaping the benefits of war, China was ready for the dawn of a new era. Roa Khan arose the midst the chaos to unite the Middle Kingdom, claiming the throne of China's new Emperor and bringing peace to the war-torn nation. Just as quickly as Roa Khan brought salvation, an evil emerged so powerful, it was rumored to be forged straight from the depths of hell. Xao Gon bitter that China had allowed it's enemies to grow strong at its broaders, formed an alliance with a demon from the Otherworld and came fourth as the leader of a new revolution. Shattering every dream of a peaceful China, Xao Gon executed Roa Khan and begin his attack on each clan territory. Led by his five demon-spawned offspring, the clans fell one by one their warriors slaughtered their lands captured. Under his rule, the Son of Heaven, Lord of Ten Thousand Years, China will be great again. In the far reaches of China, the Soo Kingdom remains one of the ancient clans still standing, all of its allies destroyed, all of China's hope resting on its castle walls.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?394127</url></doc>
