<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="395123">
  <docid>395123</docid>
  <title>Nice Knowing You</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>McGinley, Lawrence</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">21</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Burke, Joe (IV)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Paratore, Stephen</producer>
    <producer>Pineda, Marie</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Burke, Joe (IV)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Goldman, David (IV)</actor>
      <role>Married Man</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Heine, Josh</actor>
      <role>Zach</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Herlinger, Karl (II)</actor>
      <role>Jerry</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McNearney, Kathleen</actor>
      <role>Married Woman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Siegel, Jake</actor>
      <role>Scotty</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>NICE KNOWING YOU is a story about three friends on the last night of their lease in the city. Having just graduated college and now preparing for the 'real world', Scotty, Zach, and Zach's girlfriend Leah return home after one last night out. Zach, having drank too much, passes out early, leaving Scotty and Leah alone to do the remainder of the late night packing. Slowly the evening picks up as Scotty and Leah decide to toss out their old smelly sofa that has seen better days. After an exciting struggle of having to get the heavy sofa outside, they soon find themselves locked out of their apartment, left to figure out another way back in. Eventually, after locating a phone to call an emergency locksmith, they find themselves waiting on the very couch they tossed out, connecting with one another in a way they never have before. What began as just a quiet night of boxing up their lives slowly transitions into one of adventure, discovery, and the realization of what the two of them will miss most.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?395123</url></doc>
