<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="395707">
  <docid>395707</docid>
  <title>Niflheim: Blood &amp; Bullets</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Iwaszko, Nathaniel</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>War</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Iwaszko, Nathaniel</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Cooper, David (XVIII)</producer>
    <producer>Alexander, Joanne</producer>
    <producer>Alexander, Nick (II)</producer>
    <producer>Iwaszko, Nathaniel</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Iwaszko, Nathaniel</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Koikas, Andrew</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Davis, Troy (IV)</actor>
      <role>John Wodan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gannon, Jeff (II)</actor>
      <role>Zachariah Thunaer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hilton, Kaela</actor>
      <role>Michelle Eir</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McIntyre, Liam</actor>
      <role>Christopher Bragi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Phillips, Amos</actor>
      <role>Kenneth Tyr</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Podstawek, Jakob</actor>
      <role>Jason Hermod</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Poppi, Christian</actor>
      <role>Ryan Vali</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Schiopu, John</actor>
      <role>Dead Soldier</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In a world plunged into the darkness of a global conflict, an international draft has occurred for any person over the age of eighteen. Sent into the depth of battle with barely enough training to last an hour, soldier after soldier is lost, but the draft continues. The Aesir, a squad of new recruits and battle hardened veterans alike, take the war one day at a time, doing their best to survive the massacre and live to see tomorrow. Jason Hermod, a recently drafted private feels no different. He hopes to finish out his days and return home, having done his duty. But when Jason gets word that his younger sister, a fellow draftee, has been lost in the depth of the jungle, he is wrecked with guilt. Sargent John Wodan, his commanding officer, makes sure his squad is in charge of the rescue mission. And so begins Operation Baldur. The mission is simple; locate the lost squad, rescue survivors and return to camp. But when the squad begin their long trek through the jungle, it becomes clear that there is something watching, something waiting, something wicked.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?395707</url></doc>
