<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="396144">
  <docid>396144</docid>
  <title>Night Without Justice</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Weiner, Peter Kennedy</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>History</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>prison</keyword>
    <keyword>kidnapping</keyword>
    <keyword>detective</keyword>
    <keyword>murder</keyword>
    <keyword>historical</keyword>
    <keyword>violence</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">9 February 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">21</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Azzarello, Michael A.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Azzarello, Alan</producer>
    <producer>Azzarello, Michael A.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Azzarello, Michael A.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Friberg, Craig M.</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Avigdori, Jonathan</actor>
      <role>Mobster</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>David, Brian (I)</actor>
      <role>Reed Vetterli</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Duby, Jeff</actor>
      <role>Harold Thurmond</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Durham, John</actor>
      <role>Brooke Hart</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Edington, Jerod</actor>
      <role>Jack Holmes</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fox, Steve (V)</actor>
      <role>Vigilante</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kamerman, Ty</actor>
      <role>Mob Member</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kepner, Thomas James</actor>
      <role>Sheriff</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McEachern, Michael (II)</actor>
      <role>Mob Member</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Riley, John (III)</actor>
      <role>Sheriff Emig</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Smith, Adam Neal</actor>
      <role>FBI Agent Anderson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>von der Lieth, John G.</actor>
      <role>Mob Member</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>On November 27, 1933 in San Jose, California, Jack Holmes and Harold Thurmond lye in their cold cells in the county jail. Beyond their walls an angry mob starts to collect just outside of the barricades, Jack and Harold know they are seeking revenge for the killing of Brooke Hart, a beloved youth and son of a wealthy town department store owner. Inside the prison, FBI Agent Vetterli and Sheriff Emig stand ground with their men, doing whatever it takes to protect the prisoners from the angry mob numbering in the hundreds. Slowly the mob grows into the thousands, surrounding the jail and becoming more violent. The officers inside prepare themselves for the worst, armed with tear gas grenades, sawed off shotguns, and a machine gun until other police forces arrive. Amidst the chaos, Agent Vetterli know this might be his last chance to get a signed confession from the men. He and Sheriff Emig question Thurmond about the abduction of Brooke Hart and his violent murder. Harold recounts the night of the brutal event. He tells of his relationship with Jack Holmes, the mastermind behind the entire plan. Thurmond insists that Brooke was never supposed to be killed. His death was the work of Holmes when he struck him over the head with a 22 -pound concrete block. A remorseful Thurmond breaks down in tears as he talks about his involvement. Meanwhile, the vigilante starts to wear down the officers at the front and it's getting harder to hold them back as they run out of tear gas.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?396144</url></doc>
