<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="396200">
  <docid>396200</docid>
  <title>Night of Henna</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Franklin, Sharon</editor>
    <editor>Sievertson, J.D.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>asia</keyword>
    <keyword>south-asian</keyword>
    <keyword>henna</keyword>
    <keyword>arranged-marriage</keyword>
    <keyword>pakistani-immigrant</keyword>
    <keyword>wedding</keyword>
    <keyword>indo-pak</keyword>
    <keyword>sacrifice</keyword>
    <keyword>2000s</keyword>
    <keyword>immigrant</keyword>
    <keyword>pakistan</keyword>
    <keyword>usa</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">22 April 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">92</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Zee, Hassan</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Jones, Jeffrey (VI)</producer>
    <producer>Meir, Marc</producer>
    <producer>Gentile, Alessandro</producer>
    <producer>Zee, Hassan</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Zee, Hassan</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Gousis, George</composer>
    <composer>Sabah, Chebbi</composer>
    <composer>Water Music</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carlin, Joyce</actor>
      <role>Teacher</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carlin, Nancy (II)</actor>
      <role>Sue</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chesser, Poni</actor>
      <role>Rafia</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Karim, Reef</actor>
      <role>Baboo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Pooja (I)</actor>
      <role>Hava</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Marker, Craig</actor>
      <role>Justin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shah, Azhar</actor>
      <role>Bashir</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shankar, Girja</actor>
      <role>Abdul</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tayeb, Suhail</actor>
      <role>Salman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Walsh, Kevin Michael</actor>
      <role>Matt</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>After nine years spent learning "how to be a good Pakistani daughter" from the grandparents who raised her, Hava (Pooja Kumar) is excited to touch down at San Francisco International Airport and reunite with her mother, her cab-driving father, and, to a lesser extent, her surly, fully-Americanized younger brother. Thrilled by the new culture that surrounds her, Hava hopes to take advantage of opportunities less available to women in Pakistan, including enrolling in college classes and working part-time at a coffee shop. Though she manages to achieve both goals, behind her father's back of course, it seems Night of Henna is not headed toward the realization of Hava's humble dreams: the opening scene flashes forward to reveal preparations for her very traditional, very prearranged wedding day. This bit of information also casts a shadow over Hava's tentative romance with Justin (Craig Marker), a preppy musician who encourages her to explore her individuality. - After nine years spent learning "how to be a good Pakistani daughter" from the grandparents who raised her, Hava (Pooja Kumar) is excited to touch down at San Francisco International Airport and reunite with her mother, her cab-driving father, and, to a lesser extent, her surly, fully-Americanized younger brother. Thrilled by the new culture that surrounds her, Hava hopes to take advantage of opportunities less available to women in Pakistan, including enrolling in college classes and working part-time at a coffee shop. Though she manages to achieve both goals, behind her father's back, of course, it seems Night of Henna is not headed toward the realization of Hava's humble dreams: the opening scene flashes forward to reveal preparations for her very traditional, very prearranged wedding day. This bit of information also casts a shadow over Hava's tentative romance with Justin (Craig Marker), a preppy musician who encourages her to explore her individuality. (SF Bay Gaurdian)</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?396200</url></doc>
