<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="397077">
  <docid>397077</docid>
  <title>Nine Days of Hell</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Stitt, Martin</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>number-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">2002</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">29 March 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">92</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Stitt, Martin</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kunze, Julia (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Qureshi, Farhan</writer>
    <writer>Stitt, Martin</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Ecclestone, Dan</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Allen, Kate (V)</actor>
      <role>Jenny Taylor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hawkins, Silas</actor>
      <role>Dr. Dalkran Vukodlakevic</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hooper, Laura (I)</actor>
      <role>Nina Brown</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jones, Gareth (XIX)</actor>
      <role>Nadeem Kahn</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Larwood, Marek</actor>
      <role>Greg Galloway</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Messing, Martina</actor>
      <role>Dr. Marion Eissenberg</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pike, Iain</actor>
      <role>Piers Mortimer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Reynolds, Gary (IV)</actor>
      <role>Jakob Bicker</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Watson, Benjamin (I)</actor>
      <role>Michel Hawkin</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Following the death of a prominent city investor detective constable Greg Galloway is teamed up with Nadeem Kahn to look into a possible lead within the prestigious investment bank 'Bernstein and Shah'. Jakob Bicker, a successful fund manager at Bernstein and Shah, upsets the status quo with his Personal Assistant and fellow cohort in murder, Serene Antinori, by announcing his engagement to the jazz saxophonist Vick Van Doon. In a separate incident, Serene desperate to maintain their close relationship and disturbed relationship lures Jakob to a late night rendez vous and implores him to murder his rival and colleague Piers Mortimer. Jakob, desperate to end this murderous way of life looks to escape the clutches of his PA and approaches the head hunter, Zara Mosimann, with a view to relocating to South East Asia. His fiancéeVicky however refuses to move overseas and this plan is further thwarted as Zara Mosimann is pushed under a tube train by Serene. As the Police duo further seek to discover leads to the original murder they find hidden records stating that Serene had been found guilty of murder as a child. Now that Jakob Bicker's initial escape route has been cut off he is forced into drastic action. Through a contact of Nadeem Kahn's at Bernstein and Shah, Jakob lures the unsuspecting detective to his death with a view of setting up Serene with the murder. The film climaxes in a 'Timecode-esque' finale shot in real time using four cameras to follow the four key protagonists: Jakob Bicker, Serene Antinori, Greg Galloway and Vicky Van Doon to a final showdown.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?397077</url></doc>
