<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="399613">
  <docid>399613</docid>
  <title>Nocturnia</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Avila, Jac</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Bolivia">16 October 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">115</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Antoine, Erik</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Johannes, Percy</producer>
    <producer>Avila, Jac</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Antoine, Erik</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Calero, Grace</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Antoine, Erik</actor>
      <role>Tom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Craig, Nathan (I)</actor>
      <role>Remy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Crouch, Joshua</actor>
      <role>Michael</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Da Silva, Carlos J.</actor>
      <role>Anton</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mendez, Chiko</actor>
      <role>Derek</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sadr, Mark</actor>
      <role>Andrew</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A timid young man slowly descends into a pit of madness and sucks all his friends in with him. What starts as a meditative observation on adolescent turmoil slowly morphs into the disturbing exploration of a diseased mind. Michael Daly - a freshman in college who has lived in this town all his life. The story deals with his egocentric self-absorption and the obsessive feelings of presumed love that he has for a young girl named Charlotte True. A college graduate (Thom Mc Mahon) acts like a surrogate older brother to Michael and is still hard at work on his thesis. He represents all that Michael wants to become. He has many friends, a seemingly perfect girlfriend and a well rounded life. The irony being that Thom actually has more problems and is the cause of more turmoil than Michael wants to believe. Michael's best friend Remy Chappelle is a down-to-earth young man whose main interests are video games and anime. He's always there to give Michael a shoulder to lean on, even at the expense of being an emotional punching bag for his buddy's tantrums. Sammie Yorke - a perky freshman who may hold the key to Michael's salvation if only he would open the door. Andrew Monroe, a snooty rich kid, harbors deep resentments towards Thom, stemming from a long-standing grudge. A grudge and an obsession that, much like Michael's, can only lead to more pain for all involved. Alton James, Charlotte's boyfriend, struts into town on the eve of becoming a national rock star and stands in between Michael and Charlotte as a living obstacle he can never hope to overcome.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?399613</url></doc>
