<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="401072">
  <docid>401072</docid>
  <title>Not Intent on Arriving</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Ruigrok, Joost</editor>
    <editor>Stultiens, Jeroen</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
    <language>Dutch</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Netherlands">4 November 2006</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Greece">20 June 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Netherlands">102</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Ruigrok, Joost</director>
    <director>Stultiens, Jeroen</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Cuijpers, Marjolein</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Stultiens, Jeroen</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kujat, Krista</actor>
      <role>Laura</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lameris, Willem</actor>
      <role>James</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Loorbach, Liedewij</actor>
      <role>Lotus</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lumby, David</actor>
      <role>Ash</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Not intent on arriving is a film as unique and unconventional as the undertaking that spawned it. Fifteen people from five different countries were brought together through the internet to shoot a fiction film with little money and even less experience. They travelled for three months as backpackers through Peru and Bolivia, just like their fictional characters. This film shows the group trying to make a film under difficult circumstances, struggling with each other and cultural differences. The viewer is transported to beautiful places in South America where the film crew as well as the fictional characters keep getting more and more under pressure. The backstage-story is told together with the fictional story about backpacking and escapism, which results in a hybrid film that is not just fiction and not pure documentary. Thin lines and causalities between the stories make the viewer jump subtly from one into the other, eventually making an inspiring and complete document of an ambitious project.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?401072</url></doc>
