<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="401238">
  <docid>401238</docid>
  <title>Not as Good as You Think: The Myth of the Middle Class School</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Abel, Lucas</editor>
    <editor>Tucker, Nicholas</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>News</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>education</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>educational</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Sweden</country>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">12 May 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">48</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="USA">48</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Tucker, Nicholas</director>
    <director>Tucker, Nick (III)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Pipes, Sally (II)</producer>
    <producer>Itchon, Rowena</producer>
    <producer>Izumi, Lance</producer>
    <producer>Pipes, Sally (II)</producer>
    <producer>Kruger, Erin</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Chaney, Rachel (II)</writer>
    <writer>Murray, Vicki</writer>
    <writer>Tucker, Nicholas</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Jacobs, Jeremiah</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Not as Good as You Think: The Myth of the Middle Class School takes a serious look at the problems plaguing middle class education in America-problems that go unnoticed when districts are located in "nice" neighborhoods with expensive homes. Using data on school performance and interviews with parents, students, principals, and school reformers, Not as Good as You Think shatters the myth that "good" schools are found in "nice" neighborhoods. The film takes audiences on a tour of America's best neighborhoods, from posh Orange County, California to the lush green hills of Tennessee. It reveals that schools in America's middle class and affluent neighborhoods are not adequately preparing kids for higher education, or worse, operating under widespread corruption. In contrast, the film examines the success behind Sweden's education system where parents are allowed, at government expense, to choose any school that fits their children's needs-private or public-no matter the parents' income. Not as Good as You Think documents an education system in dire need of reform and gives voice to the people who are ready to take action.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?401238</url></doc>
