<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="401232">
  <docid>401232</docid>
  <title>Not a Photograph: The Mission of Burma Story</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Hubby, Tyler</editor>
    <editor>Iwanicki, Jeffrey</editor>
    <editor>Renehan, Anne</editor>
    <editor>Santo, Christopher</editor>
    <editor>Suvannavejh, John</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">22 April 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Iwanicki, Jeffrey</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Agrell, Kristen</producer>
    <producer>Suvannavejh, John</producer>
    <producer>Jacobson, Shari Sklar</producer>
    <producer>Kates, Mark</producer>
    <producer>McDonough, Walter</producer>
    <producer>Lobel, Eran</producer>
    <producer>Campbell, Matthew Vose</producer>
    <producer>Lobel, Eran</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Conley, Clint</actor>
      <role>Himself - Mission of Burma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Miller, Roger (V)</actor>
      <role>Himself - Mission of Burma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Prescott, Peter (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself - Mission of Burma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Weston, Bob (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself - Mission of Burma</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>NOT A PHOTOGRAPH documents the resurrection of the seminal post-punk band Mission of Burma, beginning in 2002 and continuing to the present. For a band deemed 'too ahead-of-their-time' during their initial existence, NOT A PHOTOGRAPH follows Mission of Burma's struggle to breathe new life into a tale that's already been recorded in rock's history books -- one that's placed them under the bright lights of acclaim, influence and legend. Mission of Burma epitomizes the age-old, artistic quandary of being influential but not famous; to have critical but not commercial success. Though relatively few saw them during their short but burning career (1979-1983), Mission of Burma inspired countless artists over the years, including 80's college-rockers R.E.M., Sonic Youth &amp; The Pixies, 90's alternative artists Moby, Nirvana &amp; Blur, and bands from the post-Nirvana/indie rock explosion such as Yo La Tengo and Spoon. After nearly twenty years and inexplicable circumstances, Mission of Burma's reunion - beginning as a handful of performances in 2002 and since catapulting into an international tour and their first studio album since 1982 - has left many begging the question: was the band truly ahead of their time, and has time finally caught up with them? NOT A PHOTOGRAPH offers a snapshot of a time before compact discs and MTV, when rock &amp; roll still had some tricks up its sleeve, and when a group of smart, young artist/musicians formed a band The New Yorker would later call "the most criminally undersung band of the 1980s." And then, when they would reincarnate two decades later, to find an audience of still-rocking forty year-olds and astute twenty year-olds standing side by side, anticipating their band's return to form.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?401232</url></doc>
