<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="401321">
  <docid>401321</docid>
  <title>Notater fra Kina</title>
  <year>1986</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Billeskov Jansen, Janus</editor>
    <editor>Hammerich, Rumle</editor>
    <editor>Wiedemann, Vinca</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>china</keyword>
    <keyword>painter</keyword>
    <keyword>non-fiction</keyword>
    <keyword>travel</keyword>
    <keyword>train</keyword>
    <keyword>acrobat</keyword>
    <keyword>child</keyword>
    <keyword>song</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Denmark</country>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Denmark">A</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Denmark">79</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Leth, Jørgen</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Leth, Jørgen</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>In 1984 Jørgen Leth, cinematographer Dan Holmberg and sound recordist Niels Torp travelled some 6,000 kilometres by train through China. The result is a very calm, beautifully perceived travelogue borne by unprejudiced curiosity and observational ability. A riverboat in a landscape of sugar-top mountains in Southern China and the many shots from the train journey are the visual leitmotifs of the film, in which we meet an acrobat, a painter in inks, some opera students from the Beijing conservatory, and a group of female racing cyclists. The camera falls in love with exquisite tai chi movements and the dexterity of the train kitchen staff, and the soundtrack gives a vivid sense of the noisy life on board, with music blaring from scratchy loudspeakers. The fact that the film should be viewed as a collection of notes on film, i.e. a kind of travel journal, is emphasised by the title and by Leth's only words on the soundtrack: "I take notes because I want to remember what I have seen. I am smoking a Chinese cigarette and I am travelling on board a train in China". (In an English version of the film, which is nineteen minutes shorter, a further three notes appear on the soundtrack).</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?401321</url></doc>
