<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="402243">
  <docid>402243</docid>
  <title>Ntituzabibagirwa</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Fontana, Carlo (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Italian</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Italy">22 June 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Italy">50</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Dell'Orso, Maurizio</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Onlus, Progetto Rwanda</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Dell'Orso, Maurizio</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Liuni, Davide</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Even now, ten years after the genocide, mass graves continue to be uncovered. It is estimated that in the three months from April to July 1994, there were almost one million Rwandans killed, mostly Tutsi. Among those, there were many Hutu moderates, rivals of the so-called "Hutu power" extremists,. The night of April 6th 1994, the president in power, the Hutu exponent Habyarimana, was killed in an attack. A few hours later, the extremists took control of the Country and started mass murdering. It was surprising how many of the people took part in these killings. The genocide was carried out by armed militias made up mostly by local citizens. The homicide machine was perfectly prepared. The Department of Defence had bought an enormous quantity of arms from abroad, including "unconventional" weapons, such as six hundred thousand machetes from China. The killers were very efficient and were able to kill over ten thousand in only one day. Canandian General Romeo Dallaire's Blue helmets suffered losses, and this convinced the UN Security Council to withdraw the major part of the forces even while the genocide proceeded rapidly. Dallaire and his men didn't have a chance to stop the carnage, but still they were able to save around 25,000 people. The genocide didn't stop until General Paul Kagame, today's President of Rwanda, who headed the Rwandan Patriotic Front, defeated the Hutu extremists who controlled the government. As a result of an escape route in south-west Rwanda - made by the "Operation Turquoise", a French military exercise authorized by the UN officially to separate the victims from the killers - those responsible for the massacre fled into adjacent Zaire, today's Democratic Republic of Congo, and blended themselves into the flood of Hutu refugees who left their country to to escape from the raids organized by the Patriotic Front.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?402243</url></doc>
