<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="405264">
  <docid>405264</docid>
  <title>O aisiodoxos</title>
  <year>1973</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Greek</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Greece</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Karagiannis, Kostas (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Mihailidis, Lakis</writer>
    <writer>Vasileiadis, Polyvios</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dakoronia, Eleni</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dogani, Eirini</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Filippides, Andreas</actor>
      <role>Haralambos Sarantis</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gavriilidis, Giorgos</actor>
      <role>Sarantis Mihalakeas</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kambani, Persa</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Krevata, Marika</actor>
      <role>Roula Antypa</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rizos, Nikos</actor>
      <role>Panos Karlis</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Smyrnaios, Giannis</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Steas, Alkis</actor>
      <role>Alkis Karlis</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tsoukalas, Nikos</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Voutsas, Kostas</actor>
      <role>Hristos Antypas</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Christos and Panos are partners is a motorcycle shop. They are trying to become the representatives of a large Japanese firm - in competition with an importer, Mr. Charalampos Sarantis. At some point, Christos, the more optimistic of the two, bumps into Mairi, daughter of Mr. Charalampos and falls in love with her without knowing that she is his daughter. Also, Nitsa, Charalampos' niece, meets and falls in love with Alkis, Panos' younger brother and the presenter of a popular television show. What is more, Mrs. Roula, the mother of Christos and a widow, meets Mr. Sarantis Michalakeas, an old flame of hers, which is now rekindled. The name of Michalakeas, however, is the same as the surname of Mr. Charalampos, and this creates a number of misunderstandings. Everything, however, turns out just fine, as Alkis sues for Nitsa's hand; Christos does the same for Mairi, and, of course, Sarantis asked Mrs. Roula to marry him as well. As for Panos, being the hesitant type, is thinking of proposing to a serious lady, Suzy, who has just opened a Japanese restaurant.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?405264</url></doc>
