<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="407719">
  <docid>407719</docid>
  <title>Off the Rocker</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bardocz, Matt</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">April 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">48</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Bardocz, Matt</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Blackburn, Christine</producer>
    <producer>Bardocz, Matt</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>If you think the Las Vegas nightlife is best left to the young and hip, then you haven't seen the senior side of The Strip. If you think the Las Vegas nightlife is best left to the young and hip, then you haven't seen the senior side of The Strip. "Off The Rocker" is an inspiring award winning forty-eight minute documentary about fiercely independent seniors, whose vigorous lifestyles bust conventional senior stereotypes in America. Five nights a week, deep in the cavernous casinos of Las Vegas, three hundred gowned and sequined seniors show up for cocktails, The Jerry Tiffe Trio, and their fountain of youth: hours and hours of dancing. Determined to stay out of the "rocking chair" society wants to put them in, these seniors develop a thriving social network around the dances that often leads to "who's getting it and who ain't." And their vitality doesn't stop there. Watch as it spills over into their community with daily activities that would challenge the endurance of a twenty year old. The honesty and humor expressed by these seniors gives viewers access to rarely considered issues of elderly vanity, relationships, marriage, and sexuality. Their story is a humorous yet poignant portrait of Americana guaranteed to influence your opinion of old age and how you'll plan to spend it.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?407719</url></doc>
