<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="409015">
  <docid>409015</docid>
  <title>Ok, Let's Talk About Me</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Mason, Bryan</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>down-syndrome</keyword>
    <keyword>disability</keyword>
    <keyword>coming-of-age</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Australia">PG</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Australia">20 April 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Australia">26</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Hyde, Sophie (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Summerton, Rebecca</producer>
    <producer>Wiseman, Andrew</producer>
    <producer>Hyde, Sophie (I)</producer>
    <producer>Mason, Bryan</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Hyde, Sophie (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Barry, Zoe</composer>
    <composer>New Pollutants, The</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jenkinson, Eddie</actor>
      <role>Jenkinson, Eddie</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"next year I'm gonna be 18, when I'm 18 I'm gonna get my own place, have a car, have a nude girlfriend and you can come around to my place for pizza" Eddie on his 17th birthday Meet Eddie. He's a seventeen-year-old boy with Down syndrome. He's stubborn and charming, funny and sometimes temperamental. Through the course of a 26-minute documentary the viewer is invited to get to know Eddie - a rare treat - and journey with him as he turns 18 and prepares to leave school. Eddie's journey toward increased independence forms the story of this documentary while Eddie, with his witty banter and continual commentary interacts with the filmmakers/camera/viewer. While most films of this kind focus on the concerns of the parents of children with a disability, this film takes a unique perspective, allowing the filmmakers and Eddie's family to guide us through whilst maintaining a focus on Eddie's own changing perspective - what is important to Eddie and what does he feel gives him a sense of independence? "Ok, Let's Talk About Me" defies stereotypes of a person with Down syndrome and explores, implicitly the notion of choice and control in Eddie's life. How will Eddie respond to the changes being imposed on him and how will turning 18 live up to Ed's high expectations?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?409015</url></doc>
