<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="409233">
  <docid>409233</docid>
  <title>Oktopus</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kieninger, Kirsten</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>caribbean</keyword>
    <keyword>carribean-sea</keyword>
    <keyword>bathing</keyword>
    <keyword>office</keyword>
    <keyword>daydream</keyword>
    <keyword>beach</keyword>
    <keyword>sea</keyword>
    <keyword>swimming</keyword>
    <keyword>bikini</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>German</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Germany">9 January 2003</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">April 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Germany">24</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Steiner, Frederik</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hoffmann, Stefan (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Steiner, Frederik</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hallwachs, Hans Peter</actor>
      <role>The Older Man</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Melles, Sunnyi</actor>
      <role>The Woman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wannek, Antonio</actor>
      <role>The Young Man</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"Octopus" is about the difficulties between humans to get together. Imagine the following situation: Three people, facing each other, are sitting in the corridor of a social welfare center. A juvenile in a state of desire. A man in a state of great longing. A woman in a state of deep confusion. The corridor is endless - no windows, white walls. Only the large-size-photo of a paradisaic beach, hanging in a fitting frame on the wall, is providing some consolation in those surroundings. Of course everyone's glance is drawn to this photo, and each of the three waiting people is having a very personal daydream, taking place on the beach. The two men, incapable of directly addressing the woman, are projecting in their dreams their ideas of a perfect encounter with the woman. In their dreams, their desire, their longing are being returned. Something they do not dare to expect from reality. Closing the film is the dream of the woman - having in store some big surprises, as the emotional world of the woman looks completely different than the two men would ever believe. So there won't be a contact at the end... or is it so?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?409233</url></doc>
