<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="410564">
  <docid>410564</docid>
  <title>On Hostile Ground</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Mermin, Liz</editor>
    <editor>Raskin, Jenny</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>women</keyword>
    <keyword>abortion</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">6 April 2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">71</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Mermin, Liz</director>
    <director>Raskin, Jenny</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Gund, Catherine</producer>
    <producer>Mermin, Liz</producer>
    <producer>Raskin, Jenny</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Verlaine, Tom</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>A small number of healthcare professionals in this country have become targets in a civil war. They receive little public support for their work and face dedicated and unpredictable opponents. Their ranks are shrinking. On Hostile Ground enters the lives of three abortion providers to reveal the obstacles (practical, legal, and emotional) that they face everyday, and shows them struggle with the decision to perform this procedure. It allows providers who work on hostile ground to tell their stories by being themselves, without the help of a narrator. They reveal what their professional decision has done to their personal and family lives. While they each have their own stories, they are all driven more by personal experiences and spiritual beliefs than by political conviction. They each express anger, confusion, and resentment in their own way. By weaving together three very different character portraits, this documentary takes an unusual approach to a volatile social conflict, portraying abortion through the personal stories of those who are in mortal danger because they provide it.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?410564</url></doc>
