<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="411323">
  <docid>411323</docid>
  <title>On the Road to the Bocuse d'Or</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Osghian, Edi</editor>
    <editor>Versteeg, Nick</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">2001</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Versteeg, Nick</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Versteeg, Nick</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Martins, Jimmy (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mills, Chris (XII)</actor>
      <role>Chef</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>O'Grady, Tracey</actor>
      <role>Chef</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Robertson, Jim (V)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>At the Bocuse d'Or, devised by famed French chef Paul Bocuse, 22 chefs from around the world are given five hours to produce two platters with twelve servings each. One platter must feature lamb, the other Atlantic sea bass. The winner gains worldwide prestige, a golden sculpture, and 13,500 Euros. (approximately $18,000 CDN) In our first documentary we introduce you to the North American contingent. The USA is sending a young female chef to Lyon. Tracy O'Grady is currently the sous chef at Kinkead's, a top dining establishment in the heart of Washington, DC. As Tracy battles the European tradition, she'll also have to convince the predominantly male panel of judges that a woman can finish on the podium. The Canadian contender is Chris Mills, a protégé of Michael Noble of Calgary's Metropolitan Hotel. Chris Mills has seen his star rise rapidly in Canada, winning several Bocuse-style competitions. You'll see highlights of the contest from start to finish, and get an idea of how hard these young chefs truly have to work in order to be judged the best in the world.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?411323</url></doc>
