<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="411492">
  <docid>411492</docid>
  <title>On the Wing</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>flight</keyword>
    <keyword>nature</keyword>
    <keyword>chimney</keyword>
    <keyword>urban-setting</keyword>
    <keyword>portland</keyword>
    <keyword>avian</keyword>
    <keyword>school</keyword>
    <keyword>bird</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2 October 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">61</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Viens, Dan</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Viens, Dan</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Viens, Dan</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>On The Wing tells the story of humans sacrificing to coexist with nature, rather than snuff it out because of its inconvenience. The documentary focuses on tiny birds called Vaux Swifts, which have adopted the chimney of a Portland, Oregon elementary school as their home during past 25 autumns. In the early days, when turning on the heat would have meant killing thousands of birds, teachers and students chose to wear sweaters to school while the birds were in the chimney. The chimney has since been retrofitted so it is exclusively for the birds. Each night during their stay, thousands of Swifts fill the sky above the school. As sunset approaches they form a synchronized vortex and funnel into the chimney. The spectacle has included up to 40,000 birds. The collection of birds is matched by that of the people. Each night, hundreds and sometimes thousands of people line the hill behind the school to watch the amazing aerial display. The nights are filled with community, fun, food and family. There is also drama. Dramatic attacks by hawks and falcons whip the audience into a frenzy. The audience has been known to watch the birds with the same reverence a symphony audience would employ, but also with the same energy one would expect at a football game. On The Wing captures the community, energy, excitement and history of the entire Swifts experience in a way that represents the many voices who have made the event what it is today.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?411492</url></doc>
