<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="411695">
  <docid>411695</docid>
  <title>Once Upon a Time in Harlem</title>
  <year>2010</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
    <genre>Music</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>dancing</keyword>
    <keyword>dancer</keyword>
    <keyword>dance</keyword>
    <keyword>gangster</keyword>
    <keyword>cotton-club</keyword>
    <keyword>1930s</keyword>
    <keyword>swing-dancing</keyword>
    <keyword>cab-calloway</keyword>
    <keyword>harlem-renaissance</keyword>
    <keyword>jitterbug</keyword>
    <keyword>once-upon-a-time-in-the-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2010</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bates III, Allen B.</producer>
    <producer>Cain, Lamont</producer>
    <producer>Giagni, Peter (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Copeland, D.C.</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>A jitterbug love story woven between the lives and times of legendary black entertainers, black and white thugs, and the common man in swinging 1930's Harlem. What makes this story unique is that it's based on thoroughly researched facts about an eye-opening, almost forgotten period in black entertainment history and pop culture nearly 80-years-ago and puts to rest once and for all any reasoning for using the "N-Word." At the time of this story, Cab Calloway is 22-years-old and just beginning to make a name for himself. Bill "Bojangles" Robinson is over 50-years-old and, although he is famous in New York, he is still unknown to the world (it occurs two-years before his first movie "The Little Colonel" with Shirley Temple). "Air steps," the Jujitsu type dance moves that made the jitterbug famous, were just beginning to make the scene. The Jolly Fellows were a street gang in Harlem that was famous for its toughness and its dancers. In fact, its founder, Herbert White, later formed the "Lindy Hoppers" and was instrumental in bringing that dance to the world. The white and black gangland violence in the script? It all happened in an almost forgotten time in America's most mythic city: Harlem.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?411695</url></doc>
