<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="412559">
  <docid>412559</docid>
  <title>One Piece: Protect! The Last Great Stage</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>based-on-comic</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Japanese</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Japan</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Japan">14 December 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Japan">46</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <writers>
    <writer>Oda, Eiichiro</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Futamata, Issei</actor>
      <role>Gabana</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ginga, Banjô</actor>
      <role>Suiku</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hirata, Hiroaki (I)</actor>
      <role>Sanji</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nakai, Kazuya</actor>
      <role>Roronoa Zoro</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sonobe, Keiichi</actor>
      <role>Randolph</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Yamaguchi, Kappei</actor>
      <role>Usopp</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The Straw Hat Pirate come across an announcement of ex-marine Lieutenant Randolph will be performing his final performance of his famous play. The gang was interested in checking out this play at the theater ship. They find Randolph rehearsing for his final act. The manager has high hopes that Randolph's final act will be a success. Only when 3 actors quit for their own reasons. When the short number of people required to lead the play, Luffy and the others decided to fill in those parts. But they soon learn that Randolph lost his own family to a gang of pirates as a kid. Ever since then, he despises all pirates. Over the years he performed his plays to give courage to those who have also lost their loved ones to pirates. Due to the injury he received in the chest from the last encounter with a pirate. It'll only be temporary when he looses his voice. Which is why he plans to retire after his final performance. Meanwhile, a Marine commander and his fleet are heading for Randolph's ship on a crime he wasn't responsible for. Will Luffy &amp; the others be able to protect Randolph's last play? And will Randolph see through that not all pirates are scum.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?412559</url></doc>
