<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="412707">
  <docid>412707</docid>
  <title>One Thousand Words</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Blair, Adam T.</editor>
    <editor>Grishman, Adam</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>number-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">14 September 2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">25</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Blair, Adam T.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Blair, Adam T.</producer>
    <producer>Mancuso, Angelo</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Blair, Adam T.</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cameron, Liz</actor>
      <role>Rose Cannon</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>D'Amato, Ricky</actor>
      <role>Phil Cannon</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Donnet, Peter</actor>
      <role>Bartender</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lomonaco, Joe (I)</actor>
      <role>Bob</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mancuso, Angelo</actor>
      <role>Chris Cooper/Jack Cannon</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Piampiano, Jim</actor>
      <role>Mac</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Yorio, Jim</actor>
      <role>Chris Cooper</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Through a photograph hanging on a gallery wall, three observers use the picture as a vehicle to relate separate stories through the picture. A photograph of an obviously depressed man hangs on the wall of a photo gallery. A nameless male observer enters the frame. After a moment of focusing on the man's face we are transported (though a transition) to a home where the man in the photograph, Chris, is talking with his wife. The conversation interrupted with violent coughs. As we get to know Chris and Beth, we find a very happy and productive relationship. Chris and Beth discuss their plans for a bright future. It becomes obvious that that have a bright future together. We also discover that Beth is pregnant. The story then twists and turns when we discover that Chris is diagnosed with cancer and has six months to live. This first act closes with Chris at the park very depressed. Though a similar transition we are brought back into the art gallery. A woman and her son now take his place in front of the photograph. Through the next two acts we are told a story about a family struggling with divorce. The women, Rose and her son Phil tell separate stories, each from their own point of view. The picture and fades to black. Suddenly we are shown the park bench as if a lens cap has just been removed. An unseen operator changes the framing and focus of the camera. Suddenly the man from the photograph runs into the frame and positions himself on the bench. The shutter fires and the "Man in the photograph" takes a self portrait. The story has an underlying theme. "What you see is not necessarily what you get" and "Don't judge a book by it's cover".</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?412707</url></doc>
