<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="412848">
  <docid>412848</docid>
  <title>One Word</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Archer, Fritz</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">12 February 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">15</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Gordon, Shalako</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Gordon, Shalako</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Gordon, Shalako</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bamgboshe, Peju</actor>
      <role>Poolhall Girl</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ginns, Ayanna</actor>
      <role>Crystal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Giordano, Dylan</actor>
      <role>Dylan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Morris, Lamorne</actor>
      <role>Marcus</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Few shorts can capture the emotion and energy of adult situations in young relationships: a brief peek behind the curtain that lies between lovers, Chris and Dylan. Opening in the midst of a heated argument, we're first privy to the inner-mind of Dylan-our protagonist, who while being subjected to what appears to be a predictable lashing, searches for a platform. Throughout the film, we are directed through his dialogue with Chris, and her roommate Susan to question Dylan's motives-are they intentions to harm, prove a point, or substantiate his masculinity? Spiked with the comic additions of Dylan's best friend and roommate Marcus, Director &amp; Writer Shalako Gordon delivers a delicately-paced, humorous, and honest bite into the flavors that create the complexities of a love affair. 'One Word' gives energy not only to the potential static that can exist in the intricacy of romance; but also illustrates how the decisions we make when in a conundrum of conflict can be influenced by the voices around us, and forever changed by what we choose to voice.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?412848</url></doc>
