<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="413475">
  <docid>413475</docid>
  <title>Onlyness... Death Understands</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Schroeder, Eric Douglas</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>death</keyword>
    <keyword>depression</keyword>
    <keyword>alone</keyword>
    <keyword>suicide</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">26 January 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">12</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Schroeder, Eric Douglas</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Zierath, Mark A.</producer>
    <producer>Schroeder, Eric Douglas</producer>
    <producer>Hastings, Patricia (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Schroeder, Eric Douglas</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>DeLisle, Jim</actor>
      <role>Spencer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Doolittle, Hudson</actor>
      <role>Gavin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Schuldt, Gene</actor>
      <role>Tim Rollins</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Onlyness is the poetic examination of the darkness that overtakes men and women regardless of the time of the day. Demons don't only come out at night. Consequently, the window that allows light into our world can become the porthole to our death. Therefore, the secret to life, for all of us, is to continuously pass open windows. Onlyness is more than a story; it is a state of mind that emerges from the depths of depression. In the film Onlyness, Gavin is young and hip while his values and ideals are "old school." His unconventional appearance and conduct don't hinder him from winning the favor of people because he is a man of integrity. He finds success by being himself and being honest. But, is he true to himself? Behind closed doors, Gavin struggles with the recent passing of his closest friend. The pain grows and the pressure becomes intense because Gavin views asking for help as weakness. His friend gone forever, Gavin is left surrounded by people who don't relate to his "old school" values and ideals. Honor, integrity and loyalty may have all died along with his friend. Desperate for help, Gavin makes attempts to reach out to people only to be misunderstood. Everyday he is surrounded by people, but he is alone. He is isolated. Life becomes hell and death becomes a viable solution. Gavin finds solace in the belief that "death understands" him and his "freedom" is just a leap of faith away.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?413475</url></doc>
