<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="415355">
  <docid>415355</docid>
  <title>Ore! Tomba</title>
  <year>1997</year>
  <type>VideoGame</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>video-game</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Japan</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">E</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Japan">25 December 1997</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">28 June 1998</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Fujiwara, Tokuro</director>
  </directors>
<plot>On a strange continent, life was pretty much easy. The people of the different areas lived in peace and wanted it to stay that way. And it did...until the day that the Seven Evil Pigs showed up. The Evil Pigs of Fire (green), Mouse (orange), Storms (red), Hauntings (pink), Water (yellow), Flowers (light blue, and the Jungle (navy blue) appeared from nowhere, collected vast amounts of gold, and began to use their evil powers to mutate the land. Flowers withered and were replaced with spores, people were chased from their homes, friends began to become enemies, villages were flooded, people were turned into mice...everything was going wrong. Meanwhile, oblivious to the magical chaos, a young caveboy was living in the wild, hunting and enjoying life. Suddenly, though, he was tossed into the problems of the world. Koma Pigs-lackeys of the Seven Evil Pigs-came along and stole his precious golden bracelet-a gift from his late grandfather. Furious, Tomba chased after them and soon discovered the plot of the Pigs. Helped by the four Old Men of Time, Tomba's quest is to gather the Seven Evil Pig Bags and seal the Pigs away, breaking their spells and freeing the enchanted areas. Can this task be accomplished, or will the entire world be placed under the spells of the pigs?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?415355</url></doc>
