<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="416024">
  <docid>416024</docid>
  <title>Os</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>surrealism</keyword>
    <keyword>experimental-film</keyword>
    <keyword>egg</keyword>
    <keyword>bone</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">15 May 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">26</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Darakchiev, Jivko</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Darakchiev, Jivko</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Darakchiev, Boris</actor>
      <role>Marcel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Desage, Sarah</actor>
      <role>Marcelle</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A French woman in her mid-thirties lives alone in a woods cabin. The first night we meet her, Marcel, a 13-year-old boy, rudely knocks on her door and welcomes himself into her life. From the very point of their introduction, a tension (sexual and otherwise) is formed between the two. The following day, the woman discloses the reason for her apparent discontent: she shows Marcel a large femur bone, which she claims to be the embodiment of her lost husband and source of her mourning. Marcel, wise beyond his age, leads the woman through a series of obstacles, which require them to pass into otherworldly locations, including some from the woman's memories. There, she must undergo tough challenges and internal sacrifices. The film progresses and it becomes clear that the woman is steadily making progress to a better state of mind and being. But in the last step in the process, she falters. The whole process is terminated. Her lust and restlessness has thrown her life into a degenerating regression. Marcel packs his bags and leaves her life the way he came into it. The poor woman is left alone in shock, regret, and confusion.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?416024</url></doc>
