<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="416304">
  <docid>416304</docid>
  <title>Osadeni dushi</title>
  <year>1975</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>War</genre>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>based-on-novel</keyword>
    <keyword>male-female-relationship</keyword>
    <keyword>love</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Bulgarian</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Bulgaria</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Bulgaria">17 October 1975</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Hungary">19 April 1979</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="East Germany">11 March 1977</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">141</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Radev, Vulo</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Dimov, Dimityr</writer>
    <writer>Radev, Vulo</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Shterev, Mitko</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chanev, Rousy</actor>
      <role>Zhak Mjurie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dimitrova, Mariana</actor>
      <role>Karmen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Englert, Jan</actor>
      <role>Otetz Eredija</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kamarashev, Valcho</actor>
      <role>Otetz Olivares</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This is an epic and dramatic film about the social tragedy of the Spanish Revolution. It is a screen version of one of the most popular novels by Dimitar Dimov (190 -1966). The action takes place during the Civil War in Spain. The accidental meeting of British noblewoman Fanny Horn with Father Eredia, a Jesuit monk, reverses their destinies. The attraction between them is very strong, yet the monk is fanatically devoted to his faith. Influenced by his religious strength, Fanny Horn follows him to a place where a typhus outbreak is raging. Pena Ronda is a camp for typhoid patients. The conditions are horrible, and the death is creeping around them. The shadows of the terminally ill move silently amid the rusty barbed-wire fences and the hospital shacks while on the outside the people of Spain are being drowned in blood. Against the background of this inferno, a passionate crime is committed. It is the work of English aristocrat Fanny who is in love with her victim-priest Eredia. There are many reasons for this personal drama: the burning tears of the Revolution, the chimera of death haunting the place and, above all, the degradation of the priest who has turned from an inspired idealist into a fanatical lunatic. Befuddled by the sterile canons of his religion, Eredia sinks into the hermetic world of his lunacy and is humiliatingly detached from the sufferings of ordinary people and his own nation. Exhausted by her experiences, Fanny starts taking morphine.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?416304</url></doc>
