<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="417580">
  <docid>417580</docid>
  <title>Our Island Home</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Spione, James</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">24 April 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">25</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Spione, James</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Vaughan, Laura</producer>
    <producer>Dickinson, Sally</producer>
    <producer>Spione, James</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Menasche, Emile</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>A pristine shoreline wonderland that is completely unique on the east coast of the United States, the Barrier Islands region of Virginia is one of America's extraordinary geological and ecological gems. Uninhabited for many years and largely protected from development, these fourteen wild islands (and surrounding waterways and saltwater marsh) now offer a prime destination for birders, kayakers, sportsmen, and eco-tourists of every stripe. But to the hardy souls who once lived and worked there, the islands afforded a culture and history as unique as their physical environment. 'Our Island Home' offers three poignant and personal vignettes, each centering on one former resident's story, to bring the Barrier Islands' vibrant and colorful past fully to life. Narrated exclusively in the voices of the people who once lived there, 'Our Island Home' features rare archival photographs of the islands' evocative landscapes and towns, and the sturdy American families who once populated them. An eye-opening first-hand account of a little-known chapter in coastal American history.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?417580</url></doc>
