<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="418608">
  <docid>418608</docid>
  <title>Outside of Nowhere</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Gwendolyn (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">18 September 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">75</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Gwendolyn (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Pesante, Nic</producer>
    <producer>Gwendolyn (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Gwendolyn (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carlson, Lindsay (II)</actor>
      <role>Clare Malcolm</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dauer, John</actor>
      <role>Tristan Mercury</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Epixa</actor>
      <role>Taryn Dean</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gwendolyn (I)</actor>
      <role>Jerica Rhian</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hanzel, Anne</actor>
      <role>Malise</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lord, Jon (III)</actor>
      <role>Donovan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Marie, Anne (VI)</actor>
      <role>Malise</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mascaro, Steff</actor>
      <role>Cassie Chailyn</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Menapace, Luke</actor>
      <role>Braeden Douglas</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Toxey, E.J.</actor>
      <role>Xavier Newton</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>During one twenty-four hour period, the lives of ten very different individuals intertwine in a nameless supernatural town with disastrous results. Jerica Rhian has been avoiding her past for quite some time, but on this particular evening, her past will no longer be avoiding her. While Jerica must employ the help of new kid in town Xavier Newton to protect her pregnant (not to mention clairvoyant) best friend Cassie Chailyn from Cassie's psychotic ex-girlfriend, Jerica also crosses paths with a number of familiar faces, including her sadistic former partner in underground crime and her ex-boyfriend who she deserted nearly a year earlier. In the midst of this chaos, ancient vampires Donovan and Malise indulge their suicidal tendencies as they decide that their undead lives are no longer worth perpetuating and ultimately plan to watch their first sunrise in centuries. To round out the bunch, alternative drug dealer Tristan Mercury sells to all of these individuals indiscriminately. Still, even a disaffected loner has ghosts in his closet, and Mercury discovers just how literal that statement can be. In the rapid, time-bending style of Pulp Fiction, Outside of Nowhere is a different kind of horror that will be certain to shock, thrill, and surprise at its every turn!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?418608</url></doc>
