<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="418773">
  <docid>418773</docid>
  <title>Over Time</title>
  <year>1999</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Japanese</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Japan</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Japan">1999</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Nagayama, Kôzô</director>
    <director>Takeuchi, Hideki</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Takai, Ichiro</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Kitagawa, Eriko</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Esumi, Makiko</actor>
      <role>Natsuki Kasahara</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hoshino, Yuka (I)</actor>
      <role>Hibiki Manabe</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ishida, Yuriko</actor>
      <role>Fuyumi Tsurumachi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ito, Hideaki (I)</actor>
      <role>Yuuki Kobayashi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Katô, Haruhiko</actor>
      <role>Kazuya Endo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kimura, Yoshino</actor>
      <role>Nazuna Kurata</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shiina, Kippei</actor>
      <role>Tatsuhiko Kuga</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sorimachi, Takashi</actor>
      <role>Soichiro Kaede</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Kasahara Natsuki is a thirty year-old hairdresser from Tokyo who comes to Sapporo to relax and enjoy a vacation during the 2000 New Year's Eve festival/party. Unfortunately, she gets locked out of her room and meets Kaede Soichirou, a 25 year-old local newspaper photographer. His kind nature impresses her, but they don't exchange personal information and write it off as a chance meeting. Like all women her age, Natsuki's worried about finding shiawase (lifelong happiness) by marrying and starting a family. When she goes to a matchmaking meeting, the friend of her would-be beau is none other than Soichirou. After that meeting takes a turn for the worst, Soichirou follows her out and cheers her up by taking her up for a ride in his single-engine plane. They part company once more, still not knowing each other's names, and write it off as a chance meeting. Arriving home, Natsuki's roommate Haruko announces that her brother Soichirou will be staying with them in their house, after being transferred to Tokyo's newspaper.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?418773</url></doc>
