<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="419379">
  <docid>419379</docid>
  <title>P.E.T. Detectives</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>New Zealand</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="New Zealand">2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">23</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Beesley, Mark (I)</director>
    <director>Bennett, Michael (VII)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Holmes, Zane</producer>
    <producer>Bennett, Simon (II)</producer>
    <producer>Gist, Christopher</producer>
    <producer>Milligan, Christina</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bennett, Michael (VII)</writer>
    <writer>Hobbs, Rebecca (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Atfield, Tyler</actor>
      <role>School Kid</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Balme, Timothy</actor>
      <role>The Laughing Man</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Blakiston, Jarred</actor>
      <role>Laurence</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cawthorne, Milo</actor>
      <role>Evan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Conolly, Shara</actor>
      <role>Jenny</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hutchinson, Mikaila</actor>
      <role>Esther</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McIver, Rose</actor>
      <role>Genevieve</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ona-Ariki, Dominic</actor>
      <role>Fred</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Varma, Rajeev</actor>
      <role>Mr. Bhana</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>If an alien falls to earth and needs to be sent home, or if a restless spirit needs help moving on the other side, the P.E.T. Detectives can help out. To most, they are four ordinary kids, working as P.E.T. Detectives, for a business that helps locate lost lorikeets, mislaid moggies and wayward whippets. But there is another important side to their profession, this is to find and relocate Paranormals, Extra-terrestrials and Time Travellers. Each detective is unique in their talent. Jenny, the eldest of the team, is able to sense an alien presence, a ghost or any person who is lost from their time, while Evan possesses a love of arcane knowledge and weird inventions. Ling's skill is her boundless computer knowledge and Fred has the talent of being able to time travel. The kids operate under the guidance of Mother - the Universal Intelligence Agency that co-ordinates teams of P.E.T. Detectives throughout the Galaxy in the eternal fight to maintain order and defeat the forces of Chaos. Watching over the four detectives is Aunt Maggie, a regal older woman who supports and nurtures the children in times of turmoil. She reminds the children: "The universe functions on harmony which means that everything that happens should happen, if disharmony gets a foothold, then life as we know it becomes impossible." Dark forces are marshalling against the detectives to achieve that very thing. The P.E.T. Detectives enemy is the seductive Laughing Man aka Jonathan, leader of the forces of Chaos. Jonathan, once known as a highly daring and dynamic detective always hated rules, and rebelled against the Mothers control. Unlike other children, when Jonathon grew older, his powers showed no sign of waning. Mother intended to exile him, however he escaped and his powers grew stronger.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?419379</url></doc>
