<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="420210">
  <docid>420210</docid>
  <title>Pag Asa</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Vea, Kevin</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Tagalog</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Philippines</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">11 April 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">10</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Sargent, Rodger (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Sargent, Lynn</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Sargent, Rodger (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bajade, Khriss</actor>
      <role>Juan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Compra, Roniel B.</actor>
      <role>Miguel</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>December 26th of 1941 the Filipino and American soldiers stationed in Manila are ordered to retreat to Bataan Peninsula and defend it. Along the way, somewhere half way in-between something goes really wrong for two Filipino soldiers. Miguel Reyes and Juan Santos have an important message to get to Bataan H.Q. before the Japanese can catch them. Miguel and Juan are stopped by a mortar which disables Miguel from continuing. Juan helps his friend out to take shelter and the unleashing of horror and war happens all around them. From outside their little hut hide out the world becomes smaller and smaller as two good friends from childhood try to keep each other from being killed. A Filipino woman is stripped naked and thrown just out of view where Miguel and Juan can only see her feet as Japanese rape and torture her. Powerless they sit and try to divert their own attention and look at the task at hand. If they don't deliver the message 1,000's of troops could be shot by friendly fire. With Miguel close to death Juan has to make a choice and a window of opportunity knocks so Juan takes it. Just outside something goes wrong and he has to save his good friend from an attacking Japanese soldier. Successful on fighting him off to only find his best friend had died. It's his turn to take revenge on the Japanese and deliver that message!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?420210</url></doc>
