<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="420338">
  <docid>420338</docid>
  <title>Pagration (Pan+Kratos)</title>
  <year>2000</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Zorzos, Gregory</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>dvd</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Greek</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Greece</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Greece">K</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Greece">16 March 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="China">6 December 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Austria">16 June 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Greece">50</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Zorzos, Gregory</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Zorzos, Gregory</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>Pangration (Pancratium) is composed of pan and kratos, and accordingly signifies an athletic game, in which all the powers of the fighter were called into action. The Pancratium was one of the games or gymnastic contests which were exhibited at all the great festivals of Greece. It consisted of boxing and wrestling (pigmi and pali), and was reckoned to be one of the heavy or hard exercises (varea or varitera) on account of the violent exertions it required. For this reason it was not much practiced in the gymnasia; and where it was practiced, it was probably not without modifications to render it easier for the boys. According to the ancient physicians it had very rarely a beneficial influence upon health. At Sparta the regular Pancratium was forbidden, but the name was there applied to a fierce and irregular fight not controlled by any rules, in which even biting and scratching were not uncommon, and in which, in short, everything was allowed by which one of the parties might hope to overcome the other.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?420338</url></doc>
