<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="420431">
  <docid>420431</docid>
  <title>Paigham</title>
  <year>1959</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">188</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Vasan, S.S.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Vasan, S.S.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Mukherjee, T. (I)</writer>
    <writer>Sagar, Ramanand</writer>
    <writer>Subbu, Kothamangalam</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Ramchandra, C.</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>B., Saroja Devi</actor>
      <role>Malti Sewakram</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Banerjee, S.N. (I)</actor>
      <role>Mill Manager</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Devi, Pratima</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Lal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Dilip (I)</actor>
      <role>Ratan Lal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Raaj</actor>
      <role>Ram Lal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kurupanju</actor>
      <role>Kundan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Motilal</actor>
      <role>Seth Sewakram</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shivraj (I)</actor>
      <role>Sitaram</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Walker, Johnny (III)</actor>
      <role>Nandu</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Widowed Mrs. Lal lives with her two sons, Ram and Ratan; an unmarried daughter, Sheela; Ram's wife, Parvati and her children. While Ram is employed in a mill, Ratan is studying engineering in Calcutta. When Ratan returns, he is offered a job at the same mill, falls in love with a Typist named Manju, much to chagrin of Malti, the daughter of the mill-owner, Sewakram. When Ratan finds out that Sewakram has been defrauding the employees, he decides to form a union, a move that is opposed by Ram, who is very devoted and loyal to Sewakram. Things go from bad to worse when the workers decide to go on strike on one hand, while Ram decides to thrown Ratan out of the house. Word gets around that Ratan is against Sewakram, and soon he gets blacklisted, Sheela who was supposed to marry Kundan, the son of Sitaram, has her marriage canceled, and the family lose their prestige and credit in the community. The question remains, will the workers continue to be at the mercy of Sewakram, and will the Lal family be re-united again.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?420431</url></doc>
