<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="420605">
  <docid>420605</docid>
  <title>Paisa Yeh Paisa</title>
  <year>1985</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Kanwar, Sohanlal</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Khanna, Ashok (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Khanna, Usha</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Behl, Nutan</actor>
      <role>Laxmi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bindu (I)</actor>
      <role>Shanti</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grover, Gulshan</actor>
      <role>Guddu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Pinchoo</actor>
      <role>Bar owner</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Satyendra</actor>
      <role>Professor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Huma</actor>
      <role>Meena</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kiran, Shashi (I)</actor>
      <role>Chunilal's son</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Paintal</actor>
      <role>Bajrang</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, Amrish</actor>
      <role>Jugal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shivpuri, Om</actor>
      <role>Seth Chunilal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shroff, Jackie</actor>
      <role>Shyam</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Verma, Deven</actor>
      <role>Sukhiram</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Sukhiram (Deven Verma) lives in a small tenement in the city with his wife, Shanti (Bindu), son Guddu (Gulshan Grover), and daughter, Meena (Huma Khan). They treat him like a servant, and would not even dream of helping him or his widowed sister, Laxmi (Nutan) who lives in a village, where she is shunned, and taunted because of her widowhood. One day Laxmi receives a letter informing her that she has inherited a lot of money, and all of a sudden her life turns for the better. The news also reaches Sukhiram, whose family are all of a sudden anxious to have Laxmi come over and live with them. Misfortune visits Laxmi, when a lawyer informs that there is not much wealth left in the estate, after paying off all debts, and Laxmi's status returns back to being shunned and taunted. Disgraced, she leaves the village and goes to Sukhiram's, where she is welcomed with open arms. She and her brother pretend that she has inherited the wealth, so as not to antagonize his family. This partly succeeds in guaranteeing her welcome and her stay with Sukhiram's family, and his adopted son, Shyam (Jackie Shroff), and his lover, a dancing girl named Sapna (Meenakshi Sheshadhari). Laxmi is aware that sooner or later Shanti and her children will find out the truth, and she will be turned out of her brother's house.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?420605</url></doc>
