<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="421865">
  <docid>421865</docid>
  <title>Panorama Ephemera</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Prelinger, Rick</editor>
  </editors>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>experimental-film</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Australia">21 February 2005</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">13 June 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">89</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Prelinger, Rick</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Prelinger, Rick</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Prelinger, Rick</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Collage of sequences drawn from a wide variety of ephemeral (industrial, advertising, educational and amateur) films, touring the conflicted landscapes of twentieth-century America. The films' often-skewed visions construct an American history filled with horror and hope, unreeling in familiar and unexpected ways. Panorama Ephemera focuses on familiar and mythical activities and images in America (1626-1978). Many creatures and substances that we hardly notice because we feel so used to them take center stage, including pigs, corn, water, telephones, fire, and rice. At first resembling a compilation, it soon reveals itself as a journey through the American landscape over time, and the story begins to emerge between the sequences. The film consists of 64 self-contained film sequences ranging from 5 seconds to 4 minutes in length arranged into a narrative. Unlike many films made using archival footage, it's primarily a combination of sequences rather than a collage of individual shots. The film is populated by American children, animals, farmers, industrial workers, superheroes, pioneers heading West, crash test dummies, and many others.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?421865</url></doc>
