<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="422502">
  <docid>422502</docid>
  <title>Paper Mario</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>VideoGame</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>witch</keyword>
    <keyword>stars</keyword>
    <keyword>bomb</keyword>
    <keyword>ghost</keyword>
    <keyword>mushroom-kingdom</keyword>
    <keyword>video-game</keyword>
    <keyword>princess</keyword>
    <keyword>plumber</keyword>
    <keyword>spoof</keyword>
    <keyword>role-playing</keyword>
    <keyword>sequel</keyword>
    <keyword>brothers</keyword>
    <keyword>invulnerability</keyword>
    <keyword>koopa-troopa</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>star</keyword>
    <keyword>bowser</keyword>
    <keyword>mario</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <countries>
    <country>Japan</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Argentina">E</certificate>
    <certificate country="USA">E</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">5 February 2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <producers>
    <producer>Miyamoto, Shigeru</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Tsujiyoko, Yuka</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>The Star Road is a magical place where wishes are granted. A sacred object called the Star Rod powers the wish-granting process, and it is protected by the seven Star Spirits. Well, it was, until the evil Koopa King, Bowser, and his henchwoman Kammy Koopa show up and scatter the Star Spirits all across the land. Bowser steals the Star Rod, and with it, gains the power to grant his own cruel desires, including defeating his longtime nemesis: the famous mustachioed plumber, Mario. Meanwhile, Mario and his brother Luigi have just been invited to a party at Princess Peach's castle. While Luigi stands around in the lobby, Mario wanders upstairs to find Princess Peach herself. They decide to have a little chat, but just then, the castle is ripped out of the ground and carried high into the sky by Bowser's own fortress. Bowser shows up to confront Mario, but Bowser harnesses the power of the Star Rod, making him invincible. After finally defeating Mario, he shoots our hero right out the window! Fortunately, Mario is made of paper in this story, and lands unharmed but unconscious in the woods. Toad nurses our hero back to health, and Mario soon finds himself having to rescue the Star Spirits, while gaining new companions and special powers along the way...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?422502</url></doc>
