<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="423291">
  <docid>423291</docid>
  <title>Paramount News Special: 1947, Year of Division</title>
  <year>1947</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Approved</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">30 December 1947</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">20</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Klein, Max</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gallop, Frank</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hughes, Howard (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself - subject of Congressional investigation</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Joyce, Maurice (II)</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Meyers, Bennett E.</actor>
      <role>Himself - subject of Congressional investigation</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Putnam, George (I)</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Annualy, the newsreel divisions of the various studios (Paramount News, RKO Pathe News, Fox Movietone News, etc.)would put together an end-of-the-year recap two-reeler, culled from their weekly newsreels, of the major events, trends in fashions and movies and other headlines from the year just ending. This one from Paramount News ranges from the "new look" in feminine fashion to the escalation of the "cold war" between Moscow and Washington. Other news events covered include the Texas City, Texas nitrate blast; the partitioning of Palestine by the United Nations; the congressional investigations into the activities of oil man/airplane builder/movie maker Howard Hughes and his associate Bennett E. Meyers; the effects of the Marshall Plan to contain Commuunism; the efforts of the United Nations General Assembly to secure peace, despite the continued abuse of the veto by the Soviet delegates, and Russia's threat to Greece, Turkey and the Mediterranean area. Other newsmakers shown included President Harry S. Truman, General Dwight D. Eisenhower, New York governor Thomas E. Dewey, General Douglas MacArthur, Henry Wallace and Senators Taft, Saltonstall, Vendenberg and others.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?423291</url></doc>
