<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="423428">
  <docid>423428</docid>
  <title>Parasite</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Perlman, Jason Eric</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">R</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">27 January 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">29</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Perlman, Jason Eric</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Perlman, Jason Eric</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Perlman, Jason Eric</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dowd, Jim (I)</actor>
      <role>Greg Whitkin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Frost, Jeffrey</actor>
      <role>IT Guy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gifford, Mat</actor>
      <role>Feral</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Glassgold, Stacy</actor>
      <role>Lara</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Griffin, Anne</actor>
      <role>Mandy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harner, D.J.</actor>
      <role>Charlotte</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Krieger, Kate</actor>
      <role>Ally</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In a world where sex is as easy as turning on a laptop, Greg Whitkin can't get enough. To his colleagues, Greg is an upright architect coping remarkably well with the unexpected death of his wife. But to the countless Internet porn sites and paid escorts he retreats to every night, Greg is an addict. The only teenage girl Greg wants nothing to do with is his own stepdaughter, Lara. Stuck in Greg's custody since her mother's car accident, Lara has no interest in bonding with him either, and spends most of her time drunk and drugged with older boyfriend, Feral. But when Greg uncovers his underage stepdaughter among the other pornographic pixels on his monitor, his secret life, as well as Lara's, is exposed. She has left behind the evidence, but Greg is just as guilty for having found it. Ashamed to reveal himself to Lara, but fueled by a new-found concern for her safety, Greg vows to hunt down the source of the underground website that's exploiting her. Finally forced to collide, Greg and Lara find they share the same wound, and these two souls once connected only by an illicit website, now share the power to heal.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?423428</url></doc>
