<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="423551">
  <docid>423551</docid>
  <title>Pardes</title>
  <year>1997</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Saluja, Renu</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Musical</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>wealth</keyword>
    <keyword>fight</keyword>
    <keyword>anti-americanism</keyword>
    <keyword>patriotism</keyword>
    <keyword>arranged-marriage</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby SR</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Poland">7 August 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Ghai, Subhash</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Farooqui, Siraj</producer>
    <producer>Ghai, Subhash</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Ghai, Subhash</writer>
    <writer>Pathak, Neeraj</writer>
    <writer>Siddiqui, Javed</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Bhatia, Vanraj</composer>
    <composer>Rathod, Shravan</composer>
    <composer>Saifi, Nadeem</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Agnihotri, Apoorva</actor>
      <role>Rajiv</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Balraj, Anand</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhatia, Madhuri</actor>
      <role>Neeta</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chaudhry, Mahima</actor>
      <role>Kusum Ganga</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ghai, Subhash</actor>
      <role>Singer in a boat</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jaykar, Smita</actor>
      <role>Padma (Paddy)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kalsi, Benu</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Karnataki, Akash</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kartha, Anita</actor>
      <role>Bit part</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Shahrukh</actor>
      <role>Arjun Saagar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khote, Shubha</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Malhotra, Pavan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Narayan, Aditya</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nath, Alok</actor>
      <role>Suraj Dev (Ganga's father)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Prachi</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, Amrish</actor>
      <role>Kishorilal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Qazir, Deepak</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sukhwinder</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Pardes, is about Kishorilal who lives in America but has not forgotten his motherland India. His attachment with the country is deep and he hopes to find a daughter-in-law for his westernized, American son, Rajiv. He is especially taken by Ganga, the daughter of his friend Suraj Dev. He offers a marriage proposal between Ganga and Rajiv and they accept. He sends his foster son, Arjun to ensure Ganga approves of Rajiv. Soon Rajiv joins them and eventually both approve of each other. The engagement is set in India with the wedding in America. Ganga leaves for America with her new family and begins to adjust to her new surroundings. Her only friend is Arjun who she begins to form a special bond with. At first everything seems OK but as time goes on she realizes that Rajiv really isn't the person Arjun described to her while she was in India. She is right when she sees Rajiv smoking, drinking and to her shock finds out that he is still seeing his former girlfriend. She confronts Arjun and he realizes that he has fallen in love with her. Unfortunately her to be father-in-law sees this and he tells Arjun to leave the city. Ganga, now alone goes to Las Vegas with Rajiv. In a drunken state Rajiv tries to rape Ganga, she manages to knock him unconscious and runs away. Arjun, finds out Ganga is missing and looks for her. He finds her at a train station crying her eyes out and her clothes torn, she explains that Rajiv tried to rape her. He agrees to send her to India back to her family. Suraj Dev is misinformed with the circumstances in which Arjun brought Ganga to India. Believing Arjun ran away with Ganga, he tries to kill him. He fails and tells Arjun to leave the house. Suraj Dev does not listen to Ganga and she is locked up in a shed. She realizes that she is in love with Arjun. By this time Kishorilal has come to India. Rajiv comes as well and is ready to kill Arjun and take Ganga back to America. With the help of her brothers and sisters she manages to escape and stop Arjun from leaving. Rajiv and his friends finds them and beats Arjun up. He manages to break free and he beats Rajiv up, just when he is about to kill him, Kishorilal stops him. The truth comes out and he confesses in front of everyone is love for Ganga, yet he walks away and leaves her. Ganga tells everyone that Rajiv tried to rape her. Kishorilal realizes that his son is not good enough for Ganga and he breaks the engagement and tells Ganga to marry Arjun. Ganga and Arjun reunite and both get married.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?423551</url></doc>
