<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="425973">
  <docid>425973</docid>
  <title>Pati Patni Aur Woh</title>
  <year>1978</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">7 July 1978</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Chopra, B.R.</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Jain, Ravindra</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Asrani</actor>
      <role>Abdul Karim Durrani</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Babi, Parveen</actor>
      <role>Neeta</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Rishi</actor>
      <role>Singer (song "Tere naam tere naam - dil karta hai ke dil...")</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kaur, Ranjeeta</actor>
      <role>Nirmala Deshpande</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Sanjeev (I)</actor>
      <role>Ranjeet Chhadha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Palsikar, Nana</actor>
      <role>Nirmala's Nanaji</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shivpuri, Om</actor>
      <role>Sharda's Father</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Adam &amp; Eve live a worry-free life in paradise. They are instructed not to eat an apple. One day they cannot resist the temptation, and both take a bite out of it. Nature takes offense and expels them from heaven. They are forced to live on Earth as ordinary human beings - together with the apple that has followed them. Now Adam is called Ranjeet Chaddha, a Sales Manager, and Eve is called Sharda. Both meet, fall in love, and get married. Both live in perfect harmony and soon become parents of a baby boy. Then one day Sharda sees signs of a lipstick on her husband's kerchief, when she questions, he clarifies and Sharda is satisfied with his explanation. What Sharda does not know that Ranjeet is carrying on with his pretty Secretary, Nirmala Deshpande, who he has convinced that his wife is seriously ill, is dying, and will marry her after her passing. Watch how hilarious events unfold and prove that Ranjeet is a liar and a two-timer, watch him repent... but hold it! Not for long!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?425973</url></doc>
