<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="427078">
  <docid>427078</docid>
  <title>Peace of Mind</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Crooker, Nathan</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 November 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">23</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Crooker, Nathan</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Balutis, Jim</producer>
    <producer>Balutis, Pam</producer>
    <producer>Crooker, Nathan</producer>
    <producer>Fisher, Sydney</producer>
    <producer>Crooker, Nathan</producer>
    <producer>Fisher, Sydney</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Crooker, Nathan</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Esteban, Anton</composer>
    <composer>Estebon, Aton</composer>
    <composer>Posell, Alexander</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Allen, Justin (I)</actor>
      <role>Jason</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Block, Eliza</actor>
      <role>Cab girl</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gannon, James P.</actor>
      <role>Subway guy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gannon, Joseph (III)</actor>
      <role>Coffee shop guy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kaasa, Rebecca</actor>
      <role>Melissa</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lavizzo, Aurelia</actor>
      <role>Subway girl</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Newton, Matt (I)</actor>
      <role>Stephen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ramirez, Jason (II)</actor>
      <role>Cab guy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Roland, Doug</actor>
      <role>James</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Peace Of Mind is a snapshot of a New York relationship. The eye of the camera brings you into an escalating romance between two people who meet by chance, and then slows down to capture a moment that alters both their lives forever. After meeting Angelina on the busy streets of Manhattan's Greenwich Village, Stephen convinces her to have a coffee with him. Over coffee, Stephen wins Angelina over with his charm and wit. As they spend more time together Stephen finds it easier to forget about his ex-girlfriend, whilst Angelina begins to see the potential for an honest and caring relationship with Stephen. As the film continues, the demons that Angelina and Stephen have repressed from each other come to the fore. Angelina's past pushes her to make a grave decision involving Stephen that will haunt her forever. Stephen's past also comes back to haunt him, when he is forced to reveal to his ex-girlfriend the fate that befell him at Angelina's hands. In the end; what started out to bear the hallmarks of a serious relationship descends into darkness; leaving Stephen with reason to fear for his life and Angelina with even more reason to question her morality. Peace Of Mind tells a cautionary tale of the dangers we face when we fail to take the time to know those we become intimate with and how the secrets of our past can never stay hidden forever.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?427078</url></doc>
