<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="428010">
  <docid>428010</docid>
  <title>Pencils</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Arjoyan, R. Nazar</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>surrealism</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">7</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Arjoyan, R. Nazar</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Arjoyan, R. Nazar</producer>
    <producer>Avetyan, Anita</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Arjoyan, R. Nazar</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kernstine, Kelsey</actor>
      <role>The Young Lady</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lafian, David</actor>
      <role>The Artist</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A troubled artist sits on the couch of his drawing room defeated. He rises and approaches his canvas. He turns, grabs Aram Khachaturian's 'Masquerade Suite' vinyl and puts it in the record player. The thumping waltz begins and the artist waltzes with the music to the canvas. He begins drawing. As the music intensifies, so does the artist's concentration and ferocity. Just before he reaches the zenith of his momentum, the very tiny and worn down pencil breaks, arresting the artist in his place. Shocked and appalled, he drops the pencil, and like an animal attacks the canvas to the ground. Finally, he gets up, retrieves the broken pencil, and leaves his house. The artist arrives at an art store and is immediately captivated by the young lady that works there. Dumbstruck by her presence, the artist begins to walk past her, stealing sneaky glances. They make eye contact. Alarmed, he looks down, repressing a smile. He approaches the counter and presents to her the broken pencil, which she takes. Nervous, the artist waits for her to come back. He pays for it and walks away. He tries one more time to make eye contact outside the store, but to no avail. However, once he leaves, she looks up, yearning for his return. Home again, the artist sets up his canvas and presses the new pencil against it, only to have it break again. Rather than raging, he smiles broadly, and runs back to the store to get the girl.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?428010</url></doc>
