<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="428182">
  <docid>428182</docid>
  <title>Pennsylvania Train Stations: Restored and Revitalized</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Sawyer, Jerry</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>History</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>latrobe</keyword>
    <keyword>world-war</keyword>
    <keyword>business</keyword>
    <keyword>pittsburgh</keyword>
    <keyword>restaurant</keyword>
    <keyword>shoeyville</keyword>
    <keyword>columbia-station</keyword>
    <keyword>train</keyword>
    <keyword>pennsylvanian-apartments</keyword>
    <keyword>train-station</keyword>
    <keyword>union-street-station</keyword>
    <keyword>soldier</keyword>
    <keyword>california</keyword>
    <keyword>railway</keyword>
    <keyword>pennsylvania</keyword>
    <keyword>library</keyword>
    <keyword>rail</keyword>
    <keyword>penn-state-public-broadcasting</keyword>
    <keyword>presidential</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">13 November 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">56</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Sawyer, Jerry</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Vosburgh, Tracy</producer>
    <producer>Sawyer, Jerry</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Sawyer, Jerry</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Burnham, Rod</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In the early 1900s, travelers could go anywhere by train. America's train stations provided a doorway to the world, becoming the heart of each community. They were part of everyday life serving as a backdrop for many mileposts in our country's history. From these stations, loved ones tearfully said goodbye as soldiers departed for two World Wars and cheered these heroes on their return. Presidential candidates criss-crossed the country bringing their message to the people from each station's platform. "Pennsylvania Train Stations - Restored and Revitalized" takes viewers on an unconventional journey to uncover the richness of these beautiful memorials to railroading and meet the people who saved them. Produced by Penn State Public Broadcasting, this film captures the charm and nostalgic beauty of stations brought back to life in exciting and unusual ways. Features segments on Pennsylvania landmarks such as: - DiSalvo's Station Restaurant, (Latrobe, Westmoreland County) - The Frame Station &amp; Gallery (Berwyn, Chester County) - The Public Library (California, Washington County) - Shoeyville (Shoemakersville, Berks County) - Chestnut Ridge Station (Palmerton, Carbon County) - East Mahanoy Junction (Barnesville, Schuylkill County) - The Station Restaurant (Tarentum, Allegheny County) - Union Street Station (Pottsville, Schuylkill County) - Youghiogheny Glass (Connellsville, Fayette County) - Stoneboro Station (Clarks Mills, Mercer County) - Historical Museum (Beaver, Beaver County) - Seiple Station (Sunbury, Northumberland County) - Woodring Station (Sunbury, Northumberland County) - Columbia Station (Phoenixville, Chester County) - Tourist &amp; Promotion Agency (Washington, Washington County) - The Pennsylvanian Apartments (Pittsburgh, Allegheny County)</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?428182</url></doc>
