<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="430722">
  <docid>430722</docid>
  <title>Pets Win Prizes</title>
  <year>1994</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Sillitto, John</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Game-Show</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>non-fiction</keyword>
    <keyword>domestic-pet</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">29 June 1996</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <writers>
    <writer>Turner, Richard (XI)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Baker, Danny (I)</actor>
      <role>Presenter (Series 1)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hewson, Sherrie</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nutkins, Terry</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Winton, Dale</actor>
      <role>Presenter</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Owners would bring in their pets to play pointless games of pet skill and agility. Snail racing, Dog snooker etc. For each game won, the owner got a choice of two envelopes. Inside one of them was a consumer durable for themselves and inside the other would be a present for their pet. The choice was random. In the final, all the winning owners took part in an animal related trivia quick-fire quiz. It was first on the buzzers and for every one they got right, their little cardboard cut out animal would move forward one square on the makeshift race track. The first one to the end or the person furthest along it when the three minutes ran up was declared the winner. Their big prize was decided by The Professor, a cute ickle pussy cat. There was a board with six sections on it, some really good (£1000, an exotic holiday), others not so good (some animal encyclopedias, and the infamous pet portrait). The Professor would be put on a board and wherever her front paws were at the end of the thirty oh-so-much-tension filled seconds (with appropriate music) would be the prize that the owner won. They could try to tempt the Professor however they pleased but they weren't allowed to actually touch her.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?430722</url></doc>
