<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="430868">
  <docid>430868</docid>
  <title>Phagun</title>
  <year>1973</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="UK">PG</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">136</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Bedi, Rajinder Singh</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bedi, Rajinder Singh</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Burman, Sachin Dev</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arora, Vijay</actor>
      <role>Dr. Suman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhaduri, Jaya</actor>
      <role>Santosh 'Toshi'</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dharmendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Gopal 'Gopu'</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gopal, V.</actor>
      <role>Mental Hospital Inmate</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kavita (I)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Prakash, Om (I)</actor>
      <role>Dr. M.K. Effendi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sajjan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Shanta Dhamle lives a wealthy lifestyle in Bombay along with her dad, Shamrao, and mom, Ansuya. She incurs their displeasure when she falls in love and gets married to a poor and overly sensitive writer, Gopal, who moves in with them, and continues to suffer verbal abuse at Shamrao's hands. On the occasion of Holi, while his book 'Agla Kadam' is being published and marketed, he puts some color on a pregnant Shanta's expensive Saree, which upsets her, she humiliates him, and he walks out. He starts writing under the pen name of Santosh, and when Shanta finds out, he changes his name to Vivek, and again to Chitrangh, and does not communicate with her. Four years later, a day before Holi, he has accumulated enough wealth, hundreds of expensive and colorful Sarees, a doll for his daughter, and is all set to return but his house and all the Sarees get burned down, devastated and shattered he leaves with one expensive Saree and the doll. Shanta brings up her daughter, Santosh, on her own after the death of her parents, and ensures she gets a good education. Santosh meets with and an orphan, Dr. Suman, and both fall in love. Shanta meets with Suman, approves of him and arranges their marriage. After Suman and Santosh re-locate to live in his house, Shanta, unable to live alone, moves in with them - much to the displeasure of Suman, who detest her interference - especially after he comes to know that she may be seeking her estranged spouse in him.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?430868</url></doc>
