<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="432238">
  <docid>432238</docid>
  <title>Pieces of a Dream</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Skinner, Skee</editor>
    <editor>Wilsbach, Timothy J.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">R</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">27 February 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">112</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Skinner, Skee</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Cooper, Jeff (VII)</producer>
    <producer>Fletcher, Flaxie</producer>
    <producer>Simmons, John (X)</producer>
    <producer>Simmons, Luther Wayne</producer>
    <producer>Skinner III, Sherman</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Branton, Paul</writer>
    <writer>Skinner, Skee</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Webb, Chuck (III)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>B, Raz</actor>
      <role>Vic</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Baldwin Jr., Marvin</actor>
      <role>Church Member</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barton, Anikko</actor>
      <role>Paul (9 yrs. old)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barton, Toni Lynne</actor>
      <role>Beautiful Lady #1</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barton, Tralia</actor>
      <role>Henreen (13 yrs. old)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Branton, Paul</actor>
      <role>Paul Thibodeaux</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Coleman, Edwin</actor>
      <role>Preacher</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>DeBrown, Ret</actor>
      <role>Paul's Grandmother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>DeVito, Daniel J.</actor>
      <role>David Lekkas</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dennis, Harold</actor>
      <role>Shepard Flockings</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Griffin, Tiffany L.</actor>
      <role>Glo's Mom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Griffith, Tre'von</actor>
      <role>Ren Davis</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>James, Ngina</actor>
      <role>Glodean "Glo" Davis</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jey, Monty</actor>
      <role>Coop</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Johnson, Cynthia (V)</actor>
      <role>Art Surveyor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Johnson, Eric (XXVII)</actor>
      <role>Stone Cold Statue #4 (LB)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>King, Joel P.E.</actor>
      <role>Chris "Black Jesus" Davis</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Luster, Anthony</actor>
      <role>Stone Cold Statue #3 (Jesse)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lynne, Toni</actor>
      <role>Beautiful Lady #1</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moore, Robert (XII)</actor>
      <role>Stone Cold Statue #1 (Hoover)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Schutz, Fred</actor>
      <role>Father Isom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Simmons, Akil</actor>
      <role>Shadow Lover #2</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Skinner, Skee</actor>
      <role>Ice Cream Man</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Walpers, Donathon</actor>
      <role>Tyrone</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Williams, Ervin</actor>
      <role>Stone Cold Statue #2 (Bubbles)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Woodie, Chase</actor>
      <role>Richard</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The uniquely intertwined lives of four kindred souls: a priest, a single mother, her teenage son, and an artist are examined in this timeless, inventive story about truth, redemption, love, and the pursuit of acceptance. Pieces Of A Dream cleverly interweaves four vignettes exploring human nature, character, and morality. Piece One--Genesis: "Now I Lay Me" ---opens with the dreams of Shepard Flockings (Shep), a charming young priest in a "close-knit" mid-American neighborhood. Well-respected by both young &amp; old alike, he struggles with the constant pressures of perceived perfection and his own desires and faith. Through endless recurring dreams and the guidance of the older Father Isom, Shep seeks the definitive answer to the age-old question, "Does sin have weight?" However, when their brightest star falls and Shep is shockingly accused of child molestation, the neighborhood is suddenly torn in half. What once seemed to be a picture of the "perfect man," is now made to be a monster, leaving the neighborhood with self-doubt, forced to look at it's own tragic flaws. Piece Two--Malachi: Golden" ---offers an intimate look into the dreams of Glodean Davis, a beautiful single mother of two. A survivor who has never known love, Glo lavishes it on her young teenage sons-Chris (aka Black Jesus), &amp; his kid brother, Ren. Looking to put an end to the hatred and demons that she's carried within for so long, she seeks redemption and answers in the aura of Shepard. As Glo pieces the whole woman together by coming to terms with her abusive past, she strives to save her son, Black Jesus, from the temptations of the streets. Piece Three--Matthew: "His Use Of The Color Red" ---leads us into the surreal world of a brilliant, yet socially reclusive misfit, Creole artist, Paul Thibodeaux. From the solitude of his window perch afar, he watches over a world from which he's distanced himself. With an almost clairvoyant intuition, Paul captures the essence of the neighborhood below on his beloved canvasses. He seems quite content in his "fishbowl-like" world, until his best friend &amp; "free-spirited" manager, David Lekkas, attempts to "ready him for the world" by tempting him with the "fruit of woman." David introduces Paul to Natasha Toussaint, a beautifully exotic French photojournalist, setting into motion a scenario that flips his life upside down, leaving David to hope Paul lands on his feet. Piece Four--The Revelation: "$tone Cold $tatues" ---picks up on the tale of morality involving Glodean's son Chris (aka Black Jesus) and his best friend, Vic. Being born without a silver spoon in his mouth or a father by his side, the alluring street corner hustlers, "Stone Cold Statues", hold some appeal in his eye. Torn between the church, his family and the luster of the streets, Chris comes to a crossroad in his life when Coop, the leader of the Stone Cold Statues, takes him under his wing. Behind Coop's apparently trustworthy facade lays a lurking, twisted time bomb ready to explode, when Black Jesus takes a stand for his beliefs. None of the individuals we encounter will ever be the same, as their lives are irrevocably changed by moral decisions made or not made. Pieces Of A Dream spirals towards an ending that will leave audiences engrossed and forever touched.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?432238</url></doc>
