<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="432595">
  <docid>432595</docid>
  <title>Piggyback</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <producers>
    <producer>Steel, Jeremy</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Voodoo Highway</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jarrott, David R.</actor>
      <role>Grady</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ruth, Andrew</actor>
      <role>Jake</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A blue truck makes its way through the central Texas hill country. Inside, tapping a postcard from his father on the steering wheel is Sam. Red-eyed, he makes his way to his family's horse boarding stable; a place he has never called home. Three years ago, Sam's mother died. In response, he hit the road finding employment as a truck driver. With each mile, he seeks to define himself and his place in the world. Grady hurls a bail of hay onto the tractor in preparation for the morning feed. He wipes his brow wondering if business will stay steady - if he'll be able to keep the stable afloat unlike his ranch, which he lost three years ago. At the barn's entrance, he looks out across the stable and the empty space reminds him of the missing half of his family. Then he sees Sam's blue truck pulling up the drive. His wheelchair rolling over the rocky dirt road, his arms, legs, face contorted with muscle spasms, Jake watches a ranch hand work with one of the horses. Jake was a boy born with cerebral palsy and has become a man with something to prove. And his brother Sam, who just pulled up, is the perfect someone to prove it to. Randall is a fixture. He's like the barn, the hay, the dirt on the ground. Randall, the surrogate older brother and ranch hand, keeps an eye on the family. Now home, Sam will reunite with his family and learn of the surprises awaiting him.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?432595</url></doc>
