<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="433392">
  <docid>433392</docid>
  <title>Pink of the Litter</title>
  <year>1967</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Gunther, Lee</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>pink-panther</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Approved</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">17 May 1967</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">6</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Pratt, Hawley</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>DePatie, David H.</producer>
    <producer>Freleng, Friz</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Dunn, John W.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Greene, Walter (II)</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>While leisurely sitting on a park bench and eating a banana, the Pink Panther throws the banana peel on the ground and is instantly cited for littering. The diminutive trial judge orders the panther to clean all the town of Litterburg's refuse-filled streets. The Pink Panther gathers all the litter into one, huge pile, but is prohibited from setting the trash on fire, and when he tries to dispose of the garbage outside the town limits, a short, pointy-nosed forest ranger orders him to remove it. The panther attempts to rid himself of the trash pile by pouring it down a hole, but the hole is a geyser, which erupts the trash back onto the town's streets. Steamrollering it and forming it into a huge paper airplane with a dynamite fuse is equally ineffective as a mid-air explosion sends the trash raining back onto the town. The panther steamrollers the litter again and converts it to pop art pictures for profitable sale. He gives the proceeds to the town, which honors him in a celebration, but to his dismay, the Pink Panther is ordered to clean the litter left behind by the revelers.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?433392</url></doc>
