<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="434244">
  <docid>434244</docid>
  <title>PixelProtector</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>screenburn</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="UK">U</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">1 March 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">720</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
<plot>PixelProtector is a DVD based premium screen diagnostic and calibration tool for all types of LCD, plasma and rear projection TV screens. If you own a large flat screen TV and you're serious about achieving optimum performance from your television and you want to preserve the life of your TV set, then PixelProtector is for you! The PixelProtector DVD is packed full of features that will ensure your television is correctly calibrated to gain the sharpest and most colourful image your TV has to offer. Optimise your display PixelProtector provides a range of tools for video measurement that support a broad range of formats and resolutions. The best measurement of a TV s picture is of course the viewer's satisfaction with the image being displayed. When looking at a moving image or even a still frame on your display, it can be difficult to know if you have any colour bleed or dot crawl(unless it is severe). Can you be sure that your panel is setup correctly? Using test signals in PixelProtector allows you to accurately adjust your screen to its full potential. The quality of analog and digital video systems can been measured indirectly by measuring the distortions of static test signals. Subjective human visual assessments can provide invaluable information for you to optimize your displays image quality. Under/over scan test screens displaying different resolutions clearly shown on screen, allow you to measure against you panels native resolution and adjust settings accordingly for perfect image placement. Specific test signals are provided for aligning and calibrating projection sets, over head projectors and rear projection. PixelProtector is the complete video test reference and maintenance tool.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?434244</url></doc>
