<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="434271">
  <docid>434271</docid>
  <title>Piya Naam Ka Diya</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>tv-mini-series</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Urdu</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Pakistan</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Pakistan">2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Khoosat, Sarmad Sultan</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Khosat, Irfan</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Qudsia, Bano</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Akhtar, Erum</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ijaz, Nouman</actor>
      <role>Sikandar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khosat, Irfan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khosat, Sarmad Irfan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The play opens with Sikandar, a lawyer by qualification and an aspiring singer entering Sitara's life who is an acclaimed playback singer of the Pakistan film industry. Sitara, on the personal level, is emotionally insecure and having failed at building personal relationships several times back, finds in this boy her love of life and supports him in every possible way to enter the field and realize his dream of becoming a successful singer. Sikandar, an opportunist, exploits the situation and not only does he manage to make himself a niche in the industry but also seizes away Sitara's newly built house, which her family was hankering for, since very long. Still not satiated with her generosity, Sitara goes on a self-imposed exile, giving up her profession; her passion; her singing for Sikandar for he was feeling intimidated by her ever-increasing popularity. What Sikandar has to offer her in return, is to ditch her for another woman- Ashie, who happens to be Sitara's friend. Ashie- the flamboyant film actress and Sikandar's heart and soul, can't stagnate her life with one man and has to move on at all levels and at any cost for as long as she is beautiful and young. All the way through the ebbs and tides of Sitara and Sikandar's relationship, and in her days of deterioration, a film hero and Sitara's friend indeed Iftikhar is there to fall back on, to look after her and help her stand up again. The emotional and psychological complexities of the real life of these four main characters and their internal conflicts lead them to an end which none of them could ever think of.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?434271</url></doc>
