<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="434577">
  <docid>434577</docid>
  <title>Plan B: Single Women Choosing Motherhood</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Cramer, Beth</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>infertility</keyword>
    <keyword>single-parent</keyword>
    <keyword>adoption</keyword>
    <keyword>sperm-donor</keyword>
    <keyword>motherhood</keyword>
    <keyword>donor-baby</keyword>
    <keyword>artificial-insemination</keyword>
    <keyword>children</keyword>
    <keyword>single-mother</keyword>
    <keyword>single-woman</keyword>
    <keyword>professional-woman</keyword>
    <keyword>family-relationships</keyword>
    <keyword>pregnancy</keyword>
    <keyword>parenting</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 April 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">65</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Cramer, Beth</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Cramer, Beth</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Frost, Harry</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Romance, love, marriage, family. This is what every little girl thinks of as Plan A for their lives. But in today's reality, many of those girls have grown into women who pursued careers, fell in and out of love and now face the tough question of how to have a family without the other factors coming first. Welcome to the women of Plan B. Intelligent, successful and vibrant, they are choosing to take matters into their own hands, and thanks to an open society and advanced reproductive technologies, they are succeeding. This documentary explores the new social picture single motherhood presents and the reasons this trend is snowballing among women in their thirties to mid forties. This film is edited as a dynamic conversation between fourteen women who never meet but, share a common bond. The film has captured their most intimate thoughts on everything from failed relationships to choosing the perfect sperm donor to the financial and emotional stakes that go along with being a single parent. As the issues of single motherhood unfold so do these characters engaging personalities. Also featured in the film is a sperm donor and a grown daughter of a single mother by choice. Both add their unique and painfully honest perspective on the subject. In what may be the most candid film to date about single moms by choice, you won't believe the hunger for this information and the amount of women considering this path. If you're even a little curious, just ask the single woman sitting next to you.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?434577</url></doc>
