<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="434655">
  <docid>434655</docid>
  <title>Planet Kamagurka</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Krijgsman, Maaik</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Dutch</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>de Vries, Simone</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Lagestee, Martin</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kamagurka</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Belgian cartoonist Kamagurka became famous in the 80's with his completely surrealistic, absurd cartoons. In Europe he is seen as an important artist and comedian. Besides drawing he writes songs, paints, tours with a stand-up comedy show and is the creator of the internationally acclaimed comic figure Cowboy Henk, which he produces together with his long-time 'partner in crime' Herr Seele. Kamagurka (Luc Zeebroek, 49) looks at things from a different angle, always going for the absurd. But with a purpose: he wants to make people think. He feels we all think along the same, worn out paths - and that bores him. He likes to invite chance into his life, and does not go for the easy way. He is extremely productive - at least 20 publications a week in different European magazines and newspapers - and he is always on the road. Whether to record his weekly radio show, commenting on an important soccer game for TV (where of course he totally ignores what goes on in the game!), drawing his cartoons in dressing rooms, café's, trains. What is it like to live like this? Has he always been like this? Does he ever get tired of himself? Is he really deep or just a clown? His first song ever is named "Constant Degoutant" and is about a boy who looks like a vagina, and at age 6 he re-illustrated the Bible. His parents were so shocked by the violence and sex they took him to the doctor. Little Luc was then put on tranquillizers. But that was then...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?434655</url></doc>
