<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="435775">
  <docid>435775</docid>
  <title>Playing with Rage</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Toni, Royce</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>women</keyword>
    <keyword>mass-media</keyword>
    <keyword>football</keyword>
    <keyword>domestic-violence</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">3 March 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Pamphilon, Sean</director>
    <director>Toni, Royce</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Pamphilon, Sean</producer>
    <producer>Toni, Royce</producer>
    <producer>Rota, John (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Costas, Bob</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Foudy, Julie</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kolber, Suzy</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sabol, Steve</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Williams, Ricky (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>There are over 100 teams of women in America who play professional football. They are mothers, daughters, sisters, and warriors. This is their story. A disillusioned television sports producer rekindles his love for sports and story telling when he befriends a women's professional football team from Austin, TX. Over a three year period we learn what the true meaning of sport is: opportunity. Football is considered to be "The Last Bastion of Male Dominance in America." In 2000, a pioneering professional football league for women was formed to tackle that notion head-on. The film explores the gender roles and opportunities for women in American society. We hear from a perennial "Who's Who" of American sports athletes and media giants from Bob Costas, Steve Sabol, Julie Foudy, Ricky Williams, and Suzy Kolber. These pioneering women come from different walks of life with a similar desire: to play the one sport that they have been denied. playing with RAGE tackles the issues of domestic violence, gender roles, U.S. laws on gender inequity, and the current sad state of the sports media and the abnormal amount of importance that is placed on today's professional male athletes and the games they play.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?435775</url></doc>
