<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="441776">
  <docid>441776</docid>
  <title>Pratibandh</title>
  <year>1990</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>remake</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">A</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">28 September 1990</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">159</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Pinisetty, Ravi Raja</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Aravind, Allu</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bazmee, Anees</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kudalkar, Laxmikant Shantaram</composer>
    <composer>Sharma, Pyarelal Ramprasad</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chawla, Juhi</actor>
      <role>Shanti</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chiranjeevi (I)</actor>
      <role>Siddhanth</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deo, Ramesh</actor>
      <role>Prosecuting Attorney</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Inamdar, Shafi</actor>
      <role>Corrupt Police Official</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>J.V., Somayajulu</actor>
      <role>Chief Minister Satyendra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jain, Madan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kharbanda, Kulbhushan</actor>
      <role>Home Minister</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lagoo, Reema</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Patel, Harish (I)</actor>
      <role>Katkar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rami Reddy</actor>
      <role>Gangster</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Born in an orphanage, brought up by his strict and unrelenting school-master, Satyendra Sharma, young Siddhanth has not been shown any love or kindness in his entire life. Now he is grown up and is a Sub-Inspector with Bombay Police and continues to live a solitary and detached life, giving to the world what the world has given him - cruelty and loneliness. When Jeevan Ram loses his election to Home Minister, Hirawat Chowdhary, he threatens to expose him. Before he could initiate legal proceedings, his dead body is found on a railway track, this is treated as a case of suicide and his file is closed. Then a young woman, a toy vendor by the name of Shanti, comes forward and claims that she is a witness to Jeevan's murder. Siddhanth protects her, even shelters and marries her, just to ensure her safety. By doing this he has offended the powers that be, none other than his former school master, who is now the State's Chief Minister, the Home Minister, his superior officer the D.I.G., an illicit liquor baron, Katkar, and a dreaded underground gangster known only as Spot Nana. Now the ball is in Spot's court and he is all set to teach Siddhanth a lesson - a lesson that may well end up taking his life, as well as the life of his pregnant wife.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?441776</url></doc>
