<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="441752">
  <docid>441752</docid>
  <title>Prateeksha</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Hakim, Nasir</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby SR</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Chatterjee, Basu (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Roshan, Rajesh</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kher, Anupam</actor>
      <role>James Brown</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mirza, Diya</actor>
      <role>Reena J. Brown</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Namdeo, Govind</actor>
      <role>Pandit Lal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shergill, Jimmy</actor>
      <role>Dr. Kishen Lal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Verma, Raj S.</actor>
      <role>John Clayton</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zutshi, Prithvi</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Kishen Lal is the only son of Pandit Lal, a devout &amp; staunch Kanyakubh Hindu Brahman from Bihar. Kishen has left his parents' home and is studying medicine while living in a hostel. It is here he meets Reena Brown, a Christian, and both fall in love. Reena has already suffered a broken-heart when her boyfriend, John Clayton, married Emily and re-located to London. Reena introduces Kishen to her dad, James, who approves and soon the couple start planning to get married through the Registrar of Marriages. When Pandit comes to know, he is enraged and visits Reena and her dad. He warns Reena that if the marriage takes place then he will never be able to get his unmarried daughter get married, as well as never welcome her and Kishen home either. An argument ensues between Pandit and James and both decide not to give their consent to this marriage. Reena also decides not to get married either. A broken-hearted Kishen, though successful in becoming a doctor, leaves the hostel and re-locates to distant Madhupur - a quiet town where Hindus go to Church and the Christians openly worship Hindu Gods. Then years later Reena re-enters his life and it is here that he will learn the truth why John dumped Reena, and the secret that James had hidden from Reena for many years.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?441752</url></doc>
