<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="441806">
  <docid>441806</docid>
  <title>Pratishodh</title>
  <year>1980</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <languages>
    <language>Malayalam</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Sasi, I.V.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Sarogi, Kailash</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Jain, Ravindra</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jayabharati</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Madhu (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Soman</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>As a child Vishwanath lived a poor lifestyle with his dad, Vasu, mom, Kamlakshi, and her sister, Shankari. Vasu used to ferry passengers on a boat named 'St. Theddeus'. Since Shankari was living with them, Vasu became more and more attracted to her, as well as got intimate with her several times, while Kamlakshi maintained her silent disapproval. When Pelli started getting intimate with Shankari, Vasu decided to warn him, but arguments turned to fisticuffs, with Kamlakshi and Vasu both getting axed to death at the hands of Pelli. Shankari became a prostitute then when she became old, she turned into a brothel-madam, while Vishwanath ran away to the city. Pelli, who lived with his brother, got intimate with another woman, the daughter of a widow, promised to marry her, but disappeared from her life for 3 years, leaving her alone to give birth to a daughter, Amini, and then kill herself. When Pelli returned, he was given the news, and decided to take Amini to live with him and his brother. 20 years later, Vishwanath has grown up and has returned to extract vengeance for the death of his parents. He does not identify himself as their son, rents the house he grew up in from Shankari, befriends Pelli, and also gets intimate with Amini. The question remains will this friendship and intimacy interfere with Vishwanath's play for retaliation?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?441806</url></doc>
