<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="442803">
  <docid>442803</docid>
  <title>President McKinley's Funeral Cortege at Buffalo, New York</title>
  <year>1901</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
<plot>This starts with the funeral procession leaving the Milburn house on Delaware avenue, Buffalo, N.Y., headed by the mounted police of Buffalo, followed by Companies I and F, of the 14th U.S. Infantry, under personal command of Major General John R. Brooke. Following them come a company of the 73rd Coast Artillery, which was then on duty at the Pan-American Exposition. The National Guard of the State of New York, consisting of picked companies from the 74th and 65th Regiments, were also in line. These march to the music of the 14th United States Infantry Band. The military Escort was followed by the Naval Contingent given below. Fifty sailors from the United States Gunboat Michigan, under command of Lieut. Minix. After them come the blue jackets with open throat shirts showing their bronze breasts, their loose black neck scarfs and sailor knots, with yellow leggings and jacket hats. Immediately following the sailors come the carriages containing President Roosevelt, U.S. Senator Mark Hanna, Senator Chauncey Depew, President Milburn, of the Pan-American Exposition, and Secretary Cortelyou, and following these is the hearse containing the body of the President drawn by four black horses and escorted by sixteen sailors and marines from the U.S. Gunboat Michigan. President McKinley's hearse is followed by many carriages containing officials and mourners. Immediately the funeral cortege passed out of view, our circular panoramic device was put into motion and a panoramic view of the Milburn house, where President McKinley died, was secured. The vast crowds are also shown in the picture, with the press and military tents in the background.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?442803</url></doc>
