<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="442946">
  <docid>442946</docid>
  <title>Prestuplenie i nakazanie</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Schaer, Esther</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>based-on-novel</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Russian</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Russia</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Russia">30 September 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">5</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Schaer, Esther</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hacipasaoglu, Serdar</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kremnov, Ilya</actor>
      <role>Rodion Romanovich Raskolnikov</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Rodion Romanovitch Raskolnikov, a handsome young student, is hopelessly in debt to his landlady. He is going to see a pawnbroker and is obsessed with not running into anyone on the way. Raskolnikov is in the process of planning the murder of Alyona Ivanovna, the pawnbroker. The thought of the crime disgusts him, but he continues to plan. After leaving Alyona Ivanovna's, he enters a tavern. Raskolnikov meets Semyon Zakharovitch Marmeladov, a drunken clerk, in the tavern. Marmeladov tells Raskolnikov that he had previously lost his position because of his alcoholism before being reinstated. He mentions how his wife was beaten a month earlier by Mr. Lebeziatnikov. Five days earlier, Marmeladov took all of the family's money and left home, squandering it on alcohol. He is afraid to go home and face his wife, Katerina Ivanovna. Their eldest daughter, Sofya Semyonovna (Sonia), has been forced into prostitution to raise money for her destitute family. Marmeladov is convinced that God will forgive Sonia. Raskolnikov leads Marmeladov home and sees the horrible condition of his family. Although he is in desperate need of money himself, Raskolnikov silently leaves some money on the windowsill. He immediately wishes he hadn't given the money away, but does not take it back. Raskolnikov's cramped quarters. His living conditions disgust him but they keep him isolated, which he desires. Raskolnikov, a former student, used to support himself by teaching children. His maid, Nastasya, tells him that his landlady, Praskovya Pavlovna, is going to file a complaint with the police because he has not paid his back rent. He receives a letter from his mother, Pulcheria Alexandrovna, about his sister, Avdotya Romanovna (Dounia). Dounia worked as a tutor for the Svidrigaïlovs. Arkady Ivanovitch Svidrigaïlov tried to seduce Dounia, who rejected him. However, Svdrigailov's wife, Marfa Petrovna, overheard their conversations and spread disgraceful rumors about Dounia throughout town. Once she realized her error, she went door-to-door to explain the situation and restore Dounia's reputation. She introduces Dounia to Pyotr Petrovich Luzhin, who wants an honorable wife without a dowry so that she will feel indebted to him. Pulcheria Alexandrovna writes that the marriage will take place in St. Petersburg, and she and Dounia will be arriving in town soon. She wants Raskolnikov to become Luzhin's law associate or partner. She writes that she hopes Raskolnikov is still saying his prayers. Raskolnikov is angered by the news, adding to his anxiety.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?442946</url></doc>
