<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="443845">
  <docid>443845</docid>
  <title>Prince Henry (of Prussia) Arriving in Washington and Visiting the German Embassy</title>
  <year>1902</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">February 1902</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
<plot>Here we show Prince Henry's first visit to the Capital of the United States. The scene opens by the Prince arriving at the Pennsylvania R.R. Station at Washington, accompanied by his suite and escorts in the following manner. A shrill blast of the bugle announces the arrival of the train. The crowd is cleared away and the open carriages that are to convey the Prince and his party to the White House draw up to the canopy, and the members of the party seat themselves in the following manner: Commander Cowles (brother-in-law of President Roosevelt). Adjutant General Corbin. Carriages containing Count Quadt in the uniform of a Knight of St. George, accompanied by Colonel Bingham, of the U.S. Army. Then follow members of the diplomatic corps and officers of the United States and German Armies and navies. The German Ambassador, Count von Holleben, finally appears as the Prince's carriage draws up. He awaits the Prince at the end of the carpeted aisle and under the canopy. Prince Henry appears, accompanied by Secretary Hay and Rear Admiral Robley D. Evans, and enters the last carriage. Here we secured a fine life size likeness of the Prince and his American escorts. The Prince is dressed in the uniform of an Admiral of the Imperial German Navy, dark blue in color with white facings, and rich in gold embroidery. The next scene on this film shows Prince Henry and Admiral Evans leaving the White House, escorted by Troops F and G of the Second U.S. Cavalry, and the film ends showing the arrival of Prince Henry and escort at the German embassy.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?443845</url></doc>
