<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="443909">
  <docid>443909</docid>
  <title>Prince of Persia</title>
  <year>1989</year>
  <type>VideoGame</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>prince</keyword>
    <keyword>computer-game</keyword>
    <keyword>maze</keyword>
    <keyword>sword-fighting</keyword>
    <keyword>prince-of-persia</keyword>
    <keyword>sword-fight</keyword>
    <keyword>potion</keyword>
    <keyword>first-of-series</keyword>
    <keyword>sword</keyword>
    <keyword>dungeon</keyword>
    <keyword>trap</keyword>
    <keyword>spike</keyword>
    <keyword>persia</keyword>
    <keyword>flask</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">E</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1989</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Mechner, Jordan</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Mechner, Jordan</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Mechner, Francis</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>It was a time of darkness. While the Sultan was away at war, his Grand Vizier Jaffar seized the reins of power. Throughout the land, the people groaned under the yoke of tyranny, and dreamed of better days. You were the only obstacle between Jaffar and the throne. An adventurer from a foreign land, innocent of palace intrigue, you won the heart of the Sultan's lovely young daughter. And in so doing, you unwittingly made a powerful enemy. On Jaffar's orders, you were arrested, stripped of your sword and possessions, and thrown into the Sultan's dungeons. As for the Princess, Jaffar gave her a choice, and an hour to decide: MARRY HIM OR DIE. Locked in her room high in the palace tower, the Princess rested all her hope on you; unaware that you're held a prisoner right below her in the Sultan's dungeons!! You must escape this hell-hole of a place; which is heavily guarded and full of extreme traps. To finally reach above to the palace to defeat the Grand Vizier Jaffar to save your lovely princess alive while restoring some stability to the people of Persia! And maybe claiming the title Prince of Persia in the process?? (Note: The above is reference to the original game; some later versions of the game {i.e. the SNES} may have a two hour time limit and more levels)</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?443909</url></doc>
