<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="445326">
  <docid>445326</docid>
  <title>Pro and Con</title>
  <year>1993</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>correctional-officer</keyword>
    <keyword>prison</keyword>
    <keyword>inmate</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">3 December 1993</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">9</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Gratz, Joan C.</producer>
    <producer>Priestley, Joanna</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>White, Chel</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Inman, Lt. Janice</actor>
      <role>Corrections Officer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nause, Allen</actor>
      <role>Inmate</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Pro and Con looks at an African American, female corrections officer, taken from interviews with Lt. Janice Inman, and a white, male inmate, written by Jeff Green. It includes self-portraits that were drawn by inmates at the Oregon State Penitentiary and animation of contraband weapons and crafts confiscated from inmates. Pro and Con uses a variety of techniques: object animation, puppets, drawings on paper, cell animation and clay painting. "Pro and Con is a brief but excellent exploration of the thoughts and emotions of those working and living in our prison system." -Rebecca S. Albitz, Pyramid Awards/Festivals: Black Maria Film Festival: Director's Choice Award, Cindy Competition: Gold Award, Annecy International Animation Festival, Northwest Film and Video Festival: Honorable Mention, Bombay International Film Festival, Worldfest Charleston: Worldfest Gold Award, Birmingham Educational Film Festival: First Prize, USA Film Festival, Columbus Film Festival: Honorable Mention, CINE Competition: Gold Eagle Award, Holland Animation Festival, Sinking Creek Film Festival, Ottawa International Animation Festival. Film and Video</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?445326</url></doc>
