<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="448054">
  <docid>448054</docid>
  <title>Pumpgirl</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Davis, Brian Philip</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>one-word-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">2 April 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Moore, Carol (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Martin, Chris (XXXII)</producer>
    <producer>Parr, Chris</producer>
    <producer>Rowe, Anthony (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Spallen, Abbie</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ballance, Peter</actor>
      <role>McManus</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dormer, Richard</actor>
      <role>Hammy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ford, Alexandra (I)</actor>
      <role>Deidre</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Heaney, Samantha (II)</actor>
      <role>Pumpgirl</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hughes, Geraldine</actor>
      <role>Sinead</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lee, Packy</actor>
      <role>Doot</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Little, Emma (I)</actor>
      <role>Dympna</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Murphy, Gerard (II)</actor>
      <role>Shawshank</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rea, Joe</actor>
      <role>Barman</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Abbie Spallen's fiercely observed, unflinching drama explores the dangerously intertwined lives of ordinary people trying to escape their humdrum existence in a rural Irish town. At the local garage, the tomboyish pump girl loses herself in girlish daydreams about stock car driver Hammy, who occasionally drops in for fuel and a fumble with her. Pump girl's co-worker, Leanne, warns her about getting involved with such a feckless married man. Pump girl naively believes that Hammy loves her and would leave his wife, Sinead, had it not been for their two children, KELLY and DARREN. After all, Hammy spends as little time with his family as possible, favoring the company of ex-con Shawshank and his low-life friends, McManus and Doot, instead. Stuck in a loveless marriage with Hammy, Sinead's need to be desired and stimulated spiritually pulls her into a maelstrom of adulterous passion with the caddish Shawshank. Unbeknownst to Sinead, Shawshank is just using her to exert power over Hammy. Shawshank looks for any opportunity to control and humiliate those around him. When Shawshank realizes that the lascivious Hammy has a soft spot for Pump girl, he orchestrates a gang rape of her, forcing Hammy to participate. Hammy is filled with conscience-stricken despair after the incident and seeks solace in his family. He appreciates Sinead and his children for what seems to be the first time. Sinead is baffled by Hammy's new-found dedication and sudden desire to have another baby. Unfortunately, she is now pregnant with Shawshank's child. Following the rape, Pump girl stalks Hammy and sees him play happy families with Sinead and the kids. Infuriated, she kidnaps Kelly and Darren. Meanwhile, as Hammy's guilt turns to self loathing, he decides to exact his revenge on Shawshank and the lads.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?448054</url></doc>
