<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="449548">
  <docid>449548</docid>
  <title>Puzzle Vision</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">93</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Lin, Frank (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Simmaly, Kongmany</producer>
    <producer>Noe Jr., Daniel L.</producer>
    <producer>Sorbo, Kevin</producer>
    <producer>Spradling II, James W.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Noe Jr., Daniel L.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Westheimer, Cody</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Erneta, GiGi</actor>
      <role>Vera Stokes</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McCraley, Lorin</actor>
      <role>Kyle Post</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Meneses, Alex</actor>
      <role>Grace Grayson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sorbo, Kevin</actor>
      <role>Harold Grayson</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This is a story about Kyle Post. Kyle Post is a troubled individual. He comes from a troubling past, has a troubling life and will ultimately live for a troubling future. Kyle likes puzzles. Since he won third place in an art contest in elementary school, his passion for jigsaw puzzles becomes the center of his life. Kyle has come from a broken childhood, fragmented and pieced together by traumatic events. He had a loving mother, but a self engrossed father with a severe drinking habit. Ultimately, Kyle takes his fathers life after a destruction of Kyle's framed puzzles that once graced the walls of the Post home. Consequences find Kyle in foster care, where, he's victimized by his foster- parents. Even at that point in his young life he stays focused and drawn into his jigsaw puzzles. Three people enter Kyle's life, which seem to escalate Kyle's life to his troubling future. Their involvement with his life appears to be a jigsaw puzzle coming together to reveal the final outcome. Harold, Grace, and Vera are fragmented in Kyle's mind, much like his focus when he is working on a fresh new puzzle. They are pieces in his puzzled life, which make up the whole of the final jigsaw puzzled picture. Kyle's fragmented past, his present fragmented view of life bring him to his future, that pieced together gives the viewer the final outcome. Just like putting a jigsaw puzzle together.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?449548</url></doc>
