<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="451178">
  <docid>451178</docid>
  <title>Que Pasa USA?: A Documentary</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Alén, Michael</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>diversity</keyword>
    <keyword>generation-gap</keyword>
    <keyword>hispanic-culture</keyword>
    <keyword>television</keyword>
    <keyword>miami</keyword>
    <keyword>spanglish</keyword>
    <keyword>minority</keyword>
    <keyword>latino</keyword>
    <keyword>immigrant</keyword>
    <keyword>cuban</keyword>
    <keyword>sitcom</keyword>
    <keyword>community</keyword>
    <keyword>bilingual</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">23 September 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hendrick, Sammy</producer>
    <producer>Tabsch, Kareem</producer>
    <producer>Alén, Michael</producer>
    <producer>Quintero, Erick</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Tabsch, Kareem</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Garcia, Andy (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Margarita Martínez Casado, Ana</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Santeiro, Luis</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Villaverde, Manolo</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Que Pasa USA?: A Documentary takes a look at the role of America's first bilingual sitcom and its social significance, but moreover it is a commentary on the portrayal of Latinos on television. Using archival footage of the program and on-camera interviews with shows creators, crew and cast as well as noteworthy Latino and minority celebrities and academics. The show was carried in over 144 different cities in the United States, it won 8 regional Emmy's it was the #1 show in Ecuador at one point and had even been broadcasted in Australia, Italy, Japan and even India. It was a hit, and nearly 3 decades after it came to an end it is still shown everywhere including on the lineup of a national cable network. This was more than a mere sitcom, it was groundbreaking television. It was the first bi-lingual television series in the history of American Television. It discussed real everyday topics that made you think but presented them in a funny manner. It showed how this working class immigrant family reacted to homosexuality, teen pregnancy, drug use, death, religion and illness. Americans could see first hand the immigrant experience and although they were different, we were very much the same and Latinos witnessed their own lives portrayed.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?451178</url></doc>
