<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="452166">
  <docid>452166</docid>
  <title>Quigley's Village</title>
  <year>1989</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">TV-Y7</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">September 1989</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">25</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Carlstone, Ed</producer>
    <producer>Hitchens, Karen</producer>
    <producer>Merryman, Sara</producer>
    <producer>Carlstone, Ed</producer>
    <producer>Taylor, Jim (XXIX)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Auger, Robert (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Auger, Debra</actor>
      <role>Molly/Lemon</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Auger, Robert (II)</actor>
      <role>Dexter/Spike</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Black, Jim (V)</actor>
      <role>Danny/Trundle</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carlson, Rick (IV)</actor>
      <role>Mr. Quigley/Milty</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lessard, Paul (II)</actor>
      <role>Alex/Bubba</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"Quigley's Village" is a kids' show which employs both live actors and puppets. Mr. Quigley is the leader of the town, with Trundle, a parrot, living in a cage on Quigley's front porch. Other neighborhood kids include Bubba, a chimp; Danny Lion and his younger sister, Lemon (so named because of her pastel yellow-colored fur); Spike, a girl porcupine who talks with a bit of a Brooklyn accent; Milty, a moose; and Alex, a fox. The humans who work and live in the village besides Mr. Quigley include Dexter, a handyman; Molly, the letter carrier; and Dr. Caramore, the local physician who is always glad to help the kids whenever they're ill. Each episode centered around a particular life lesson; for example, hard work and practice (Spike wanted to tap dance in the village's talent show, but she never practiced and froze up on stage), avoiding temptation (Bubba's mother made three banana cream pies for the village's bake sale, but ate them after his mother told him not to), overcoming fear (Lemon was frightened when Dr. Caramore told her she had to give Lemon a shot for her sore throat, but Lemon didn't feel the shot), and exercising patience (Danny and Bubba wanted to make popcorn in Mr. Quigley's popcorn popping machine, but Mr. Quigley told them to wait until he got the top half of the popper. Danny and Bubba went ahead anyway and popcorn flew all over the playground).</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?452166</url></doc>
