<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="452105">
  <docid>452105</docid>
  <title>Quiero volver</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Franco, Andrea</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">16 November 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">52</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Franco, Andrea</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Franco, Andrea</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Andrea, Franco</writer>
    <writer>Franco, Andrea</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Araujo-Alvarez, Enrique A.</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arana, Rocio</actor>
      <role>As herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Reategui, Paolo</actor>
      <role>As himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>del Castillo, Magaly</actor>
      <role>As herself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The dream of every single immigrant, is to return to their country someday. Not only because they miss their family and friends, but other things such as the food, the neighborhood, the streets, the stores, the customs. Quiero Volver ( I wanna go back) is the story of one of those immigrants. Magaly is a Peruvian girl who moved to Miami, from Lima, Peru, with her entire family when she was 14 years old. Then, after a couple of years, her family decides to move back to Lima. But Magaly, already grown up, living independently and having established a life in Miami, decides to stay. So she lets her family move back and stays in Miami by herself. Then, after 10 years of leaving Lima, Magaly decides that it is time to make a trip back to her country. She has missed everything about Peru ever since she got to Miami, and her longing for visiting and learning more about her country is inevitable. She cannot wait until she gets on the plane to go back, to see her friends, her family, and the country that she left so long ago. She tells us "I wanna know where I come from, I wanna be with my people, I wanna know what life there is all about". Quiero Volver is not only the story of a Peruvian immigrant of the United States, but the story of every single immigrant in the world. Not only Latin American, but anyone who left their country to live somewhere else will feel identified with Magaly's story, and her experience of returning to her country. It is a very intimate look at her life, as we follow her around her life in Miami, and then hop on the plane with her to go to Peru.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?452105</url></doc>
