<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="452981">
  <docid>452981</docid>
  <title>Race</title>
  <year>1996</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Haidarian, Ryan</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ghahremani, Siamak</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Jazz, Jamey</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hennings, Sam</actor>
      <role>Sam Dalton</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McCord, Gloria</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Dalton</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Meyers, Larry John</actor>
      <role>Rib</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>'Race' is a story of incorruptible intent, exposing the color of the human heart. Sitting on a time bomb of anxiety, Mance Hopkins is a small town prison inmate. Other than his color, we know nothing of his crime. But a story of pain and love bleeds from Hopkin's eyes as he paces in his cage, searching for a way out of anguish. What bothers him is not his cell. There's something out there - a time bomb waiting to go off. Breaking out of his shackles with a sudden surge of determination, he risks life and dignity in search of that thing which is greater than him. The object of his quest lies a night and a day away, beyond a bridge, a river and a set of train tracks. The hazards of nature and four viciously trained dogs set out to hunt down the escapee and trigger a race of no return. The path less trodden leads the protagonists, inmate, tracker and all, to a climactic summit of confrontation with the self. Dynamically paced to reflect the inner journey of a mesmerized audience, this film is a rendezvous with one man's demons and another man's God. Set in small town Texas, the film unfolds associations that are painfully true to some of the most fundamental issues underlying a much afflicted world community - thus staying loyal to the universal pun against time: 'race'.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?452981</url></doc>
