<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="453167">
  <docid>453167</docid>
  <title>Racing Naykid</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Marino, Len</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Reality-TV</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">23 June 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Marino, Len</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bethea, Mark</producer>
    <producer>Janicek, Jim</producer>
    <producer>Lux, Cindi</producer>
    <producer>Marino, Len</producer>
    <producer>White, Scotty</producer>
    <producer>Johnson, Gary (XXII)</producer>
    <producer>Walsh, Ashley</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Marino, Len</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>DeCarlo, Mark</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lux, Cindi</actor>
      <role>Race Driver</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lux, Fred</actor>
      <role>Crew Chief</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>White, Scotty</actor>
      <role>Race Driver</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Cindi and Scotty had set the standard in SCCA Touring One racing. Both had impressive resumes. Cindi won 11 road racing championships and was SCCA National Driver of The Year. Scotty racked up more than 80 victories and was a 6 time T1 Division Champion. At the end of the 2006 season Cindi, Scotty along with their principal sponsor decided it was time to make the jump to the pros and compete in the 2007 SPEED World Challenge! They had everything lined up. Two new race cars were ordered and no expense was spared transforming NayKid Racing into a world class professional team. Then they got a"the"call. Their principal sponsor, citing financial woes, was pulling the plug. Most people would cut their losses and call the whole thing off. Not these two! They took out second mortgages on their homes and they're going racing! Their butts are on the line and we're tagging along for the ride no matter how bumpy it gets! The Long Beach Grand Prix and The Grand Prix of Utah are in the can. Next race Mosport, Canada.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?453167</url></doc>
