<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="453610">
  <docid>453610</docid>
  <title>Raftaar</title>
  <year>1975</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">1975</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Dinesh-Ramanesh</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Shivdasani, S.I.</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Sharma, Om Prakash (I)</composer>
    <composer>Sonik, Master</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bansal, Indira</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Birbal</actor>
      <role>Bankelal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chatterjee, Moushumi</actor>
      <role>Rani/Rita</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Choti, Mohan</actor>
      <role>Sakharam taxi-driver</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Choudhary, Arpana</actor>
      <role>Radha (Pramod's wife)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Denzongpa, Danny</actor>
      <role>Pramod Kumar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jankidas</actor>
      <role>Rani's dad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumari, Lalita</actor>
      <role>Rani's step-mom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kundan (I)</actor>
      <role>Kundan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Manisha (I)</actor>
      <role>Dancer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mehra, Vinod</actor>
      <role>Vikram</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moolchand</actor>
      <role>Rani's prospective father-in-law</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, Madan (I)</actor>
      <role>Rita's dad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ranjeet</actor>
      <role>Chandu Banjara</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sunder (I)</actor>
      <role>Bankelal's dad</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>City-based Vikram is hired as a Manager by Kumar, a wealthy businessman, and asked to report for duty to a distant town in rural India. Vikram arrives there and carries out his duties. He meets with pretty village belle Rani, and both fall in love with each other. When Kumar arrives for an inspection, he finds everything satisfactory, and asks Vikram to run an errand for him out of town. A few days later, Kumar comes to know that Vikram has been arrested by the police, found guilty by the courts, and sentenced to a year in jail. A year later when Vikram is released he finds that Rani is missing, and believed to be dead. A devastated Vikram attempts to try and put his life together when some hoodlums attack him - with a view to kill him. Vikram escapes, but is seriously wounded, and is looked after by a band of gypsies. After Vikram recovers, he re-locates to the city together with a woman named Radha and her child, in order to help her find her missing husband. It is then he comes across Rani and Kumar. But this time Rani claims that she is Rita, and has nothing to do with him. Vikram must now get to the bottom of this mystery and find out if Rani really is deceased, and if not, then who exactly is Rita, and what is her relationship with Kumar?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?453610</url></doc>
