<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="453858">
  <docid>453858</docid>
  <title>Rahi Badal Gaye</title>
  <year>1985</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bhosle, Waman B.</editor>
    <editor>Shirali, Gurudutt</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">U</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">5 April 1985</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Tandon, Ravi</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Malhotra, Ravi (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Joshi, Madan</writer>
    <writer>Mirza, Humayun</writer>
    <writer>Mirza, Mahrukh</writer>
    <writer>Mirza, Shahrukh</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Burman, Rahul Dev</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ashalata</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Azmi, Shabana</actor>
      <role>Bhavna</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kalra, Prem</actor>
      <role>Aziz Mian</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Col.</actor>
      <role>Wing Commander Kapoor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Rishi</actor>
      <role>Amar Lal/Flight Lieutenant Pavan Kumar Saxena</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Shakti (I)</actor>
      <role>Vikram Mehra 'Vicky'</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kolhapure, Padmini</actor>
      <role>Sangeeta</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mohan, Prem</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nath, Rajendra</actor>
      <role>Raghunathan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Oberoi, Suresh</actor>
      <role>Dr. Mehra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Taneja, Sunder</actor>
      <role>Police Inspector</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Amar lives in picturesque Kashmir in Northern India, and makes his living working as a guide for tourist together with his friend, Aziz. Amar is in love with a young woman, Bhavna, who works in a hotel as a receptionist, but is afraid to tell her. He does so with the help of Bhavna's sister, Sangeeta, and finds out to his delight that Bhavna also loves him. Before they could decide on any marriage plans, Sangeeta befriends a young man by the name of Vikram alias Vicky Mehra, who is an alcoholic and a womanizer. Amar manages to convince Sangeeta to not to have to do anything with Vicky, after a violent confrontation. Shortly thereafter, Amar meets with an accident by falling down a mountain, leaving Bhavna devastated and depressed to an extent that she loses her mind altogether. Then a look-alike of Amar in the shape and form of Flight Lieutenant Pavan Kumar Saxena comes to Kashmir for a visit, and is immediately mistaken for Amar. Dr. Mehra, who is treating Bhavna, asks Pavan for his assistance to meet Bhavna and pose as Amar, but Pavan refuses. Sangeeta decides to seduce him in order to get him to change his mind, and she succeeds. Pavan meets Bhavna and she starts to recover slowly. It is then she finds out that Pavan is really in love with Sangeeta; and tries to prove to the police and the community that Amar's death was a homicide and not an accident. But will anyone believe someone who has lost her mind?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?453858</url></doc>
