<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="454730">
  <docid>454730</docid>
  <title>Ram Bhakta Hanuman</title>
  <year>1948</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Sadanand, K.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>History</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Wadia, Homi (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Wadia, Homi (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Tripathi, S.N.</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Amarnath (I)</actor>
      <role>Shri Angadhji</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chatterjee, Sona</actor>
      <role>Devi Maa Sita 'Janki'</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dalpat</actor>
      <role>Shri Meghnath</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Joshi, Prabhash</actor>
      <role>Shri Lakshmanji</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Trilok (I)</actor>
      <role>Bhagwan Shri Ram</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Kamal</actor>
      <role>Shri Nal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumari, Leela</actor>
      <role>Patrani Mandodari</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Patel</actor>
      <role>Vanar Raj Shri Bali</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sharma, Niranjan</actor>
      <role>Sugreev/Lankeshwar Shri Ravan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shribhagwan (I)</actor>
      <role>Shri Vibhishan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tripathi, S.N.</actor>
      <role>Bhagwan Shri Hanuman</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Lankeshwar Ravan abducts Devi Maa Sita from Panchvati during their 14-year exile, defeating Jatayu, who lives long enough to inform Sita's husband, Bhagwan Shri Ram, and his brother, Lakshman, that Sitaji has been forcibly taken in the Southern direction in Ravanji's flying chariot. Shri Ramji enlists the help of Bhagwan Shri Hanuman initially by slaying his brother, Bali, who had dethroned Sugreev and abducted his wife. The search then commences for Sitaji with Hanumanji leaping across the seas to Lanka, killing Ravan's son, Akshaye, and passing on Ramji's message to Sitaji, who is being held in the Ashok Vatica and refuses to give in to Ravan's demands as she is fully aware that he is cursed and will be torn in seven pieces if he dares to molest any woman against her wish. After being captured by Ravan's son, Meghnath, Hanuman does escape, but not before setting Lanka afire with his tail. Ramji, along with an army of apes and bears, descends upon Lanka, kills Ravan's brother, Khumbakaran; while Hanumanji resurrects Lakshman, who was fatally wounded by Meghnath. Lakshman eventually kills Meghnath, while Ramji, with the help of Ravan's brother, Vibhishan, kills 10-headed Ravan. After letting Sitaji sit on a fire-lit pyre to ensure her purification, they return triumphantly to Ayodhaya where Ramji is crowned king. Watch what happens when Hanumanji knowingly insults Sitaji and the impact this has on Ramji and his Darbar.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?454730</url></doc>
