<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="454891">
  <docid>454891</docid>
  <title>Ramgarh Ke Sholay</title>
  <year>1991</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Muthu, A.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="UK">PG</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">21 June 1991</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">123</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Dewani, Ajit</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Jariwala, Rajendra S.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Dewani, Ajit</writer>
    <writer>Mirza, Miraq</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Malik, Anu</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhanushali, Kishore Anand</actor>
      <role>Johny 'Dev Anand'</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hingoo, Dinesh</actor>
      <role>Dinesh Chandani</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Amjad (I)</actor>
      <role>Gabbar Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Anand (IV)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Manmauji</actor>
      <role>Havaldar Dhandakar - Bombay</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mehmood Jr.</actor>
      <role>Ghanshyam 'Ghanu' 'Ghaniya'</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nath, Rajendra</actor>
      <role>Inspector Ghanekar - Bombay</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Patel, Harish (I)</actor>
      <role>Inspector Himmat Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rathod, Navin</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Saxena, Vijay</actor>
      <role>Vijay 'Amitabh Bachchan'</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Naive and talkative Jaiwanti lives a poor lifestyle in modern day Ramgarh along with her aunt, and drives a taxi-cab named 'Banno'. Her village was the one that was terrorized by dreaded bandit Gabbar Singh until two ex-convicts, enlisted by a crippled Thakur, captured him, had him arrested, found guilty, and sentenced to 17 years in prison. When Gabbar hears that an impostor has taken over his place, he awaits his date of discharge, returns to the region along with his goons Lamba and Goriya, kills the impostor, welcomes home his foreign-based daughter, Neelam, who is not aware of his criminal background, and only knows that her dad runs a business crushing rocks and stones. When Gabbar starts extorting money from residents, some of who rebel and are killed, and the police, led by Inspector Himmat Singh, refuse to intervene, Jaiwanti, after watching 'Tridev', writes to Bollywood actors Vinod Khanna, Jackie Shroff, Govind, Anil Kapoor, and Amitabh Bachchan to intervene and save their lives. Everyone scoffs at her, but then to their surprise Amitabh, Anil, Dev Anand, and Govinda actually show up - leading to a chain of events that will threaten to tear apart the entire region under the terror of Gabbar - especially when Jaiwanti finds out that Amitabh, Anil, Dev, and Govinda are actually cowardly junior artistes named Vijay, Munna, Johnny, and Chee Chee respectively - on the run from Bombay Police - after defrauding Bollywood movie ('Chardev') Producer, Dinesh Chandani.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?454891</url></doc>
