<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="457299">
  <docid>457299</docid>
  <title>Reaper, Sheeper, Treasure Seeker</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>death</keyword>
    <keyword>stop-motion</keyword>
    <keyword>surrealism</keyword>
    <keyword>grim-reaper</keyword>
    <keyword>puppet-animation</keyword>
    <keyword>pirate</keyword>
    <keyword>sheep</keyword>
    <keyword>clay-animation</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">30 June 2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">15</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Lieber, Dave (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Lieber, Dave (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Lieber, Dave (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Lifton, Jason</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Reaper, Sheeper, Treasure Seeker" is a Clay/Puppet animated story about Death, a Sheep, and four Pirates, and how their lives coexist and intersect in a coincidental and cosmic fashion. Death, The Grim Reaper, hates his job, the Sheep is much better suited for Death's job, and the pirates are simply trying to do their own job. Three parallel story lines continue independently, and in coming together, solve each other's conflicts. Made entirely by Dave Lieber in one year, Reaper, Sheeper, Treasure Seeker is an animated comedy that has received laughs at all of it's showings, and several festival awards. The director was once told by a member of a festival's screening committee that the sheep sent a 4-year-old running frightened out of the screening room, and they turned it off. Dave saw it as a fairly positive reaction. "The Sheep is only supposed to look cute. Underneath, he's pretty darn evil. The exact opposite could be said for the Grim Reaper. He looks pretty bad, but under the cloak, he's just a cute little sheepish guy who hates his job. Y'know, except without all the flesh and skin and fur and stuff</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?457299</url></doc>
