<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="457951">
  <docid>457951</docid>
  <title>Red Bull Air Race World Series</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Giberson, Brian (II)</editor>
    <editor>Shuey, Wendy</editor>
    <editor>Smith, Courtney (VII)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Sport</genre>
  </genres>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">4 October 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <producers>
    <producer>Chegwidden, Logan</producer>
    <producer>Stephan, Andrew (I)</producer>
    <producer>Leepson, David</producer>
    <producer>Goodling, Joel</producer>
    <producer>Goodling, Joel</producer>
    <producer>Goodling, Joel</producer>
    <producer>Dorsey, John (IV)</producer>
    <producer>Wahlund, Brian</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Buchan, Mieke</actor>
      <role>Herself - Field Reporter (2008)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Goldberg, Mike (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Preston, Alan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The Red Bull Air Race, established in 2003 and created by Red Bull, is an international series of air races in which competitors have to navigate a challenging obstacle course in the fastest time. Pilots fly individually against the clock and have to complete tight turns through a slalom course consisting of pylons, known as "Air Gates". The races are held mainly over water near cities, but are also held at airfields or natural wonders. They are accompanied by a supporting program of show flights. Races are usually flown on weekends with the first day for qualification then knockout finals the day after. The events attract large crowds and are broadcast, both live and taped, in many nations. At each venue, the top nine places earn World Championship points. The air racer with the most points at the end of the Championship becomes Red Bull Air Race World Champion. The 2005, 2006, 2007 and 2008 series were won respectively by the American pilots Mike Mangold, Kirby Chambliss, Mangold again and Hannes Arch from Austria. Four new pilots from four countries will join the Red Bull Air Race World Championship in 2009: Canada's Pete McLeod, Japan's Yoshihide Muroya, Australia's Matt Hall and Germany's Matthias Dolderer.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?457951</url></doc>
