<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="458214">
  <docid>458214</docid>
  <title>Red Mamba</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Jackson, James (X)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">9 December 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">20</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Jackson, James (X)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Jackson, James (X)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Jackson, James (X)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Jackson, James (X)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Factor, Jason</actor>
      <role>Oz</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McDown, Chuck</actor>
      <role>The Watcher</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Valenzuela, Isreal James</actor>
      <role>Barry's Brother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Williams, Don (XI)</actor>
      <role>Doctor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Williams, Don (XV)</actor>
      <role>The Doctor</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A bright sunny day in the deep wilderness fades to black for Oz and Lucy, two teens on a quest for a magical sex drug which grows wild in a mythical mushroom field known as Cloud 9. Feeling a little apprehensive during their days journey, Lucy questions Oz about an alarming story they were told at the last service station. Oz assures her that the story about a man who claims to have seen a caveman in the woods was either a delusion caused from his eating a similar but poisonous variety of the sex drug known as the "Red Mamba", or more likely a spook story to keep poachers clear of the treasured fungus in Cloud 9... Or is it? After Oz plays a childish game of hide and seek, things take a tragic turn for the couple and Lucy finds herself lost and alone in the wild. She tirelessly continues adrift until she unwittingly awakens in the very mushroom field the doomed couple had set their course. In a surreal encounter reality becomes less ordinary and Lucy finds herself flung into a psychological nightmare on a TRIP of no return!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?458214</url></doc>
