<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="459241">
  <docid>459241</docid>
  <title>Rehguzar</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Urdu</language>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Masudi, Faruq</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kothari, Kesar</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Shrivastava, Adesh</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Aswani, Saloni</actor>
      <role>Neha M. Kapoor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bacchani, Asha</actor>
      <role>Reena M. Kapoor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bedi, Rakesh</actor>
      <role>Big B</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hirjee, Vrajesh</actor>
      <role>Anwar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Mushtaq</actor>
      <role>Parvez</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maruti, Guddi</actor>
      <role>Shabana</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shergill, Jimmy</actor>
      <role>Rahul Khanna</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Verma, Rajeev</actor>
      <role>Manmohan Kapoor</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Rahul Khanna works as a laborer in Dubai, United Arab Emirates, and has family living in India. He is unhappy at work, as he had opted for a desk job, but was swindled by unscrupulous employment agents. He daydreams of a better life, gets into an argument with his Supervisor and is fired. He finds work at 'Big B' restaurant, but seeks employment elsewhere, only to quit due to dissatisfaction. Then breathtakingly beautiful Neha enters his life and everything changes, he decides to start his own business as a recruitment agent, invests a lot of money getting visas, but eventually finds himself in trouble with the Police, who do not arrest him, but confiscate his visas, leaving him penniless and in debt. He finds employment and tries to stick to it, but again gets fired when he misbehaves with his Manager. He finds his niche in an organization run by Manmohan Kapoor initially as a Sales Representative, then is promoted to Branch Manager, finally is offered the partnership with a condition that he must marry Kapoor's daughter. When Rahul refuses, he gets fired, loses everything and is all set to start all over again, but through Neha's encouragement takes a loan, starts his own business, which takes off in a big way, making him one of Dubai's millionaires. When he introduces himself to Neha's dad, he gets a shock when he finds that it is none other than Manmohan himself, who is delighted to have him as his son-in-law. The wedding is arranged, and on the very day of the marriage, Rahul is arrested by the Police as drugs had been confiscated from his apartment. If found guilty, Rahul may well face the death penalty, or a long prison term, and thereafter be deported back to India - thus shattering his and Neha's dreams forever.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?459241</url></doc>
