<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="460991">
  <docid>460991</docid>
  <title>Resident Dave</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">15 August 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">26</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Bromley, James</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Delucia, Cesar</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bromley, James</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Whittemore, Dan</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Adel, Bruce</actor>
      <role>The Mailman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Burnett, Kammy</actor>
      <role>Cougar #1</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ennis, Joey</actor>
      <role>Cougar #2</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Golomb, Cazzy</actor>
      <role>Brianna</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hodges, Schoen</actor>
      <role>Repo Man</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kay, Alison (I)</actor>
      <role>Stacey</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>MacKenzie, Ryan</actor>
      <role>Dave Waterman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Swanson, Jacob</actor>
      <role>Trent</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The sun is shining in Dave Waterman's world. The hot young Hollywood producer's latest project is the talk of the town, sweeping through the film festival circuit and fast tracking his career. Dave congratulates himself by renting out a big new house, splurging on a big new truck and throwing himself a big party with all of his new friends. Things take a turn for the worse when the Mailman shows up, and the bored Hollywood elite amuse themselves by hurling insults at the poor guy. It occurs to Dave that this may somehow come back to haunt him. Days go by and Dave's mailbox remains empty. Days turn to weeks. The big checks he's been counting on to pay for all of his fancy new stuff don't show up. Important papers from people who want to work with him don't show up. Dave tries in vain to reconcile with his Mailman, but the Mailman won't budge in teaching Dave his lesson. Eventually, Dave realizes he simply cannot win his battle against the bureaucracy, and is forced to give up his fancy new house, his fancy new truck and his fancy new friends, and go back to where he came from with the hard learned lesson.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?460991</url></doc>
