<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="461214">
  <docid>461214</docid>
  <title>Restore</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Lee, Phil (VI)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 August 2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">13</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Smith, Hakeem</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Smith, Donald G.</producer>
    <producer>Ferguson, Anthony B.</producer>
    <producer>Smith, Hakeem</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Smith, Hakeem</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ferguson, Jason (VI)</actor>
      <role>Son</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Julien, Max (I)</actor>
      <role>Coach Barnes</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Miller, Lorrhonda</actor>
      <role>Woman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Williams, Marc (IV)</actor>
      <role>Donovan Taylor</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Restore is the story of Donovan Taylor (Marc Mdoc Williams), a young man in desperate need of a job. This need has clouded his vision. The strain of monetary absence has had its affect on Taylor. After shaking off the thought of felony robbery with a side of assault, Taylor comes face to face with his ego. Coach Cecil Barnes (Max Julien aka Goldie) who died six months earlier, is standing right in front of Taylor asking for time and effort, without any apparent reward in waiting. Donovan, in short, is asked to open his eyes. After some coaxing, Donovan agrees to help his dead former high school basketball coach retrieve a very important plant from his uncaring son and return it to Burch Park. Barnes and his wife rescued the plant from the park many years prior. Now it was time to restore it to its original place. After a short visit to Barnes' son's house Taylor and Barnes head over to the park. Donovan returns the plant to the ground after a little work. Something then happens that Donovan never expected. And his reaction is something that you'll never expect. Restore. When all you can do is think of yourself.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?461214</url></doc>
