<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="461989">
  <docid>461989</docid>
  <title>Revenge Tragedies</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Supannarat, Pornpatchaya</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>revenge</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">25 September 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Supannarat, Pornpatchaya</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Daniels, Gary (I)</producer>
    <producer>Supannarat, Pornpatchaya</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Supannarat, Pornpatchaya</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chien, Fernando</actor>
      <role>Ian</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chiu, Cindy</actor>
      <role>Ariel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Daniels, Gary (I)</actor>
      <role>Dan</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Revenge tragedies is the tragic tale of two young lovers, Ian and Ariel, and about how their lives were torn apart. Ian and Ariel are two illegal immigrant from Asia that work in a restaurant owned and run by Dan, a Caucasian male with an eye for the ladies and a will to match it. One lazy morning in bed Ian decides it is time to propose to Ariel who gleefully accepts and the wedding is set for the first day of Spring. At work later that day we see there is an uneasy relationship between Ariel and Dan who likes a drink while at work. Obviously Ariel is uncomfortable under the maligned attentions of Dan. The next evening Ian becomes ill and can not go to work so Ariel is forced to go alone. At the restaurant Dan has been drinking as usual and inappropriately makes an advance on Ariel. To get away Ariel goes to the bathroom to touch up her make up and is unknowingly pursued by Dan who, once he has cornered her in the bathroom, proceeds to rape her violently. Upon her return home Ariel is crying and Ian softly asks what is wrong and Ariel tells him what happened. In a fit of rage Ian heads to the restaurant where he sees Dan celebrating his conquest with a glass of wine. Ian checks his anger to go back home and take care of Ariel but once he arrives home he finds the unspeakable, Ariel has cut her wrists and bled to death in the bath. With unchecked rage Ian heads back to the restaurant and finds Dan relieving himself in the same bathroom where he raped Ariel and proceed to bludgeon him to death with a skillet from the restaurant's kitchen.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?461989</url></doc>
