<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="461909">
  <docid>461909</docid>
  <title>Revealing Hate</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>white-supremacist</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">71</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Wilson, Mariah</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Wilson, Mariah</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>Donning swastikas and brown shirts, or long white robes and hoods, the attendees of a white supremacist rally are without a doubt a disquieting and memorable sight. Coated with heavy symbolism that pierces deep into the darkest shadows of America's racial history, Klan members, neo-Nazis, and other right wing extremists are easily passed off by most as simply members of a 'hate group.' But in order to combat the existence of these organizations, we must first understand them. How do members of these groups acquire their beliefs? How does the white supremacist movement exist now, in a country where it is considered by many to be a relic of the past? And what are its goals for the future? On the other side of the coin, what is it like to be a victim of violence perpetrated by this movement? Or what is it like to attempt to infiltrate or monitor right wing extremism, despite the dangers? The film "Revealing Hate" will attempt to answer some of these questions, through telling the stories of those who have prosecuted, photographed, protested, infiltrated, and even participated in these organizations. Each individual's story, told separately in a vignette style, will shed more light on these philosophies that continue to run deep within the fringes of our society.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?461909</url></doc>
