<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="462077">
  <docid>462077</docid>
  <title>Reverb</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Lewis, Mark Edward (I)</editor>
    <editor>Machnik, Justin</editor>
    <editor>Riedl, H. Charles</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">106</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Lewis, Mark Edward (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Carter, Lizz</producer>
    <producer>Ebner, Christian (II)</producer>
    <producer>Lewis, Mark Edward (I)</producer>
    <producer>MacCallum, Carmen</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Bitner, Cory</composer>
    <composer>Gingerich, Andrew (I)</composer>
    <composer>Lewis, Mark Edward (I)</composer>
    <composer>Lloyd, Darren (I)</composer>
    <composer>Proppe, Jerry</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Andrei, Alina</actor>
      <role>Chrissy, The Parish Follower</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barany, Mitch</actor>
      <role>Dusty</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carter, Lizz</actor>
      <role>Julie Reisman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>DeLeskie, Malcolm</actor>
      <role>Murray</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Habicht, Brian</actor>
      <role>Marty Eichenbach</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jacket, Leanne</actor>
      <role>Tammy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kelly, Dave (VIII)</actor>
      <role>Jeff Timmens</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Loizos, Stephen (I)</actor>
      <role>Rock Penesicci</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mitchell, Barb</actor>
      <role>Cindy Moynahan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rushing, Ty</actor>
      <role>TNT</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Jeff Timmens is a New York journalist in trouble. His employment at the Central Music Network (CMN) will be terminated if his next work isn't Pulitzer material. Unfortunately, his boss sends him to Iopa, Iowa to document a story that is so ridiculous, it is sure to only get him fired: the National Karaoke Competition. Documenting several of the contestants' lives, Jeff finds that the life of "Kroakers" is far more interesting and eccentric than he could have ever imagined. Julie Reismann, Mary and Marty Eichenbach, and William Moynahan frequent the Hannibal's bar, while Rock Penesicci will only attend Stubbie's Pub. Determined to beat each other out for the coveted spots in the Starkroaker Host Invitational Talent Search (S.H.I.T.S.), when they all make it, the happy facades of the Midwest melt into a pot of backstabbing that is only rivaled in in the city's church. Bobby Jones Kingdom Tabernacle of Truth Church: where Bobby Jones bludgeons and brainwashes his congregants into believing that Karaoke is of the devil. But when the regional winners of the competition arrive to compete along side the Iopans for the coveted "Golden Kroak" microphone, the hapless Iowa natives realize that they may not be as prepared for the competition as they thought. Drastic and sometimes illegal measures are taken by all to ensure their possession of the highest prize in all of Karaoke. Meanwhile, Jeff, with his secretly placed secret cameras, documents the contestants' outrageous home life. From husband beating Cindy Moynahan to the Eichenbach's MWATS breathing techniques to Rock's mafia funded father, Jeff finds himself with a story that combines divas and domestic disturbances, baptizing and backstabbing, winners and wineos. It's a story whose telling could only be enhanced by one thing: reverb.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?462077</url></doc>
