<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="462075">
  <docid>462075</docid>
  <title>Reverb</title>
  <year>1999</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1999</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">50</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Lage, Milton</director>
    <director>Mendoza, Linda (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Hill, Dave (V)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Armisen, Fred</actor>
      <role>Interviewer</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>REVERB, the critically-acclaimed weekly HBO music series spotlighting emerging talent, ran for four season (1997-2001). REVERB captured the energy and spontaneity of live music by taking viewers on stage, backstage, and into the audience at some of the nation's premier venues. Joining artists on tour, without special staging or second takes, REVERB created an unfiltered, authentic and intimate experience where the viewer became part of the live show dynamic between artist and fan. A joint effort of HBO and Warner Music Group, REVERB featured a wide variety of artists from major and independent record labels. Artists performances featured on REVERB included Archers of Load, Bad Religion, Beastie Boys, Beck, Ben Folds Five, Bettie Serveert, Blondie, Bjork, Built To Spill, R.L. Burnside, Calexico, Tracy Chapman, Cheap Trick, Cibo Matto, Paula Cole, Cornelius, Cornershop, The Cult, Dinosaur Jr., Pete Droge, Eels, Everclear, Everlast, Fastball, Flaming Lips, Foo Fighters, Fountains of Wayne, G. Love &amp; Special Sauce, Goldfinger, Grant Lee Buffalo, Green Day, Ben Harper, Robyn Hitchcock, Hole, Imperial Teen, Kid Rock, Lemonheads, Live, Melvins, The Mighty Mighty Bosstones, Moby, Morphine, Mos Def, Pavement, Pennywise, Primus, Rage Against The Machine, Reverend Horton Heat, Rocket from the Crypt, The Roots, Sebadoh, Semisonic, Smash Mouth, Sigur Ros, Super Furry Animals, Son Volt, Soul Coughing, Joe Strummer, Talib Kwali, Third Eye Blind, Walt Mink, Scott Weiland and Wilco.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?462075</url></doc>
