<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="464283">
  <docid>464283</docid>
  <title>Rishte Naahte</title>
  <year>1965</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Gopalakrishnan, K.S.</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Mohan, Madan (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Abraham, David (II)</actor>
      <role>Collector</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ameeta (I)</actor>
      <role>Roopa</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Behl, Nutan</actor>
      <role>Savitri</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dhumal</actor>
      <role>Diwanji</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hussain, Nasir (I)</actor>
      <role>Thakur Narendrapal Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jamuna (I)</actor>
      <role>Kalpana</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jeevan (I)</actor>
      <role>Roopa's Father</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kanhaiyalal (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Raaj</actor>
      <role>Sunder</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Verma, Deven</actor>
      <role>Raja</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Thakur Narendrapal Singh (Nazir Hussain) is a generous and kind-hearted landlord and zamindar. He has a daughter Kalpana (Jamuna) and a son Raja(Deven Verma). Distrusting his son and his new wife, Roopa (Ameeta), he asks a village laborer, Sunder (Raaj Kumar) who is honest, loyal and hardworking, to marry his daughter. In this manner, Sunder and Kalpana get married, and soon Kalpana gives birth to a daughter (Baby Shakila). Tragically Kalpana passes away, and the Thakur, Sunder, and the child are devastated. The Thakur asks Sunder to get married to Savitri (Nutan), who is the daughter of his childhood friend, the local Collector (David). He hopes that in this manner the child will get the love of a mother. Sunder reluctantly agrees, and soon Savitri and he get married. Savitri is unable to win the love of the child nor does she get any affection from Sunder, as he is unable to get Kalpana out of his mind and thoughts. In the meantime, Roopa's dad (Jeevan) is plotting the death of Sunder, so that his daughter can take over the wealth of the Thakur after his death.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?464283</url></doc>
