<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="464449">
  <docid>464449</docid>
  <title>Ritam zivota</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Ivanovic, Snezana</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Serbo-Croatian</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Bosnia and Herzegovina</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Bosnia and Herzegovina">6 December 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">78</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Puska, Enver</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Durakovic, Jasmin</producer>
    <producer>Puska, Enver</producer>
    <producer>Puska, Sandra Dizdarevic</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Puska, Enver</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Puska, Enver</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Agincic, Alija</actor>
      <role>Doctor II</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ahmetasevic, Suada</actor>
      <role>Umma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Becic, Zorana</actor>
      <role>Maja</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Colovic, Rade</actor>
      <role>Daut</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Diklic, Jasna</actor>
      <role>Emma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Drmac, Mario</actor>
      <role>Nedim</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dzenisijevic, Nela</actor>
      <role>Hana</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Filipovic, Tarik</actor>
      <role>Damir</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nevrt, Tomislav</actor>
      <role>Doctor I</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Veljovic, Nebojsa</actor>
      <role>Salih</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In the forefront of the story we have Salih. After having been imprisoned in a concentration camp during the war, Salih has decided that from then on, he is not going to be hungry ever again and that all his life will be dedicated to pleasure and worship of the joy of living. A family man, every day more and more in love with his lovely wife Emma and more and more worried about his daughter Maja, Salih has a restaurant where he prepares his chef d'ouvre course: mixed meat for four. The love between Salih and Emma is ideal, perfect. They are in love with each other more and more every single day. Their concern and love for their daughter Maja, aged 27, is endless. Their care is even more intensified due to the fact that Maja, as every decent representative of the contemporary society, does not really enjoy Salih's mixed meat, eats little, cares about the amount of fat and sugar in blood and is always on some kind of a diet. Whereas Salih worries about Maja's eating, she has her mind set on other problems. She is in love with Damir, a cheater and seller of stolen automobiles. Moreover, he is married and recklessly cheats on his wife around the clock. Hurt, angry and humiliated, Maja decided to break up with Damir, understanding that she does not really mean much to him. Zulha, her aunt is a very interesting and special person. She does some dark magic. Well, in Bosnia they would say: he throws and takes of curses (sihir). Maja confesses her pain and problems and together they throw a curse, a sihir on Damir. It says: every time that Damir is about to come during sex, he will remain trapped, stuck in the woman's vagina. The phenomenon is called vaginal cramp..</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?464449</url></doc>
