<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="465146">
  <docid>465146</docid>
  <title>Roadtrip to Orlando</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>spanking</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">March 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">63</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Miller, Keith (V)</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Black, Rick (II)</actor>
      <role>Spanker</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brandon (IV)</actor>
      <role>Spankee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gold, Justin (II)</actor>
      <role>Spankee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sean (VI)</actor>
      <role>Spankee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sterne, Jeff (II)</actor>
      <role>Spanker</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Summers, Justyn</actor>
      <role>Spankee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Todd (IV)</actor>
      <role>Spankee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wood, T.J.</actor>
      <role>Spanker</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In this seventh of the telling named "Spank This" series, four more scenes of merciless discipline on a total of five mischievous boys' behinds are meted out by four firm-handed educators during a road trip to Orlando, where the kids get tanned hotter then even sunny Florida's sun ever would. First, Todd not only failed to obey his dad's order to do laundry but brutally slammed the door of the dryer so hard that startled father TJ Wood, who was unloading the car, hit his head on the car door. Todd is taught is thought a lesson he won't be able to ignore during their time in Florida as it is hotly impressed on his humiliatingly bared hide while he is bend over the car for sparkling spankings, first by hand on his jeans, then on his shorts, and now his hide is warmed up by table tennis bat on the naked nates. Next, while Rick Black was resting on the couch after the long journey, his kid Todd has the bad idea to pop a balloon to wake him abruptly- just as quickly the insolent prankster is ordered over the knee for several spankings making sure he won't be comfortable either, and regrets his misbehavior sorely whenever anything touches his hiney, as he gets it good four times: first on his jean, then on his shorts, next on a wedgie and finally in utterly exposed total nudity. The next spankee, Justyn Summers, is a local who wants to be in a movie badly enough to consent to be spanked, a job Jeff Sternes never shirks, so he sits down on the side of the bed and bends him over the knee to spank his humble backside just like a bad boy's, first by hand on his jeans, then on the boxers and even stark-naked, and as finally he is order on all four on the bed for a hell-hot dose on his hot hide with a hard board. Finally there's Justin Gold and Brandon, who were good and went to their room where Brandon wanted to nap, when Justin's playful nature made him give his mate a few smacks, which causes them to start wrestling on the bed to get each-others boxers of and treat a bare butt as they were well-thought a boy's is meant to be: spanked, spanked and spanked again.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?465146</url></doc>
