<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="465980">
  <docid>465980</docid>
  <title>Rock &amp; Roll Jeopardy!</title>
  <year>1998</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Music</genre>
    <genre>Game-Show</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>non-fiction</keyword>
    <keyword>quiz-show</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">12 May 2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>McCarthy, Kevin (VII)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Friedman, Harry (I)</producer>
    <producer>Johnson, Gary (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Rhine, Jim</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kaplan, Steve (III)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brown, W. Earl</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Donaldson, Colby</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fox, Loretta</actor>
      <role>Announcer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Garrett, Brad (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Goen, Bob</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Griffin, Kathy</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kaye, Jagger</actor>
      <role>Winning Contestant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McKean, Michael (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Probst, Jeff</actor>
      <role>Host</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tauscher, Clint</actor>
      <role>Himself - Contestant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Varner, Jeff (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wohrman, Larry</actor>
      <role>Contestant</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>VH1's popular music variant of the classic game show with a twist. As always, contestants were given the answers, but it was up to the contestants to supply the questions. Three contestants competed; six categories, all music-related in some way, were announced, each containing five answers each (ranging from $100 to $500, depending on difficulty). The contestant selected to go first chose a category and dollar value (e.g., "Going to Work" for $100), to which host Probst read the answer to ("This Dolly Parton No. 1 hit was the title song of her movie, which she co-starred in with Jane Fonda and Lily Tomlin"). The contestant who gave the correct question ("What is '9 to 5?'") won the dollar value of the answer and got to select the next answer; any incorrect answer caused him to lose that amount from his score and allowed the other contestants a chance to answer; players with enough incorrect questions often had negative scores. Thereafter, the contestant giving the last correct question selected next; answers on "Rock &amp; Roll Jeopardy!" often made liberal use of audio and video clues. Hidden somewhere behind one of the answers was a "Daily Double," which allowed the contestant to bet up to all of his current winnings on an answer (or $500 if he had less than that amount), appropriately added or subtracted from his/her score. After all 30 answers were played (or an undefined time limit expired), the game moved into the second round, "Double Jeopardy," where six new categories of five questions each (now with values of $200 to $1,000) announced. The third-place player chose the first category and answer; hidden on the board were two "Daily Double" answers (where players could wager $1,000 if they didn't have that amount). At the end of the "Double Jeopardy" round, all players with at least $1 were allowed to play "Final Jeopardy"; contestants with $0 or negative scores were disqualified. Probst announced the category, to which the contestants wagered up to all their current winnings on their ability to provide the correct question. Contestants here were required here to write their answer in the form of a question (though the rule was enforced for Final Jeopardy!, Probst, unlike Fleming or Trebek, was sometimes more lenient with contestants about the phrasing rule during the Jeopardy! and Double Jeopardy! rounds). Contestants who answered correctly had their wager added to their score; incorrect answers, of course, or failing to phrase properly caused their wager to be deducted, frequently leading to $0 winnings. The day's highest money winner won $5,000 (or, in later years, the cash equivalent of their score if greater than $5,000, plus a $1,000 Sony card); the runners-up received consolation prizes. Celebrities from the pop music world frequently competed, donating their cash winnings to charity.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?465980</url></doc>
