<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="467836">
  <docid>467836</docid>
  <title>Ronald Reagan: The Hollywood Years, the Presidential Years</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Hagen, Kent</editor>
    <editor>Vosburgh, Steven</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">22 August 2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">104</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Pugliese, Dante J.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Miller, Jeff (VIII)</writer>
    <writer>Vosburgh, Steven</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Allyson, June</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cronkite, Walter</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dahl, Arlene</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Donaldson, Sam (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Flynn, Errol (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kissinger, Henry</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mayo, Virginia (I)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Meese, Ed</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Powell, Colin</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Reagan, Ronald (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Schwarzkopf, Norman</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>REAGAN: THE HOLLYWOOD YEARS will take a look at the actor as he goes from local sports broadcaster to respected leading an using film clips, interviews and rare footage. This one a kind documentary traces the ups and downs of his on-screen career, his marriages to Hane Wyman and Nancy Davis and his role as a "friendly witness" during the McCarthy hearings. Every picture from KINGS ROW and KNUTE ROCKNE to HELLCATS OF THE NAVY and THE KILLERS is covered including the star's appearances alongside Errol Flynn, fellow future politician Shirley Temple and a chimp named Bonzo. Interviews with June Allyson, Virginia Mayo and Arlene Dahl portray what Reagan was like on the set and at home. Athlete, soldier, movie star, statesman - REAGAN: THE HOLLYWOOD YEARS paints a remarkable picture of one of the most fascinating figures of the twentieth century. REAGAN: THE PRESIDENTIAL YEARS documents Ronald Reagan's extraordinary transformation from a Hollywood movie star to a legendary force in American politics. From political spokesman to Governor of California, Reagan's rapid rise in leadership carried him all the way to the White House where he would inscribe an indelible legacy into te pages of world history. Join Ed Meese, Sam Donaldson, General Colin Powell, General Norman Schwarzkopf, Dr. Henry Kissinger, Walter Cronkite and many other notables as they recount the life, the times and the policies of a man who symbolized an entire ear; REAGAN: THE PRESIDENTIAL YEARS.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?467836</url></doc>
