<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="470266">
  <docid>470266</docid>
  <title>Rulers of Half the World</title>
  <year>1902</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>prince</keyword>
    <keyword>denmark</keyword>
    <keyword>staircase</keyword>
    <keyword>car</keyword>
    <keyword>royal-castle</keyword>
    <keyword>princess</keyword>
    <keyword>king</keyword>
    <keyword>empress</keyword>
    <keyword>czar</keyword>
    <keyword>royal-family</keyword>
    <keyword>czarina</keyword>
    <keyword>queen</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">November 1902</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
<plot>This film is one of the most remarkable Biograph subjects ever obtained, and constitutes a moving picture not only immensely interesting but possessing the greatest historical value. It was taken by special royal permission on Sept. 10, 1901, at Fredensburg Castle, the residence of the King of Denmark, on the occasion of a birthday celebration of the ruler of Denmark. Our picture was taken from the Court of Honor, looking towards the grand staircase. The first portion of the scene reveals the little Royal Princesses' Olga and Tatiana of Russia descending the steps, accompanied by Court officials. A few minutes later their Majesties appear, and after observing with interest the photographic proceedings, enter the carriages which successively drive up to receive them. In the first carriage is to be seen the King of Denmark, the Queen of England, the Czar and Czarina of Russia. In the second carriage, King Edward VII of England, the Dowager Empress of Russia, King George of Greece, and the Prince Royal of Denmark.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?470266</url></doc>
