<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="471291">
  <docid>471291</docid>
  <title>Rustom Sohrab</title>
  <year>1963</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Urdu</language>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Bedekar, Vishram</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ramsay, F.U.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Ramsay, Kumar</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Hussain, Sajjan</composer>
    <composer>Sajjad (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Agha, Shah</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Azad (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hiralal (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kailash, P. (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Prithviraj</actor>
      <role>Rustom Zabuli</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lillian (II)</actor>
      <role>Homa</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Murad</actor>
      <role>Mazadan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nath, Prem (I)</actor>
      <role>Sohrab</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sajjan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Powerful and mighty Rustom Zabuli (Prithviraj Kapoor) of Iran while on a visit to India,rescues a horse-drawn carriage of Shehzadi Tehmina (Suraiya). Impressed by his strength, the Shehzadi offers to employ him, but Rustom refuses. The Shehzadi has his horse abducted and brought to her palace, Rustom follows. Once there, the Shehzadi confesses her love for Rustom, and Rustom too falls in love with her. They are married with great pomp. Due to war in Iran, Rustom must return to defend his king. The Shehzadi's enemies plot to overthrow her father and her, but Shehzadi manages to escape. She gives birth to a son. She must never reveal her husband's true identity to her son or else he will be killed. So Rustom's son, Sohrab (Premnath) grows up without any knowledge of his mighty and famous father. The Shehzadi's enemies now aware of Sohrab, who has acquired his father's strength and might, plot to make both father and son fight, a fight from which only one man can emerge alive and victorious.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?471291</url></doc>
