<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="472723">
  <docid>472723</docid>
  <title>Saan darating ang umaga?</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Filipino</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Philippines</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Philippines">10 November 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>De Los Reyes, Maryo J.</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Amador, Pinky</actor>
      <role>Agatha Rodrigo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Davao, Charlie</actor>
      <role>Leonardo Rodrigo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Estrada, Gary (I)</actor>
      <role>Dindo Rodrigo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fuentes, Shirley</actor>
      <role>Mylene</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ignacio, Dion</actor>
      <role>Raul</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kurdi, Yasmien</actor>
      <role>Shayne Rodrigo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mercado, Lani</actor>
      <role>Lorrie Rodrigo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Montes, Jacob</actor>
      <role>Joel Rodrigo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Torre, Joel</actor>
      <role>Ruben Rodrigo</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Saan darating ang Umaga? is about the Rodrigo clan led by the powerful patriarch Leonardo. Leonardo is a wealthy businessman who is very proud of his humble beginnings. It was only through hard work and diligence that he was able to achieve all the luxuries in life. Today, he is one of the most respected and well known businessmen in the real estate business. And because of this he also expects his two sons to Dindo and Ruben to follow his lead. Dindo and Ruben are architects working for their father's company. But it was Ruben who took after his father's ideals and compassion for the business. Not only is he talented but he is kind-hearted. He is a loving to Lorrie and a caring father to his daughter Shayne. Dindo, meanwhile, is the opposite of Ruben. He and his wife Agatha are very dependent and still live with Leonardo. Aside from not having a child, Dindo has been rumored for having an extramarital affair with his secretary Mylene. When Leonardo passes away, the Rodrigo patriarch leaves all his wealth as well as the firm to Ruben. But unknown to Ruben, his father's last will marks the beginning of a series of misfortune in their family. Ruben and Lorrie have been longing to have another child since their only daughter Shayne is already a teenager. However, they will find out that Lorrie can no longer bear a child, leading them to adopt a young boy named Joel. Joel's presence provides an overwhelming happiness to Lorrie and Ruben. But it will be the beginning of Shayne's rebellion when she begins to feel neglected. Shayne will then meet Raul who will give her the attention she has been looking for from her parents. Will Ruben and his family survive all the misfortunes coming their way? Can Ruben keep his family from falling apart? Will Joel be a target by Dindo and Agatha to amass the wealth they have been longing for? What if Joel, the source of happiness of Lorrie and Ruben, becomes the source of the family's grief later on?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?472723</url></doc>
