<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="473538">
  <docid>473538</docid>
  <title>Safe</title>
  <year>2011</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2011</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <producers>
    <producer>O'Brien, Caroline (II)</producer>
    <producer>McMenamin, Paul</producer>
    <producer>Palminteri, Chazz</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Vetere, Richard</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Palminteri, Chazz</actor>
      <role>Eddie</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Eddie Tucci's final score just might get him killed but, for once in his life he's willing to take a chance. A slick safe cracker and career thief, Eddie is a dying breed. He's always made a practice of using his instincts to guide him through a career stealing thousands from unsuspecting businesses. Unfortunately, one week changes everything for his family, as his brother Jack convinces him to take down a safe at a business he was warned about. When Jack is unable to get out in time, he's caught by the police and is sentenced to 10 years, leaving his wife Melissa and son Wayne to continue with a life on the wrong side of the law. In comes detective Ralph Parisi, a local cop who's targeted Eddie, whose official record is as clean as Mother Teresa's, as public enemy number one. With Jack gone, Eddie decides to put together his last big score using his nephew Wayne, an aspiring young thief. As is turns out Melissa has an idea of her own. She approaches Eddie with the opportunity of a lifetime; take down a late mobster's hidden stash which could be worth millions. Eddie finds himself crossing the line when he professes his feelings for Melissa and learns that her feelings are mutual. There's only one problem now, with Jack doing time Eddie needs a new partner and finds himself working with Wayne and his firecracker of a girlfriend Jennifer. Against every instinct Eddie takes the mobsters stash down but Detective Parisi gets tipped off. In a last and desperate effort, Parisi attempts to put Eddie away for good by making Melissa an offer she can't refuse. Get your husband back, your son off of the hook and give me Eddie. The stakes are high, the rewards are higher and no one wants to play it safe.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?473538</url></doc>
