<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="473824">
  <docid>473824</docid>
  <title>Sahara no se vende</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Gorostiaga, Aritz</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>human-rights-abuse</keyword>
    <keyword>decolonization</keyword>
    <keyword>sahara</keyword>
    <keyword>occupation</keyword>
    <keyword>morocco</keyword>
    <keyword>western-sahara</keyword>
    <keyword>spain</keyword>
    <keyword>land-conflict</keyword>
    <keyword>front-polisario</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Spain">7</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Spain">5 October 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Spain">84</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Arellano, Luis (II)</producer>
    <producer>Calderón, Joaquín (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Arellano, Luis (II)</writer>
    <writer>Calderón, Joaquín (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Pastor, Gorka</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>In April 2007, during the celebration of the 4th edition of Sahara International Film Festival, three friends embark on the adventure of running a photography workshop for young refugees in the refugee camp of Dajla in south Algeria. The pictures produced by the seventeen participants in the course allow them to discover a rather striking reality, how after thirty three years of waiting in the Hammada, the most inhospitable area of the Algerian desert, the Saharawi refugees are in a critical situation, on the verge of desperation with no patience left and ready to resume the armed struggle against the occupying Moroccan forces A very dynamic and fresh editing is accompanied with rhythms and superb songs from well renowned international artists in order to create a superb language that takes us closer to the forgotten Saharawi people, a people with an unclear future. The film is a visual trip through the history of the Saharawi people and its situation on the refugee camps in south Algeria and the keys for the future of a conflict that lasts for over 33 years.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?473824</url></doc>
