<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="475225">
  <docid>475225</docid>
  <title>Sam and Max Hit the Road</title>
  <year>1993</year>
  <type>VideoGame</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Mystery</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>midget</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Clark, Sean (I)</director>
    <director>Stemmle, Michael</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Clark, Sean (I)</producer>
    <producer>Stemmle, Michael</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Purcell, Steve (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Bajakian, Clint</composer>
    <composer>Land, Michael (I)</composer>
    <composer>McConnell, Peter (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Clark, Marsha</actor>
      <role>Trixie the Giraffe-Necked Girl/Evelyn Morrison</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Delk, Denny</actor>
      <role>Shep Kushman/Burl Kushman/Lee Harvey</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Farmer, Bill (I)</actor>
      <role>Sam/Psychic/Flambe/Vanuatoo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jameson, Nick</actor>
      <role>Max/World of Fish fisherman/Various</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Keyes, Irwin</actor>
      <role>Bruno</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pope, Tony</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The year is 1950 and Sam and Max are a pair of detectives somewhere in New York. While Sam is a no nonsense, dry humored, drab individual, his bizarre life is kept interesting by partner Max, a perverse and sadistic midget with a psychotic sense of humor, violent tendencies and a swearing fetish. Living in a rundown office building/office, they pass through life day by day off of saved money from their glory days, and spend time watching TV and participating in other strange activities as they wait for an assignment. One day, after a dry spell of employment, Sam and Max are called to the scene of a kidnapping at a local tourist trap. It seems two human oddities, a Bigfoot and a giraffe necked girl, have been kidnapped, and the Siamese twin brothers, who are no stranger then the oddities they promote, are paying a large cash sum up front for the return of their prized possessions. From there Sam and Max must travel across country in search of the two, as well as contend with a rock and roll musician who may be responsible for the demise of the Bigfoot.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?475225</url></doc>
