<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="475476">
  <docid>475476</docid>
  <title>Same Room, Same Time</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Figueiredo, António</editor>
    <editor>Gaudêncio, Miguel</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Portugal</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Portugal">30 January 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Portugal">25</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Gaudêncio, Miguel</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Valente, Alexandre</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Draper, Tommy</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jerónimo, Albano</actor>
      <role>Man</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A young professional worker in a fast moving contemporary metropolis, his life is fast and his needs are complex: he has a regular girlfriend but he wants more, he needs more, although he has no time for love, romance or the emotional intimacy that characterizes conventional relationships. Thus he has engineered the perfect arrangement to suit his lifestyle: every week he meets the same woman in the same swish hotel suite for a hot sexual transaction that both players enjoy for free. But on this particular occasion the woman seems troubled. She has grown dissatisfied with the purely physical nature of the relationship; her heart is crying out for more and her voice is now speaking for her heart. The man grows increasingly frustrated by her demands for something more than what had been initially agreed, which leads her to more desperate measures than either of them had ever dreamed possible. As tensions begin to fray and tempers flare the narrative races toward a double, final confrontation.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?475476</url></doc>
