<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="475559">
  <docid>475559</docid>
  <title>Sammen</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Morheden, Mattias</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>child-welfare</keyword>
    <keyword>death-of-mother</keyword>
    <keyword>father-son-relationship</keyword>
    <keyword>grief</keyword>
    <keyword>mourning</keyword>
    <keyword>sorrow</keyword>
    <keyword>loss-of-wife</keyword>
    <keyword>death-of-wife</keyword>
    <keyword>orphanage</keyword>
    <keyword>mother-son-relationship</keyword>
    <keyword>family-relationships</keyword>
    <keyword>husband-wife-relationship</keyword>
    <keyword>accident</keyword>
    <keyword>love</keyword>
    <keyword>loss-of-mother</keyword>
    <keyword>one-word-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Norwegian</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Norway</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Norway">11</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Spain">September 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Norway">23 January 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Canada">14 September 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Norway">100</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Jordal, Matias Armand</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ween, Odd</producer>
    <producer>Rysstad, Tom</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Jordal, Matias Armand</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Söderqvist, Johan</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Espolin, Jonathan</actor>
      <role>Man in bar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Såheim, Fridtjov</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Waage, Odin</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A family of a father, a mother and their son is looking forward to go on vacation. On the way they experience an accident, and their lives are suddenly and unexpectedly turned upside down. This is a story about a father and his son's journey through a landscape of sorrow, after they tragically lose the one person they love the most. It's about how they deal with their new everyday life without her, and their strain to win control over the new situation. The woman who dies was the "glue" that kept the family together, and without her they feel like they have to make a new start, a situation that exhausts them both. They realize that they haven't spent much time together, and have a hard time trying to communicate with each other. Even simple things like making a meal becomes a challenge. The father experience the loss of this woman so strongly that he isn't able to pull himself together and take responsibility of his own and his son's life. In pure desperation he meets with the children welfare service, and when his son is temporarily sent to an orphanage, he isolates himself from his surroundings and rejects every attempt for contact, even from his own son. But the son refuses to give up hope that they can become a family again, and fights bravely to get his father back to life. The film is a drama about loss and love, told in a realistic style with a great deal of humour and warmth.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?475559</url></doc>
