<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="477859">
  <docid>477859</docid>
  <title>Sarfarosh-E-Hind</title>
  <year>1999</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Pillay, E.P.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">1999</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Kaushal, D.R.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kaushal, D.R.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Kaushal, D.R.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Khan, G.A.</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ali, Ishrat</actor>
      <role>Ansari</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Amrapurkar, Sadashiv</actor>
      <role>Chief Minister Bandrekar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bakshi, Arun</actor>
      <role>Crippled soldier</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Behl, Ravi</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Desai, Meghna</actor>
      <role>Reporter Megha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dhawan, Siddharth</actor>
      <role>Raj Bandrekar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jalota, Anup</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Satyendra</actor>
      <role>Kamath</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kher, Anupam</actor>
      <role>DCP Arun Bedi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Kiran (I)</actor>
      <role>Ranjit Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lever, Johnny</actor>
      <role>Babu Khabardar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Madhu (IX)</actor>
      <role>Inspector Shalu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mohan, Ram (I)</actor>
      <role>Bandrekar's associate</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>55 years after attaining independence from the British, India still continues to struggle against issues such as crime, poverty, malnourishment, and corruption. A honest businessman Ranjit Singh, who is forced to bribe the State Chief Minister, Bandrekar, and a Pakistani ISI Agent, Ansari, so that he can open an arms factory; Megha, a press reporter, who witnesses the death of 3 terrorists at the hands of Raj, the son of the Chief Minister; D.C.P. Arun Bedi, who at one time was known as the Sarfaresh-E-Hind, is now a mere tool in the hands of his politically-motivated superiors and politicians; Ranjit's son, Amar, who is a college student, gets killed by terrorists; Pappu, the Chief Minister's married son, carries on with a number of prostitutes in his residence; and a crippled soldier sings and bemoans the regression everywhere. Amidst this background, Raj recalls that his father had killed his mother during his childhood, and has him arrested - knowing fully well that his father is a man who had not hesitated to kill his wife, will not surely spare him. The question remains: Will the authorities be able to protect the son against the father? And who will even attempt to stop Ansari from inflicting sectarian and religious violence?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?477859</url></doc>
