<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="478473">
  <docid>478473</docid>
  <title>Satta Bazaar</title>
  <year>1959</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Dave, Ravindra</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Dave, Ravindra</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Abbas, Khwaja Ahmad</writer>
    <writer>Dave, Mohanlal G.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Shah, Anandji Veerji</composer>
    <composer>Shah, Kalyanji Veerji</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Choudhury, Savita</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Choudhury, Vijaya</actor>
      <role>Kala</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dutt, Uma</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Krishnakant (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumari, Meena (I)</actor>
      <role>Jamuna</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moolchand</actor>
      <role>Chamanlal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sahni, Balraj</actor>
      <role>Ramesh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sen, Asit (I)</actor>
      <role>Bholanath</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Suresh (II)</actor>
      <role>Shyam</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tiwari, Ramayan</actor>
      <role>Badriprasad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Walker, Johnny (III)</actor>
      <role>Jagat</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Widower Ramesh lives a comfortable lifestyle with his daughter, Kala, but is advised to re-marry so that Kala can get the love and caring of a mother, so he re-marries Jamuna. But Kala hates Jamuna and will not even call her "Maa", but Jamuna continues to strive to care and love her as her own, despite of giving birth to a baby boy. Years pass by, Kala has now grown up, is in love with Ramesh's business partner, Bholanath's son, Shyam, who are of a different caste. Ramesh disapproves, but Jamuna convinces him otherwise, and the couple get formerly engaged. After the engagement, Ramesh gets to meet multi-millionaire Badriprasad, who accumulated wealth through the stock exchange. Ramesh takes a interest and invests heavily, he does win some money, but his luck soon changes when he loses everything. He is on the verge of bankruptcy, and the only man who can save him now is Badriprasad on one condition - that Kala must marry his son, Pritam. Will Ramesh agree to this trade, and break Kala's heart and her engagement with Shyam?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?478473</url></doc>
