<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="478442">
  <docid>478442</docid>
  <title>Satori Stress</title>
  <year>1984</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Rysselinck, Monique</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>love</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Japanese</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Belgium</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Belgium">KT</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">75</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Gobron, Jean-Noël (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Gobron, Jean-Noël (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Donato, Nicola</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gobron, Jean-Noël (I)</actor>
      <role>Jean-Noël</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Inamura, Akiko</actor>
      <role>Akiko</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Leaving Europe to look for Akiko, Jean-Noël discovers her city, the exotic Tokyo. A documentary on everyday life in Tokyo, its KABUKI theater, its nostalgic TAKENOKOZOKU dances, its thousands of suit-and-tie executives, its geishas, its Western style marriages, its tranquil green areas, its pulsating nightlife... Yet, the commentary, which deliberately often strays away from the images, throws into question the objectivity of the documentary film. Here, what we see is inseparable from the experience of its young maker as he cast a loving eye on a people and its culture. GRAND PRIX NATIONAL DU FILM DE REPORTAGE ET D'AVENTURE 1984 ORIGINALITÉ DE L'AVENTURE VÉCUE ORIGINALITÉ DU MONTAGE MEILLEUR COMMENTAIRE Parti à la recherche d'Akiko, Jean-Noël découvre sa ville, Tokyo l'exotique. Documentaire sur la vie quotidienne à Tokyo, ses nuits chaudes, son théâtre KABUKI, ses danses nostalgiques de TAKENOKOZOKU, ses milliers de cadres cravatés, ses geishas, ses mariages à l'occidentale, ses quartiers campagnards... Mais le commentaire, en un décalage délibéré par rapport à l'image met en question toute l'objectivité du document filmé. La vision ici est inséparable du vécu du jeune réalisateur qui pose sur un peuple et une culture un regard amoureux. Fictional documentary by Jean-Noël Gobron Length: 75' - 16 mm &amp; 1" - colour French or English version - 1984</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?478442</url></doc>
