<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="478448">
  <docid>478448</docid>
  <title>Satrangi</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>pakistan</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Urdu</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Pakistan</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Pakistan">May 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">18</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Shahzad, Anjum</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ahmad, Zohaib</actor>
      <role>Rayan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ali, Agha</actor>
      <role>Khayyam</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ansari, Hamza</actor>
      <role>Shehzore</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gul, Ambreen</actor>
      <role>Rushna</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gul, Sehar</actor>
      <role>Bisma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Fawad</actor>
      <role>Behzaad</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Behzaad is a filthy rich guy who is always at daggers drawn with his busy lawyer father. Neshmia is a middle class girl who has stopped seeing eye to eye with her mother ever since she remarried. Rayan is a middle class guy with white-collared job. Shehzore is from a remote village who believes urban life was invented for him! Khayyam thinks he is a musician who has yet to find his instrument and his style of music. Rushna is a girl who stopped acting like a girl long time ago! Bisma is more in need of love than being in search of love. These seven people embark on a journey of a lifetime. Behzaad builds a special bus for this purpose. These youngsters board it and leave from Karachi. Superficially, for all of them, this is just a tour that will take them to Khyber in just three days. But actually, the travel stretches to months as each one discovers that everyone on this journey has a lot of emotional baggage. And, more importantly, they don't have to be together to form rainbow! ..... Actually, EACH one of them is rainbow!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?478448</url></doc>
