<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="479334">
  <docid>479334</docid>
  <title>Sawt-e-Sarmad: The Sound That Intoxicates Man</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Grace, Terrance</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">6 April 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">27</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Grace, Terrance</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Grace, Terrance</producer>
    <producer>Rahman, Zeyba</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Grace, Terrance</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Music remains the one universal language that every human inhabits. It requires no interpretation, and yet it's simplicity of spirit and importance to the soul is often overlooked by it's definition as genre: Pop; World; Classical; Jazz. At it's essence, music is the first and most precious act of nature. For man, it is the path to the divine. Sawt-e-Sarmad or The Sound That Intoxicates Man, according to Sufi tradition, is abstract by nature. It's vibrations exist on another level, too fine to be seen or heard. In Morocco, The Fes Festival Of World Sacred Music gathers musicians and thinkers from many faiths and traditions in an attempt to seek out this cosmic symphony, both on stage, and in forums for dialogue on pressing global issues. This work is a visual and aural interpretation of the space that for many, remains undefined. Like the medieval medina of Fes, it is a journey through a labyrinth of color and texture, with winding paths that abruptly end with the sudden and miraculous opening of the beginning.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?479334</url></doc>
