<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="479931">
  <docid>479931</docid>
  <title>Scattergories</title>
  <year>1993</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Game-Show</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>non-fiction</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">26 January 1993</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Dawson, Mitt</producer>
    <producer>Sussman, Sharon</producer>
    <producer>Noah, Robert</producer>
    <producer>Wheeler, Burt</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Clark, Dick (I)</actor>
      <role>Host</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lahoda, Leslie</actor>
      <role>Juror</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sussman, Steve</actor>
      <role>Juror</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tuna, Charlie</actor>
      <role>Announcer</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"Scattegories" was a short-lived attempt to cash in on the popular Hasbro board game of the same name. Two teams of four contestants each, one all males and the other all females (one a returning championship team), competed. Host Clark announced a category (e.g., something found in a refrigerator); the team chosen to go first were given a letter (e.g., S) and had 20 seconds to list up to six items in that category, with each response worth 1 point. The opposing team could then challenge any of the responses for any reason; if a majority of the jury (a gallery composed of 12 former contestants) agreed, that answer was deleted and 1 point deducted from the score. Then, the pre-taped answers from five celebrities were played. The team earned 2 points if the celebrity gave a different answer, while they lost 2 points if the celebrity's answer was the same. After play finished on that question, the other team played the same category using a different letter. A second round, with double point values, was played with a new category. The team leading at the end of the second round won $500 and played a bonus round. In the bonus round, a new category was announced and five letters shown; the team had 25 seconds to list 10 words, two words for each letter. Each celebrity's pre-taped response was played; if at least three celebrities gave different responses than those given by the team of contestants, the team won a cash bonus (which began at $4,000 and increased by $1,000 per show until claimed); otherwise, the team won $200 per celebrity not matched.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?479931</url></doc>
