<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="480208">
  <docid>480208</docid>
  <title>Schat</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Vos, Sander</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Dutch</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Netherlands">25 September 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Netherlands">10</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>van den Dop, Tamar</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>De Jesus, Sherman</producer>
    <producer>van Eijk, Cécile</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bax, Wim</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Holt, Klaas ten</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Acda, Thomas</actor>
      <role>Brother in law</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Borreman, Gustav</actor>
      <role>Man</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Buit, Bodhy</actor>
      <role>Cousin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Koole, Ricky</actor>
      <role>Sister</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Latin, Daniel</actor>
      <role>Dancing man</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Latin, Isabel</actor>
      <role>Dancing woman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Meerman, Karin</actor>
      <role>Mother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nooter, Michiel</actor>
      <role>Best friend</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Eva is beautiful, successful and single. On her 35th birthday, her friends give her as a special gift the only thing she doesn't have but always wanted. A man. But the question is, how best to use him? Fortunately, he comes complete with an owner's manual. Eva decides he should first clean up after the party, then make himself a bed on the sofa. The next morning, he surprises her with breakfast. When later Eva finds him taking a shower she is shocked by the sight of his nakedness. Eva becomes more appreciative when she sees how popular the gift is with her family. It begins to occur to her that at last she may have found the ideal man. Even so, soon his cheery kindnesses start getting on her nerves and she impulsively decides she simply must return him. Eva is surprised to regret sending him back. After searching the dark city in vain, she realizes how much she misses him. Never before has she been happier than finding him at home waiting for her. At last the kiss. In the morning, Eva wakes up in his arms. This gift is for real, but just as she is finally able to accept this man, something disconcerting happens...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?480208</url></doc>
