<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="482518">
  <docid>482518</docid>
  <title>Se &amp; inse</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Guwallius, Kolbjörn</editor>
    <editor>Monke, Styrbjörn</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Swedish</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Sweden</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Sweden">29 April 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Sweden">14</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Guwallius, Kolbjörn</director>
    <director>Monke, Styrbjörn</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Guwallius, Kolbjörn</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Guwallius, Kolbjörn</writer>
    <writer>Monke, Styrbjörn</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Byström, Clara</actor>
      <role>Julia Eriksson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Citron, Ola</actor>
      <role>Ove N Dahlman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Johansson, Sofia (II)</actor>
      <role>Julia's friend</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Löfkvist, Jens</actor>
      <role>A young man</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A black comedy shaded a little towards yellow-green. Julia Eriksson is a 25 year old girl who has been working in different service occupations, like most young people. Although she is indeed educated, she can't get a real job in her profession due to the current situation on the job market. When she is once again unemployed after a short deputy job, she decides to attend to her situation herself - she is starting her own business. Whilst not having any real money to begin with, she turns to the government's employment agency to apply for a grant to start her own company, a service available in special circumstances in Sweden. Employment officer Ove N Dahlman is a man who does his job, and he's good at it, too. He gives people real work and he's proud to help. He knows that he is good at finding "the right man for the right spot" and has no thoughts whatsoever that people would in fact have any will of their own. It is to Ove that Julia comes this cold winter morning. As if it the clash would't suffice, Julia had forgotten all about her meeting and happened to drink a few too many beers the night before. Obviously, she's not at all set for the happening...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?482518</url></doc>
