<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="483123">
  <docid>483123</docid>
  <title>Seasons of Change: The African American Athlete</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>History</genre>
    <genre>Sport</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">8 February 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Winn, Jeff (III)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Puner, David</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Puner, David</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ali, Muhammad (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jones, Marion (II)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McCray, Nikki</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McNair, Steve</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Saunders, John (IV)</actor>
      <role>Himself - Host</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Scott, Charlie (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shell, Art</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Smith, Kenny (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Smith, Tommie</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stewart, Dave (V)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>As part of ESPN's 2002 Black History Month programming, this show honors some of the "foot soldiers" of sports - the second and third generation of barrier breakers who continued the fight on the fields and courts of America. In the 50s and 60s, as the Civil Rights Movement escalated and began to level the playing field for all Americans, a small group of Black athletes were conducting their own non-violent revolution. This program pays tribute to the lives and careers of the second wave of Black athletes. In this roundtable program, we learn about the achievements of second generation athletes Charlie Scott, Tommie Smith, Dave Stewart, and Art Shell; superstars who toiled under a sometimes subtle and sometimes overt racism - but who helped to create an environment where today's superstars thrive largely on their ability alone. We also hear about their experiences on the frontlines of change in the sporting world. The show brings their contemporary counterparts - younger players (Kenny Smith, Steve McNair, Nikki McCray, and Marion Jones) - who have benefited from their careers. The two generations of superstars engage in a discussion of life as a Black athlete and the issues still facing players of color. The often untold part of the story is simply "so then what happened?" Jackie Robinson opened the door, but Hank Aaron entered the room; Barry Bonds calls the place his own. By bringing together the latter two generations, Seasons of Change: The African American Athlete creates an awareness of the battles that were fought and those yet to be won.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?483123</url></doc>
