<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="483810">
  <docid>483810</docid>
  <title>Secrets</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Durham, Maurice</editor>
    <editor>Young, Elgin</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">37</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Durham, Maurice</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Durham, Maurice</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bell, Lela</actor>
      <role>Rosa Alizonda</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Davila, Gerardo</actor>
      <role>Husband</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fauntleroy, Walter</actor>
      <role>Rapist</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Favors, Darian</actor>
      <role>Man in yard</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hilliard, Channez</actor>
      <role>Young girl</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hilliard, Xzavier</actor>
      <role>1st Boy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jackson, Gregory (IV)</actor>
      <role>Captain Sam Wesley</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lowe, Darius</actor>
      <role>2nd Boy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>O'Neill, Dennis (I)</actor>
      <role>Policeman</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Jamie Starks, a determined newspaper reporter, becomes enthralled in a serial rapist case in her neighborhood. After an emotional meeting with Rosa, one of the attacker's latest victims, Jamie becomes suspicion of Rosa's neighbor who eyes her suspiciously as she leaves the woman's home. Later that night, a noise summons Jamie downstairs to investigate. Just when she feels she can relax again, she is grabbed from behind by an intruder. Jamie is gruesomely attached and tortured as Rosa, who has decided to grant Jamie's request for a detailed description of her own story, narrates her experiences unknowing that the woman herself has fallen victim to an eerily similar fate. The rapist tortures Jamie, forcing her to her knees and crawling over to where he sits on her bed. Later, he stands and spins the woman around before knocking her onto the bed. The man mauls the woman through the night. Rosa finishes writing about her ordeal and heads in for the night. Jamie suffers for hours through the ordeal with the man, until finally, she passes out. But the heartless man is relentless as he continues to pound her lifeless body. The next morning, Jamie awakens to find the man gone, but she is unable to finish dialing the three numbers that will bring the authorities. After getting into the shower, she suddenly remembers that she has seen the man who attacked her before.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?483810</url></doc>
