<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="483911">
  <docid>483911</docid>
  <title>Secrets of a Sorority Girl</title>
  <year>1945</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Livingston, Roy V.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>pretty-girl</keyword>
    <keyword>gambling</keyword>
    <keyword>blackmail</keyword>
    <keyword>police-officer-killed</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Austria">1949</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">15 August 1945</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">58</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Landers, Lew</director>
    <director>Wisbar, Frank</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Alexander, Max (I)</producer>
    <producer>Stern, Alfred</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Sayre, George Wallace</writer>
    <writer>St. Claire, Arthur</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ferguson, Frank (I)</actor>
      <role>Justin Farley</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harmon, Marie</actor>
      <role>Judy O'Neill</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hugo, Mauritz</actor>
      <role>Charles Stevens</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>James, Rosemonde</actor>
      <role>Carol Miller</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Johnson, Marilyn (I)</actor>
      <role>Jeannie Cooper</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kenyon, Mary</actor>
      <role>Barbara Chase</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Marsh, Caren</actor>
      <role>Audrey Scott</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Murphy, William (I)</actor>
      <role>Andy Jones</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Richards, Addison</actor>
      <role>John Hamilton</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vallin, Rick</actor>
      <role>Paul Reynolds</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vogan, Emmett</actor>
      <role>Joseph Kelland</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Walker, Ray (I)</actor>
      <role>Whitey King</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Warde, Anthony</actor>
      <role>Nick Vegas</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Watkin, Pierre</actor>
      <role>Dr. Harlan Johnson</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Linda Hamilton (Mary Ware), president of Alpha Beta Sorority and Conover College campus queen, faints while at a sorority party in the company of ex-reporter Paul Reynolds (Rick Vallin), who is taking a post-graduate course. Linda learns from doctors that she has only one year to live but hesitates in telling her father, District Attorney Hamilton (Addison Richards), who is devoting his energies to wiping out illegal gambling. Linda goes with Paul to the Blue Parrot Cabaret, a notorious gambling den. Bail bondsman Justin Farley (Frank Ferguson) telephones casino owner Nick Vegas (Anthony Warde) that the police are about to make a raid and Vegas, knowing Linda is the district attorney's daughter, takes pictures of her. Several nights later, Paul takes Linda to another gambling house and more pictures are taken showing her at the roulette table and drinking. Realizing that she has hurt her father by going to the places he is trying to exterminate, she still goes to a plave ran by Whitey King (Ray Walker.) Reynolds arrives and he and Whitey get into a fight which is interrupted by a raid. Paul rescues Linda, who has been knocked unconscious. A motorcycle cop chases Paul's car and is killed when he runs into the car after Paul brakes sharply. Paul revives Linda and tells her she had been driving the car (quickly justifying the belief of audience members that no Rick Vallin character could stay heroic through a whole film.) Paul then goes to Linda with the pictures and reveals he is the secret leader of the gambling rackets, and tells her to ask her father to resign or he will give the newspapers the pictures. She refuses and Paul goes to civic committee meeting, where Mr. Hamilton is being proposed to run for governor, and shows him and other officials the pictures, plus Linda's stolen diary in which she has written about the wreck with the motorcycle policeman. Hamilton arrest his daughter and she is put on trial for the killing. Probably not a big deal to one who has only a few more months to live...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?483911</url></doc>
