<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="484545">
  <docid>484545</docid>
  <title>Seema</title>
  <year>1955</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Joshi, D.B.</editor>
  </editors>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">U</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <directors>
    <director>Chakrabarty, Amiya</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Chakrabarty, Amiya</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Chakrabarty, Amiya</writer>
    <writer>Chandrakant (V)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Pankal, Jaikishan Dayabhai</composer>
    <composer>Raghuwanshi, Shankarsinh</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ajay (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ali, Mamtaj</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Behl, Nutan</actor>
      <role>Gauri</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deep, Premlata</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Devi, Pratima</actor>
      <role>Superintendent "didi"</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dubey, C.S.</actor>
      <role>Banke Lal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kamal, Neel (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khote, Shubha</actor>
      <role>Putli</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Krishnakant (I)</actor>
      <role>Radha's Husband</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Raj, Jagdish</actor>
      <role>Doctor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sahni, Balraj</actor>
      <role>Ashok 'Babuji'</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shivraj (I)</actor>
      <role>Kashinath</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Singh, G.B. (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sunder (I)</actor>
      <role>Murlidhar</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>After her parents pass away, teenager Gauri goes to live with her paternal uncle, Kashinath, and his wife. She is ill-treated there, made to do all the housework, and abused by her aunt. She is also asked to work as a servant for meager wages in another household, and her earnings are taken away by her aunt. One day, Kashinath is summoned to the Police Station where he is told that since Gauri has been convicted of stealing a necklace from her employer, she is placed under his care for 12 months. Kashinath undertakes to look after her, but she manages to escape, and beats up Bankelal, who had originally accused her of stealing the necklace. The Police are summoned again, and this time Gauri is placed with Shree Satyanand Anarthalaya, an orphanage run by a compassionate Manager, Ashok. Gauri revolts against all the rules imposed upon her and she is placed in solitary, where she ends up breaking all the windows and furniture. Then one day she escapes, beats up Bankelal severely, and returns back. She is once again placed in solitary. Then Ashok and his associate Murlidhar find out that Bankelal had framed Gauri, and they inform the Police, who make Bankelal confess. In this way, Gauri gets a pardon, and is asked to leave the orphanage, but she refuses to do so and stays on after promising that she will always obey Ashok. When Ashok has a heart attack, she proposes to stay and look after him, but Ashok wants her to leave and get married to Murlidhar. The question remains, will Gauri disobey Ashok or keep her promise and get married to Murlidhar?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?484545</url></doc>
