<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="487386">
  <docid>487386</docid>
  <title>Seulpeun yeonga</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>tv-mini-series</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Korean</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>South Korea</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="South Korea">5 January 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <producers>
    <producer>No, David (I)</producer>
    <producer>Yong, Yoo Chul</producer>
    <producer>Leonard, Terry (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Eun, Lee Sung</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jin, Hee-kyung</actor>
      <role>Audrey</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jo, Kyeong-hwan (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kang, Nam-kil</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kim, Hee-seon</actor>
      <role>Hae-in</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kim, Yeon Joo</actor>
      <role>Hwa-Jung</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kwone, Sang-woo</actor>
      <role>Joon-young/Joon-kyu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Renni-Calliope, Christopher</actor>
      <role>Richard-Waiter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Yeon, Jeong-hun</actor>
      <role>Gun-woo</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Hye-In was blind when she was born, Jun-Young's mother work in night clubs and make Jun-Young being laughed by friends. Once Jun-Young and Hye-In walked together, Hye-In gave Jun-Young a sliver card badge with her name "Hye-In". Hye-In's aunt, Audrey, took Jun-Young's mother(all cash) and bring Hye-In and left Jun-Young. Jun-Young (Sang-Woo Kwone) grew up, with mother died, father re-married. the remarried mother took all Jun-Young's money away, and Jun-Young has to work in construction sites to earn money for his college studies. He met Lee Gun-Woo (Yeon Jeong-Hoon, originally Song Seung-Heun) and Gun-Woo also met Hye-In in the street in USA, just outside Harvord University. Gun-Woo buy Hye-In new dress, and gave Hye-In money so Hye-In could see again. Hye-In open her eyes, saw Gun-Woo, she didn't know that Jun-Young is still alive, and began to love Gun-Woo. Gun-Woo told Jun-Young to meet his new girl. Jun-Young saw Hye-In, lost control. Hwa-Jung, the cheerleader of Jun-Young's class, only loves Jun-Young. But Jun-Young doesn't love Hwa-Jung. Hwa-Jung even return Hye-In's USA letters to Hye-In, make Hye-In commit suicide. Audrey met Willie, the USA sailor, but he was mad, and crazy, drunk easily and even horny. He even rape Hye-In. Jun-Young saved Hye-In from some bad guys when Hye-In was captured on a street (waiting Jun-Young) with her teddy bear. Jun-Young finally played the "sad Sonata" to make Hye-In to recognize himself. Gun-Woo was angry that Jun-Young and Hye-In are known before and even love together. Jun-Young ask Gun-Woo to hit himself, but Gun-Woo force both Hye-In and Jun-Young to leave away from himself as far as they could go. Gun-Woo inherit father's business and offended a Korean company boss. the boss sent a killer to plan to kill Gun-Woo but finally Joon-Young took that bullet up. Gun-Woo ask friend to send Joon-Young to hospital. Doctor said Joon-Young had his kidneys destroyed and must have immediate operation to save life. But Joon-Young refused and died in HyeIn's concert. 14 years later, HyeIn found her son able to play guitar like his father, Joon-Young.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?487386</url></doc>
