<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="488419">
  <docid>488419</docid>
  <title>Sex Wars</title>
  <year>2000</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <editors>
    <editor>Mussari, Sam</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Game-Show</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>tv-show</keyword>
    <keyword>non-fiction</keyword>
    <keyword>syndicated</keyword>
    <keyword>short-lived</keyword>
    <keyword>battle-of-the-sexes</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">2 October 2000</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">2 October 2000</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <producers>
    <producer>Schultz, Howard (I)</producer>
    <producer>Pitman, Jacqui</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Andreen, Keith</writer>
    <writer>Cohen, Vic</writer>
    <writer>Green, Jocelyn</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Pietsch, Scooter</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bernard, Kristian</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bolick, Lisa Marie</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brandt, Barry</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cole, Jennifer (I)</actor>
      <role>Host</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>D'Alessio, Peter (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fisher, Kimberly</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hatley, Adam</actor>
      <role>Adam</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Roth, J.D.</actor>
      <role>Host</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Two teams of three contestants of the opposite sex competed to answer questions on this "Family Feud" clone. Round 1 is called "Land Mine," where hosts Roth &amp; Cole asked each gender two separate questions, three of these answers are true and one is false (which is the "Land Mine"). Each contestant on a gender's team is asked to choose 1 of the 4 answers, if right, then he/she will get 5 points, and a bonus 5 points for finding all 3 answers. If at anytime a contestant on a team lands on a "Land Mine," then all the remaining points goes over to their opposing team. Round 2 is called "The List". On the show's website, a series of surveys were asked by both sexes. Each one is given a category (Ex. The top 10 kinds of donuts for men, the top 10 things women notice about men), and either side bids on how many answers they can come up with that's on the list. Teams alternated bids until one side bids all 10 or challenged their opponents to name that entire list. Each correct answer is worth 10 points, and an incorrect answer knocked that contestant (on a gender's team) out of the game, if all players on 1 team have been knocked out, the other team can steal the points by coming up with only 1 right answer. In Round 3, hosts Roth &amp; Cole asked a series of questions to 2 separate teams and players tried to buzz in and guess whether each one is either men or women. (Ex. They're more than likely to return a Christmas present - Men or Women?) If right, the team scored 10 points, if wrong, the points automatically go to the other side. Last question was worth 25 points. In the fourth and final round, 2 separate teams must wager at least half of their points on one final question, on which the opponents had the right to choose the subject for the opposite sex. If the question they answered was right, then they win whatever they wagered, if not, they lost that wager. Team with the most points at the end of the round earns an additional $10 for each point scored.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?488419</url></doc>
