<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="489444">
  <docid>489444</docid>
  <title>Shaadi No. 1</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="UK">15</certificate>
    <certificate country="Australia">M</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">3 November 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Dhawan, David</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bhagnani, Vashu</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Malik, Anu</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ali (I)</actor>
      <role>Advocate H.S. Gulati</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chaudhary, Sophiya</actor>
      <role>Dimple Kothari</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chhabria, Aarti</actor>
      <role>Rekha Kothari</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deol, Esha</actor>
      <role>Diya</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dutt, Sanjay</actor>
      <role>Lakhwinder 'Lucky' Singh Lakha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gill, Avtar</actor>
      <role>Punjab Police Inspector Khudabaksh Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Joshi, Sharman</actor>
      <role>Aryan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Fardeen (I)</actor>
      <role>Raj</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Javed (I)</actor>
      <role>Marriage Registrar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Soha Ali</actor>
      <role>Advocate Sonia</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Zayed</actor>
      <role>Veer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kiran, Shashi (I)</actor>
      <role>Goverdhan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Menon, Suresh (I)</actor>
      <role>Panditji</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shah, Satish</actor>
      <role>Kothari</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Yadav, Rajpal</actor>
      <role>Mr. Y</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Kothari finds himself in a jam when his hair-growth, water colors for students, and Agarbatti products misfire resulting in lawsuits. He decides to kill himself but is saved by three men: Raj, Veer and Aryan, who give him alternate ideas to market his products with such positive results that he hires them. He finds out that all three married to Bhavna (who is so engrossed with Bhagwan Shri Tirupathi that she has no time for her Pati); Diya (a busy film actress); and Sonia (an equally busy lawyer) respectively but are sex-starved. He confides in them that he has three unmarried daughters, Rekha, Madhuri, and Dimple, who would prefer to fall in love with and then get married. He asks the trio to woo and then betray them so that he can get them married to boys of his choice. The trio agree to do so and re-locate abroad to meet the three females. To their pleasant surprise they turn out to be real beauties and they decide to woo and keep them. Aided by Kothari himself the trio have no problems in making the nymphets falls in love with them, and that done they return home to find that their respective wives have a newfound brother, Lakhwinder Singh Lakha. The Kothari sisters are unable to keep away from their lovers and follow them back home and the three males meet them on the sly. Hilarious complications, with a touch of popular Filmi dialogs and references to old Bollywood hits, arise when Lakhwinder discovers their dirty little secret and is all set to tell their respective wives leaving the hapless friends no choice but to decide to do away with him. Watch what happens after they finally succeed in doing away with Lakhwinder.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?489444</url></doc>
