<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="489638">
  <docid>489638</docid>
  <title>Shadoevision</title>
  <year>1995</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2 September 1995</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Cirino, Chuck</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Stevens, Shadoe</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Christner, Gil</actor>
      <role>Norman 'Norm' Jones</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hilton, Jeffrey (III)</actor>
      <role>Dorely Shrivel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stevens, Shadoe</actor>
      <role>Djony Dakota/Dr. Milton Oak</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>All television, all over the world, is suddenly interrupted by someone who looks like a cross between Mark Twain and Albert Einstein. Again and again he says cheerfully, "This is NOT Mind Control. Think about it." In the streets, panic ensues and Norman Jones finds himself racing out of control, through doorways through other dimensions, and finally falling through the universe and into the Jules Verne designed "WorldView Auditorium." Plummeting into an open seat, he finds himself in the middle of the talk show broadcast of one, Djony Dakota. Here he learns that his girlfriend, Faith Pate', has been kidnapped, and is being held for ransom and some good times. He also learns that, in his panic, in his haste, he left an interdimensional doorway open. Now, the fate of Faith, and the entire Universe, hangs on whether Norman can change the future, by closing the door to his past. And the clock is ticking. Do you understand: LAUGH NOW, THINK LATER? PSYCHIC INTOXICATION? BRAINWORMS? Did you know that you have "Laughter Glands" that periodically need to be squeezed? IF NONE OF THIS MAKES SENSE TO YOU, IT MAY ALREADY BE TOO LATE.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?489638</url></doc>
