<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="489694">
  <docid>489694</docid>
  <title>Shadow Life</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Popalis, Jonathan</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>1990s</keyword>
    <keyword>satire</keyword>
    <keyword>dotcom</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">11 May 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">21</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Yeger, Aaron</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Selano, Michael</producer>
    <producer>Yeger, Aaron</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Yeger, Aaron</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Caswell, Laura</actor>
      <role>Elena</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pasyk, Peter</actor>
      <role>Jeremy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Popalis, Jonathan</actor>
      <role>Paul</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Jeremy thought he had it all. A fledgling law career, one of the best friends in the world in Paul, and of course, he had Trisha. The girl he planned to spend the rest of his life with. Or at least, so he thought. When Trisha dumps him for another guy, Jeremy is heart broken. After weeks of moping around and being down on himself, Paul decides to take it upon himself to thrust Jeremy back into the dating world. Jeremy is of course reluctant. First of all, he's not exactly thrilled about the idea of seeing someone else after getting his heart crushed. Secondly, while Paul is a great guy, he also seems to have a couple screws loose, and his opinion of what a good woman would be for Jeremy is highly questionable. And lastly, this woman in question is a co-worker with Paul at his surreal 90s throwback dot-com company, where everyone seems to be as weird as Paul. It takes some needling but Paul finally convinces Jeremy to meet her. Really, what's the worst that could happen? It couldn't hurt to meet someone new... Right?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?489694</url></doc>
