<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="490004">
  <docid>490004</docid>
  <title>Shafted</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Game-Show</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>gamble</keyword>
    <keyword>goodbye</keyword>
    <keyword>israel</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Australia">G</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Australia">11 February 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Australia">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Sutcliffe, Graeme</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Wood, Adam (III)</producer>
    <producer>Boughen, Michael</producer>
    <producer>Cameron, Wayne</producer>
    <producer>Callaghan, Rory</producer>
    <producer>Spry, John</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Ho, Chris (I)</writer>
    <writer>Rickerby, Graeme</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>White, Brenton</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Symons, Red</actor>
      <role>Himself - Host</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The Australian version of the British elimination quiz. Six contestants begin by making a bid of up to $500 that they will start the game with. The contestant with the highest bid is immediately "shafted" (eliminated), becoming the first to hear Red Symons say to them the show's catch-cry, "You've been shafted." The contestant with the second highest bid begins the first round by choosing one of four categories, and each player then bids an amount out of what they have that they will stake on each question they answer. After a number of questions are asked, the final question of the round is a "half question" - the contestants hear the first part of the question, then make a bid from the money they have at that point. The contestant with the highest bid hears the rest of the question and then has to answer it - the amount they bid gets added to their total if they answer correctly, or removed from it if their answer is incorrect. The contestant with the most money after the half-question earns the right to shaft someone from the game - the person they nominate then replies by saying why they think they should stay. The leader can stick with their choice or change it, but if they change, the newly-chosen contestant gets no right of reply. In subsequent rounds, the contestant with the most money chooses from the remaining categories. After three rounds, the two remaining contestants bring their amounts to the final round and play for the combined total. Facing each other, the contestants make a secret decision to share or shaft, discuss this decision with each other and then make their final decision, which is subsequently revealed. If they both decide to shaft, they both leave with nothing. If they both decide to share, the money is split equally between them. If one decides to share and the other to shaft, the contestant who shafts gets all of the money and comes back on the next night as a "master shafter".</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?490004</url></doc>
