<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="490290">
  <docid>490290</docid>
  <title>Shalloween</title>
  <year>2010</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>halloween</keyword>
    <keyword>one-word-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">10 October 2010</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">87</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Jager, Phyllis</producer>
    <producer>Longi, Steve</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Jager, Phyllis</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jager, Phyllis</actor>
      <role>Miranda</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>An innocent celebration of fun shifts when, on a bitter Halloween evening in 2000, fourteen year old Luke Latham, a quiet, bookworm type, has finally had enough of shallow minded kids teasing him. The taunting and the poking fun of his awkward ways by the other kids will be no more. He's tired of being called The Gangly Tree Man Killer. Even his sister Lindsay has turned on him. She does nothing but stand there laughing while they goad him. He begins to terrorize her by stalking her while she has sex with a boyfriend and leaving a calling card so she knows he was watching, lurking. He doesn't stop there. Her beloved hamster, Mr. Wooby, is found hanging upside down in her closet. Dangling from a noose made of soft tree bark. After being sent to live in a series of treatment centers, and a succession of psychiatric evaluations, Latham's problems were serious enough that he was declared a ward of the state. There, he remained locked away and dormant for 10 years. When a glitch in the system raises no red flags during a facility transfer, Latham is inadvertently set free to roam, to prey on the innocent, to feed his insatiable thirst for bloodshed. Things are about to change and Latham's hometown of Woodcliff Lake, New Jersey will never be the same. He begins a murderous trek back to his native land in search of retribution to events from his past. This hallow eyed boy has grown into a homicidal man determined to carry out his murderous mission. That evening, the neighborhood's in full Halloween swing. Monsters and ghouls are everywhere. Soft, candlelight illuminates from spookily carved pumpkins flickering in just about every window. Lawns are dressed in spooky gore, life like scarecrows wait at nearly every front door, and, there's a storm rolling in. On October 31st, 2010, The Gangly Tree Man Killer returns to where it all began. He brutally and inexplicably massacres each and every one who ever laughed at him, mocked him, teased, or ridiculed him leaving his victims drenched in their own blood. Each slaughter is performed in an Earthy manner as Latham lives up to his Gangly Tree Man Killer reputation. His clues, all relative to the Earth and trees. His murder weapon a thick, intricately carved staff made of a tree trunk. The torture escalates, his pleasures heightened. It's obvious, they've created a monster. Every massacre becomes more poetic than the next. Drenched in more blood. He relishes in his fury and violence. Each butchery bloodbath, the soul soothing nourishment that stimulates his famine. A pulsating finale will have horror enthusiasts screaming as Latham saves his darling sister Lindsay for last. Will anyone rescue her? Can anyone stop him? There is going to be hell to pay and pay they shall!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?490290</url></doc>
