<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="490562">
  <docid>490562</docid>
  <title>Shanghai Bound</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>James, Simon (XV)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>asian</keyword>
    <keyword>industrialist</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Mandarin</language>
    <language>Shanghainese</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">19</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Lu, Lucy (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Barnett, Christopher (II)</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Shanghai is leading China's economic revolution. With the financial, commercial, and industrial sectors all growing at breakneck speed, it has become the country's richest, largest, and most populated city. The transformation has been spectacular. And it's not only the big corporations which are getting rich. Only 30 years ago, self-employment was prohibited, millions stuck in state-run factories for life. But today former factory laborers are becoming bosses of their own, adapting to the new capitalist trend. This is now a land of opportunity, and millions are finding their fulfillment within it. Mrs Pei Yao Xu, is one woman with a triumphant story to tell. At 76, she has witnessed at first hand the turbulent formation of modern China; all the while laboring as a book binder, for Shanghai's largest printing factory. She never dreamed of owning a book binding factory of her own. But when the opportunity came, in the form of Deng Xiao Ping's Economic Reforms, she grabbed it with both hands; becoming one the earliest beneficiaries of the reforms in Shanghai. Today, Mrs Xu is the proud owner of a thriving enterprise, within an industry she has never grown tired of. With an ever growing workforce, and strict deadlines to meet, she faces new challenges each day. Shanghai Bound, looks at this unlikely female entrepreneur, from her socialist roots, to her present day capitalist lifestyle. We follow her on to the factory floor, where she gives an intimate portrait of how her small but productive enterprise is run, and what threats she has had to overcome.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?490562</url></doc>
