<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="490657">
  <docid>490657</docid>
  <title>Shankar Parvati</title>
  <year>1979</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Khade, Ram</editor>
    <editor>Surve, Vithoba</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>History</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Gujarati</language>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Chandrakant (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Shah, S.</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dave, Nalin</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Desai, Manher</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dhinu</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Inamdar, Virendra</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mishra, Jayendra</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mitra, Shyamlal</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Polson</actor>
      <role>Nandi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Trivedi, Arvind</actor>
      <role>Bhagwan Shri Shivji/Shivshankar/Shiv Shakti/Maheshwar/Natwar/Janardhan/Shambhu/Mahadev/Natraj/Vishwanath/Parmeshwar</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Bhagwan Shri Narad approaches Bhagwan Shri Shivji with a proposal to get married to Devi Maa Sati. Initially Shivji refuses but when he is told that even Bhagwans Brahmaji and Vishnuji have already been married to Savitriji and Lakshmiji respectively, he must also do so. Shivji accepts and gets married to Satiji. They reside in harmony, and even conjoin as one to annihilate two indestructible demons. Trouble looms when Satiji's dad deliberately neglects to invite them for a Yagna. Satiji travels there alone and pleads with her dad to relent and invite Shivji but he refuses and insults her husband - resulting in her jumping in the Yagna fire and killing herself. An enraged Shivji sends Veer Bhadra to destroy the kingdom and kill Satiji's dad. After Veer Bhadra slays him, Shivji himself appears to answer Satiji's mother's pleas and brings back her much repentant husband to life. Thereafter Shivji retires. When demon Tarakasur gets a boon from Brahmaji he forcibly evicts Bhagwan Shri Indra from Devlok, defeats and humiliates Vishnuji and Brahmaji themselves, who approach Shivji and ask him to re-marry Devi Maa Parvati, who is actually Satiji's reincarnation, so that they sire a child, who will be the only one to slay Tarakasur. After testing Parvatiji, Shivji marries her and shortly thereafter a son, Kartikeya, is born, and a few years later he does slay Tarakasur. Parvatiji then gives birth to Bhagwan Shri Ganesh, instructs him to protect her virtue at any cost - he does so with disastrous results and gets beheaded by Shivji. A repentant Shivji then brings him back to life with the head of an elephant. Their two sons grow up, Ganeshji proves to be the more intelligent and gets married to Riddhi and Siddhi, the daughters of Brahmaji and sisters to Naradji. Then Brahmaji grants the boon of immortality to another demon, Mahisasur, and the only one who can slay him is Parvatiji herself. She does succeed in slaying him but her anger gets out of control and she sets about to destroy the entire world. Worried Devas approach Shivji to find a solution to end Parvatiji's wrath - and it is then Shivji comes up with a unique plan to placate his angry wife.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?490657</url></doc>
