<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="490700">
  <docid>490700</docid>
  <title>Shantav den</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Bulgarian</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby SR</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Bulgaria</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Bulgaria">11 March 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Bulgaria">78</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Pesheva, Silviya</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Cholakov, Georgi</producer>
    <producer>Jeleva, Pavlina</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Braneva, Ina</writer>
    <writer>Pesheva, Silviya</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Petkov, Bozhidar</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Atanasova, Elena</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kazakova, Bilyana</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kazakova, Vesela</actor>
      <role>Ina</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mirkov, Stoyo</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tsonev, Kosta</actor>
      <role>Grandfather</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ugrinov, Toni</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>18-years old Ina looks after her eccentric, always surprising, Grandfather. She gives drawing lessons and hopes to make a career as children's book illustrator. One day after a medical examination, the doctor announced that her Grandfather is in danger of suffering a heart attack. He gives her a prescription for an expensive, but in his opinion, effective medicine, which he recommended that she buy as soon as possible. Ina does not have enough money, and she calls her friend Ivo to ask him to lend her some. She goes home without the medicine. The next day she has an entire series of unpleasant incidents. All her hopes of helping her grandfather, fail. At that moment, Angel, a young potter, arrives. He brings her the pots she had ordered. With surprising ease and understanding, he helps Ina finish off the mosaic she had begun a long time ago. The Grandfather, pleased that he has managed to remove the 'bad' people from the path of his granddaughter, gives his blessing to the pleasant young boy.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?490700</url></doc>
