<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="491937">
  <docid>491937</docid>
  <title>Shehzada</title>
  <year>1972</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Shankar, K.</editor>
    <editor>Veluswamy, G.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">U</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <directors>
    <director>Shankar, K.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kapoor, Surinder</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Dharamraj, R.K.</writer>
    <writer>Krishan, Rajendra</writer>
    <writer>Rangaram, R.K.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Burman, Rahul Dev</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arora, Sonoo</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bawra, Gulshan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Choti, Mohan</actor>
      <role>Nandu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dewan, Karan</actor>
      <role>Ratan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gulzar, Rakhee</actor>
      <role>Chanda</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Halam</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jairaj, P.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khanna, Rajesh</actor>
      <role>Rajesh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Prasad, Badri</actor>
      <role>Police Inspector</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, Madan (I)</actor>
      <role>Chanda's maternal uncle</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shastri, Shreeram</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sunder (I)</actor>
      <role>Nekiram</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Circa British rule in India, wealthy DIG of Police is approached by Devdutt, a poor freedom fighter, who would like his daughter, Janki, to get married to the DIG's son, Ratan. The DIG and his wife Rajlaxmi refuse to have to do anything with Devdutt, but Ratan refuses to marry anyone else. They eventually relent and agree to this marriage. Shortly after the marriage, riots ensue between the police and freedom fighters, and as a result the DIG is killed. Rajlaxmi blames Devdutt for his death, and asks a pregnant Janki to leave her house. Unable to stand up for his wife, Ratan remains a silent spectator while his wife is thrown out. Janki goes to live with her father, who eventually passes away, and it is then Janki gives birth to a son, Rajesh. Years later, Rajesh has grown up, drives a truck, and is in love with a local shop-keeper, Chanda, who he would like to marry. Janki would like her son to go and meet his dad, and when Rajesh does so, Rajlaxmi arranges a pompous welcome for him with open arms, hoping that he will leave his mother and stay on with her. But Rajesh refuses to do this unless Rajlaxmi apologizes to Janki. An enraged Rajlaxmi refuses to do so, and asks Rajesh to leave. Rajesh and Chanda get married, and soon Chanda gets pregnant. Then the police arrest Rajesh, for which he may face several years in prison. He is held in the local police station. The truth does prevail, the real culprit is caught, and Rajesh is let go. He returns home to find out that everything is not the same anymore. Chanda has given birth a baby boy, and now lives with Rajlaxmi, and refuses to return home. Rajesh must now find out what compelled Chanda to leave Janki and go to live with Rajlaxmi.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?491937</url></doc>
