<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="494096">
  <docid>494096</docid>
  <title>Shooters</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Proudfoot, Meaghan</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>sicily-invasion</keyword>
    <keyword>wwii</keyword>
    <keyword>sicily</keyword>
    <keyword>d-day</keyword>
    <keyword>photo</keyword>
    <keyword>wwii-in-italy</keyword>
    <keyword>canadian</keyword>
    <keyword>europe</keyword>
    <keyword>army</keyword>
    <keyword>elbe-river</keyword>
    <keyword>invasion</keyword>
    <keyword>one-word-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">19 April 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">49</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>O'Regan, James (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>O'Regan, James (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>O'Regan, James (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Huggett, Andrew</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Calder, Al</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>O'Regan, James (I)</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Roos, Charles</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Spencer, Michael (III)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Weeks, Lew</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The Canadian Army Film and Photo Unit (CFPU) was the last such unit formed by the allied armies. But, they were the first in scooping the world on the major events in Europe: the invasion of Sicily, the top story of the century - D-Day1, the liberation of Paris, the Elbe River link up of the Allied armies, the first feature documentary shot while under fire, and only footage shot of action leading to a Victoria Cross. This documentary has its own first. Viewers will see, for the first time, original colour footage of the D-Day operation. They will see clips of the unit's first production Wood for War about the Canadian Forestry Corps at work in Scotland, as well as clips from the CFPU's own newsreels, both never before seen on television. Through fresh interviews with veterans of the CFPU and its archival newsreels, viewers will see the story from the men who shot the film: Charles Roos, the first allied cameraman ashore on D-day; the late Al Calder, who parachuted over the Rhine and shot that operation; Michael Spencer, the unit's first editor, who worked on the feature documentary above; and, the late Lew Weeks, who shot the liberation of Paris. This history takes on a personal flavour through three highlights. In the first, James O'Regan relates a small detail in the Invasion of Normandy on D-Day: a despatch rider, O'Regan's father Brian (1924-1999), played a small but key role that had helped the world first learn of this mighty event from the CFPU. In the second, we see how Brian became the first Canadian to enter Dieppe after the Invasion. In the third, we see how Brian became the subject of a world scoop photo at the Elbe River Link Up between the US and Soviet armies.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?494096</url></doc>
