<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="494938">
  <docid>494938</docid>
  <title>Shree Ganesh</title>
  <year>1962</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Lakhe, Ram</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>History</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">1962</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Dharwadkar, S.S.</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Mast, C.K.</writer>
    <writer>Mistri, Babubhai</writer>
    <writer>Pande, Vishwanath</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Rani, Bulo C.</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Desai, Ramesh</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dutt, Uma</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Indira (VI)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kala, Jeevan</actor>
      <role>Dancer/Singer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Saroj</actor>
      <role>Dancer/Singer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumari, Krishna (I)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mahipal</actor>
      <role>Bhagwan Shri Krishan 'Gopala' 'Kanhaiya'/Bhagwan Shri Ram</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Malka (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moolchand</actor>
      <role>Chhatrajeet's Palace Guard</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nandkumar, Master</actor>
      <role>Young Bhagwan Shri Krishan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tiwari, Ramayan</actor>
      <role>Prachand</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>After giving birth to Bhagwan Shri Kartiyeke, Devi Maa Parvati forms a child-human image from clay, adopts him, and asks him to guard the house and not let anyone in while she bathes. The child refuses to let anyone in, including Bhagwan Shivji himself, who beheads him. When a tearful Parvatiji pleads, Shivji brings the child back to life with the head of an elephant, and names him Gajanand, and assures him that no one will make fun of him. Gajanandji grows up, slays a fire-spouting demon, and proves that he is wiser than his brother, and marries Ridhi and Sidhi. When Chandramaji (Moon) mocks him, Gajanandji curses him, darkening his face, and when he pleads with both Shivji and Parvatiji, Gajanand relents, lifts the curse off, but cautions him that whenever anyone looks at Chandramaji on Bhadrapath Chaturthi (the 1st of the 10 day Ganesh Chaturthi fest), they will be equally cursed. Gajanandji does not realize that this curse will have an adverse effect on none other than Bhagwan Shri Krishan, who looks at Chandramaji on the fated day, gets cursed, ends up with discord in his marital life with Rukmaniji, due to his affair with Satyabhamaji, the daughter of Chhatrajeet, who has arranged her marriage with Satdharma, and who will soon accuse Krishnaji of theft, deceit, and of killing his brother, Prachand. Krishanji will have to redeem himself from this curse as well as fulfill a promise he made to Vrashraj (King of Bears) in a previous birth as Bhagwan Shri Ram.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?494938</url></doc>
