<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="494923">
  <docid>494923</docid>
  <title>Shravan Kumar</title>
  <year>1984</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>Gujarati</language>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Chandrakant (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bambri, Shantichandra G.</producer>
    <producer>Barula, Jagdish P.</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Lahiri, Bappi</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhaduri, Chandrima</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhattacharya, Abhi</actor>
      <role>Maharaja Dashrath</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhushan, Bharat (I)</actor>
      <role>Maharishi Shantvarkumar Sharma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dulari (I)</actor>
      <role>Maharashtrian devotee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gadkar, Jayshree</actor>
      <role>Annapurna</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sachin (I)</actor>
      <role>Shravankumar S. Sharma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sen, Asit (I)</actor>
      <role>Deaf devotee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shivraj (I)</actor>
      <role>Laxm's husband</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Singh, Dara (I)</actor>
      <role>Dumb devotee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sunder (I)</actor>
      <role>Gurudev</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tripathi, Kumud (II)</actor>
      <role>Devi Maa Maya</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>When Shantvarkumar Sharma and his wife, Gyanvati, find out they are unable to conceive, they pray for years to Bhagwan Shri Brahma, who eventually appears before them, blesses them, tells them they will soon be proud parents of a devoted son, but warns them not to see him or else they will lose their vision. True enough, a son, Shravankumar, is born, but barely after a month after his birth, the couple break their promise, see him, and become blind. One day at the riverbank, Gyanvati finds that her son is missing, but he is eventually brought back to them unharmed by none other than Maharaja Dashrath, who has been childless for years. Shantvar and Gyanvati bless him with not one but four sons. Years later Shravankumar has grown up and is very devoted to his parents, he even prefers to worship them instead of God, much to chagrin of Devi Maa Maya, who decides to test his devotion. When he finds out that it was because of him they lost their vision, he undertakes to take them on a holy Trithyatra (prilgrimage) so as to restore their vision, he decides to carry them in a palanquin,instead of a chariot offer by Dashrath, and they share many adventures including getting blessed by Bhagwan Shri Shiv himself. On the last leg of their pilgrimage, Dashrath is hunting a man-eating tiger, while Shravan has gone to the riverbank to get some water for his thirsty parents. Dashrath thinks that the tiger is drinking water, shoots it, and instead kills Shravan. When a horrified Dashrath takes the water to his parents, they curse him that his dead body will never be carried by his sons, and he will be separated from his most beloved son. Soon after this both of them die, leaving Dashrath to atone for his sin - a sin that will result in the reincarnation of Bhagwan Shri Vishnu himself as his son, Bhagwan Shri Ram - who will be separated from him to satisfy a whim of Dashrath's wife, Kaikeyi, thus leading to epic Ramayan.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?494923</url></doc>
