<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="495083">
  <docid>495083</docid>
  <title>Shrinking Charlotte</title>
  <year>2010</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">20 January 2010</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Eram, René</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Edner, Robert</producer>
    <producer>Bullock, Brian (III)</producer>
    <producer>D'Amico, Tamela</producer>
    <producer>Troebs, Katie Willard</producer>
    <producer>Gordon, Michael Z.</producer>
    <producer>Hennessy, Michael (II)</producer>
    <producer>Mayeux, Molly M.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Eram, René</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Biggs, Becky</actor>
      <role>Waitress</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jones, Mary-Charles</actor>
      <role>Young Charlotte</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lillard, Matthew</actor>
      <role>Rick Bicknell</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Martin, Liz (II)</actor>
      <role>Husky Cowgirl</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Parkes, Braden</actor>
      <role>Matt Bicknell</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Trammell, Sam</actor>
      <role>Jeff Bicknell</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Willard, Fred</actor>
      <role>Walt Bicknell</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Shrinking Charlotte is romantic comedy about three single men who stalk and date a woman in therapy in order to learn about honesty, fate, and eventually love. First we have Jeff, a shrink in need of a shrink - repeatedly rescuing his melodramatic, hypochondriac mother, who has a habit of dying and traveling towards the white light. Jeff's dating life revolves around finding the perfect woman, but the truth is, he's searching for one just like dear old mom. Next we have T.J whose wife has thrown him out after she caught him womanizing. Although T.J. is working hard to mend his marriage, there is one large hindrance - namely, a big bossy sister in law, who plays mouthpiece for T.J.'s wife. Finally, we have Rick, Jeff's charismatic bastard brother, who is a father to a troubled fourteen year old with a quick line and keen wit. Rick's problem in the dating world is that he's the ultimate psycho-bitch from hell magnet. In the film's opener, Jeff confides to T.J. and Rick that he's secretly in love with his client who, albeit a little looney tune, "she's working on it." When Rick hears about this neurotic patient of Jeff's, he immediately steals her phone number and the chase is on. Over the course of the film, our men discover just who Charlotte really is. And after experiencing her fabrications, deceit, manipulation and Kung Fu kicks, Rick and T.J. throw in the towel and discover their true fate.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?495083</url></doc>
