<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="495050">
  <docid>495050</docid>
  <title>Shrimanji</title>
  <year>1968</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">160</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Dayal, Ram</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Nayyar, O.P.</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anand, Dev</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Choti, Mohan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hiralal (I)</actor>
      <role>Advocate M.L. Gupta</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jeevan (I)</actor>
      <role>Diwan Jeevanlal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Johar, I.S.</actor>
      <role>Johar M. Gupta/Pran</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Raj (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khanna, Rajesh</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Kishore</actor>
      <role>Kishore M. Gupta/Miss Franco</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Rajendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moolchand</actor>
      <role>Jeevanlal's Sindhi associate</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mukri</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Murad</actor>
      <role>Judge</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sen, Asit (I)</actor>
      <role>Major Champala Rai</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sunder (I)</actor>
      <role>Kishore's friend</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wasti</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Yakub</actor>
      <role>Morgue Watchman</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The year is 1942 and Advocate M.L. Gupta lives a wealthy lifestyle along with his wife, Maya, in Churchgate, Bombay. One day he travels to Calcutta, and during an air raid by Japanese fighter aircraft, takes shelter with a prostitute, Panna, who drugs and then seduces him. The next day Gupta returns home and decides to forget about this affair. Shortly thereafter he and Maya become parents of a male child and name him Johar. Four years later Gupta finds out that Maya has adopted a male child, Kishore, and suspects her of having an affair and asks her to leave. Johar keeps asking for his mom, so Gupta has him re-located to America. Twenty years later the Gupta family is fated to meet again. With Kishore being recruited by Gupta to tutor an irresponsible Johar, who instead of becoming an Advocate, has forsaken the worldly possessions, and become a Sadhu. Kishore soon finds out that Johar is pulling wool over his dad's eyes, both become friends and woo two young women, Asha and Lata respectively. The two women live with their respective widower dads, Major Champala Rai and Diwan Jeevanlal. Johar hires a private investigator to try and locate his mom, then elopes with Lata and marries her much to the chagrin of her dad who wants her to marry a man named Pran. Johar does find his mother living with Kishore but before he could inform her that he is her son, she is arrested for killing Jeevanlal, and the eye-witness is none other than Lata.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?495050</url></doc>
