<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="495283">
  <docid>495283</docid>
  <title>Shukriya: Till Death Do Us Apart</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Musical</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">8 October 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Sinha, Anupam (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bachan, Meenu</producer>
    <producer>Blackburn, Dr. Phil</producer>
    <producer>Chopra, Ashwani</producer>
    <producer>Bhatnagar, Vibha</producer>
    <producer>Ragini</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Arora, Jeetu</writer>
    <writer>Sinha, Anubhav</writer>
    <writer>Sinha, Anupam (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Agnihotri, Rati</actor>
      <role>Sandhya K. Jindal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bahadur, Rana Jung</actor>
      <role>Uday R. Jindal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chopra, Ashwani</actor>
      <role>Doctor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Indraneel</actor>
      <role>Yash</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kher, Anupam</actor>
      <role>Karam Jindal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mehra, Aarti</actor>
      <role>Shivani</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sengupta, Indraneil</actor>
      <role>Anjali</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sharma, Anupam</actor>
      <role>Sameer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shivdasani, Aftab</actor>
      <role>Rohan "Ricky" Verma</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Thirty years ago Karam Jindal together with his widowed mom, Gayatri, and wife, Sandhya, had immigrated to London, England. Shortly thereafter Gayatri gets cancer and tragically passes away. Then, Sandhya gives birth to two daughters, Anjali and Sanam. The Jindals accumulate wealth, and are now one of the wealthiest families' in London. Anjali gets married to Akash, while Sanam is on the look-out for her beau. With Karam's 60th birthday coming up, Anjali is busy with preparations for a grand party, while Sanam has already started with her make-up. Karam hopes to get Sanam married to Yash, his employee, who is like a son to him. Add to that is the inauguration of the "Gayatri Jindal Cancer Hospital" which is to be done on the same day. With the preparations under way, Karam brings home a young man, Rohan "Ricky" Verma, to live with them for a few days. Sanam has already met him and is quite friendly with him. She confides in her mom that she would like to marry Rohan, and her mom indicates that she approves of him. They get a shock when Karam vehemently opposes any alliance with Rohan, and refuses to divulge the reason(s). For it is only Karam who knows that Rohan is not who he claims to be - for he is Death himself - accompanying Karam during his last four days on Earth.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?495283</url></doc>
