<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="497351">
  <docid>497351</docid>
  <title>Silver Star!</title>
  <year>1994</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>cult-favorite</keyword>
    <keyword>lost-classic</keyword>
    <keyword>making-of</keyword>
    <keyword>anniversary</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">18 July 1994</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">11</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Edwards, TJ</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Edwards, TJ</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Edwards, TJ</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Andrews, Julie (I)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chaplin, Saul</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Craig, Michael (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Crenna, Richard</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hackett, Shelah</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Karlan, Richard</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kidd, Michael</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Landis, Jeanette</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Massey, Daniel (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Oppenheimer, Alan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wise, Robert (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Robert Wise and Saul Chaplin became so enchanted with Julie Andrews during the filming of THE SOUND OF MUSIC, that they wanted to create a new film to showcase Julie's versatility. Julie Andrews explains how Wise and Chaplin made her want to do the film, and how the challenge of playing Gertude Lawrence (with numerous onstage musical numbers) gave her the chance to play a lot of different people while playing one person. Michael Kidd, and his wife/assistant Shelah Hackett Kidd, explain how they worked out the musical numbers, and join Wise, Chaplin, and other cast members recalling what it was like working with Julie. The film's initial misfortunes (financial disappointment, cutting, retitling, etc) are discussed, along with the film's later resurrection as an underrated cult classic. Julie, Wise and Chaplin express their feelings about this well crafted film finally becoming available to audiences. Before the 25th Anniversary Screening of a new 35mm stereo print of STAR! at the Director's Guild Theatre in Hollywood, the Creators and Cast reunite onstage. Robert Wise introduces The Star, and Julie takes the stage as a packed theatre gives her a standing ovation. After being unavailable for many years, this lost classic musical is finally back onscreen where it belongs.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?497351</url></doc>
