<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="498943">
  <docid>498943</docid>
  <title>Sirf Romance: Love by Chance</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">1 May 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="India">160</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Bundela, Raja</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Sharma, Deepak (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Sood, Vikram</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Anand, Anand Raj</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Aman, Zeenat</actor>
      <role>Durga Putri</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Babbar, Raj</actor>
      <role>Rguveer Pratap Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bakshi, Arun</actor>
      <role>Jarnail Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhardwaj, Beenu</actor>
      <role>Grpreet</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bundela, Raja</actor>
      <role>Terrorist</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ghai, Gaurav</actor>
      <role>Harry</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Shabnam</actor>
      <role>Abida</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Haider</actor>
      <role>Raja</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Mobin</actor>
      <role>Mobin Khan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Mohsin</actor>
      <role>Salim</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nath, Alok</actor>
      <role>Gaffoor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pandey, Hemant</actor>
      <role>Takhat Singh</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Raja is single but ready to mingle. He tries his best to get a girl friend but every time he has been rejected by the beauties. One fine day incidentally he comes across a dead drunk girl called Anamika, who is about to run over the train, Raja saves her life. When she comes to know all about Raja, they start seeing each other. Now Raja feels that this is the girl, he wants to marry. However, he never understands the way Anamika behaves, every time they meet, there is a fight between them, a kind of love and hate relationship. By the time, he finds that Anamika had lost her fiancé; about a year ago and she is trying to find him in Raja. Now Raja is totally broken. His aunt was trying to convince him about the girl she has chosen for Raja. Now Raja decides to visit his aunt. When he reaches over there, destiny plays the roll. The girl is none other than Anamika; both reunited. Other side of this story is about family values and traditions. Harry and Salim the two guys are very close friends of Raja. Both are caught between their love and family values. Neither they can leave their girl friends nor can they dare to abandon their parents. Ultimately, Raja's mother becomes the bridge between ethics and modern culture, and they succeed to get the blessings of their parents. Now the celebrations; all three friends Raja, Harry and Salim are SIRF RAMANCING, BUT LOVE BY CHANCE</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?498943</url></doc>
