<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="498905">
  <docid>498905</docid>
  <title>Siren</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Lieber, Chris</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>adultery</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>murder</keyword>
    <keyword>neo-noir</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">15 October 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">18</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Mandapat, Andrew</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Pinyan, Gary</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Mandapat, Andrew</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Wilhoit, Jerry</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Korda, Sarah</actor>
      <role>Charlie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lytle, Stephanie (I)</actor>
      <role>Sonora</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mercer, John</actor>
      <role>Kanesworth</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mercer, John A.</actor>
      <role>Kanesworth</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pedemonte, Gregory</actor>
      <role>Ned</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>SIREN is a film noir about adultery, betrayal, greed, and murder. NED, a dying man, tells the tale in the past tense through voice-over. The story unfolds as Ned, a bank employee, sees pictures of his woman CHARLIE having sexual relations with his boss. KANESWORTH, the private investigator who took the photos, taunts him. In a fit of rage, Ned bludgeons the private eye dead. Ned quickly confronts Charlie, a manipulative femme fatale who uses sex as a bargaining chip. She convinces Ned to disregard her dalliance and persuades him to rob his bank with her instead. They rob the bank and kill his boss in the process. The couple's next step to paradise is to kill off Ned's homely and unsuspecting wife SONORA. Charlie hatches a plan to poison her at the lounge where she sings. After Ned poisons Sonora, Charlie arrives on the scene with the intention of killing Ned and running off with the loot. Ned has similar designs, which is to kill Charlie. Unbeknownst to Ned, Sonora rises from the floor gun in hand. Charlie and Sonora proceed to shoot Ned. Ned's wife and mistress are lovers who planned this outcome all along using Ned as their unwitting accomplice. As Charlie professes her love for Sonora, Sonora kills her. Ned, bleeding badly from his wounds, accepts his fate and tells Sonora the truth; she drank real poison! Sonora does not believe him and saunters away from the scene, victorious! While Ned lights his final cigarette and closes his narration, Sonora walks confidently into the night. However, after a few steps, she drops the bag of money, gasps for air, and collapses. The moonlight shines on her corpse. The bag of money left in the middle of the dark street.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?498905</url></doc>
