<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="499544">
  <docid>499544</docid>
  <title>Six Short Days, One Big Adventure!</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Mystery</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>teaching</keyword>
    <keyword>evolution</keyword>
    <keyword>religion</keyword>
    <keyword>creation</keyword>
    <keyword>christian</keyword>
    <keyword>animatronic</keyword>
    <keyword>dinosaur</keyword>
    <keyword>creationism</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 September 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Henderson, Cathy (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ham, Ken (I)</producer>
    <producer>Zeoli, Billy</producer>
    <producer>Mason, Dale</producer>
    <producer>Zovath, Mike</producer>
    <producer>Henderson, Cathy (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Byrd, Roger (I)</composer>
    <composer>Davis, Buddy</composer>
    <composer>Gilberti, Phillip</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Davis, Buddy</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hosmer, Andy</actor>
      <role>Ivan Idea</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stine, Brad</actor>
      <role>Dr. Noah Tall</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The Creation Adventure Team embarks on an unexpected adventure when they use amazing new inventions to help a student with her science report. Buddy Davis and friends reveal the wonders of the six days of Creation, with the help of the hilarious "ABC Cam," showing that the universe is the work of God and not millions of years. It all makes sense when the class looks through "BR" Glasses! From a submarine deep underwater to an airplane high above the earth, Buddy Davis and his team are out to explore! Biblical Reality glasses reveal the unseen truth about God and the world around us. This kid-friendly series for ages 7-12 combines live- action with cutting edge special effects and animatronics, plus 2D and 3D animation. Every episode is accompanied by a fun song and tons of humor. (The Creation Adventure Team series features real-life dinosaur expert and recording artist Buddy Davis. He has dug up Duckbill dinosaur fossils in Alaska and recorded several Christian music albums, but Buddy is probably best known for his life-sized dinosaur models. Among these is a full-size T-Rex for display at the Answers in Genesis Creation Museum near Cincinnati, Ohio.)</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?499544</url></doc>
