<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="501573">
  <docid>501573</docid>
  <title>Slightly Single in L.A.</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Eghbalian, Peggy</editor>
  </editors>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>acronym-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>city-name-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>place-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Will, Christie</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Becker, Michael (XXI)</producer>
    <producer>Morgan, Mark (IV)</producer>
    <producer>Most, Jeff (I)</producer>
    <producer>Rice, Jeff (I)</producer>
    <producer>Will, Christie</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Will, Christie</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bennett, Jonathan (I)</actor>
      <role>Seven</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Duff, Haylie</actor>
      <role>Jill</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Dale Squire is a hip, quirky, independent single gal living in the glossy city of Los Angeles. She makes ends meet by working in the obscure world of reality television, while pursuing her passion as a photographer. After several failed attempts in quasi-relationships, Dale concludes that finding a meaningful relationship in L.A. is impossible. After all, a girl can only take so many toe-sucking fashion photographers and star-seeking personal trainers. And in Los Angeles, there are many of these men. But being anti-social is tough for any young girl in Hollywood, and with Dale's entourage - Jill: a high maintenance ex-soap star obsessed with her own wedding, Becca: an honest C-list actress waiting for her big break in Hollywood, Seven: Dale's flamboyant house mate, and Hallie: a super sexy, laid back jewelry designer - she is lucky to have such a reliable group of friends in a city where it's easy to get lost. With Jill's frantic wedding right around the corner, Dale finds herself reflecting on the significance of marriage, and the mutual respect needed for a successful relationship. When Zach, a successful heartthrob actor and old friend of Dale's, finds his way back into her life, Dale slowly starts to think that maybe finding love in L.A. is possible - the only problem is that her realization might have come too late, leaving Dale in a silent love triangle, with no way out.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?501573</url></doc>
