<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="501774">
  <docid>501774</docid>
  <title>Slo-Mo</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Krokidas, John</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>turtle</keyword>
    <keyword>surrealism</keyword>
    <keyword>student-film</keyword>
    <keyword>oscars</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Greece">15 September 2001</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">2 June 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">24</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Krokidas, John</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kassell, Nicole</producer>
    <producer>Rutkowski, Nadja K.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Farrow, Zeke</writer>
    <writer>Krokidas, John</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Turner, John (X)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Birch, Mark (II)</actor>
      <role>Howie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Marotz, Leslie</actor>
      <role>Chloe</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moennig, Katherine</actor>
      <role>Raven</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Simpson, Jimmi</actor>
      <role>Alex</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stresen-Reuter, Ned</actor>
      <role>Doorman</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Think New York is tough? Imagine it a hundred times faster. Except for you. Welcome to Slo-Mo. Struggling through a bad case of writer's block, lazy Alex (Simpson) arrives home to find that his girlfriend Chloe (Marotz) has left him, his apartment is completely empty, and he's still only on the first page of his novel. Feeling like the whole world has left him behind, Alex storms outside to realize that it actually has. The entire city is rushing past him in fast motion. Dodging his way around zooming pedestrians and oncoming taxis, Alex stumbles upon The School for the Motionally Retarded. In class, Alex discovers rebel chick Raven (Moennig) and a group of other down-trodden 'slo-mos' who introduce him to the pleasures of being slow: 'No one asks you for change or directions.' But when Alex returns home to find that Chloe wants him back, he wishes nothing more than to speed back up and leave this slow new world behind. Can Alex climb back up to speed? Will he win back Chloe? Will he ever write the second page of his novel? Sometimes it takes being a 'slo-mo' to discover the right way to go-go.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?501774</url></doc>
