<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="502267">
  <docid>502267</docid>
  <title>Small Voices: The Stories of Cambodia's Children</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Rosenblatt, Jason</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">5 August 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">82</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Connell, Heather E.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Connell, Heather E.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Connell, Heather E.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Strausberg, Sherene</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Follows, Megan</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Thirty years ago, the Khmer Rouge perpetrated genocide upon their own people. Attempting to create a classless society, they killed nearly 1.7 million people, primarily the adult, educated and artistic population. Three decades later, the children born to the uneducated, poverty-stricken survivors face a bleak future. With the farming lands in the countryside decimated, and little opportunity in the cities, thousands of children are struggling to survive. Abandoned by destitute family members, or forced to work in order to support themselves and relatives, these children are left vulnerable and exposed. On the streets of the capitol city of Phnom Penh, there are over 12,000 children living, begging and working. Through their eyes, their day-to-day heartbreak, dangers and hopes come to life. As we watch these snapshots of their lives, a common theme reveals itself: These children are desperate to be educated. Desperate to have a chance to change their lives but are lacking the resources to do it on their own. Charam is one of those children -- a twelve-year-old beggar who supports his mother and little sister while they live on the corner of a sidewalk. His life begins to change through the intervention of a local grassroots shelter -- the Cambodian Children's Fund. As he starts his journey to gain acceptance into the non-profit school, other stories of the CCF's children help reveal the issues plaguing Cambodia. Leakhena -- a 13- year- old girl from Battambang abandoned by her parents at a pagoda temple when they could no longer feed her. Meng Ly-- a 14-year-old boy from the Kandal farming provinces whose family cannot grow enough crops because they lack the right equipment. Layseng-- a 12 -year- old girl and Hov Nhagn-- a 13 -year- old boy, whose families were forced to leave the countryside and live at the city dump, working over twelve hour shifts picking through garbage looking for enough things to recycle in order to eat. They all share a common dream - school. In Cambodia, underpaid teachers charge students to attend class - making education a dream few can afford. Often a day's wage begging on the street or scavenging at the dump will only yield enough either for a day's food or a day in school. Shelters like CCF are trying to stem the tide of illiteracy and poverty, but are often under funded and over capacity. Despite the obstacles, Charam, Leakhena, Meng Ly, Layseng and Hov Nhagn are determined to chase their dreams and change the course of their lives forever.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?502267</url></doc>
