<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="503010">
  <docid>503010</docid>
  <title>Snake Tales</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>snake</keyword>
    <keyword>tales</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Australia">5 September 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Nettheim, Daniel</director>
    <director>Strasser, Ralph</director>
    <director>Verso, Nicholas</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Beane, Alix</writer>
    <writer>Carroll, Sam (III)</writer>
    <writer>Luno, Brendan</writer>
    <writer>McLeod, Doug (III)</writer>
    <writer>Mrksa, Kris</writer>
    <writer>Shirrefs, Mark</writer>
    <writer>Watt, Anthony (III)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fleming, Nicholas</actor>
      <role>Harrison Sailendra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Horvat, Danielle</actor>
      <role>Skye Sailendra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maguire, Liam (I)</actor>
      <role>JJ Johnson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rowsthorn, Peter</actor>
      <role>Jake Johnson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Schumann, Ben</actor>
      <role>Goober</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tang, Lucas (I)</actor>
      <role>Digby Nyugen</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Set in the dry heat of Outback Australia, in a strange and possibly mystical place called Barren Barren, SNAKE TALES is a comedy about two teenage girls trying their best to grow up normal. They live with their eccentric families, the Australian Johnson Family and the British Sailendra Family in a run-down snake park, 300 kilometres from the nearest town. Tiger Rose Johnson (13) was raised in outback Australia surrounded by snakes and very little else. She's mature beyond her years, smart, hardworking and quick-witted, but knows very little about normal teenage life. She thinks the Olsen twins are those two calves born last spring on the neighboring farm. Skye Sailendra (13), on the other hand, was raised in the bustling metropolis of London, surrounded by friends, boutique shops, and a constant stream of admirers. She's fashionable and stylish, but knows very little about thinking or doing things for herself (That's what boyfriends are for, right?) A twist of fate sees these two incompatible girls living under the same roof and begrudgingly sharing a bedroom. The convergence of these two families in the remote setting stirs up some fiery conflicts and some unlikely friendships.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?503010</url></doc>
