<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="503111">
  <docid>503111</docid>
  <title>Snaps</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Sanders, Mark (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">10</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Sanders, Mark (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Harris, Kerry (V)</writer>
    <writer>Sanders, Mark (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kent, Greer</actor>
      <role>Toni</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maloney, Donna (II)</actor>
      <role>Tanya</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Theaker, Kent</actor>
      <role>Eric</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Toni and Tanya need a model...and quickly. The model that was supposed to do the Urban Decay photo shoot didn't turn up. Their assistant, Brian, is running frantically all over the neighbourhood trying to find someone, anyone, so they can meet their agency deadline. Enter Eric. Tall, lanky, and definitely not a model. He is approached by the women, and agrees to pose for the shoot, mainly because Tanya offers him $250 to do it. The women pull out all the stops and tell him all the secrets of the industry. Eric really starts get into the moment, and begins to sound like he really is a model, not just a man out for a walk in the park. All of a sudden, Brian shows up. During the photo shoot the women have completely changed Eric's wardrobe, and have dressed him exactly like Brian. Eric notes this, but not until the women and Brian make their frantic get away. A few moments later the police suddenly over take Eric, who is standing there holding a wad of cash and all of the props from the shoot, wondering what the heck just happened. He learns that the secret number one of modeling may be always ask to keep everything, but all he knows now is that he did not ask to be a patsy for an armed robbery.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?503111</url></doc>
