<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="504237">
  <docid>504237</docid>
  <title>Social Animal Social Soul</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Tressler IV, Samuel</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 May 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">9</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Tressler IV, Samuel</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kecken, Scott</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Tressler IV, Samuel</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tressler IV, Samuel</actor>
      <role>All</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In the beginning, man developed from the apes, hunting and gathering in groups, dependent on each other for survival. Today, man has constructed an industrial machine to live in, each working on different parts day in and day out in order for the whole machine to run smoothly. In the afterlife, as is generally accepted, we will each be invited to a grand party in the sky with all of our loved ones. From the beginning until the end, mankind is dependent on social interaction, so much so that each sacrifices him or herself in order for the group. Social Animal Social Soul analyzes mankind's dependence on social interaction and satirically depicts the impossibility for the individual to survive within this system of conditioning. Our main character notices within his reflection that he is no different than his peers, first within a tribal setting. With this revelation he attempts to change when discovering the civilized world. He is immediately tossed into the workforce and soon realizes that he has changed but is now no different from this new group of people. He finally is whisked into heaven only to once again reveal that his transformation and growth has only led him to become like everyone around him. The ambiguous conclusion forces no opinions, but raises the question of whether individuality is possible at anytime within our existence.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?504237</url></doc>
