<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="504324">
  <docid>504324</docid>
  <title>Sociology of Me</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Reed, Jim (III)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">22 November 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Reeder, Cory</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Becker, Phillys</producer>
    <producer>Bloom, Lori</producer>
    <producer>Reeder, Cory</producer>
    <producer>Appezzato, Michelle</producer>
    <producer>Bloom, Amy (II)</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>A Journey through a man's life, as told by those who have known him. "Throughout my life people around me have always told me that I should write a book about my life. Well, I am not a writer, I am a filmmaker, and so I have decided to make a film about it." These are the words of the director of "Sociology of Me", Cory Reeder. Born in the 70's, baked in the 80's, drunk through the 90's and now earning a self proclaimed comeback in the new millennium, he has experienced the depth of love, sadness of death, horror of murder and delirium of addiction. He is an artist, musician and poet, but most passionately, a film maker, and is setting out to tell his life story in a most unique way. In the form of a documentary. This story is not a look back at a life, but an introduction to a person who is at his prime. He has chosen to have his story relayed by those characters. "I always thought my friends and family were interesting enough to relate who I am, so I devised this concept:" "I have always known that I wanted to be a filmmaker and, along with other people's admissions, I have always thought that my life story would make an interesting film. But, to take that story, my story, and put it in the hand of friends, enemies, family and colleagues and have them relate it to an audience? That may turn into a completely different story of it's own."</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?504324</url></doc>
