<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="505027">
  <docid>505027</docid>
  <title>Soldier's Dream</title>
  <year>1903</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1903</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
<plot>Human nature has its differing sides of life and this trait of character is fully shared by our soldiers, and though their business is fighting the battles of our country, "the boys in blue" have a tender side to their natures. For the most part they have left happy homes and loved ones who they know are thinking of them day by day, and it is but natural that those so left should occupy a very large share in the thoughts and cares of the soldier when on duty. Our subject beautifully illustrates this dual side of soldier life. In the commencement of the film is shown the soldiers' camp, with sentry doing guard duty, camp-fires are lit and a tired soldier is seen snatching a few hours of repose in front of it. As the smoke arises from the fire pictures appear which supposedly illustrate the dreams which visit the sleeping man. Doubtless his thoughts fly across the sea as he thinks of the home and dear ones for whom he pines, and his dreams following in this course, picture of the home he has left appears with wonderful fidelity in the rising smoke. Anon, his sleeping visions change, the clang of arms, the thunder of the cannon and the shriek of shells remind him of the battles through which he has passed and the comrades he has left on the bloody field never to rise again, but as some author has remarked, "'Tis not always bullets that kill," and brave hearts that shrink from no dangers in war are tenderly touched by visions of loved ones at home. Thus in the mixed dreams of the old home, its joys and its music, and the strenuous life which he is now living at the present, the soldier boy passes his fitful night, and awakening find that all is but a dream, and gladly hails the dawn which brings him one day nearer to his own dear land. Appealing, as does this wonderful film, to the most patriotic and human sentiments, it is enthusiastically received wherever shown, and no exhibitor should consider his outfit complete without a copy of it.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?505027</url></doc>
