<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="505132">
  <docid>505132</docid>
  <title>Soledad</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Andrich, Chiara</editor>
    <editor>Baena, Martin-Esteban</editor>
    <editor>Berrocal, Angel</editor>
    <editor>Hernández, Carlos (XVIII)</editor>
    <editor>Naranjo, Beatríz</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>post-apocalyptic</keyword>
    <keyword>lonely</keyword>
    <keyword>violence</keyword>
    <keyword>old-man</keyword>
    <keyword>gas-mask</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
    <country>Argentina</country>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Argentina">Unrated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Argentina">28 March 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Argentina">25</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="Canada">19</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Baena, Martin-Esteban</director>
    <director>Íscar, Ricardo</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Baena, Martin-Esteban</producer>
    <producer>Zeglen, David</producer>
    <producer>Salas, Isabella (I)</producer>
    <producer>Baena, Roberto</producer>
    <producer>Durrieu, Mario</producer>
    <producer>McGrory, Patricia</producer>
    <producer>McGrory, Rob</producer>
    <producer>Tiepelmann, Walter</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Íscar, Ricardo</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Baena, Martin-Esteban</actor>
      <role>Kane</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Birkett, Mike</actor>
      <role>Pasq</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Duong, Liem</actor>
      <role>Kane</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A man awakens in a toxic landscape, the ruins of an extinct civilization. Surrounded on all sides by a vast system of highways that run high above the ground, he searches for other survivors. After days of searching, the man comes across another survivor. Initially overjoyed, the man soon realizes his new-found companion does not share his enthusiasm and optimism for survival. 'Soledad' is about two men who find themselves isolated in a hostile world with no familiar surroundings, left to their own devices. Each character reacts differently to this stimulus. The idealist sees hope and the possibility of rescue at every turn, possibly by other survivors, like himself. A broken pocket-watch he finds on the ground is enough to convince him other survivors are nearby. The other man is a stoic and fatalist. The same watch can only confirm what he has already suspected for so long: a bitter residue of humanity is all that remains. Only death without salvation awaits their idle bodies. However conviction in one's belief is not enough, as both are determined to convince each other, first through reason and discussion, of their respective ideologies. When that fails, it is only through violence that they are able to determine an outcome that surprises them both. Only through violence are they able to share the ideals they hold so dear, ideals they are willing to defend to the bitter end.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?505132</url></doc>
