<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="506217">
  <docid>506217</docid>
  <title>Somewhere Only We Know</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>New Zealand</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="New Zealand">22 May 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="New Zealand">10</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Lawrence, Jamie (V)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Lawrence, Jamie (V)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Lawrence, Jamie (V)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Keenan, Camille</actor>
      <role>June</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Minto, Matthew</actor>
      <role>Doug</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Somewhere Only We Know is a silent film that tells the story of indomitable love and how it redefines the spirit of the human being. The story begins in a nursing home. June is eighty-three, with advancing Alzheimer's. She sits in her chair by a window overlooking a garden. This is her world. A place where the remaining time of her life passes slowly. Her husband, Doug, takes the bus to visit her each day; bearing flowers, to feed her and comb her hair and whisper sweet nothings that mean everything. But beneath his eyes, is something lost, wounded and unforgotten. In a collage of images showing June and Doug's life together, we discover a secret. This is when we meet Edna, clutching a photo of two young women, grinning full of life. The picture is of Edna and June as their younger selves. The photo plunges us back into wartime New Zealand when June and Edna are young and radiant. Their lives appear to be much different as we watch them in a series of moments together, 1940's gorgeous, fearless, inseparable. In love. That is until June's encounter with a young stranger named Doug. Secretly consumed with heartbreak and jealousy at the wedding of June and Doug, Edna boldly kisses June on the lips. But as best friends, June ignores any hidden meaning it may have had. In the hope of forgetting the past, June tries to set Edna up with a handsome man over dinner; only the women find themselves locked in each other's arms instead. Their love affair ensues, until Doug finds out and confronts the women in a fit of rage. June abandons Edna to follow her husband, and tries to lead a "normal" life, but finds it impossible as Edna writes to her in secrecy. The story returns to June as an old woman in the nursing home, when Doug is confronted by the past after finding a hidden photo sent to June from Edna. In a true expression of love, Doug invites Edna to see June once more in an effort to reconcile. It is here that Doug and Edna share a long gaze, an understanding of what it truly is to be in love with the same woman, from its first delicate moments to its last.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?506217</url></doc>
