<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="508594">
  <docid>508594</docid>
  <title>Southern India: A Collision of Cultures</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Eberhart, Jennifer</editor>
    <editor>Richardson, Scott (IX)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>video-institute</keyword>
    <keyword>southern-india</keyword>
    <keyword>religion</keyword>
    <keyword>hindu</keyword>
    <keyword>travelogue</keyword>
    <keyword>student-film</keyword>
    <keyword>study-abroad</keyword>
    <keyword>caste-system</keyword>
    <keyword>christianity</keyword>
    <keyword>bangalore</keyword>
    <keyword>canisius-college</keyword>
    <keyword>india</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">21 April 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">28</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Eberhart, Jennifer</director>
    <director>Irwin, Barbara (II)</director>
    <director>Richardson, Scott (IX)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Eberhart, Jennifer</producer>
    <producer>Richardson, Scott (IX)</producer>
    <producer>Irwin, Barbara (II)</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>Follow the journey as a group of students and faculty travel to Southern India with the 'Christianity on the Road Less Traveled' program at Canisius College. Southern India: A Collision of Cultures documents religious, social, economic, and cultural aspects of this ancient and fascinating country as experienced by the group on their month-long immersion trip in the Summer of 2007. The film explores the caste system, technology industries, Hindu and Jain religions, the roots of Christianity in India, and the natural beauty of the country. In a place where many cultures collide, the hopes and dreams of the Indian people are strikingly similar to those of the travelers. Using a 'travelogue' style, the film follows the group from their arrival in Chennai to central and coastal regions, including Bangalor, Goa, and Kottayam, as well as Poovar Island in the Arabian Sea. Tour guides, religious leaders, and educators provide insight into the history of places visited and the present lives of those who live there. The travelers also express their thoughts and reflections on what they see and experience.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?508594</url></doc>
