<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="509773">
  <docid>509773</docid>
  <title>Speed</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kothari, Hemal</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>hostage</keyword>
    <keyword>cell-phone</keyword>
    <keyword>telephone</keyword>
    <keyword>kidnapping</keyword>
    <keyword>telephone-call</keyword>
    <keyword>race-against-time</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">19 October 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Bhatt, Vikram</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Dhamija, Girish</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Chakraborty, Pritam</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arora, Amrita</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chaudhary, Aashish</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chaudhary, Sophiya</actor>
      <role>Monica</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dutta, Tanushree</actor>
      <role>Sanjana</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khalsekar, Ashwini</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Zayed</actor>
      <role>Sandeep 'Sandy' Arora</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khera, Rajesh</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Matondkar, Urmila</actor>
      <role>Richa S. Verma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shivdasani, Aftab</actor>
      <role>Kabir Khan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Suri, Sanjay</actor>
      <role>Siddharth Verma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zutshi, Rajendranath</actor>
      <role>Raj</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Zayed comes to London to convince his girlfriend Minisha to give him another chance to prove his love for her. Meanwhile, Sanjay, an undercover MI5 agent, receives a CD from Sohail Khan and his lady, Tanushree, which contains the recording of his kidnapped wife, Urmila, and is asked to follow the instructions. He asks his colleague Amrita to crack the code and moves off. He's completely confused about what's happening. Soon he realizes that he is being used as a weapon to assassinate the PM of India on his London tour. As he is still not agreeing to plans, Sohail finally decides to kidnap his kid. Sanjay's kidnapped wife, Urmila, starts trying to escape. Her only ray of hope is the telephone call she's accidentally made to Zayed Khan. He's in touch with her throughout the movie on his cell phone. Continuously talking with her and giving her moral support. As Zayed decides to help Urmila, his love of life,Minisha gets pissed off and threatens to break up again. A happy-go-lucky brat Zayed, who never takes anything seriously, risks his own life to save an unknown family just because of a call. Aashish Chaudhary - the super-cop of London is in charge of security of the visiting Prime Minister. But as his girlfriend has her birthday the very same day, Ashish is caught between his personal life and duty. He obviously chooses the later. Will Sohail and tanushree succeed in their sinister plans? And will Zayed be able to save his love life with Minisha?, Will Urmila and her kid live another day just with the help of Zayed's phone? Will Ashish be able to protect the life of the Prime Minister?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?509773</url></doc>
