<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="510918">
  <docid>510918</docid>
  <title>Split Second</title>
  <year>1986</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Game-Show</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>non-fiction</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">15 December 1986</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Pasila, Henry</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hall, Monty</actor>
      <role>Host</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hoyt, Sandy</actor>
      <role>Announcer</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>As was its 1970s predecesor, "Split Second" was a fast-moving game show where three contestants, one a returning champion, competed to answer general knowledge questions and win cash. Host Hall announced a category (e.g., "Female Music Video Stars") and a question relating to the category ("Who was the star of the following music videos?"); the players were shown three clues ("Like a Virgin," "Girls Just Want to Have Fun," "Who's Ever in New England"). All three contestants rang in, the one who rang in first having the first chance to select a clue and provide an answer. If he was right, he won a share of the pot; his/her opponents could answer two or possibly all three questions. Players were rewarded based on their ability to answer $10 each if all three contestants provided one right answer; $25 if two of them were right; and $50 if just one answered all three questions correctly (by the way, the correct answers were, in order, Madonna, Cyndi Lauper and Reba McEntire). After an undefined time limit, dollar values were doubled (i.e., $20, $50 and $100). In the game's final round, contestants were seeded based on their score up to that point the player in the lead needing four correct answers to become champion, second place requiring five and third place requiring six; ties required the players to answer the lesser of the required number of questions. The player who met his/her requirements first was the day's winner. That player moved on to the bonus round, played one of two ways 1. The player chose three of five screens; if they all read "CAR," they won that prize and left un-defeated, otherwise, they won a "FUR" or a "TRIP" and returned to the next show. 2. The player chose one of five screens; if it said "CAR," they won the car and retired un-defeated, otherwise it was $1,000 and a return to the next show, where a championship win meaning improved odds. Five-time champions retired undefeated and won a new car.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?510918</url></doc>
