<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="512478">
  <docid>512478</docid>
  <title>St. Bernard Parish: After the Flood</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Astrausky, Jim</editor>
    <editor>Lintner, Hannah</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>hurricane</keyword>
    <keyword>louisiana</keyword>
    <keyword>katrina</keyword>
    <keyword>natural-disaster</keyword>
    <keyword>flood</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">30 December 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">50</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Astrausky, Jim</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Barr, Jessica (I)</producer>
    <producer>Astrausky, Jim</producer>
    <producer>Carey, Dan (III)</producer>
    <producer>Norton, Sue (I)</producer>
    <producer>Lintner, Hannah</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Astrausky, Jim</writer>
    <writer>Lintner, Hannah</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>In August of 2005 hurricane Katrina slammed into the Louisiana coast. St. Bernard Parish, a proudly spiritual and tightly knit community which borders New Orleans' 9th Ward, became the first county that has ever been completely destroyed by a natural disaster. Out of 27,000 homes and businesses only five were left undamaged by the storm. Over one year later piles of rubble and debris still line the parish streets and only forty percent of the community has returned home. Residents live off of their dwindling savings in FEMA trailers as they suffer through the bewildering process of picking up the pieces of their lives. Meanwhile the town council struggles through the grueling process of obtaining relief money for the parish and the people who love it. The money is slow in coming and there never seems to be enough and yet, the council refuses to give up the fight. This is the untold story of the undying spirit of a community starting with nothing but determined to rebuild against all odds.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?512478</url></doc>
