<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="512768">
  <docid>512768</docid>
  <title>Stag: Final Indulgence Uncensored</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Tinney, Copeland</editor>
    <editor>Tran, Knick</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Reality-TV</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">3 May 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ricamore, Scott</producer>
    <producer>Habeeb, Tommy</producer>
    <producer>Hays, Marshall</producer>
    <producer>Allen, Clark (I)</producer>
    <producer>Tolbert, Donny</producer>
    <producer>Tran, Knick</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Habeeb, Tommy</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Our first bachelor Omarr is one smooth customer who loves to groove on the dance floor and flirt with whatever female is closest. Once his dirty dancing bachelor party is caught on tape, he has to scramble to find a way out of trouble... even if it means finally buying that engagement ring he's been putting off. Will the long-overdue jewelry be enough to convince his fiancée Anna that he's serious about marriage? The second wild bachelor party follows Lance, another king of the dance floor that has finally found his dancing queen in Crystal, his lovely fiancée. But when this reformed ladies man runs into some ex-girlfriends out on the town during his bachelor party, will this blonde bombshell brigade from the past have the ammunition to destroy the happy couple? They may get the Final Indulgence, but they won't have the last word! Watch the wildest, hottest reality show on television, where real-life couples put their love to the test before walking down that aisle. Will their relationship survive its greatest test? Find out on STAG: Final Indulgence Uncensored... on Events IN DEMAND Pay-per-View.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?512768</url></doc>
