<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="513330">
  <docid>513330</docid>
  <title>Stanley Rubin: A Work in Progress</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Drake, Linda</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">49</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Tighe, Kellett</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Tighe, Kellett</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Tighe, Kellett</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Benjamin, Richard (I)</actor>
      <role>As self</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Clark, Susan (I)</actor>
      <role>As self</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hiller, Arthur</actor>
      <role>As self</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Holliman, Earl</actor>
      <role>As self</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hughes, Kathleen (I)</actor>
      <role>As self</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Karras, Alex</actor>
      <role>As self</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rubin, Stanley</actor>
      <role>As self</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>After a lifetime in the film and TV industries, during which he wrote and produced over seventy-five movies and television shows, won the very first Emmy the night of the very first Emmy's, President of the Producers Guild of America for years, and one of the first Board Members of The Writers Guild Of America - Stanley- age eighty-eight - returns to UCLA to complete his undergraduate degree, left unfinished seventy years before. Stanley tells us about his childhood, parents, and the emotional scars he suffered as a result of his parents divorce. We meet Kathy his wife of fifty-two years and witness their humorous repartee as well as the deep love and commitment between them. Stanley tells great old Hollywood insider stories, involving everyone from Howard Hughes, Clint Eastwood, Marilyn Monroe, Otto Preminger, to Lew Wasserman. While interviewing Stanley and Kathy we inter-cut their interviews with their movies. We follow Stanley to UCLA while he tries on his cap and gown for graduation, and - for old times sake - visits the current editor in chef of the UCLA Daily Bruin, culminating with Stanley graduating.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?513330</url></doc>
