<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="513404">
  <docid>513404</docid>
  <title>Star Child: The Beginning</title>
  <year>2010</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">May 2010</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <producers>
    <producer>Adusumilli, Tanya</producer>
    <producer>Bland, Kim</producer>
    <producer>Cameron, Luke (I)</producer>
    <producer>Cook, James Magnum</producer>
    <producer>Donnelly, Damien (I)</producer>
    <producer>Gowdy, Joey Paul</producer>
    <producer>Gray, Ronald L.</producer>
    <producer>Henderson, Sherilyn</producer>
    <producer>Hernke, Hans</producer>
    <producer>Kinnamon, Patricia</producer>
    <producer>Kutsick, Michael</producer>
    <producer>Lewinski, Ted R.</producer>
    <producer>Nguyen, Steve (I)</producer>
    <producer>Pozo, Joseph</producer>
    <producer>Rose, Katherine Victoria</producer>
    <producer>Srivastava, K. Raj</producer>
    <producer>Connolly, Deborah</producer>
    <producer>Cook, James Magnum</producer>
    <producer>Criss, Nancy</producer>
    <producer>Milstead, Darrell</producer>
    <producer>Pecchia, Stefano</producer>
    <producer>Schad, Alexis Marissa</producer>
    <producer>Sylvester III, Dominick John</producer>
    <producer>Baird-Monks, Nick</producer>
    <producer>Criss, Nancy</producer>
    <producer>Fallaize, Gene</producer>
    <producer>Jackson, Travis A.</producer>
    <producer>Milstead, Darrell</producer>
    <producer>Thomas, Jeffery A.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Porter, Ernest</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Criss, Nancy</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>While I was a young boy, I would lie next to my bedroom window watching the stars at night. I felt that I belonged somewhere in the galaxies that star people were watching us. A million years before the birth of Christ from the beginning of the Ice Age, the council elders from other planets look down at earth watching its people go from cave dwellers to modern man. The council decided to send 1000 star children to help with the guidance of mankind into the future. The star children had three rules which they must abide by; one they may not interfere with their religion, second interfere or be members in any wars and third do not interfere with free will. A million years plus and mankind is still engaged in wars and now time is getting close for the star children to go home. The question, has man learned enough, will man learn to protect the earth and all its animals, fish in the seas, birds and the air? Will man respect the earth he lives on, or the air he breathes? It's your choice, it's your earth, and it's your future, if any. Man must learn from his mistakes and learn from those who would help. The elders hoped that some time in the future, planet earth could join its sister planets and take its place on the council of elders. To understand this we will follow the life of a star child.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?513404</url></doc>
