<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="514560">
  <docid>514560</docid>
  <title>Station Master</title>
  <year>1942</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">157</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Luhar, Chimanlal</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Aundhkar, Vishnupant</writer>
    <writer>Santoshi, P.L.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Naushad (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Adib, Prem</actor>
      <role>Arun</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Devi, Pratima</actor>
      <role>Didi (Niranjan's sister)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gulab (I)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jeevan (I)</actor>
      <role>Manikbabu (Shyama's dad)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kaushalya</actor>
      <role>Shyama</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sethi, Jagdish</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shakir (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Usha lives a poor lifestyle with her widowed father, Parmanand, who is the Station Master of Rangpur Railway Station in India. She is smart, intelligent and educated, and is expected to marry someone of equal status. A railway employee, (Pointsman), Kalicharan, would like Usha to get married to Niranjan, who is the DTS of Indian Railways, and this will ensure that Kalicharan's son will also get employed with the Railway. Both Kalicharan and Parmanand approach Manikbabu, another Railway employee, who wants his semi-senile daughter, Shyama, to marry Arun, a Guard with the Railway. Soon Niranjan's sister comes to see Usha, approves of her, and goes home to make preparations for a marriage. But Usha has fallen in love with Arun, wants to marry him, and refuses to marry Niranjan, who is twice as old as her and a widower as well. Usha's decision has an adverse effect on all the local rail employees, and as a result no one is able to avert an accident that takes place between an express and a goods train. Watch what happens when the Government orders an Inquiry into this incident, and the effect this will have on the lives of all railway employees - some or all of whom may be found guilty and may face imprisonment.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?514560</url></doc>
