<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="514695">
  <docid>514695</docid>
  <title>Stay Good</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">13 October 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="USA">8</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Perez, Julie (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Perez, Julie (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Amato, Alissa</actor>
      <role>Friend 2</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Amato, Ross</actor>
      <role>Boy 2</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bisgaier, Peter</actor>
      <role>Dad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Borenzweig, Sam</actor>
      <role>Boy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brainin, Tammy</actor>
      <role>Principal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Goldman, Travis</actor>
      <role>Clerk</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Huang, Amy</actor>
      <role>Friend 1</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Merritt, Courtney</actor>
      <role>Jessica</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>It is Monday morning - a golden beam of sunlight illuminates a bedside table. On this table we see a stack of prayers cards, books about the lives of the Saints, a Child's Catholic Pictionary, a picture of St. Rita, a rosary and a small statue of Mother Teresa. This room is Jessica's - she is 12 years old and wants to be a nun. Her alarm rings an electronic version of "Jesus, Joy of Man's Desiring". She gets up and today, like every other day, she goes to St. Mary's church to say her prayers before school. As she's walking to class, she sees a boy she has never seen in her neighborhood before. He...is beautiful. Her eyes are locked onto him as she walks right into her friends. Her prayer cards go flying into the air. The girls stop to help her pick them up - all the time poking fun at her for wanting to be a nun, as they usually do - and of course all nuns are virgins - so she'll have to stay a virgin for the rest of her life. They tell her what they think she'll be missing, but they really don't have a clue about sex and she doesn't believe them...they can't possibly be right. Jessica's friends run off when the school bell rings, but the young BOY comes over to help her pick up her prayer cards. He is more beautiful than she thought, she finds herself staring at him. He touches her hand; Jessica doesn't know what to do, so she runs away. The next morning, instead of going to church, she walks to the bookstore. She purchases a book about sex and brings it to the playground. As she's showing her friends the pictures in the book, the principal walks up to them. Alarmed, Jessica's friends run off and the book falls to the ground - the principal, seeing this interesting book, quizzically looks at Jessica...She is busted.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?514695</url></doc>
