<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="514907">
  <docid>514907</docid>
  <title>Steel &amp; Silk</title>
  <year>2011</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Mystery</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>revenge</keyword>
    <keyword>stepfather</keyword>
    <keyword>punctuation-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>1980s</keyword>
    <keyword>terrorist</keyword>
    <keyword>1982</keyword>
    <keyword>ampersand-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>nun</keyword>
    <keyword>mumbai-india</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">25 July 2011</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Armstrong, Andy (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Armstrong, Andy (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Ward, Kevin D.</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Our story begins in Mumbai in 1982. Children play at an orphanage. An expensive chauffer driven limousine pulls up and parks outside. From within it steps a man. With him is a children's uniformed nanny. They greet the nuns who run the orphanage. Separated from the large group of children are three young girls. They are each about the same age, but very different in looks. The nuns scoop them up and carry them to the limousine. The girls are smiles and laughter. We never see the man, but from his body language we can tell that he feels the same. Man, nanny and girls all drive away in the limousine. We montage through the next years to see the girls grow and develop. We see that one is very athletic and that she excels at school sports, then at dance and judo and karate. Eventually, we see her competing in judo and karate competitions worldwide. First, she competes against girls her size, then against bigger older girls, then against boys and eventually against men. We see her being filmed in exercise and women's self defense videos. She's clearly both a celebrity and a champion. The next girl we see through the years riding a bicycle, then in a "peddle car", then upon a small kid's motorcycle and then driving go-carts. We see her competing in go-carts, on motorcycles and then eventually in racecars. We see her traveling the world racing and rallying. She too is both a celebrity and a champion. The third girl is without question the brain of the three. We see her in mathematics contests and spelling bees at age five and then surrounded by university professors and performing huge, absolutely incredible mathematical calculations at age seven, leaving all the adults speechless in the process. By the time she's an adult, she is running a rocket propulsion lab facility at NASA. She is interviewed on TV, is a guest speaker at "packed house" university lecture halls and a guest of honor at "up scale dinners" around the world. She's both a star and a champion. Back in modern day India, the girls all arrive at their stepfather's home. They each have their own individual forms of transportation. The rocket scientist arrives in an electric-powered car fueled by solar panels. The athletic celebrity pulls up in a huge Hummer. And the racer arrives in an Aston Martin. Their father's bodyguard greets all the girls warmly. He is about fifteen years older than the girls. He's ex military, very handsome, charismatic and obviously a very tough guy in the understated way of James Bond. The girls all hug him. The chauffer who picked them up from the orphanage when they were babies and the nanny who looked after them while they grew up, now both quite old, also come out to meet the girls. They are all obviously like family to them. They all are walking towards the mansion when there is massive explosion and fireball. The house is engulfed in fire and smoke. The girls rush in to find their stepfather. The bodyguard pulls out his gun while the chauffer and nanny start to weep. We all know it's too late. Their stepfather is dead. Our story is the girl's quest to find out who killed their father and why. They enlist the help of the bodyguard to train them in the use of weapons and military maneuvers. He is also as intent on revenge as the girls. He feels responsible for letting their stepfather get killed. The chauffer and nanny provide base camp back up when the girls turn their old childhood home into an operations command and training center. The girls and the bodyguard form a powerful, skilled and deadly team. They discover their stepfather was killed by a group of drug smuggling terrorists who import arms and export heroin. They have been smuggling their wares on board ships owned by the girls' stepfather and when he discovered them, he had told the authorities. Unfortunately the people he told are corrupt and they told the terrorists, so he was targeted for assassination. Now the girls have a mission on their hands: to stop the terrorists and to avenge their stepfather.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?514907</url></doc>
