<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="514912">
  <docid>514912</docid>
  <title>Steel Broken</title>
  <year>2011</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Nord, Richard</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>lawyer</keyword>
    <keyword>ex-convict</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2011</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <producers>
    <producer>Peoples, Theresa</producer>
    <producer>Steineckert, Stacy</producer>
    <producer>Stack, Jeanne</producer>
    <producer>Miner, Tim (III)</producer>
    <producer>Riley, Hope</producer>
    <producer>Steineckert, Stacy</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Riley, Hope</writer>
    <writer>Whitney, Jane (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Miner, Tim (III)</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>The issue of prison overcrowding is shoved into the media spotlight when a terrifying pedophile is released early into society only to kill again. In four contrasting stories, we see the common thread of violence and injustice that plagues our penal system. Michael Stevens is a young attorney in the justice department who must try to hunt down a solution to this unsolvable problem before the powder keg explodes. During his journey, he crosses paths with his former love, Gina, a mother of two who is awaiting the release of her incarcerated husband Jason, a man actually rehabilitated by the broken system... if only he can survive his final days in prison. Gina finds herself torn between her loyalty to Jason and her family, and the promise of a better life she sees in Michael. And then there's Shawn, a young black man whose future seemed set in concrete from the time of his birth. A good kid who has been given no opportunities in life and has been forced to make decisions based on survival rather than morals or ethics. In the end, all of these lives will be intertwined and their fates shared, determined not by the choices they would like to make, but by those forced upon them by a horrifically violent and corrupt justice system.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?514912</url></doc>
