<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="515995">
  <docid>515995</docid>
  <title>Stingers Rule!</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>kids-and-family</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2 June 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Tempest, Martin (III)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Wand, Danielle</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Coyle, Patti Hogan</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Baum, Conor</actor>
      <role>Richard</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cherry, Paul</actor>
      <role>Officer Miller</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Coyle, Patti</actor>
      <role>Bertha Bowzaire</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Crick, Ben</actor>
      <role>Oliver</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Edward, Emerson</actor>
      <role>Doufas</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Handley, Kirstie</actor>
      <role>Dorcas</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hawkins, Hugo</actor>
      <role>Asbo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hudson, Jo</actor>
      <role>Madam Poshki</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ing, Jonathan</actor>
      <role>Mike O Phone</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Johnson, Hannah (V)</actor>
      <role>Raven</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jones, Malcolm (IX)</actor>
      <role>Sir Horace</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jordon, Claire</actor>
      <role>Tiff</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Leeks, Andrew</actor>
      <role>Stephen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Leeks, Stephen</actor>
      <role>Stan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pasqualino, Luke</actor>
      <role>Anthony</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Reading, Peggy</actor>
      <role>Ida</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A local children's football team springs into action when they risk losing their beloved old ground to property developers. Can The Stingers raise enough funds to save the historic pitch and its crumbling clubhouse with time, bad luck and Bertha Balzare against them? Thanks to the devious and greedy Bertha and her unfortunate son, Richard, one of England's oldest football grounds is scheduled to be bulldozed and converted into a new property development. Horrified by the prospect of losing the ground, Antony and Rosie round up the troops to try and raise enough money to buy back the property. After a week of comically unsuccessful fund raising, The Stingers are not only in greater debt but they're also about to run out of time. When all hope seems to be lost, Richard Balzare inadvertently reveals that the local council has organized a sponsored walk to Scarfell Pike, England's highest peak. Recognizing an brilliant opportunity when it presents itself, The Stingers spring into action seeking sponsorship from the community. Now their task becomes steeper than Scarfell Pike itself as a skeptical bunch of misfits with low morale, low expectations and lower fitness levels face their greatest challenge. The day of the big walk dawns. As the brass band plays The Stingers off, Bertha forces Richard to join The Stingers on their walk as a spy to ensure that they can't possibly finish the walk. The Stingers, although dubious of Richard's motives, take him on board. From mad camp leaders to very bad English weather, a gang of Goths and a painfully long Margaret Thatcher slide show at the Grantham Museum, The Stingers seem destined not to reach the peak. But determination and impressive team work result in a heart-felt victory for The Stingers, leaving Bertha Balzare, literally, in the mud. The team's football ground is saved, spirits soar and even a little romance blossoms along the way. Back of the net!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?515995</url></doc>
