<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="516150">
  <docid>516150</docid>
  <title>Stockholm: Volume 1</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Culham, Padraic</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>stockholm-syndrome</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">21</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>McKay, Michael (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>McKay, Michael (I)</producer>
    <producer>McKay, Michael (I)</producer>
    <producer>Timmins, Sara Elizabeth</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>McKay, Michael (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Carmassi, Giulio</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cook, Amanda (IV)</actor>
      <role>Cheryl</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Forde, Liz</actor>
      <role>Blonde</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hynes, Jennifer</actor>
      <role>Brunette</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McKay, Michael (I)</actor>
      <role>Andy</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Stockholm is an exploration of the Stockholm Syndrome, a victim's response to being totally reliant on a captor. It becomes a reliable tool of manipulation to one brilliant, chronically amoral, landlord, told from the secret, sound-proofed basement room of this serial rapist and murderer. Andy takes in boarders in the room where his daughter used to live, and on the rare occasions where conditions are right, he drugs and keeps them in a special room, where they are constantly watched. Liz Beneteau is his latest prize, a beautiful naive girl from Ohio who arrived in Los Angeles attempting to become an actress. If she is to survive this ordeal, and maintain her sanity, she will have to convince him that she is in love with him, the acting role of a lifetime, then wait patiently for her chance to escape. Nothing Simpler. But two problems complicate the matter. First, Beth (the name Andy prefers to call her) learns that there have been others. She knows Andy killed his wife and daughter. How many others she doesn't know; nor what they did to earn the full measure of Andy's retribution. Second, despite the circumstances, Beth really is falling for Andy.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?516150</url></doc>
