<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="519272">
  <docid>519272</docid>
  <title>Stunt Dawgs</title>
  <year>1992</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <genres>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <directors>
    <director>Grusd, John</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Fox, Melody (II)</writer>
    <writer>Himmell, Todd</writer>
    <writer>MacGillivray, Cliff</writer>
    <writer>O'Donnell, Kevin (V)</writer>
    <writer>Trout, Earl L.</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Atkin, Harvey</actor>
      <role>Budyear/Half-A-Mind</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Budd, Barbara</actor>
      <role>Nina Newscaster</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Crone, Neil</actor>
      <role>Needham/Whiz Kid</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Morton, Greg (I)</actor>
      <role>Crash/Velma/Splat</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rubin, Ron</actor>
      <role>Airball/Slime</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stocker, John</actor>
      <role>Richard P. Fungus</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Swanson, Greg</actor>
      <role>Skidd/Lucky</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The show revolves around the manic antics of the Stunt Dawgs, a band of Hollywood stuntmen (and one woman) who double as troubleshooters. The team, led by the gung-ho Needham, consists of: Splat (a wealthy guy who speaks like Dudley Do-Right and specialized in plane stunts), Crash (the cool African-American who specializes in car wrecks; he also has the misfortune of being endlessly pursued by an obsessed female fan named Velma), Sizzle (the token female whose passion is pyrotechnics) and the rookie Skidd (an unkempt New-Age dude who drives a motorcycle). They also have a dog mascot named Human. The Dawgs' adventures always seem to involve foiling the schemes of a crazed villainous Hollywood producer/director named Richard P. Fungus and his band of stuntmen; the Stunt Scabs, consisting of Airball (Fungus' sycophantic French sidekick), Budyear (a big lunk who'd do anything for money), Half-A-Mind (a disfigured stuntman who has the habit of falling to pieces-literally-and of course, has a notoriously small intellect), Lucky (who, of course, wasn't; he attracts bad luck wherever he goes), and Whiz Kid (a geeky genius responsible for the Scabs' technology). Fungus also has a slimy lawyer at his disposal named Slime.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?519272</url></doc>
