<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="521108">
  <docid>521108</docid>
  <title>Summer Reunion</title>
  <year>1999</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
    <genre>Adult</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>sexual-fantasy</keyword>
    <keyword>gay</keyword>
    <keyword>sex</keyword>
    <keyword>softcore</keyword>
    <keyword>homosexual</keyword>
    <keyword>hardcore</keyword>
    <keyword>erotica</keyword>
    <keyword>gay-love</keyword>
    <keyword>orgy</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">X</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">65</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Osborne, Greg</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Eustace, Stephen</producer>
    <producer>Osborne, Greg</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Osborne, Greg</writer>
    <writer>Strait, Patryk</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ashton, Geoff</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brooks, Kristian</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Parker, Reed</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Richards, Zach</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Taylor, Frank (III)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Rendezvous is a stunningly sexy adventure unlike anything you've seen in an erotic video format before. The challenge extended to the director was to bring to the screen the most vivid and provocatively charged scenes of intimacy that have ever appeared in a Greenwood Cooper video. He has succeeded in delivering an arousing fantasy that boldly pushes the envelope of sensuality in directions most of us have only imagined. Bo and Matt are a couple of sexy young lovers who allow you to follow them on a romantic getaway tot eh quaint Golden Gate Bed &amp; Breakfast in enchanting San Francisco. No sooner have these two young hunks checked into this inn for gay men and they find themselves willing victims of the sensual spells of their new surroundings. Eight strapping hunks seductively add to the arousing nature of the Bed &amp; Breakfast's tempting environment and lead you and our couple on a sexually charged journey where fantasies, real and imagined, are vividly and erotically brought to life. The ten entrancing men in this video share with you the wonder and excitement of the fantasies fulfilled and will have you rushing to book your own romantic getaway. Rendezvous marks an exciting new chapter in the world of sensually themed videos and is, without question, the most unforgettable erotic experience we've ever produced.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?521108</url></doc>
