<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="521929">
  <docid>521929</docid>
  <title>Sunstone</title>
  <year>1979</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>experimental-film</keyword>
    <keyword>art</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">3</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Emshwiller, Ed</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Emshwiller, Ed</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Emshwiller, Peter</actor>
      <role>The Shape</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Electronic Arts Intermix describes Ed Emshwiller's pioneering experimental concept video as a digital sculpture: "Sunstone is a landmark tape. Symbolic and poetic, it is a pivotal work in the development of an electronic language to articulate three-dimensional space. The opening image is an iconic face, which appears to be electronically 'carved' from stone. A mystical third eye, brilliantly crafted from a digital palette, radiates with vibrant transformations of color and texture. Sculpting electronically, Emshwiller then transforms perspectival representation: the archetypal 'sunstone' is revealed to be one facet of an open, revolving cube, each side of which holds a simultaneously visible, moving video image. Created with complex technology over an eight-month period, this emblematic spinning cube metaphorically describes a three-dimensional, temporal space, both hyperreal and simulated. Emshwiller's humanistic approach to technology ushered in the 1980s with a new electronic vocabulary for conceptualizing and visualizing images in space and time. Reflecting an image-saturated world. SUNSTONE marked a new stage in electronic art."</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?521929</url></doc>
