<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="522903">
  <docid>522903</docid>
  <title>Supply Curve</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Matheny, John (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">10 November 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Mott, Tom (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Mott, Tom (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Diaz, Christina Marie</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Matheny, John (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Alvarez, Rina</actor>
      <role>Gina</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Newman, Michael (VII)</actor>
      <role>Adam Smith</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The economic principle of supply and demand is contingent upon two curves: the demand curve and the supply curve. The latter determines how much of a good is willing to be supplied at a given time considering the circumstances. The higher the price, the more of an item will be sold, raising the curve. Simultaneously, an age old axiom - "Sex sells" - exists as a wise solution to problems in selling any item, used in marketing strategies worldwide. However, creating a piece of modern wisdom, advertising great Jef I. Richards once said that sex sells only if you're selling sex. All of these things considered, then what happens when the Theory of Supply Curve is applied to selling sex? In a seedy strip club, an average guy realizes that a single dollar will only gain the attentions of a beautiful erotic dancer, but more money offered will raise the curve of what she is willing to supply him. When he offers the right price for a night with her, who will ultimately win? If his money determines the curve, then he should also possess power over her. If sex proves to be the one thing that is not applicable to all of the standing rules, then it's possible that she will determine her own curve.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?522903</url></doc>
