<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="524799">
  <docid>524799</docid>
  <title>Sweden on $8 a Day</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Rozender, Morgan</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">10 August 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">7</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Rozender, Morgan</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Rozender, Morgan</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Rozender, Morgan</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Guest, Sarah</actor>
      <role>Tahitian Slut</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Klemencic, Andrew</actor>
      <role>Traveler</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>He's 28 years old. After high school, he went backpacking in Europe. He ended up in Sweden. He married a Swedish woman in order to stay in the country. He got a job with American Airlines, taking international ticket orders over the telephone. Because of his new occupation, he gets free flights all over the world. Naïve and unmotivated, our character quickly turns to a fake, jet-set bohemian lifestyle. After September 11th he is laid off from his job. His relationship falls through. With time to kill, free American Airlines flights for another year and a constant supply of Swedish social security cheques, he travels around the world. Our character develops an addiction to his way of life. We meet our character at a major turning point. His benefits have run out. His makeshift life is collapsing. His world is a suitcase and an addiction he can no longer support. What will he do? Who will he turn to for help? "Sweden on $8 a day" was shot in Toronto, Canada during a weekend in February 2004 on a budget of less than $100.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?524799</url></doc>
