<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="525695">
  <docid>525695</docid>
  <title>Swinging Ski Girls</title>
  <year>1981</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adult</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>sex</keyword>
    <keyword>hardcore</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Trendall, Don</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carlson, Susie (I)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cassidy, Rick</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Elkins, Sondra</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Franklin, Tania</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Marie, Anne (II)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McIntosh, Flora</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Jack is the bartender at the only club in Bend, Oregon, a college ski resort. Much of his time is spent renting out showers to young ladies and renting space at the peepholes to young men. Most of the girls know about the peepholes and don't mind. Libby is a student at the university and needs a date (and a ride) for the big ski weekend. She meets Rick at the local ski shop and suddenly has a date! Libby and Rick are so turned on to each other that they pull the car off the road before they get to the ski lodge and really get to know each other! Meanwhile, Jack tires of peering through the peephole, and decides that it is time for some action. Catherine doesn't object to his in-shower massage , but she doesn't want anything else. Her friend Chrissie, however, wants everything else, so Jack is happy to oblige. Rick and Libby finally arrive at the Lodge and manage to get involved in the nude open air pool, where they meet (and make) many new friends.The next day, the ski slopes! And that night, the after ski activities, including a special performance by Norma.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?525695</url></doc>
