<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="527392">
  <docid>527392</docid>
  <title>TBS Movie Extra</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Perkins, Rex</editor>
  </editors>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">7 October 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Sherwood, Barbara</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Blaker, Adam (I)</producer>
    <producer>Brodt, Timothy</producer>
    <producer>Stewart, Dave (IV)</producer>
    <producer>Saylor, Stephen Mark</producer>
    <producer>Miller, Mike (XVII)</producer>
    <producer>Andrew, Dane</producer>
    <producer>Blaker, Adam (I)</producer>
    <producer>Fleece, Larry</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Fleece, Larry</writer>
    <writer>Stewart, Dave (IV)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Devon, Dayna</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Merkin, Michele</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Siegel, Mike (I)</actor>
      <role>Host</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>TBS has joined forces with the highly rated, nationally syndicated newsmagazine Extra to create TBS Movie Extra, a Thursday night movie showcase which combines blockbuster movies with insider news from Hollywood. TBS Movie Extra will provide viewers with a front-row seat to the entertainment business, with the added strength of Extra's comprehensive, innovative coverage of the entertainment industry, and its leadership in celebrity journalism and breaking news. Each week, during breaks in the movie, hosts Mike Siegel and Dayna Devon will provide eye-popping coverage of the stars, take viewers to the sets of major films and television shows, report on major music projects and concerts, and cover all of Hollywood's backstage happenings. Included in its reporting of the latest entertainment news, TBS Movie Extra will offer its audience first looks at their favorite movies and television shows. The show will also grant unparalleled access inside Hollywood celebrity activities and offer in-depth interviews with entertainment's finest.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?527392</url></doc>
