<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="529393">
  <docid>529393</docid>
  <title>Takedowns and Falls</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Dobson, Joshua</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Sport</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>high-school-sports</keyword>
    <keyword>wrestling</keyword>
    <keyword>championship</keyword>
    <keyword>high-school-wrestling</keyword>
    <keyword>coming-of-age</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Hickey, Todd</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Harpster, Noah</producer>
    <producer>Henley, Youree</producer>
    <producer>Liu, Addison</producer>
    <producer>Matchett, Leo</producer>
    <producer>Hickey, Todd</producer>
    <producer>Ledger, Kirk</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>Every autumn thousands of high school wrestlers throughout the state of Pennsylvania begin the season with the hope of making it to the PIAA State Championships in Hershey. Few ever make it, even less win, but for all, the journey to obtain one of the most elusive titles in high school athletics is one of pain, commitment and sacrifice. Takedowns and Falls follows a small cast through one high school wrestling season in Harrisburg, Pa. The film showcases the sport, the sacrifice of its athletes and dedication of its coaches. It reveals stories of triumph and defeat...pressure and expectation... mental and physical preparation and concepts of personal achievement, as told through the lives and experiences of... A Wrestler...A Coach...A Team... and the pursuit of a common dream. The film is about these former and current athletes dedicating themselves to a sport and lifestyle that has no hope of making them rich and famous. Never will they be a household name, but because of the sports incredible localized popularity, in places like Harrisburg, PA high school athletes often find themselves on the front page of the newspaper. Whether it is the misunderstandings of the sport and its athletes or self-imposed, wrestlers are often rather isolated from the world of "popular" sports. Despite its intense following and crowds, it is often the black sheep of high school sports programs. This film examines what separates these athletes from their peers and what makes them the same. Takedowns and Falls explores building foundations of humility, family, friendship, individualism and teamwork, via the quest for State Championships.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?529393</url></doc>
