<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="529604">
  <docid>529604</docid>
  <title>Takkar</title>
  <year>1995</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Rajendran, A.R.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">14 July 1995</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Rangachary, Bharat</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bohra, Suresh</producer>
    <producer>Bohra, Mahendra R.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Banmali, Bhushan</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Malik, Anu</composer>
    <composer>Nikhil (I)</composer>
    <composer>Vinay (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ali, Ishrat</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bedi, Rakesh</actor>
      <role>Convict Kaku</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bendre, Sonali</actor>
      <role>Mohini</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dalvi, Sudhir</actor>
      <role>Commissioner of Police</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Inamdar, Shafi</actor>
      <role>DCP Mishra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Joshi, Mohan</actor>
      <role>Raja Thakur</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khakhar, Sameer</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Mukhtar (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kunika</actor>
      <role>Sheena Vasudev</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Muthu, Pramod</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shah, Naseeruddin</actor>
      <role>Inspector D'Costa</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shetty, Sunil (I)</actor>
      <role>Ravi Malhotra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Talsania, Tiku</actor>
      <role>Mamaji</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vachani, Ajit</actor>
      <role>Sikander Bakht</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Raj Malhotra and Mohini are in love and are to get married. After the engagement ceremony, the marriage is scheduled to take place in 4 days time during which Raj and Mohini must stay apart. On the day of the wedding, Mohini and her family are informed that Raj has been hospitalized, critically injured when he was shot by Police Inspector D'Costa in an encounter. They are also informed that Raj has been charged with possession of drugs. After Raj recovers, he is tried in Court and sentenced to 4 years in prison. Mohini believes that Raj is innocent, and decides to wait until he completely his sentence and then marry him. Appalled at the way he was treated by the police and law, Raj studies law in prison, and finds out that there are several other inmates who would like to get their hands on Inspector D'Costa. In the meantime, D'Costa is attracted to Mohini and gets friendly with her. Due to his good conduct, Raj is discharged after 2 1/2 years and is now a qualified lawyer. Shortly thereafter Mohini and Raj get married. This does not discourage D'Costa as he still lusts after Mohini. Mohini complains about Raj to DCP Mishra. Shortly thereafter DCP Mishra is shot dead in an encounter with terrorists, who were holding some children as hostage. With several years of meritorious service, five medals, it is very likely that the next DCP will be D'Costa, and if that happens Raj and Mohini can rest assured that he will turn their lives into virtual hell - and there will be no one they can turn to for help.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?529604</url></doc>
