<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="530212">
  <docid>530212</docid>
  <title>Tall as Trees</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Shapiro, Joe (III)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>trees</keyword>
    <keyword>manila-philippines</keyword>
    <keyword>tall</keyword>
    <keyword>seattle</keyword>
    <keyword>boeing</keyword>
    <keyword>filipino-american</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby SR</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">14 March 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">85</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Ponce, Gil</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bracamonte, Josie</producer>
    <producer>Gonzales, Fe</producer>
    <producer>Bennett, Garrett</producer>
    <producer>Fraser, Brent David</producer>
    <producer>Borlaza, Emmanuel H.</producer>
    <producer>Granados, Rey</producer>
    <producer>Ponce, Gil</producer>
    <producer>Todoroff, Tom</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Des Voigne, Darren</writer>
    <writer>Ponce, Gil</writer>
    <writer>Titus, Mark (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cortez, Rez</actor>
      <role>Commander</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Del Rosario, Monsour</actor>
      <role>Amador</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Domingo, Apple</actor>
      <role>Mira</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Esturco, Ihman</actor>
      <role>Reuben</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fraser, Brent David</actor>
      <role>William</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Granados, Doris</actor>
      <role>Mylee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gutierrez, Chin Chin</actor>
      <role>Maria</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lacana, Carlo</actor>
      <role>Jude</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Quiban Jr., Alejandro</actor>
      <role>Shutoy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rodriguez, Pierro</actor>
      <role>Bhotong</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Jude, an 8-year old Amerasian boy, leads a life of privilege in the Philippines. After Jude's father William, an American expat from Boeing, receives a promotion in Seattle, he breaks the news that Jude and his mother Maria will soon follow. Jude and Maria are vexed to leave their home island but the strength of family spurns them on to a new life. En route to Seattle, Jude and Maria stop at the US Embassy in Manila to obtain the final immigration papers. A violent typhoon floods the city and separates Jude from his mother, changing his life forever. Alone, hungry and disconsolate on the streets of Manila, Jude seeks help from a crooked cop, Amador, and runs into a street kid, Bhotong, who demands a price for being in his territory. Jude quickly learns he must be wary and trust no one. After an ethereal apparition of St. Michael delivers Jude from the malevolent 'Kapre' of his dreams and folklore, Jude meets Shutoy and a unlikely but unbreakable bond of friendship forms. Shutoy, a street smart boy, shows Jude not only how to survive on the streets but how to love life there. Soon, Jude and Shutoy meet Mira, a young girl who teaches both boys how to find beauty even when it seems there is none. Through his friends, Jude endeavors to make enough money to find his way home to his father in America. William searches desperately for Jude but cruel twists of timing and the greedy dishonesty of Amador lead to an overwhelming collision that changes everyone involved forever.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?530212</url></doc>
