<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="531353">
  <docid>531353</docid>
  <title>Taprooting</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Stephen, David Edward James</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">6 March 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">29</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Stephen, David Edward James</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Krishna, Tricia</producer>
    <producer>Stephen, David Edward James</producer>
    <producer>Stephen, James G.</producer>
    <producer>Garrett, Preston</producer>
    <producer>Hennen, Sean</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Hennen, Sean</writer>
    <writer>Stephen, David Edward James</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dixon, Dar</actor>
      <role>The Doctor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Elling, Andrew</actor>
      <role>Man on Road</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Elliott, Kieron</actor>
      <role>Cuin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ingle, Tiffany</actor>
      <role>Dead Woman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Krishna, Kayla</actor>
      <role>Little Girl</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lindsay, Shawn (II)</actor>
      <role>Emily</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Martin, Lynda (II)</actor>
      <role>Nurse on TV</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McCrann, Jeffrey</actor>
      <role>Edward</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McNamara, Evan</actor>
      <role>Scott</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>After an unstoppable disease decimates the world's population, sparing only the lives of 0-Negative blood type carriers, what is left of human civilization is forced to recover from the fallout. In the middle of this ravaged landscape are three survivors - brother and sister, Scott and Emily, and Cuin, a man who has lost everything to the pandemic. Waiting out the end of the world in a tiny apartment together, they are coping with indescribable loss and searching for an answer to the devastation. But when a message of salvation finds its way to them, these wayward travelers set out down an uncharted path toward hope. What the three will soon learn is the natural order of the world might be a dangerous thing, but there's nothing more cunning or cruel then the desperation of mankind fighting for every last inch of survival. Across the back roads of America, Emily, Cuin, and Scott will travel an unfamiliar and mysterious terrain, where the destination is unclear and the journey could cost them their lives. Faced with the difficult question of who has the right to survive and who doesn't, the trio will be forced to confront other survivors along the way who are all too willing to answer.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?531353</url></doc>
