<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="531394">
  <docid>531394</docid>
  <title>Tara</title>
  <year>1992</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>tantra</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Oriya</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Jena, Bijoya</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Dutta, Bimal</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chaurasia, Suniel</actor>
      <role>Shyama</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jena, Bijoya</actor>
      <role>Tara</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The daughter of a poor priest living in a remote village, is sold off as a bride to an apparently well off stranger, SHYAMACHARAN, who lives in a distant town. Shyamacharan, a practicing Tantrik initiates Tara into the rites of Tantrism, who pursues it seriously and evolves spiritually. Tara gradually discovers that her husband is a small time crook. However Shyama falls in love with her and wants to change for the better, so he decides to sell his property and start a business elsewhere, where he'll not be recognized as a thief and harassed by the police. SANATAN DAS, a philanthropist and a social worker of reputation, runs an Ashram for destitute women and is a prospective buyer of Shyama's land. But Shyama is keen to sell his property to a petty contractor for a better price, even though the latter has an eye on his wife. Tara misunderstands Shyama and thinks that he is trying to prostitute her. So she leaves him and seeks refuge in the Ashram. She is highly impressed by Sanatan's moral values and wide knowledge, but one day she discovers that he is as weak as any ordinary man. Disillusioned, Tara returns to her husband. A repentant Sanatan comes to Tara to apologize, but she refuses to acknowledge. The next day he is found dead! The police declare it a case of suicide by drowning. Tara is moved by his greatness. One morning, she is discovered in a trance sitting near the Kali temple of her father's village. The villagers deify her. Shyama, grabs the opportunity and basks in the glory of Tara's fame. One day in the midst of a celebration, where Tara is being worshipped as the Goddess Kali, the police arrive to arrest Shyama for Sanatan's murder. A visibly shaken Shyama pleads with Tara to save him but she refuses. Enraged, he destroys her. Does die or achieve nirvana?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?531394</url></doc>
