<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="531678">
  <docid>531678</docid>
  <title>Tartarin de Tarascon</title>
  <year>1934</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>French</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Bernard, Raymond (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Milhaud, Darius</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Andres, Mas</actor>
      <role>The Hairdresser</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Camus, Charles</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Charpin, Fernand</actor>
      <role>Bravida</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hélia, Jenny</actor>
      <role>Baïa</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kerly, Louis</actor>
      <role>Castel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Leblond, Henriette</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mathis, Milly</actor>
      <role>Jeannette</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maupi, Marcel</actor>
      <role>Tastevin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maximilienne</actor>
      <role>Mme Ladevèze</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mouriès, Auguste</actor>
      <role>Barbassou</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ollivier, Paul</actor>
      <role>Costecalde</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Poupon, Henri</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Raimu</actor>
      <role>Tartarin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Saint-Granier</actor>
      <role>The Prince</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sinoël</actor>
      <role>Bézuquet</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vilbert, Henri</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>d'Yd, Jean</actor>
      <role>Ladevèze</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Tartarin is the local hero in the small provincial town of Tarascon. He shows off about imaginary adventures in Africa, where he has never been, as a Lion Hunter, which he is only in his imagination. Even though the locals know he has never been to Africa, they keep hoping he will leave one day. After a misunderstanding, and much gossip, everyone thinks that Tartarin plans to actually take the trip. Initially reluctant, he is eventually convinced by his friend Bravida, who warns him about the growing shame the delay has caused him all across town. Tartarin meets an ex-convict on the train who calls himself a Prince and offers to travel with him to Algeria, in the hope of stealing his money with the help of a girl, Baïa. Tartarin leaves for the desert and as soon as the first lion is in sight, the "Prince" escapes with his money. Tartarin shoots the lion and gets arrested by the local police because the animal was a blind sacred lion. He is condemned to pay a fine for which he must sell his weapons since his money was stolen. He sends the lion skin to Tarascon, and after having learned the truth about Baïa and the Prince, Tartarin, feeling stupid, decides to go back home. Expecting to have to move to another town, he is surprised at the station by all the inhabitants, anxious to meet the lion killer they are so proud of.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?531678</url></doc>
