<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="531940">
  <docid>531940</docid>
  <title>Tat wam asi</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Indonesian</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Netherlands">19 November 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">50</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Erawati, Made Enny</producer>
    <producer>Hosking, Richard</producer>
    <producer>Lynch, Dale</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>On October 12, 2002, two bombs exploded in packed night clubs in the tourist centre Kuta on the Indonesian island of Bali. 202 people were killed. TAT WAM ASI shows how a culture with deep traditional roots copes with this act of terror perpetrated by Muslim extremists. Spiritual advisers from different religious backgrounds tell their stories. Sensitive natures had observed prophetic signs: an artist dreamed that an aeroplane penetrated two buildings full of people. By means of a cleansing ceremony, people try to restore the harmony of the macrocosm and microcosm that the attack has thrown out of balance. The catastrophe can be seen as a warning from the Supreme Being, who in the end has the best intentions for humanity. But there are more mundane worries, too. What kind of blow has been dealt to tourism, a major economic factor on the island? The Balinese may have to consider other sources of income. In the wake of the shocking event, the Balinese community is focused more on interpretation and introspection than on anger and revenge. General Pastika, who led the successful investigation into the attacks, hopes that tolerance will remain a guiding principle. After all, in the end we all have the same god.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?531940</url></doc>
