<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="534569">
  <docid>534569</docid>
  <title>Tell-Tale Art</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Goldsmith, Noah</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">14 June 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">52</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Lanni, Jeremy Dylan</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Goldsmith, Noah</producer>
    <producer>Lanni, Jeremy Dylan</producer>
    <producer>Sellers, Bradley</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Lanni, Jeremy Dylan</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ellis, Tawny Fere</actor>
      <role>Lenore</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fere, Tawny</actor>
      <role>Lenore</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moran, Ed (III)</actor>
      <role>Officer Morley</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Walsh, Thomas F.</actor>
      <role>Allan</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A successful artist named Lenore brutally murders her husband, dismembers his body with a hacksaw, and conceals the pieces within a grotesque sculpture masquerading as modern art. Why? Perhaps Lenore was right in claiming it was Allan's cataract eye that drove her to do it. The milky orb was certainly repulsive to behold. But did it really pass judgment on Lenore's every move? Did it really scour her soul with a supernaturally critical glare? That's for you to decide. What's certain is that one night Lenore picked up a hammer, stole upon her sleeping husband, and bludgeoned him to death. She then sawed the body into neat sections, worked them into a plaster sculpture, and waited for the police to arrive. And when one Officer Morley questioned Lenore, something made her lose her composure. What exactly shattered her resolve? That, like Lenore's motive, is a mystery. Perhaps Lenore's conscience made a spectacular - if somewhat belated - appearance. Or perhaps Allan's ghost returned from the grave and got his righteous revenge. All we know for sure is that Lenore dissolved into a gibbering wreck, confessed to her heinous crime, and remains stark raving mad to this day!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?534569</url></doc>
