<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="536330">
  <docid>536330</docid>
  <title>Terry Southern's Plums and Prunes</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Khanna, Dev</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">1 September 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Canada">19 July 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">9</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Khanna, Dev</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Khanna, Dev</producer>
    <producer>LoGuidice, Joe</producer>
    <producer>Southern, Nile</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Southern, Terry</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Knight, Tom (VI)</actor>
      <role>Brad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Planche, David</actor>
      <role>Tommy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>de Yonge, Anita</actor>
      <role>Donna</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>From one of the most influential writers of the twentieth century, Terry Southern (Screenwriter on Dr. Strangelove, Easy Rider, The Cincinnati Kid and the author of such novels as The Magic Christian and Blue Movie) comes a hard-hitting short script combining the author's satiric eye with his surrealist impulse first published in PLAYBOY Magazine in 1967. TERRY SOUTHERN'S PLUMS AND PRUNES was originally intended as part of an anthology of Risque Cinema entitled "Pardon me Sir, But is my Eye Hurting your Elbow", but wasn't made due to its "questionable taste". That is, until now. Forty years later TERRY SOUTHERN'S PLUMS AND PRUNES is a reality in all its twisted and perverted glory. Set in 1950's picturesque America, TERRY SOUTHERN'S PLUMS AND PRUNES is the story of Brad, or more generally, about the male fear of growing old. Featuring a marvelous Free Jazz Soundtrack and flawless photography, TERRY SOUTHEN'S PLUMS AND PRUNES is a thought-provoking expose on the male psyche with a Grand Guignol finish. A sexual fantasy rooted in reality--a nightmare reality of aging in a youth-centered world.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?536330</url></doc>
