<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="537706">
  <docid>537706</docid>
  <title>Thatta Kedona: The Toy Village of Pakistan</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Polzer, Joachim</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Urdu</language>
    <language>German</language>
    <language>Punjabi</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Germany">11 August 2005</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Iceland">30 October 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">183</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Polzer, Joachim</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Polzer, Joachim</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Polzer, Joachim</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Drakulich, Sonja</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dönnhöfer, Christa</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Groch, Karola</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Keindl, Inge</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nohl, Tobias</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pintsch, Norbert</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Steck, Bernhard</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Thatta Kedona is a remarkable village in rural Pakistan. 36 volunteers from Western countries have visited and coached the village people in a help to self help project since 1991. Dolls and tin toys reflecting regional cultures of Pakistan are products which generate cash income for the farming families through the local cooperative-like NGO. But those volunteers from Western countries are also having fun by working creatively in a remote village of Islamic society with strong overlays by the traditional culture of Indus Valley (Harappa 3.000 B.C.), the Mogul period, influences from the colonial British-India period and the Punjab country culture. Hence the playfulness of a "toy village" is on both sides: for the villagers by manufacturing hand-craft toys for cash in a not-yet industrialized region avoiding rural exodus to the big cites (poverty slums that are generated in cities by migration). -- And on the other side one can notice the joy of Western volunteers being confronted at work by their own history framework but in present time and with a very foreign and sometimes strange context.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?537706</url></doc>
