<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="538331">
  <docid>538331</docid>
  <title>The 36</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>super-powers</keyword>
    <keyword>based-on-novel</keyword>
    <keyword>god</keyword>
    <keyword>spiritual</keyword>
    <keyword>action-hero</keyword>
    <keyword>science-fiction-literature</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <producers>
    <producer>Chopra, Gotham</producer>
    <producer>Chopra, Mallika</producer>
    <producer>Chopra, Deepak</producer>
    <producer>King, Fredric</producer>
    <producer>Fox, Kevin (II)</producer>
    <producer>Robbins, Isen</producer>
    <producer>Schoof, Aimee</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Chopra, Deepak</writer>
    <writer>Fox, Kevin (II)</writer>
    <writer>Greenberg, Martin (II)</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>It is believed by many ancient religions that to prevent the destruction of mankind and the unraveling of reality, there must always be 36 pure souls on the earth, maintaining the balance of good and evil. When one of these 36 pure souls is lost, a replacement must be chosen -- and unbeknownst to American Doctor Michael Aulden -- he is the chosen one. But what fate has he been chosen for? -- In a burned out village in Kosovo, two soldiers are struck down by a flash of blinding light... In a Nevada laboratory, a cynical scientist analyzes a bizarre life form -- and discovers the impossible... People everywhere confront bizarre, terrifying phenomena. All the around the world the fabric of reality is unraveling as the number of pure souls has been reduced by one. Michael Aulden is aware of none of this as he runs to help a stricken neighbor, only to be charged with the bloody murder of the man he came to save. He does not know that it is all a ploy to keep the balance favoring evil, to tempt him into making a mistake that will turn hell loose on earth...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?538331</url></doc>
