<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="540629">
  <docid>540629</docid>
  <title>The Archaeology of Comedy</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Konkle, Tom</editor>
    <editor>Vanzo, Kurt</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>comedy-duo</keyword>
    <keyword>sketch-comedy</keyword>
    <keyword>dvd-feature</keyword>
    <keyword>spoof</keyword>
    <keyword>mockumentary</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">5 April 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">118</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Konkle, Tom</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Vanzo, Kurt</producer>
    <producer>Beeler, David (I)</producer>
    <producer>Konkle, Tom</producer>
    <producer>Beeler, David (I)</producer>
    <producer>Konkle, Tom</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Beeler, David (I)</writer>
    <writer>Konkle, Tom</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Konkle, Tom</composer>
    <composer>Sherwood, Michael (I)</composer>
    <composer>Vanzo, Kurt</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Beeler, David (I)</actor>
      <role>Richard Lagina</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bobo, Shannon</actor>
      <role>Hot Chick</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Konkle, Tom</actor>
      <role>Sir Doctor George Flightus</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Neill, Michael</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The two hour search for comedy's Holy Grail continues in Dave and Tom's outrageous look back at the history of comedy. You've seen actors Dave Beeler and Tom Konkle on other TV shows, now watch them discover a lost Monty Python-influenced sketch comedy troupe that bucks the norm of sketch today; instead opting for a more deliberate and cerebral approach. Delightfully nostalgic yet unmistakably original, you''ll be glued to your screen as they take a look back on "this business of funny." From prehistoric pornography to poetic clowns on mountainsides, after watching Dave and Tom you''ll agree that history has never been this much fun. A spoof of BBC and Discovery Channel documentaries that promise to reveal a great mystery, this DVD is as one reviewer put it, "a silly journey through a world of scenarios... ranging from unfathomable science discoveries to absurd game shows, from sickly polite bank robberies to ego maniacal hat entertainers....their work achieves comedy on a level commensurate with Monty Python, Mr. Show and Little Britain, and highlights a sparkling sense of the off-color, rude and the importance of wacky nonsense. Always unexpected and always entertaining....."</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?540629</url></doc>
