<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="540636">
  <docid>540636</docid>
  <title>The Archer and the Suns</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Edwards, William (XVI)</editor>
    <editor>Jiang, Joe</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Mystery</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>envy</keyword>
    <keyword>surrealism</keyword>
    <keyword>tragedy</keyword>
    <keyword>chinese-story</keyword>
    <keyword>conspiracy</keyword>
    <keyword>chinese-mythology</keyword>
    <keyword>action-hero</keyword>
    <keyword>3d-animation</keyword>
    <keyword>self-sacrifice</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>China</country>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">G</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <directors>
    <director>Duan, Paul</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Duan, Paul</producer>
    <producer>Duan, Paul</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Duan, Xi (II)</writer>
    <writer>Wan, Qiaoshu</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Li, Stephen</composer>
    <composer>Ueda, Masami</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>The Archer and the Suns (also called Houyi Shoots the Suns), a traditional heroic epic widely told in China for thousands of years, is about a brave young god who discards his immortal status and descends to the human world to save the humans world. God Xihe gives birth to 10 suns and asks them to appear in the sky in turn, giving essential light and heat to the human beings. However one day all 10 brother Suns flock out together in the sky. They begin burning the earth and throwing the human beings into unprecedented disasters: earth dried and cracked, crops withered, forests burned into vast deserts. Houyi, the God of Archer, volunteers to shoot the Suns. With the help of his wife Chang'er, and after experiencing countless hardships and challenges, he shoots down 9 Suns and secures the humans of safe, peaceful life. Feng Meng, one of Houyi's students, has cast greedy eyes at this beautiful lady Chang'er, and grudges at their marriage and the great achievements Houyi has made. Queen Mother of the West gives Houyi two grains of panacea for immortality as an award for his accomplishments. Feng Meng holds Chang'er under duress attempting to snatch the panacea. Chang'er has no choice but devours the panacea, the moment she finds her body floating up to the moon. A loving couple is abruptly parted. A heroic epic ends up in tragedy.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?540636</url></doc>
