<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="541019">
  <docid>541019</docid>
  <title>The Ascent of Mount Blanc</title>
  <year>1903</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">17 January 1903</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Ormiston-Smith, Frederick</director>
  </directors>
<plot>We have just received from the Warwick Trading Company of London, Eng., an extraordinary series of moving pictures made last September by Mr. F. Ormiston-Smith, the celebrated mountain climber. Mr. Ormiston-Smith, accompanied by two famous Oberland guides and three porters, started from Chamonix in Switzerland and with his moving picture camera, made the perilous ascent to the very summit of Mont Blanc, 15,781 feet high. During the trip, which occupied several days, Mr. Ormiston-Smith was able to secure pictures of some of the most difficult phases of modern mountaineering. The photographing was carried out under exceptional difficulties owing to the great height, bitter cold, mountain sickness, snowstorms, avalanches, etc., but the films are all good photographically and the action of intense interest. The series is made up of the following eighteen pictures: 1. Preparations for the Ascent and Departure of the Party. 2. Crossing a Mountain Torrent. 3. Party leaving the Pierre Pointue Inn, 6,800 feet. 4. Crossing the Glacier des Bossons. 5. The "Junction" of Glaciers de Taconnaz and des Bossons. 6. Traversing the Glacier de Taconnaz. 7. Climbing the Ice Pinnacles on the same Glacier. 8. Arrival of the Party at the Grands Mulets. 9. Reaching the Grands Mulets, 10,120 feet. 10. Life at the Grands Mulets. Partaking of Refreshments. 11. Sunset Panorama from the Grands Mulets, 7 P. M. (Unique.) 12. Leaving by Moonlight for the Summit. 13. Ascending the Snow Slopes towards the Petit Plateau, 3 A. M. 14. A Cloud Sea from the Petit Plateau, 4 A. M. A wonderful sight photographed from above the clouds. The preceeding three pictures are probably the first successful moving picture views secured at that time of the early morning. 15. Crossing a Snow Bridge near the Grand Plateau, 15,000 feet. 16. Finding a way over a great crevasse near La Tournette, 15,300 feet. 17. Ascending the Slope below the summit over a Snow Bridge during a Snowstorm, 15,500 feet. 18. The Summit of Mont Blanc, 15,781 feet.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?541019</url></doc>
