<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="541167">
  <docid>541167</docid>
  <title>The Attachment</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Davis, Nicholas</editor>
    <editor>Stier Jr., Peter</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">20 September 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">15</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Nicoll, Alex (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Roldan, Sean</producer>
    <producer>Nicoll, James</producer>
    <producer>Nicoll, Rita</producer>
    <producer>Nicoll, Alex (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Nicoll, Alex (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gray, Sean (II)</actor>
      <role>Ryan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moranno, Rene</actor>
      <role>Steve</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Riedy, Sean</actor>
      <role>Mike</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The Internet has revolutionized our way of life enabling us to communicate and share information with anyone anywhere at any time, a virtual world of education and information. However, just below the surface of this informational super highway there lurks something much darker. A realm where human desires are tested to their very limits, where needs are fulfilled through exploitation and suffering. A cyber meeting place for those driven by sexual desire and money, a place where fetishes can be explored and boundaries crossed, a place where anyone can go and where reality and fiction blur, where the line between right and wrong can be crossed, where carnal desire can outweigh human morality and a man can become a predator. A dark haven protected by cryptic passwords and firewalls, a place from which to view the world and everyone in it. However, tonight, in this realm of images and thoughts, in this underworld of secrets one man's life will change forever, because tonight someone is watching him!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?541167</url></doc>
