<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="542263">
  <docid>542263</docid>
  <title>The Battle of Chemulpo</title>
  <year>1904</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>War</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">March 1904</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
<plot>We are the first in the field with a wonderfully accurate and realistic series showing the highly exciting conflicts between the Russians and Japanese. These films will be the most wonderful money earners of the century. The people of America are greatly excited over the doings of the little brown fellow and the big giant with whiskers. The battles are just far enough away to make business good in this country without causing the awful hardships of war. No war series offers the highly picturesque coloring and exciting action. Both sides are fierce and desperate fighters and the background of strange huts and villages is entrancing in the extreme. It is a series of motion war pictures that will live for years after peace follows death and carnage, and the accuracy and thrilling features can not be questioned. We are admirably situated for getting out the successive films of this series with the utmost promptness. With several correspondents in the field, arrangements for the reception of first copies of foreign made films, night-and-day arrangements here for getting out the positives, nobody can compete with us. Besides, we have on our staff a former naval expert who is thoroughly familiar with all the locations in the far East that will come under the focus of public vision during the war. His assistance and advice will be invaluable to assist in establishing the accuracy of details in our reproductions of the most thrilling and yet-to-be famous films. No series of war films has ever drawn the money that our new reproductions of the Japan-Russian struggles will. This picture shows a wonderfully thrilling battle between the Japanese and Russian Warships at the entrance to the harbor of Chemulpo. The Japanese fleet approaches and challenges the enemy. The Russian Warships "Variag" and "Korietz" come out and a fierce engagement follows. Reports state over 600 shots were fired, the battles lasting over two hours. The Russians knew evidently that they were going to inevitable death, for the brave Commander of the "Variag," before going, sent a letter to the Russian Consul couched in the following terms, "I go out to fight, sink or swim," and under the fierce fire of the Japanese fleet is soon reduced to a wreck. They had fought until the ship was unmanageable. Their Commander did well to bring the ship into harbor. Shortly after reaching the harbor what was left of the ship, once the pride of the Russian Navy, was blown up. The rolling waves, the shells bursting in the air and the water all add to the scene. You can see the shells as they hit the "Korietz" and "Variag," and finally as a fitting climax to all, comes the blowing up of the "Variag" after the return to the harbor. Words can hardly describe the scene. This film has never been, or will be, equaled.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?542263</url></doc>
