<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="542345">
  <docid>542345</docid>
  <title>The Battle of the Yalu</title>
  <year>1904</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>War</genre>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
<plot>Of all the reproductions of Russo-Japanese battle scenes, this stands out in a class by itself; for it is the only production carried out under strict military orders. Large bodies of troops, correctly uniformed, are employed and manoeuvred exactly as in actual warfare. There is, therefore, absolutely nothing "fakey" in the film. The opening scene shows Japanese skirmishers, with a rapid fire gun, opening the engagement with an attack on the Russian position at the crest of a hill. Japanese reserves are brought up and a gallant charge up the hillside is made. The Russians, however, are quickly strengthened by the arrival of a battery of field guns which open up on the Japs, causing them to retreat with considerable loss. Next we see the Russians in force defending a position at the edge of a ravine. On their left is a straw-thatched Corean house. Japanese shells are exploding in every direction, and one of them finally strikes the house, blows up the roof and fires the structure. The Russians slowly fall back before the Japanese onslaught, and then retreat in a rout as a Japanese regiment pluckily charges their position. In the final scene the Japanese line is seen entrenched along a wooded hillside. A Russian battery of two guns dashes up at top speed, unlimbers and starts a bombardment of the trenches where the Mikado's flag is flying. Their fire is so hot that the Japs find it necessary to capture the battery at all hazards. A battalion is detailed to the task and in extended order advances through the woods, volley-firing as they come. Russian rifle men hurry up to support the battery and the fight becomes terrific, the losses on both sides being heavy. The Japs finally make a furious charge on the battery and, after a thrilling hand-to-hand conflict, capture it. As the scene ends the Japanese standard bearer is exultantly waving his banner over the captured guns.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?542345</url></doc>
