<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="542627">
  <docid>542627</docid>
  <title>The Beckoning</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Hastie, Peter</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Mystery</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>artist</keyword>
    <keyword>old-woman</keyword>
    <keyword>glasgow</keyword>
    <keyword>hospital</keyword>
    <keyword>graveyard</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">41</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Hastie, Peter</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hastie, Peter</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Dibble, Graeme</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Callaghan, Liz</actor>
      <role>Waitress</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hart, Tom (V)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hughes, David (XLIII)</actor>
      <role>Landlord</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>K is awoken from a deep sleep by the sound of banging from outside his apartment. Going to his front door, he looks through his peephole and spies a beautiful woman entering the apartment opposite, having dragged a large trunk up the stairs. He is smitten and smiles from cheek to paint-besmudged cheek. Later that day, he hears the same banging and rushes to his door to introduce himself to the woman, only it is not her, but a family moving a fridge into the apartment opposite. Mystified, K visits his landlord, who stays at the bottom of the stairs, but the landlord knows of no woman living in the apartment opposite K, the family he saw are the only residents. Perturbed, but not wishing to let it overwhelm him, K sees the woman the very next day serenely sipping coffee in a coffee shop. He tries to approach her, but she seems to disappear, then just as soon appear again across the road, looking back at him as if beckoning him towards her. So begins a spiral of events as the woman appears, then disappears time and again, constantly evading K's grasp as she leads him across the city as day turns to night, as youth turns to age, and as art turns to real life and vice versa. The question is, does the woman really exist or has K created her?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?542627</url></doc>
