<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="543358">
  <docid>543358</docid>
  <title>The Bet</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Lewis, Philip (V)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>debt</keyword>
    <keyword>gambling</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Ireland</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Ireland">3 November 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Ireland">12</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Lewis, Philip (V)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Byrne, Ciara (II)</producer>
    <producer>Courtney, Paddy C.</producer>
    <producer>Kearney, Richard</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Kearney, Richard</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Burke, Celine</composer>
    <composer>O'Shea, Niall (II)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bonham, Robbie</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brennan, Fran (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carr, Margo</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Courtney, Paddy C.</actor>
      <role>Jimmy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fortune, Brian</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kelly, Slaine</actor>
      <role>Lynn</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lindsay, Owen</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Morrison, Steven (VI)</actor>
      <role>Tom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Scanlan, Emmet</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Jimmy is your average young man drifting through life, not sure what he's after, working a crummy job in call center and yearning to be more than he is. Although charming, chatty and good looking, he is prone to landing himself in debt and he is scared of talking to attractive girls, especially Lynn, who is the woman of his dreams, and the company receptionist. Jimmy lands himself in debt to a local loan shark, Vince, a man of vicious principal who you would not want to cross. Instead of sending letter reminders to his customers, Vince's preferred method of debt collection is extracting fingers using a blunt pliers. So when threatened by Vince, Jimmy is in big trouble and needs to make money by the end of the day. Being a big gambler, Jimmy constructs what he thinks is a great idea to make money. Jimmy places a bet with everyone at work that he will not utter one word between 9am - 5pm - this great idea quickly turns sour as everyone becomes his enemy. The rules of 'the bet' are made and Jimmy has got to think on his feet at all times of the day. Armed with pens, paper, pointing and facial expressions, Jimmy must battle the psychotic loan shark, an angry boss, Anthony (Jimmy's smug nemesis at work), and evil pranks from colleagues. Jimmy must choose his words carefully if he is to save his fingers and maybe even charm the girl of his dreams on the worst day and also, the most exciting day of his life.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?543358</url></doc>
