<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="543883">
  <docid>543883</docid>
  <title>The Big Squeal</title>
  <year>1933</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>two-reeler</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">9 July 1933</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">20</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Lamont, Charles (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Christie, Al</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Adamson, Ewart</writer>
    <writer>Pagano, Ernest</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bevan, Billy</actor>
      <role>Jake Burke</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Christy, Dorothy</actor>
      <role>Natalie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Clyde, Andy</actor>
      <role>Andy Wilson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>French, Charles K.</actor>
      <role>Charlie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jamison, Bud</actor>
      <role>John</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McCall, William (I)</actor>
      <role>Bill</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Andy Wilson (Andy Clyde), a millionaire pig farmer from Kansas, comes to Chicago (unless New York has a stock yard district)looking for his girl friend, Natalie (Dorothy Christy) who had left the Sunflower state as she did not care much for the company of pigs and/or pig handlers, although Andy wasn't rich when she left, else she would have most likely been a bit more tolerant. Andy runs into his old friend Jake (Billy Bevan), who has been married for about a year to another belle from Kansas, that Andy hasn't met. He invites Andy out to the house and, of course, he is called away on business and asks Andy to stay and entertain his bride Betty (Ethyl Sykes, which is how she spelled it until some researcher changed it to Ethel), who Andy still hasn't met, although she did dain to stick a hand out of her bedroom door for Andy to shake, as she too has an aversion to pig farmers, even rich ones like Andy who was also the Pig-Calling Champion of Kansas three years running. Betty calls a friend over to take her place. The friend---what a coincidence---is Andy's old girl friend, and she peeks out and recognizes Andy and also a million reasons why she now likes him better than she did. She invites him into the bedroom where she is spread out, wearing silk pajamas, on the chaise lounge and, like Cleopatra, is not prone to argue. Andy, of course, thinks his old girl friend is now his friend's wife. Will Andy yield to temptation despite his fondness for his old friend?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?543883</url></doc>
