<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="543863">
  <docid>543863</docid>
  <title>The Big Showdown</title>
  <year>1974</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Game-Show</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>non-fiction</keyword>
    <keyword>partially-lost-tv-series</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">23 December 1974</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Schneider, Dick</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Greenberg, Ron</producer>
    <producer>Lipp, Don</producer>
    <producer>Dobbins, Shelley (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cunningham, Heather (I)</actor>
      <role>Assistant (1974-1975)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Daniel, Dan (II)</actor>
      <role>Announcer (1974-1975)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fredericks, Dirk</actor>
      <role>Announcer (pilot episode)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Peck, Jim (I)</actor>
      <role>Host (1974-1975)</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Three contestants, one a returning champion, competed. Six categories (each assigned a point value) and a "payoff point" (the score players try to get by correctly answering questions). Host Peck reads a toss-up question, with correct answers determining control of the board. The contestant answered questions in an attempt to hit the payoff point without going over; the first to obtain the payoff point won a cash bonus. Two rounds were played in such fashion, after which came a speed-up round; the two top-scoring players moved on to the Final Showdown, with only three categories and a payoff point of seven. The first to reach the payoff point was champion and moved to the "Big Showdown" bonus game. In the "Big Showdown," the contestant was presented two huge dice with the words "SHOW" and "DOWN" printed in place of the sixes (the dice were otherwise regulation). If, on the first roll of the dice, they roll both "SHOW" and "DOWN," the player won $10,000; otherwise, a payoff point was established (whatever the player rolled initially) and the player was given 30 seconds to roll "SHOW" and "DOWN" for $5,000. Hitting the payoff point meant $250 per roll plus 5 bonus seconds after the first 30 had expired. After the initial 30 second time period, the only way one could win was to roll "SHOW" and "DOWN." Those who failed to roll the two magic words returned to play again.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?543863</url></doc>
