<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="544350">
  <docid>544350</docid>
  <title>The Black Door</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <genres>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>nudity</keyword>
    <keyword>devil-worship</keyword>
    <keyword>ritual-sacrifice</keyword>
    <keyword>human-sacrifice</keyword>
    <keyword>male-frontal-nudity</keyword>
    <keyword>supernatural-power</keyword>
    <keyword>pentagram</keyword>
    <keyword>male-nudity</keyword>
    <keyword>fake-documentary</keyword>
    <keyword>satanic-ritual</keyword>
    <keyword>suicide-by-hanging</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Spain">18 October 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">96</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Wong, Kit (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ng, See-Yuen</producer>
    <producer>Leslie, Brian (I)</producer>
    <producer>Lowe, Lucas</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Carbon, Julien</writer>
    <writer>Courtiaud, Laurent</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Koss, Shane</composer>
    <composer>Rosa, Christopher</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ainslie, Jason</actor>
      <role>Ward</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Benson, Jason</actor>
      <role>Milodragovitch</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Blatch, Kevin</actor>
      <role>Father Maxim Trenton</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Burns, Barry (I)</actor>
      <role>Doctor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Druxman, Joan</actor>
      <role>2nd Nurse</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gallinaro, Sergio</actor>
      <role>Steven</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gordon, Frances (II)</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Krummel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hainsworth, John</actor>
      <role>Morgen - old</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McBurney, Francis</actor>
      <role>Carvalho</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McDonald, Brenda (III)</actor>
      <role>Old Woman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McDonald, Cameron (I)</actor>
      <role>Morgen - young</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moore, Staci Tara</actor>
      <role>Meg</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Parra, Carlos (V)</actor>
      <role>Balmeseda</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Prowse, John (II)</actor>
      <role>Father</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Seattle, USA, 1999. At the demand of MEG, a camera crew investigates the strange course of events that brought STEVEN H., her boyfriend, to be hospitalized. Steven's condition is serious. His body has been severely lacerated by an unknown assailant. The doctors think it could be a wild animal, or maybe even a man with extremely long and hard nails. Steven is also suffering from a mysterious infection that spreads inside him at an alarming speed... The camera crew investigates on Steven's past weeks, hoping to find the truth and learn what really happened to him. Steven was doing historical research on trading between Mexico and the US, and had focused his work on a man called Balmaseda, a prosperous Mexican businessman who disappeared in 1932. This apparently innocuous research led Steven to a much darker discovery... Everything seems to revolve around a group of mysterious characters, all members of a satanic sect : The Black Door. Balmaseda was one of them. The mystery is about to be unveiled, thanks to the discovery of a terrifying 8mm film shot by the sect in 1932. These images plunge the crew in the middle of a drama where Steven is another victim of the sect. The keys to the mystery are this 8mm film, a video that Steven shot the night he was attacked - in an abandoned mansion that belonged to the Sect, and a mysterious old man that Steven met and who knows more than he pretends... As time runs out for Steven and his girlfriend, the crew must find the answer to supernatural events that started 60 years ago but are still very much present. For the Black Door is among us and the gate they opened to hell has never been closed...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?544350</url></doc>
