<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="544382">
  <docid>544382</docid>
  <title>The Black Knight</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>History</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>color-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>christian</keyword>
    <keyword>john-hunyadi</keyword>
    <keyword>christianity</keyword>
    <keyword>sword</keyword>
    <keyword>turkish</keyword>
    <keyword>king</keyword>
    <keyword>hungary</keyword>
    <keyword>europe</keyword>
    <keyword>ottoman</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>muslim</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hungarian</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Hungary</country>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <producers>
    <producer>Csáky, Attila</producer>
    <producer>Almog, Michael</producer>
    <producer>Lengyel, Andras</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Lengyel, Andras</writer>
    <writer>P. Koltai, Gábor</writer>
    <writer>Tabb, Michael</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Mid 15th century Europe is in peril - only the greatest hero can save the West from the invasion of the Muslim Turkish Empire. Hunyadi, Sword of God tells one of the most inspiring and moving stories of European history. It offers a unique chance for a major actor to play a role that can be an unprecedented opportunity in an artist's career. This epic story is played out on several levels. Above all, it is the drama of a self-made man, who becomes one of the most feared military leaders of his time, and his immediate family with a son he grooms to be his successor and king of Hungary, a major power at the time; and his younger son, Matthias, who at first is all but ignored by his father as a potential soldier or monarch. As fate would have it, it is Matthias who becomes king and establishes a Rennaissance court that earned the respect of the civilized world. Hunyadi is also a historical epic with grand battle scenes, spectacular locations, including Rome, Constantinople and Hungary, as well as a host of interesting characters. Apart from the role of the great father figure Hunyadi, the invincible military commander, the role of his two sons, his wife, the Sultan, the Pope and many others create unique vehicles for talented actors. In the recent wave of successful historical films in the last few years, the filmmakers hope to find a global audience for Hunyadi, Sword of God, with its high drama, great action scenes and unforgettable performances.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?544382</url></doc>
