<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="544589">
  <docid>544589</docid>
  <title>The Blessing of Prometheus</title>
  <year>2000</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Young, Christopher K.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>akron-ohio</keyword>
    <keyword>canton</keyword>
    <keyword>classic-literature</keyword>
    <keyword>ohio</keyword>
    <keyword>prometheus</keyword>
    <keyword>cleveland-ohio</keyword>
    <keyword>digital-video</keyword>
    <keyword>mythology</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 November 2000</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">20</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Young, Christopher K.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Smith, J.E.</producer>
    <producer>Young, Christopher K.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Young, Christopher K.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Young, Christopher K.</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cox, Joseph (I)</actor>
      <role>A vulture</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gutauckas, Jennifer</actor>
      <role>Alcestis</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kendrick, Damion</actor>
      <role>Prometheus</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lipscombe, Rigel</actor>
      <role>A vulture</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Perdomo</actor>
      <role>A vulture</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Smith, J.E.</actor>
      <role>Admetus</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Smith, James E. (I)</actor>
      <role>Admetus</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Young, Christopher K.</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The Blessing of Prometheus is a retelling of the Prometheus fire legend and the tale of Admetus and Alcestis. Prometheus gave the gift of fire to mankind, but fire was only to be used by the gods, so he was punished by being chained to a rock whereupon vultures eat his liver to have it restored and eaten again on a daily basis for eternity. Admetus was a king who found favor with the god Apollo. Apollo bargained with the three fates that when it came time for Admetus to die, that another be taken in his stead. When Admetus fell ill, the fates instead took his wife. Admetus, not the author of the bargain in the first place, pleaded with Persephone, daughter of Hades, and struck a deal to resurrect Alcestis. Alcestis would be brought back every spring, but must return every fall, hence the mythological reason for the seasons. The fire legend is likened to a detective on the search for brutal home invaders. Admetus and Alcestis are a typical couple who fall victim to the home invaders, the wife taking a bullet meant for her husband (dying in his stead). As they are leaving, the detective is the first to respond, and shoots one of the invaders in flight. Seeing this, the widower desires to bring a similar end to each of the men who invaded his home that night (the forbidden gift of fire). The Blessing of Prometheus is narrated with the actual story of the Greek mythological tales, but is visually narrated by dark, nightmarish images.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?544589</url></doc>
