<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="544684">
  <docid>544684</docid>
  <title>The Blonde Mystique</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Miller, Jesse James</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">52</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Aitken, Sally</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hodgson, Trevor</producer>
    <producer>Paperny, David</producer>
    <producer>Shumiatcher, Cal</producer>
    <producer>Mehler, Audrey</producer>
    <producer>Nault, Lisa</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Aitken, Sally</writer>
    <writer>Dunnison, James</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Burke, Dennis (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Aitken, Sally</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arnason, Aubrey</actor>
      <role>Herself - Host</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Case, Angela</actor>
      <role>Herself - Host</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hefner, Hugh M.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Holness, Karen</actor>
      <role>Herself - Host</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>For women, being blonde is about more than just having a head of fair hair. Today, as throughout history, there is a prevailing mystique about being blonde. Envied, reviled, lusted after, joked about, blondes are magnets for their allure, yet mocked for their supposed lack of intelligence. Are blondes truly perceived by others as sexier, younger, and more adventurous than women with differently coloured locks? How much of the image of blondes is founded, and how much is fiction? In THE BLONDE MYSTIQUE, brunettes Angela Case and Karen Holness and blonde Aubrey Arnason team up on an entertaining quest into the heart of blondness, setting out to discover for themselves if there really is such a thing as a blonde mystique and, if so, exactly what it is. Seeking information and answers, our dynamic trio uncover remarkable details about blondes throughout history, and the booming business in making the unblonde blonde....and the blonde even blonder. They do field research to see if blondes really are treated differently from their non-blonde counterparts, questioning men on their preferences in the street, taking to the highway - where our hosts play a damsel in distress with a broken down car, and on a night out at the clubs. And then the ultimate test: Angela, Karen and Aubrey will each change her hair colour. The brunettes become blondes and the blonde a brunette to see what life is like on the other side of the peroxide bottle, and whether being blonde actually colours not just others' perception of you, but your own view of yourself. By turns fascinating, funny and perceptive, THE BLONDE MYSTIQUE is full of surprises and delights. Your view of blondes will never be the same.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?544684</url></doc>
