<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="545725">
  <docid>545725</docid>
  <title>The Bozo Super Sunday Show</title>
  <year>1994</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>bozo-the-clown</keyword>
    <keyword>clown</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">31 December 2000</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hall, Allen (IV)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>D'Auria, Joey</writer>
    <writer>Leva, Scott H.</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Baugh, Taylor</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brown, Roy (II)</actor>
      <role>Cooky the Cook</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>D'Auria, Joey</actor>
      <role>Bozo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Eurich, Robin</actor>
      <role>Rusty the Handyman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gregory, Michele</actor>
      <role>Tunia</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gregory, Michele</actor>
      <role>Tunia (1994-1998)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mitran, Andy</actor>
      <role>Professor Andy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Paul, Doug (II)</actor>
      <role>Show Announcer</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"The Bozo Super Sunday Show" was the final incarnation of what was once an institution across America. As before, the show's colorful host, Bozo the Clown always be-decked in a blue outfit, red hair and nose and oversized shoes led the activities for the show's audience of children, youth groups and organizations, and adults. Staples of the show included songs, skits, stories, circus and vaudeville acts and games. The Grand Prize Game invited (as picked at random) one boy and one girl from the audience to toss ping-pong balls into a line of six buckets, from increasing distances, for prizes. And of course, the cream pies kept flying in the faces of the regular cast members. By 1997, Bozo began leading exercises for the children, and videotaped segments of trips to such educational places as a museum and fire station, were featured. The Chicago-based "Bozo Super Sunday Show" was the last show featuring the immortal clown to be produced, as many stations that had their own local Bozo shows (180 stations at one point) had ceased production of either daily or weekly shows to air syndicated childrens programming or, probably more often than not, tabloid news (e.g., "A Current Affair") and trash-talk programs such as Jerry Springer. Throughout Bozo's 40-year Chicago run, more than 2 million "boys and girls, moms and dads" were members of the studio audience.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?545725</url></doc>
