<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="546784">
  <docid>546784</docid>
  <title>The Busy Bee</title>
  <year>1903</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">September 1903</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
<plot>A striking series of fifteen pictures showing every phase of bee culture. The entire series is so absolutely different from anything that has ever been done before in motion pictures, that it must be seen to be appreciated. Every scene is of magnificent value photographically, and in many cases the bees are shown in such a near view that there appears to be considerable magnification. The men who are working about the bees are, for the most part, unprotected from the stings, and this alone lends an unusual interest. For educational work this series is absolutely without a rival. In England they have proved not only a great attraction when added to a regular programme of miscellaneous subjects, but they have been shown with great profit by exhibitors who have made a specialty of booking dates with schools and churches. 1. Capturing a Swarm of Bees from a Tree. The bee farmer secures the swarm by dropping same into a basket. 2. The old Straw Hive with Bees entering and flying about. A general view. 3. The Bees drinking Honey. An enlarged view showing platform outside of hive. 4. Bees pulling away Flowers which had dropped in front of Hive. An interesting picture of four or five bees removing a blossom. 5. Skeps showing Comb and Bees. The hive turned upsidedown with full view of combs filled with honey, previous to smoking out bees. 6. Smoking out the Bees from Skep into Basket. This operation is necessary in the transfer of the bees from the old fashioned skep to the modern frame hive. 7. Inside view of Basket Containing Bees. The inside of a two foot diameter basket literally alive with thousands of bees. 8. Placing Bees in front of Hive. The bees are shaken from the basket on to the platform in front of the hive and the bee master scoops up the bees with his naked hand showing them the way into the hive. 9. General view of a modern Bee Farm. Showing scores of bees being examined by the bee culturer. 10. Bee Farmer examining Comb. An enlarged view of the structural character of the hive and position of the combs. 11. Foundation ready to be placed into Hive. To be worked up into comb by the bees. 12. Foundation to be worked into Comb by the Bees. Enlarged view of foundation of cells of the comb. 13. Brood Comb with Queen and Workers. Busily engaged depositing honey into cells. 14. Comb with cells Capped. The larvae have been hatched out and fed, and are now enclosed in the cells where they develop into bees. 15. Magnified view of Comb. Showing eggs; the larvae being fed by the workers. This picture conveys an excellent idea of the ceaseless activity of the BUSY BEE, and forms an appropriate ending to one of the most interesting series of Natural History Studies.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?546784</url></doc>
