<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="547158">
  <docid>547158</docid>
  <title>The Calling</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Clement, Simon (I)</editor>
    <editor>Greenway, Daniel</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">8</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Kershaw, Stuart</director>
    <director>King, Alyssa</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Kershaw, Stuart</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>d'Oliveira, Miguel</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cope, Chris</actor>
      <role>Winston Rose</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>At once both comical and darkly disturbing, The Calling is an exploration of man's lust for adventure and the extraordinary places it can lead him. From the monotony of western living to the magnetic attraction of both wilderness and warfront, filmmaker Stuart Kershaw follows the young men willing to 'risk all' to realise their heroic desires and give their lives undeniable worth. Kershaw explores how the jarhead marine is indoctrinated like the Islamist suicide bomber or the lustful, wandering hermit shapes himself a new vision of the world from his connection with nature and isolation in the wild. As Kershaw moves closer to understanding his private motivations, he must suspend balanced rationale like the radicals around him, if he is to understand the priceless virtues of belonging and belief Kershaw explores why the jarhead marine is indoctrinated like the Islamist suicide-bomber. How the lustful, wandering hermit shapes himself a new vision of the world from his connection with nature and isolation in the wild.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?547158</url></doc>
