<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="547961">
  <docid>547961</docid>
  <title>The Cetacean Experience</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Redeker, Volker</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Germany">December 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">27</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Redeker, Volker</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Redeker, Volker</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Redeker, Volker</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>The harbor of San Sebastian de la Gomera on the canary islands. From here Christopher Columbus started out westwards across the Atlantic ocean in 1492 to discover the new world. About 500 years later a small group of marine-life enthusiasts meet aboard a 40-meters sailing-ship from the 1920s, the Catherina. The ship is chartered for a special one-week-sailing-expedition and leaves the harbor on a sunny Saturday morning in march 2005. The people aboard the ship come from countries all over the world, differing in age, profession and background, but they are all there for one reason: to watch whales and dolphins in their natural habitat. For that reason they joined cetologist Fabian Ritter an his team from M.E.E.R. to be their guides. The non-governmental organization M.E.E.R. is dedicated to the conservation of whales and dolphins and their natural habitat. The camera follows the group on their way through the sea southwest of gomera with its incomparable high species diversity of whales and dolphins, that makes this area one of the most outstanding places in the world where humans can meet cetaceans(the biological order of whales and dolphins) in the wild. Supported by a carefully selected Soundtrack this film gives an impression of how truly amazing this experience is.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?547961</url></doc>
