<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="548344">
  <docid>548344</docid>
  <title>The Cheyenne Kid</title>
  <year>1930</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Thompson, William P.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Western</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>lost-film</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 May 1930</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Jaccard, Jacques</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Canutt, Yakima</writer>
    <writer>Jaccard, Jacques</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Burns, Fred (I)</actor>
      <role>Sheriff Hank Bates</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Canutt, Yakima</actor>
      <role>Marshal Utah Kane</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ellis, Frank (I)</actor>
      <role>Henchman Gorman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Forman, Tom B.</actor>
      <role>Windy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jaccard, Joan</actor>
      <role>Betty Thorpe</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Knights, Violet</actor>
      <role>Madge</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lyons, Cliff (I)</actor>
      <role>Cowhand</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McKee, Lafe</actor>
      <role>Dad Thorpe</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mower, Jack</actor>
      <role>Duke Porter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wilsey, Jay</actor>
      <role>Buck Allen/The Cheyenne Kid</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Buck Allen, The Cheyenne Kid, has been accused of holding up the payroll car of the Cody Dam Construction Company, and is being pursued by U.S. Marshal Utah Kane and Sheriff Hank Bates but they lose him. Buck proceeds to the home of Betty Thorpe where he meets Duke Porter who is posing as his friend and who advised him that by running away from the law, he can keep out of jail and force the guilty party to confess. Hiding in the barn, he hears a conversation between Gorman and Madge and he leaps to the floor as Gorman runs out. Gorman shoots at him but hits Madge instead. The Marshal and Sheriff ride up and Buck, knowing that Madge needs medical attention, gives himself up and is jailed. Marshal Kane believes that Buck is innocent and is on the hunt for the guilty party but allows the sheriff to believe that Buck is guilty. Kane has the sheriff bring Gorman to the jail and tells Buck and Gorman of an old Indian legend that when two people are given one weapon between them, the survivor will be the innocent party. He throws a bull-whip between them and says that is the weapon.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?548344</url></doc>
