<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="548496">
  <docid>548496</docid>
  <title>The Chimera Project: Middlesbrough</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Light Surgeons, The</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">15 November 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Light Surgeons, The</director>
    <director>Price, James R.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Price, James R.</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>This film charts a day in the life of this troubled but proud North East town. The industry that gave birth to the urban area is still very present in the town, but large scale unemployment and misguided governance have given the area terrible problems with dereliction, drugs, and prostitution, and a bad image problem in the country at large. The film looks at the people who choose to live there, and how a sense of community, love, home, and hope keep them there. This film was produced in 2003 as the flagship commission of the first North East "AV festival" in the three regional cities of Newcastle, Middlesborough and Sunderland. It was the second of two "Chimera Projects" commissioned by The Tyneside Cinema in Newcastle with the support of regional councils and funding bodies. The idea of the Chimera Projects was to create a portrait of a city through creative collaboration with its local inhabitants - artists, musicians, writers, photographers and animators observing and commenting on their own city. At their premieres the finished films were remixed and performed live with the music that was composed by the local participants for the films. The project was directed from a production space in Middlesbrough in autumn 2003 by Light Surgeons member James Price, and was then edited by The Light Surgeons at their London base. The local contributing artists were Jamie Macdonald, Nicky Peacock, Clive Tonge, Lindsay Roe, Liz McCormack, Sam Harrison, Rayees Rashid, Robert Page, Russell Smith, Marni Henderson, Katherine O'Connor, Imogen Busby, and Marty Collantine.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?548496</url></doc>
