<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="548879">
  <docid>548879</docid>
  <title>The City</title>
  <year>1939</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Lawrence, Theodore</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">1939</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">26 May 1939</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">20</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Elton, Ralph</director>
    <director>Steiner, Ralph</director>
    <director>Van Dyke, Willard</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Rodakiewicz, Henwar</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Mumford, Lewis</writer>
    <writer>Rodakiewicz, Henwar</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Copland, Aaron</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carnovsky, Morris</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Made by a group of people with, if not an axe to grind, a purpose in mind, which appears to be a plug for future suburbia and back to the idyllic towns of the past and the Big City would just be a place where people work but not live. Or something like that, as it is told in a schizophrenic method that primarily drones on about ...it started like this and it was good, and it becames this and it was bad, yada, yada, yada. Based on how America looks today...large metroplexes surrounded by super highways surrounded by look-alike suburbs with more super highways leading out to other metroplexes--- the goal was accomplished but the results aren't what was envisioned in 1939. The film was made possible by funding from the Carnegie Corporation of New York and has a definite leftward-slant which is no surprise based on some of the names connected with the original film. It was later adapted and edited into an entry of John Nesbitt's Passing Parade at MGM in 1944 (PCA No. 9620) called "The World of Tomorrow" with a new score by Nathaniel Shilkret, adaptation and narration by John Nesbitt and edited by Harry Komer.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?548879</url></doc>
