<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="548916">
  <docid>548916</docid>
  <title>The City in the Image of Man: Ideas and Work of Paolo Soleri</title>
  <year>1972</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>cities</keyword>
    <keyword>architecture</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">14 May 1972</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">81</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Brockway, Merrill</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Brockway, Merrill</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Chodorov, Stephan</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Clarke, Arthur C.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Collins, George (XII)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gallahue, John</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gibson, Kenneth (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Safdie, Moshe</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Soleri, Paolo</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stolwijk, Jan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Toffler, Alvin</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Udall, Stewart L.</actor>
      <role>Himself - Host</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ylvisacker, Paul</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Wide ranging exploration of the ideas of architect Paolo Soleri. With Paolo Soleri, architect, philosopher; Stewart Udall (former Secretary of Interior and head of an environmental consulting firm); Kenneth Gibson, Mayor of Newark, N.J.; Alvin Toffler, author ("Future Shock", etc.); scientist/future-thinker Arthur C. Clarke ("2001: A Space Odyssey", etc.); Moshe Safdie, architect ("Habitat"); Prof. John Gallahue (Columbia Univ., New York City.) and others. An illustrated series of interviews about Paolo Soleri's ideas. Themes: architecture, the future of urban centers, the Earth's ability to sustain itself under the increasing load of human population, the interaction of art and utility, the future of ideas we take for granted,( such as progress and technology), and the changing nature of man himself. Stewart Udall is on-camera host and voice-over narrator. Soleri is seen in dialog with a wide range of persons whose concerns and expertise intersect his own ideas. A great deal of film and photographs illustrate the themes discussed. The main theme discussed in this footage: cities are the man made landscape and are essential to the continuation of civilization; but new cities must evolve in response to a changing world; they must be integrated places, built up into three dimensions, not out endlessly across the landscape..</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?548916</url></doc>
