<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="549091">
  <docid>549091</docid>
  <title>The Climb</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Weslak, Steve</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">October 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">52</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Johnston, Mark (VI)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Haldane, Heather</producer>
    <producer>Young Leckie, Mary</producer>
    <producer>Hemstreet, Tambre</producer>
    <producer>Johnston, Mark (VI)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Johnston, Mark (VI)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>McGrath, Jim (I)</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>On October 5th, 1982, Laurie Skreslet scaled more than twenty-nine thousand feet to become the first Canadian on Mount Everest. For Canadians, it was moment of unadulterated pride. For Skreslet and his fellow climbers, it was a triumph littered with bitterness, broken relationships and the bodies of four dead men. The Climb is a documentary that takes Skreslet and fellow summiter Pat Morrow back to Base Camp, reliving the traumatic and triumphant events of 1982. But this is no stroll back to the mountain. Pat Morrow faces the challenge of a mystery illness that might prevent his return to the mountain. And Laurie Skreslet has brought his nineteen year old daughter, Natasha - a young woman who has hardly seen her father in ten years. The Climb traces the build-up to the 1982 Canadian climb of Everest, tracks the drama of the journey up the mountain and nearly 25 years later follows Skreslet and Morrow as they piece together their recollections during an emotional trip back to Nepal and Everest's storied base camp. The film will deliver the immediacy of the events as they unfolded on the mountain through the use of unique archival footage shot in 1982, while at the same time gripping the audiences with a present-day narrative of those still haunted by those tragic and triumphant days as they re-visit Base Camp together for the first time since The Climb.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?549091</url></doc>
