<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="550217">
  <docid>550217</docid>
  <title>The Core</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Jensen, Birger Møller</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>quantum-mechanics</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Danish</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Denmark</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Denmark">11 August 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Fox, Robert (III)</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Fox, Robert (III)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bateson, David</actor>
      <role>Niels Bohr</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Munk, Troels II</actor>
      <role>Niels Bohr</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A personal first person account of how the famous Nobel prize winning physicist Niels Bohr (1885-1962) lost his innocence when experiencing how his formulas were the basis for the Atomic Bomb thrown on Hiroshima in 1945. Though never before seen personal footage from Bohr's Rolex camera, personal photos and beautiful shot 16mm footage from Copenhagen we hear Bohr tell the story of how he took the responsibility when realizing the consequences of his atomic knowledge. It is a close up account based exclusively on Bohr's own words. In the1920s Bohr came to realize that nothing is as it appears on the atomic level. This insight was the beginning of quantum physics and famous discussions with Albert Einstein. The Quantum States brought Bohr to reach for answers in the ancient Indian and Japanese traditions - On one hand gaining knowledge and wisdom on the other leaving death, destruction and desolation in Hiroshima in 1945. After the Second World War, Bohr pleaded for openness between East and West with President Roosevelt and Churchill.. He was not heard. Many experts agree that Bohr was 50 years ahead of his time.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?550217</url></doc>
