<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="550313">
  <docid>550313</docid>
  <title>The Cosmodrome Futurists</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Scaff, Julian H.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Czech</language>
    <language>Russian</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Netherlands">23 April 2005</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">10 August 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Netherlands">14</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Scaff, Julian H.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Scaff, Julian H.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Scaff, Julian H.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Scaff, Julian H.</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bolden, Galina</actor>
      <role>Dr. Marina Reshetnikova</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rossano, Federico</actor>
      <role>Dr. Enzo Montazzoli</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Scaff, Julian H.</actor>
      <role>Voice over</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>de Ruiter, Jan-Peter</actor>
      <role>Dr. Joost Van Dijk</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In 1976, a group of Russian scientists working at the Baikonur Cosmodrome in Kazakhstan discovered that they shared an interest in earlier Russian Futurist and avant-garde movements, and they viewed the Russian Revolution as the first great Futurist revolution. They also believed that the next great futurist revolution would be cultural rather than political, and would manifest as the merging of science, technology and art to the point where art was indistinguishable from technology. While not much is known about the players in this small and short-lived movement (due to the fact that scientists in the Soviet space program were closely guarded secrets), it is known that they were primarily driven by the astrophysicist Yuri Tchechenko and his wife Jelena Tchechenko, an electrical engineer. Yuri and Jelena were predominantly interested in music, and specifically in ways that music can be composed and recorded by purely technological means. What they attempted to do, without the knowledge of the Soviet government, was the most audacious and extraordinary artistic act in the 20th century.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?550313</url></doc>
