<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="550683">
  <docid>550683</docid>
  <title>The Cowpokes Ball</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Roth, Jeff (VIII)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 June 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">15</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Jackson, Sally (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Jackson, Kelly (V)</producer>
    <producer>Jackson, Sally (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Jackson, Kelly (V)</writer>
    <writer>Jackson, Sally (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Henderson, Pam (II)</actor>
      <role>The Midlife Gals assistant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jackson, Kelly (V)</actor>
      <role>One of the Midlife Gals</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jackson, Kelly (VI)</actor>
      <role>KK</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jackson, Sally (I)</actor>
      <role>One of the Midlife Gals</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Perella, Marco</actor>
      <role>TV station manager</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The ongoing story of two middle-aged sisters, KK and Sal in Austin, Texas. They host a local access channel program on Sunday mornings Called, THE MIDLIFE GALS. Their mother, The Ancient One owns the station. They consume Bloody Marys and appetizers as they discuss their latest attempts to insinuate themselves into Austin high society goings on. All the social world knows them as hapless, utterly unsophisticated and lacking in ANY social graces whatsoever...and they DRINK. Their smarmy station manager, Marco, is having an affair wtih the town's hostess with the mostess, Diane, who won't let The Midlife Gals into any social function if she can help it. KK and SalGal attempt to get in to The Cowpoke's Charity Ball with an auction benefiting The Maimed and Mutilated Rodeo Clown's Foundation. They make an auction item per instructions from their social secretary, Pam. It is a cow patty cake. Although they are rejected at the door due to the poor quality of the fake invitations made by Pam for them, they do manage to sneak the cake into the auction and it is purchased for $5000 by the Governor of Texas at the ball . This outrages both Marco who dreams of taking over the station and his mistress, the hostess, Diane. The ultimate slap in the face to the two of them is that the Governor drops by the Midlife Gals' weekly show to share the cow patty cake with them!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?550683</url></doc>
