<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="551427">
  <docid>551427</docid>
  <title>The Curse of Sherwood</title>
  <year>1987</year>
  <type>VideoGame</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>History</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">September 1987</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <producers>
    <producer>Brewster, Derek</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Brewster, Derek</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Robin Hood and his merry men are confronted with their biggest challenge to date! The evil Cult of Sagalia has overtaken Sherwood Forest, instilling fear into the hearts of the peaceful forest dwellers. Robin and the rest of the band are relying on you, as Friar Tuck, to rid the forest of this evil force and then get back to normal pursuits like robbing the rich to give to the poor. In the meantime Robin and his men battle valiantly on, but the odds are definitely stacked against them. Werewolves roam the forest day and night watching and waiting for any likely looking prey. Hideous animated skeletons appear when they're least expected and should you be unfortunate enough to come across one of the Priests of Salagia, well, your days are numbered. Already one attempt to rid the forest of the Cult has failed. You had arranged to meet the Bishop of Derby to try to carry out an exorcism. When he failed to arrive on time you set out to look for him and at the edge of the forest you find his body, he had been slain by a black arrow. But on his body you notice a blood-stained parchment section bearing the following rhyme, could this possibly be the answer? 'For fire protection you must amass Werewolves fangs and a Scrying glass Then travel through the misty wood To take them to the Witch of Good From the man of solitary means A parchment guide is what you need Without it you may go astray And in the forest lose your way To buy the means to safety walk A firey monster you must stalk He holds the price with precious metal Convey to the hermit without much fettle A silver cross must be found Before you feel safe and sound On the pentagon it must be dropped And the portal of evil will be stopped' With the parchment as your only clue you hurry back to the camp to find Robin and his men surrounded and fighting for their lives. You are their only chance, you must follow the clues and destroy the source of evil before it claims its final victory.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?551427</url></doc>
