<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="551525">
  <docid>551525</docid>
  <title>The Cypherian</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Johnston, D.K.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">18</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Johnston, D.K.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Johnston Sr., David K.</producer>
    <producer>Johnston, Carolyn Blake</producer>
    <producer>Johnston, Katherine R.</producer>
    <producer>Welch, Shannon Marie</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Johnston, D.K.</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Allen, Vince</actor>
      <role>Caleb Wallace</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bukowsky, Maddie</actor>
      <role>Amy Patton</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bukowsky, Sam</actor>
      <role>Monk 1</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Corbin, Christopher</actor>
      <role>Servius Augustus Cyriacus</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Johnston, D.K.</actor>
      <role>Monk 2</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Newton, Jacob</actor>
      <role>Cody - Bodyguard</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Page, Jeremiah</actor>
      <role>Vincent Wallace</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vox, Dylan</actor>
      <role>Lucifer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Watts, Benjamin (I)</actor>
      <role>Jason - Bodyguard</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Weinstock, Brett (II)</actor>
      <role>Gabriel</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>At the dawn of man's existence the powers of Heaven and Hell each chose a single human representative. Their purpose, to guide and protect mankind. Gifted with immortality, power, and strength the Cypherian line was created. A Cypherian, named Servius, was charged with the protection of Jesus Christ. After the Crucifixion Servius turned his back on his charge and vanished into history. Mankind was then left unprotected. Today a new child is to be born into the world. One that will influence man's existence forever. The powers of Heaven send the Archangel Gabriel to, once again, attempt to recruit Servius to help them in the protection of the unborn child and its mother Amy. Little does Amy know she is being targeted by not only the Prince of Darkness, Lucifer, but also by a family dedicated to obtaining the powers of the Cypherian themselves. While Servius struggles against his hatred for those he once served and his sympathy for humanity Caleb and Vincent Wallace hope to use the mother and her child to lure Servius into their trap. Servius must choose to take up the charge he once abandoned or leave the destiny of the unborn child in the hands of fate.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?551525</url></doc>
