<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="551972">
  <docid>551972</docid>
  <title>The Darkside of Happiness</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Travis, Ryan (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Russian</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby SR</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">20 November 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">20</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Travis, Ryan (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Travis, Michael (IV)</producer>
    <producer>Travis, Ryan (I)</producer>
    <producer>Weiner, Ari</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Travis, Ryan (I)</writer>
    <writer>Weiner, Ari</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>de Corpo, Jim</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Amendola, Nicci</actor>
      <role>Trisha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Clark, Beau (I)</actor>
      <role>Jason</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cox, Stephen (IV)</actor>
      <role>Tyler</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Downey, Danny</actor>
      <role>Man in Bed</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gekht, Michael</actor>
      <role>Loki</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Graf, David Alan</actor>
      <role>Man in Car</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Guilmette, Steve</actor>
      <role>Vladimir</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Latzer, Josh</actor>
      <role>Ivan</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Beneath the flashing lights of a smoke-filled nightclub, a rebellious punk rocker named Tyler unleashes years of pent-up frustration through the hard-hitting notes of his electric guitar. While in his rock-and-roll element, he is completely empowered, strong and sexy. In the raging crowd just a few feet in front of him stands Nicole, a head-turning vixen with a tortured past and dark secret. Tyler spots Nicole, whose steely blue eyes are fixed on him. They exchange glances loaded with instant attraction, passion and mystery in hopes of a fresh start. This is where their adventure begins. Will they be able to overcome the impossible? Tyler, unloved by his mother and disillusioned with God and humanity, struggles to find faith in something. Nicole, at first seemingly innocent, slowly reveals to Tyler her own difficulties of an abusive father and horrific life for herself and younger sister, Trisha. She entrust to his compassionate ear that only through her deep faith in the Virgin Mary has she been able to survive such abuse. Breaking into the middle of their newly formed courtship with the fierce slap of the back of his hand onto Nicole's cheek stomps her father, Vladimir. Bearing witness to brutality, Tyler sets out to wrest Nicole from the clutches of this malicious man. Together, they embark down a treacherous path and frightening confrontation with the Russian mob that forces Tyler to find faith in a religion he knows nothing about along his courageous quest to rescue the girl he loves.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?551972</url></doc>
