<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="552485">
  <docid>552485</docid>
  <title>The Death of a Composer: Rosa, a Horse Drama</title>
  <year>1999</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>opera</keyword>
    <keyword>horse</keyword>
    <keyword>live-performance</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Italy">4 September 1999</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Greenaway, Peter</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>van Breemen, George</producer>
    <producer>Kasander, Kees</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Greenaway, Peter</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Angel, Marie</actor>
      <role>Esmeralda</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Blanford, Phyllis</actor>
      <role>Index Singer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gillett, Christopher</actor>
      <role>Lully</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Greenaway, Peter</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Smeets, Roger</actor>
      <role>Alcan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Terracini, Lyndon</actor>
      <role>Juan Manuel de Rosa</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This is a TV adaptation of a 1993 opera entitled "Rosa," with a libretto by Greenaway and score by Louis Andriessen. "Rosa" is the first in a projected series of 10 operas, each dealing with the death of a famous composer - some real (Anton Webern, Jean-Baptiste Lully, John Lennon), others fictional. "Rosa" falls into the latter category; it tells the story of Juan Manuel de Rosa, a Brazilian who went to study music in America but spent most of his time in the cinema instead, becoming particularly entranced by Westerns. Now 32 years old and residing in an abandoned Uraguayan slaughterhouse, Rosa has become one of Hollywood's foremost composers, specializing in (what else?) Westerns. He also has a beautiful 19-year-old fiancee, Esmeralda, but he pays her little heed, instead lavishing his attentions on a black mare named Bola. One day, a group of men attired as cowboys arrive at the abattoir and kill both Rosa and Bola; an investigation is conducted, with particular suspicion!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?552485</url></doc>
