<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="552691">
  <docid>552691</docid>
  <title>The Delivery Man</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Firpo, Ryan</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">30 March 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">25</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Firpo, Ryan</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Firpo, Ryan</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Ulibarri, Ian</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Callero, Eric</actor>
      <role>Gary</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dean, Wayne Anthony</actor>
      <role>Floyd</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deverman, Chad</actor>
      <role>Jimmy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Devoto, Kelly</actor>
      <role>Susie Solomon</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kasin, Michael</actor>
      <role>The Masked Man</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lanahan-Kalish, Damian</actor>
      <role>Greg</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"You let standards fall like that, the next that goes is pride. And once you lose pride, you might as well be buried, because you're a dead man walking. And that's where we're at right now: an entire country of f%@kin' zombies." So says Jimmy -- a career criminal of the 'thinking' sort -- while staring out the windshield of his parked Cadillac, thoughtfully munching a hamburger and fries. He lectures an audience of one -- Susie Solomon -- a hapless teenage prostitute who is currently bound, blindfolded, and gagged in the back seat. After Jimmy's philosophical appetite has been satisfied, he begins the long drive to the middle of nowhere to complete the job he was hired to do, and deliver Susie to a warehouse and a group of men whose ultimate intentions for the girl remain, at least to him, a mystery. Once inside, Jimmy is commended for his work. He is paid handsomely - nearly twice what he was promised. All is well in Jimmy's world. Another rung ascended on the criminal ladder, money in his pocket, and the pretty, naive girl from Idaho is about to learn a lesson that should swear her off 'hooking' forever. But, maybe, he suddenly realizes as he studies the 'scenery' around the warehouse, they're going to do more than just 'teach her a lesson'. When Jimmy finally learns of her true fate, he must make a decision: take the money and run, or stay and try to save Susie Solomon?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?552691</url></doc>
