<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="553076">
  <docid>553076</docid>
  <title>The Devil in the kitchen</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <editors>
    <editor>Schaarschmidt, Boris</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>los-angeles-california</keyword>
    <keyword>gourmand</keyword>
    <keyword>gourmet</keyword>
    <keyword>soul-mate</keyword>
    <keyword>restaurant</keyword>
    <keyword>dark-comedy</keyword>
    <keyword>cooking</keyword>
    <keyword>chef</keyword>
    <keyword>california</keyword>
    <keyword>gourmet-chef</keyword>
    <keyword>silverlake-los-angeles</keyword>
    <keyword>foie-gras</keyword>
    <keyword>food-critic</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <directors>
    <director>Schaarschmidt, Boris</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Schaarschmidt, Boris</producer>
    <producer>Gebroe, David</producer>
    <producer>Brindl, Herbert M.</producer>
    <producer>Coogan, Tracy</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Brindl, Herbert M.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kirst, Patrick</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ball, Jonas</actor>
      <role>Christian</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brindl, Herbert M.</actor>
      <role>The Chef</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Christopher, Jennifer</actor>
      <role>Tara</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Coogan, Tracy</actor>
      <role>Ann</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Chef Herbert and Ann are soul mates. They share the same insatiable appetite for fine cuisine and fine wine. Together they have created a haven for gourmets and gourmands, running and owning their dream restaurant in Silverlake, Los Angeles, where they can enjoy the fruits of their labor. Of course running such a fine restaurant does not go unnoticed, so naturally the critics have come to sample this very delicate cuisine. One such critic, Mr. Spagat, arrives - he is the most famous and harshest food critic of them all, renowned for using his power to equally praise and degrade a restaurant in the same sentence - maybe to raise his food guide sales? He finds the liver a little too fatty, a little too tasteless, has potential but still a little too bland for his tastes.  He decides to take a star away from Chef Herbert which has cost them dearly. A year has passed and Mr. Spagat has returned to review the restaurant yet again. This time Chef Herbert and Ann have cooked up a very special and surprising recipe, one that will tickle the taste buds and tantalize the pallet and keep you wanting more.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?553076</url></doc>
