<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="553299">
  <docid>553299</docid>
  <title>The Diamond Head Game</title>
  <year>1975</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Game-Show</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>non-fiction</keyword>
    <keyword>hawaii</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">6 January 1975</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Kyne, Terry</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Fishman, Ed</producer>
    <producer>Freer, Randall</producer>
    <producer>Fishman, Dave</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Thicke, Alan</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Eubanks, Bob</actor>
      <role>Host</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Thompson, Jim (V)</actor>
      <role>Announcer</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Aside from special weeks of various game shows taped in Hawaii, "The Diamond Head Game" remains the only game show based in the 50th state (the show was actually shot on the island of Oahu) ; the show itself took place on a specially constructed set, complete with four "islands" and a "Money Volcano." Eight contestants competed, each island having two contestants. In a series of four best-of-three rounds, Eubanks asked the contestants general knowledge questions; the first contestant to get two points, earned through correct answers or opponents' incorrect answers, won a prize and became that island's "representative" to "climb Diamond Head" (the on-stage "volcano"), played after all four islands' representatives were determined. The contestants stand at the foot of the three-step Diamond Head; Eubanks reads a question with 12 possible answers. The contestants alternate giving answers until either an incorrect answer is given, an answer is repeated or someone doesn't answer; that contestant is eliminated, and the surviving contestants win $50 and move up one step. The last remaining contestant wins the right to go into the "Money Volcano." In the "Money Volcano" round, the contestant enters a large glass case and has 15 seconds to grab as many wind-blown dollar bills and slips with the names of prizes written on them. Eubanks then takes 10 of the slips/bills and, one at a time, reveals each. The contestant can stop at any time and keep what they've won, or continue until all 10 have been shown (at which point he/she keeps everything) ; however, if Eubanks shows a $1 bill, the game is stopped and the contestant loses everything.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?553299</url></doc>
