<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="553222">
  <docid>553222</docid>
  <title>The Devil's Wedding</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Lindsay, Tom (III)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">16 January 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">15</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Cadan, Dan</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Doring, Nicola</producer>
    <producer>Headey, Lena</producer>
    <producer>Neate-James, Claire</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Cadan, Dan</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carter, Pip</actor>
      <role>The Devil</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Foreman, Jamie</actor>
      <role>The Narrator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Graham, Stephen (I)</actor>
      <role>The Hotelier</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Headey, Lena</actor>
      <role>The Devil's Bride</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>When the Devil and his Bride-To-Be arrive at an eerie and decrepit hotel, their intention is to spend more than one night together. They are there to perform unholy matrimony and spend the rest of their lives, wicked side by wicked side, cosily roasting in matrimonial hell. The Hotelier, who suffers from the same eerie decrepitude as the hotel in which he resides, is terrified into giving them the 'Penthouse' in which to perform their celebration. But before they can ring their wedding'b-hell' and exchange their twisted vows, a cold reality dawns as they realize that no guests are joining them in their celebration. It transpires that the Devil was late sending out the invitations and will now stop at nothing to placate his infuriated Bride. There is only one that can help them, our petrified Hotelier. During his personal mêlée, the Devil lowers his guard and reveals himself to be nothing more than a desperate man. The now-not-so-petrified Hotelier seizes a chance never before known to man and offers the Devil a deal. Sell him his soul, in exchange for his being their guest at the wedding. The Devil, stuck between a rock and a hot place, knows that this is the only way he can make his Bride happy and reluctantly agrees. The Hotelier sidelines in the ways of the man above and agrees to marry the single-souled pair with consequences that the Devil himself could never have dealt.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?553222</url></doc>
