<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="553436">
  <docid>553436</docid>
  <title>The Digital Cinema Filmmaker's Training Course</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>digital-film</keyword>
    <keyword>filmmaking</keyword>
    <keyword>hamden</keyword>
    <keyword>digital-filmmaking</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">G</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">10 June 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">1440</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Hamden, Rush</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hamden, Rush</producer>
    <producer>Hamden, Tatiana</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Hamden, Rush</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Corona, Ivan</actor>
      <role>Director of Photography</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gresch, John (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hoel, Laura Renee</actor>
      <role>Rachel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Horn, Karl</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ivanova, Tatyana (II)</actor>
      <role>Detective</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jacob, Tom</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Landry, David</actor>
      <role>Main Character, Jake</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Navoyan, Levon</actor>
      <role>Restaurant worker</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Svendsen, Joel</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Turner, Bill (XII)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The Digital Cinema Course begins by detailed instructions on building a screenplay with proper structure and solid characters. Many screen writing textbooks have also done this, but the course is the first to do it by use of a dramatic short film teaching writers the basics of overcoming obstacles and disasters. This is then furthered by second more concise section outlining how to write in clear instructions. It categorizes specific methods and tools, and inspires writers who may have given up on dramatic storytelling. The following section describes how to physically construct a screenplay, what paper to use, how to bind it, and how to format the content. This is done with the use of computer graphics. Once the storytelling sections are complete, the course moves on to teach film editing. Starting with the history of editing and progressing to current digital nonlinear editing, the section prepares the filmmaker for the field. It abides by the rule that the best cinematographer or director is first a competent editor. After the editing section, the course moves on to discuss filmmaking equipment and gear, from the basic C-stand to the intricate use of color gels and corrective filtration. It prepares filmmakers for the technical aspect of making movies with HMI, tungsten, and fluorescent lighting. After the equipment section, it explores basic production in a controlled studio environment. Lighting, lenses, shots, depth of field, composition, and axes of movement. The course then applies all the concepts learned in the movie production section. By far the longest of the sections, at about 12 hours, it puts all the principles to the test on a real movie set. It carries with it all the variables that can assault filmmakers while trying to make a digital film. After the movie production section has been completed, the course moves on to the advanced lighting section. This is the most detailed of the sections, concentrating for hours on the art of lighting a film set with faith to the script's intention. Whether lighting to mimic candlelight, firelight, or fluorescent warehouse lighting, this section discusses the most difficult situations that a cinematographer may confront. The Digital Cinema Course is also accompanied by a color technical manual for the field, a checklist, and a preparation CD.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?553436</url></doc>
