<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="553978">
  <docid>553978</docid>
  <title>The Dome</title>
  <year>2010</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Greilich, Jef</editor>
  </editors>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Rives, Chip</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Karabinas, David</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>In an age of monolithic retractable roofs, corporate luxury boxes, and multi-story high-definition "Godzilla-tron" screens, it's easy to forget where it all began. Conceived by a larger than life Texas Judge who didn't want his daughter to suffer through any more rained out ballgames, the Astrodome forever changed the world of sports and entertainment. Like nothing anyone had ever seen, "The Dome" defied the odds simply by design, and once completed, redefined the expectations of what was possible. The story of "The Dome" begins in an era when American ingenuity knew no bounds, and with a man who didn't know the meaning of failure. A flamboyant and successful politician, broadcaster, developer and sportsman, Judge Roy Hofheinz promised baseball perfect weather in order to secure Houston a major league baseball team, and he wasn't going to let something like the city's notoriously swampy climate get in his way. Amidst a chorus of doubters who couldn't imagine it was possible to create a building large enough to play baseball indoors, "The Judge" as he was known to friends and foes alike, spear-headed the controversial construction of the Harris County Domed Stadium. Concerns ran the gamut from rain occurring inside the building, to the dome itself snapping off like a rubber band, but less than three years and $40 million dollars later, the Judge would prove them all wrong. Opened to the public in 1965, the world's first domed stadium was considered an architectural marvel. Immediately billed as the 8th Wonder of the World, everything about the building reflected the cutting edge technology of the day. Air-conditioning kept the 18-story building a pleasant 72 degrees no matter what was going on outside, and luxury "sky boxes" replaced the traditional "nose-bleed" sections found in other ballparks. From the four-story "Astrolite" scoreboard above, to the bright green "Astroturf" below, visitors to the Dome were treated to a spectacle of industrial wizardry and engineering firsts that often proved more compelling than the action occurring on the field. Playing host to Presidents and Kings, astronauts and cowboys, heavy weight champs and legendary athletes, the story of the Astrodome is more than just that of an arena whose time may have come and gone. The Dome created the modern age of the multi-purpose event center, and the history of the Dome becomes not only a history of sports, but of some of the greatest entertainment and cultural events of the last forty years. From the Game of the Century to the Battle of the Sexes, from Elvis to Selena, from the members of the Republican Party to the evacuees of Hurricane Katrina, the Dome has seen it all. It remains today a living testament to a man, a city, a country, a time, and a vision. It's a story we've all had the pleasure of living...it just needs a voice.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?553978</url></doc>
