<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="554408">
  <docid>554408</docid>
  <title>The Driver</title>
  <year>2010</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>sex-crime</keyword>
    <keyword>mob</keyword>
    <keyword>murder</keyword>
    <keyword>car-chase</keyword>
    <keyword>hooker</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">R</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2010</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">95</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Barbet, Ken (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Lamothe, Connie</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Brennan, Michael P.</writer>
    <writer>Lamothe, Connie</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Borgia, Rick</actor>
      <role>Tony</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>DeLaurentis, Alexis</actor>
      <role>Maria</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Devon, Tony</actor>
      <role>Lenny</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lamothe, Connie</actor>
      <role>Regina D'Angelo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mann, Christopher (II)</actor>
      <role>Lee Staples</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Marcell, Joseph</actor>
      <role>Gordon</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mazzotta, Sal</actor>
      <role>Joey D'Angelo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Proval, David</actor>
      <role>Bruno</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Riviezzo, Vincent</actor>
      <role>Carlo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>The Greaseman</actor>
      <role>Frankie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vigoda, Abe</actor>
      <role>Don Politano</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Williams, Johnny (I)</actor>
      <role>Sharkie</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In many ways, Joey D'Angelo is like any man in his 40's: his hair's a little lighter around the edges, his skin isn't as tight as it once was, and his stomach can't handle the spicy food as well as it once could. Joey is also a family man. He has a lovely wife and two beautiful children. He would do anything for them. But Joey has another family to answer to: the mob. It is for this family that Joey works and earns a rather lucrative living. He's currently on the lower level of the family, a driver delivering hookers to some rather shady, unsavory people. He's good at his job and has ambitions for advancement. He has a need to prove himself to the boss, Vito Politano. It is this ambition that fuels him. As Joey battles his own hubris, he must ultimately make choices as to where his loyalties lie and how far he is willing to go. His internal struggles are fraught with moral ambiguity and ethical dilemmas that are manifested by his ever-weakening stomach and hair-trigger temper. When the one person closest to Joey is threatened, he will find that it just isn't possible to achieve balance between his two families and must choose which one he wishes to be a part of. He may find this realization came too late. Joey is a classic anti-hero. He has many flaws but he is essentially kind-hearted. He is fully aware of the dire consequences of unchecked ambition as it is reflected back at him from the ancient, lonely eyes of Don Vito. Can Joey save himself? Will he be able to find salvation in his family?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?554408</url></doc>
