<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="557566">
  <docid>557566</docid>
  <title>The Fighting Ranger</title>
  <year>1948</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Pierson, Carl</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Western</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>framed-for-murder</keyword>
    <keyword>rustling</keyword>
    <keyword>inheritance</keyword>
    <keyword>fall-off-cliff</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">15 August 1948</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">57</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Hillyer, Lambert</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Sarecky, Barney A.</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Adamson, Victor</actor>
      <role>Townsman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brown, Johnny Mack</actor>
      <role>Johnny Brown</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Clark, Steve (I)</actor>
      <role>Ward Henderson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hatton, Raymond</actor>
      <role>Banty</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Henderson, Ray (II)</actor>
      <role>Bushwhacker</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hughes, Charlie (I)</actor>
      <role>Dave Sinclair (Boy)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jolley, I. Stanford</actor>
      <role>Pop Sinclair</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Larsen, Christine (I)</actor>
      <role>Julie Sinclair</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Morante, Milburn</actor>
      <role>Gus (Ranch Cook)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Parker, Eddie (I)</actor>
      <role>Henchman Ned Gill</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Perkins, Peter (I)</actor>
      <role>Henchman Adams</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Reed, Marshall (I)</actor>
      <role>Hack Sinclair</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Woodward, Bob (II)</actor>
      <role>Henchman Bender</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Range Johnny Brown (Johnny Mack Brown) shoots fugitive Sinclair (I. Stanford Jolley) after a long chase, and before the latter dies he accuses his cousin Hack (Marshall Reed) of framing him for a murder, so he can inherit the ranch of his Uncle Henderson (Steve Clark.) Johnny places Sinclair's ten-year-old son Dave (Charlie Hughes) at Ranger hedaquarters for safety, while he gets a job at the ranch with the help of his friend Banty (Raymond Hatton). Johnny catches henchman Gill (Eddie Parker as Edwin Parker)cutting fences in preparation for rustling the catte, and Henderson's locks him up, but Gill escapes that night with the aid of Hack. Hack, the ranch foreman, has his henchmen ambush himself and his uncle while carrying the money for new cattle purchases. Johnny regains the money after killing Gill. Suspicious of his nephew, Henderson rides the range and is shot by Hack's henchmen. Before he dies, he makes anew will naming Dave as heir and Johnny as his guardian. Johnny beats up Hack for assaulting Banty when the latter catches Hack snooping for the new will. Hack attempts to make Sinclair's widow, Julia (Christine Larson as Christine Larson), suspicious of Johnny and she goes to see if her son Dave is at the Ranger headquarters. Hack folows, intending to do away with the two of them, but Johnny and Banty foil his plans in a blazing gun battle.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?557566</url></doc>
