<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="558112">
  <docid>558112</docid>
  <title>The First, Last Race</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">12 February 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Jensen, Jeff (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Jensen, Jeff (I)</producer>
    <producer>Hargrove, Robert</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Alzola, Mickey</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jensen, Jeff (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mulder, Eddie</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Soderblom, Nick</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tracy, Greg</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Hollywood Stuntman, Jeff Jensen, rides the new Ducati Terra Mostro from his home in Malibu, California, to the Pikes Peak Intn'l Hill Climb, races it and then rides it home afterwords. This would be a huge undertaking from any man in his mid-twenties, but, at twice that age, Jeff hasn't figured that out yet. Explore the mind set of a man that thinks he can still ride a motorcycle 1,400 miles one way, then race it in the Premier Class, on a road with thousand foot cliffs and no guard rails against World Class racers and then turn around and ride it home. Why does he think he won't be humiliated by the competition even though his first and last race on Pikes Peak was 9 years ago? After all, he didn't even finish the last time and this race, he's riding a stock, untested dual-sport road bike against the Factory Teams' riders and bikes. If that's not enough, he's doing all this with a broken leg and an artificial knee. What makes stuntmen and racers do such things? Why do they think they're bullet proof? In his search for this answer, he asks a couple of friends and fellow racers in the hill climb. One's a former National #1 racer that, at 65 yrs old, continues to beat his own record and has nothing to prove to anyone. Also, the 68 year old stuntman who's record has gone unbroken for 14 years but is now battling cancer and is scheduled for surgery 2 weeks after the race.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?558112</url></doc>
