<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="558231">
  <docid>558231</docid>
  <title>The Flag</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>War</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>based-on-true-story</keyword>
    <keyword>vietnam-era</keyword>
    <keyword>patriotism</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>prisoner-of-war</keyword>
    <keyword>vietnam-war</keyword>
    <keyword>hope</keyword>
    <keyword>prisoner</keyword>
    <keyword>prisoner-of-war-camp</keyword>
    <keyword>soldier</keyword>
    <keyword>military</keyword>
    <keyword>flag-burning</keyword>
    <keyword>flag</keyword>
    <keyword>vietnam</keyword>
    <keyword>military-history</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">14 October 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">13</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Hinojosa, Rene</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hinojosa, Rene</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bloodgood, Paul Michael</actor>
      <role>Kelly</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carley, Jeff</actor>
      <role>Fox</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harper, Jason (IV)</actor>
      <role>Freeman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kwok, Kevin</actor>
      <role>Vietnamese Guard</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nguyen, Anh Huu</actor>
      <role>Lead Vietnamese Guard</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Vietnam 1968. Several American soldiers are held prisoner within the depths of a Vietnamese war-camp. Fox (Jeff Carley) has reached the limits of what he can endure and begins to contemplate suicide. His efforts are thwarted when he begins to receive a tap communication from Kelly (Paul Michael Bloodgood). Kelly offers encouragement in the form of a prayer but learns that Fox has lost all hope. He instructs him to look for him in the courtyard the next morning. Under the watchful eye of Vietnamese guards, Fox works in the courtyard alongside Freeman (Jason Harper). Fox learns that Kelly is highly respected among the other prisoners and that he has been instrumental in keeping up morale. Later Fox spies Kelly nearby and works his way toward him. Kelly hands him a makeshift American flag that he has pieced together from various bits of cloth as a symbol of hope. But their meeting is short-lived when the Lead Vietnamese Guard (Anh Nguyen) breaks them up and takes hold of Kelly. Kelly is beaten for conversing with the other prisoners and is later returned to his cell. Fox, encouraged by the flag thanks his new friend. Kelly simply asks him to share it with the others within the compound. After months of secretly passing the flag among their comrades, Fox once again obtains it and makes a move to pass it to Freeman during their morning duties in the courtyard. The Lead Vietnamese discovers their prize and begins to angrily question them about who made it. Kelly runs forward, confessing to the guard that he is responsible. And to the horror of Freeman and Fox, their friend is executed before their very eyes. Later, Freeman is moved to the cell once occupied by Kelly and is encouraged when Fox begins to communicate with him from the other side of the wall. With their future uncertain, Fox holds on to the hope Kelly instilled within them all and in his memory begins to stitch together a new flag.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?558231</url></doc>
