<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="559207">
  <docid>559207</docid>
  <title>The French Spy</title>
  <year>1912</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">17 June 1912</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Trimble, Laurence</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Brooke, Van Dyke</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Humphrey, William (I)</actor>
      <role>An Arabian Chieftain</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Morey, Harry T.</actor>
      <role>An Arab Leader</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shea, William (IV)</actor>
      <role>A Whirling Dervish</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Williams, Earle</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Young, James (I)</actor>
      <role>Colonel Birnelli</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>General Derimond, with his wife and daughter, Mathilde, are captured by pirates. The pirate captain claims Mrs. Derimond as his property. She resists. She is forced to walk the plank, and drowned. Mathilde is struck dumb by the sight. The General and Mathilde are sold as slaves to the Moors. Mathilde escapes and accomplishes her father's rescue. Colonel Birnell, a French officer, marries Mathilde. He starts to the front at the head of his regiment. Disguised as a French lancer, she accompanies him. Mohammed, the Arab Chief, is captured by the French. He attempts to shoot the Colonel and is prevented by Mathilde piercing the Arab's arm with her sabre. She volunteers to go as a French spy. She reaches the enemy's fortress, disguised as a harmless Arab boy, and allowed to remain with them. SOURCE: newpspaper advertisement (Nov.12,1912) In battle, the Arabs take Colonel Birnell prisoner. He is placed in the fortress. He suffers torture rather than betray the French army. Mathilde, as previously instructed, shoots a flaming arrow high in the air. It is the signal for the attack. The French forces burst into the fortress, routing the Arabs with great slaughter, saving Mathilde and her husband.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?559207</url></doc>
