<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="559536">
  <docid>559536</docid>
  <title>The Future of Food</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Gilliam, Vivien Hillgrove</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">27 September 2005</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">14 September 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">88</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Koons, Deborah</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Jones, Molly (I)</producer>
    <producer>Maamouri, Sara</producer>
    <producer>Needham, Sara</producer>
    <producer>Needham, Sara E.</producer>
    <producer>Spurlock, Morgan</producer>
    <producer>Butler, Catherine Lynn</producer>
    <producer>Koons, Deborah</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Koons, Deborah</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Boekelheide, Todd</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>THE FUTURE OF FOOD offers an in-depth investigation into the disturbing truth behind the unlabeled, patented, genetically engineered foods that have quietly filled U.S. grocery store shelves for the past decade. From the prairies of Saskatchewan, Canada to the fields of Oaxaca, Mexico, this film gives a voice to farmers whose lives and livelihoods have been negatively impacted by this new technology. The health implications, government policies and push towards globalization are all part of the reason why many people are alarmed about the introduction of genetically altered crops into our food supply. Shot on location in the U.S., Canada and Mexico, The Future of Food examines the complex web of market and political forces that are changing what we eat as huge multinational corporations seek to control the world's food system. The film also explores alternatives to large-scale industrial agriculture, placing organic and sustainable agriculture as real solutions to the farm crisis today. The Future of Food reveals that there is a revolution going on in the farm fields and on the dinner tables of America, a revolution that is transforming the very nature of the food we eat.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?559536</url></doc>
