<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="560013">
  <docid>560013</docid>
  <title>The General Electric College Bowl</title>
  <year>1959</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Game-Show</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>non-fiction</keyword>
    <keyword>college</keyword>
    <keyword>company-sponsor-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">TV-G</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">8 March 1959</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Hultgren, Bob</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Cleary, John (I)</producer>
    <producer>Moses, John (IV)</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bellairs, John</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brandt, Mel</actor>
      <role>Announcer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Earle, Robert (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself - Host</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Earle, Robert (II)</actor>
      <role>Host (1962-1970)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ludden, Allen</actor>
      <role>Host (1959-1962)</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"College Bowl" began as a radio series, with Allen Ludden (best known for hosting "Password") as host. He continued his hosting duties when the series moved to television. Two four-member teams, each representing a college or university, competed; one was a returning champion. Ludden read a toss-up question (usually difficult) rooted in the liberal arts; subjects ranged from mathematics and science, engineering, literature, law and history to physics, music, philosophy, journalism and much more. Correct answers allowed the team to answer multiple-part bonus questions (which could involve the use of maps, graphs and sound-bites of music and famous speeches); control passed to the other team for any incorrect question. Each game lasted 24 minutes, divided in halves; between halves, a short film promoting the challenging team's university was played. The winning team at the end of the game won $1,500 for their school's scholarship fund, while losing teams won $500 (the stakes would increase by the end of the show's run). Winning teams could stay for up to five weeks, at which point they won a special trophy. Local stations often aired "High School Bowl," a high-school adaptation of "College Bowl" with four-member teams from local high schools competing in an otherwise identical format. Ludden left the show in the Summer of 1962 to do "Password," and was replaced by Robert Earle. The show moved from CBS to NBC the following year, and began broadcasting in color.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?560013</url></doc>
