<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="560999">
  <docid>560999</docid>
  <title>The Glass House</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Rahmanian, Hamid</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>drug-addiction</keyword>
    <keyword>human-rights</keyword>
    <keyword>women</keyword>
    <keyword>children</keyword>
    <keyword>middle-east</keyword>
    <keyword>rap</keyword>
    <keyword>youth</keyword>
    <keyword>iran</keyword>
    <keyword>abuse</keyword>
    <keyword>charity</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Persian</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby</soundmix>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Iran</country>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 September 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">92</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Rahmanian, Hamid</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hibbard, Melissa (III)</producer>
    <producer>Mark, Ari</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Hibbard, Melissa (III)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Bergeaud, David</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>The fringes of Iranian society can be a lonely place, especially if you are a teenage girl with few resources to fall back on. Finding Home follows four girls striving to pull themselves out of the margins by attending a one-of-kind rehabilitation center in uptown Tehran. Forget about the Iran that you've seen before. With a virtually invisible camera, the girls of Finding Home take us on a never-before-seen tour of the underclass of Iran with their brave and defiant stories: Samira struggles to overcome forced drug addiction; Mitra harnesses abandonment into her creative writing; Sussan teeters on a dangerous ledge after years of sexual abuse; and Nazila burgeons out of her hatred with her blazing rap music. This groundbreaking documentary reflects a side of Iran few have access to or paid attention to: a society lost to its traditions with nothing meaningful to replace them and a group of courageous women working to instill a sense of empowerment and hope into the minds and lives of otherwise discarded teenage girls.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?560999</url></doc>
