<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="561142">
  <docid>561142</docid>
  <title>The Goblin Man of Norway</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Cheel, Jay</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">24 October 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">24</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Cheel, Jay</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Llewellyn, Sean</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Cheel, Jay</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Byl, Katie</actor>
      <role>Roboticist #3</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cox, Terrance</actor>
      <role>Lawrence Dixon</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Evans, Dave (XXI)</actor>
      <role>Mark Hoyt</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Foley, Joe (III)</actor>
      <role>Roboticist #4</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jackowski, Zack</actor>
      <role>Roboticist #5</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lilienkamp, Katie</actor>
      <role>Roboticist #3</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Meyer, Nils</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Niosi, Robert</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Roberts, John (XXXVI)</actor>
      <role>Roboticist #1</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shaw, Ian (V)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tedrake, Russ</actor>
      <role>Roboticist #2</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>When a mechanical humanoid is found buried deep within the Norwegian ice, a team of scientists and professors debate the consequences of embracing a technology that could change the world forever. The "Goblin Man" baffles experts and sparks a wave of wild speculation across the globe. Some believe it is a creature described in ancient Scandinavian mythology, while others are convinced it is evidence of a long lost, scientifically advanced society. As the academic and scientific communities clash over the moral implications of reconstructing an alien technology, curiosity surrounding the mysterious being intensifies in the popular media. While Roboticists struggle to understand and integrate the new-found technology into modern civilization, philosophers and conspiracy theorists expose what they claim is an attempt to cover up a doomsday message, warning of the deadly potential of the mysterious artifact. Meanwhile, the "Goblin Man of Norway" museum exhibit tours the world in a controversial attempt to profit from one of history's most sensational archaeological finds. Could it be a piece of ancient weaponry? Does the 'Goblin Man' truly hold connections to the Norse myths? Or is it simply a hoax, perpetuated by the popular media?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?561142</url></doc>
