<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="561503">
  <docid>561503</docid>
  <title>The Gomorrah Club</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>debauchery</keyword>
    <keyword>sex</keyword>
    <keyword>club</keyword>
    <keyword>adult</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="UK">R18</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">14 November 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">119</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>B'gunne, Hazza</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hadley, Andy 'Roody'</producer>
    <producer>B'gunne, Hazza</producer>
    <producer>Jasperado</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>May, Jimi</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Bogstar, Dadda</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Capri (II)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cheryl (I)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cipher, Lou</actor>
      <role>The Man in the Mask</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Demetri (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Donna-Marie</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hooper, Steve (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Katalin (III)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Law, Lucy</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pk (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tracy, Brett</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Relish cordially invite you to slip into the Gomorrah, a saucy underground club set in the throbbing heart of London, where acts of debauchery are common place and fornicating members are always on show. Join the man in the mask, the demented ringmaster, as he leads our intrepid reporter Ashley on a titillating journey into the secret society of the Gomorrah people. The Initiation: In the main audience chamber, the Man in the Mask unveils a new member who is hoping to join the ranks of the Gomorrah; but under the watchful eye of the other club members can he withstand the trial? Two's company, three's an orgy: Having had her eyes well and truly opened by the initiation, Ashley takes her leave of the main audience chamber and sets about exploring the rest of the club. She enters one bedchamber to find two masked maidens teasing one lucky member out of his black tie. Ashley takes a seat in the corner and begins to take stock of the situation as the secrets of the Gomorrah begin to be revealed. Desire for the Sire: A beautiful blindfolded lady has been sprinkled with the dust of lust and demands to be sated by the Man in the Mask. Unable to wait patiently, she feasts impatiently on a voluptuous young vixen under the master's all seeing eye. Sodomy In Gomorrah: The Man in the Mask deals with an unhappy member of staff by paying him his wages in kind. When one of the most trusted of the Gomorrah girls is summoned, there is no looking back and all debts are off as the magic of the club envelops them. Gomorrah always comes: Having resisted all the urges and sexual tests set, Ashley makes her excuses and leaves the club. Thinking that she has made it home with her pride in tact, she comes across a tramp being abused by a man in black tie. Unbeknown to her, this is in fact her final test and back at her apartment she finally succumbs to the Gomorrah's power; failing magnificently with both of them! So dust off the dinner jacket, accept this invitation for cocktails and nipples and join the masquerade ~ remember, if you can't get pleasure today, there's always Gomorrah.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?561503</url></doc>
