<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="561779">
  <docid>561779</docid>
  <title>The Gospel Blimp</title>
  <year>1967</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bushelman, John A.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>gospel</keyword>
    <keyword>religion</keyword>
    <keyword>satire</keyword>
    <keyword>commander</keyword>
    <keyword>christian</keyword>
    <keyword>evangelism</keyword>
    <keyword>voice-over-narration</keyword>
    <keyword>based-on-book</keyword>
    <keyword>christianity</keyword>
    <keyword>neighbor</keyword>
    <keyword>blimp</keyword>
    <keyword>evangelical</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <directors>
    <director>Yeaworth Jr., Irvin S.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Yeaworth Jr., Irvin S.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bayly, Joseph</writer>
    <writer>Nelson, Rudy</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bubar, Paul</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>O'Donnell, Bob (VI)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>George and Ethel are concerned about the salvation of their next-door neighbors, but don't know how to reach them with the good news of Jesus Christ. During an evening get-together of George and Ethel's Christian friends, everyone is captivated by the sight of a blimp flying overhead. Then Herm gets a bright idea: why not use a blimp to proclaim the Christian message to the unchurched citizens of Middletown? The group incorporates, buys a used blimp, hires a pilot, then commences to evangelize their hometown by towing Bible-verse banners, 'firebombing' folks below with gospel tracts, and broadcasting Christian music and programs over loudspeakers. But a series of misadventures puts the blimp ministry in jeopardy. And George becomes increasingly uneasy about the methods and business practices of International Gospel Blimps Incorporated and its "Commander", Herm. Do the personal sacrifices made by the group's members justify the results? And will George and Ethel's next-door neighbors ever receive the gospel message?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?561779</url></doc>
