<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="561887">
  <docid>561887</docid>
  <title>The Grand Era</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Brown, Les (VIII)</editor>
    <editor>Taormina, Angel</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>History</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>French</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>France</country>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">29</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="USA">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Taormina, Angel</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Taormina, Angel</producer>
    <producer>Taormina, Angel</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Taormina, Angel</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>"The Grand Era" focuses on the major influences that shaped the era in the fields of architecture, literature, art, religion, music, and everyday life. It discusses the importance of French national pride and their passion for preserving history. Parisians never tired, even in the face of war and revolution, from rebuilding and restoring those things that were close to their hearts. The mindset of the Grand Era was that history was to be learned from so that everything new could be created to be better. It was an age of admirable work ethic, trailblazing creativity, shocking intellectualism, and the notion of liberty, equality, fraternity - a peasant could sip tea with a king, and a barmaid could share wall space with Venus. The Grand Era ushered in a new way of life and introduced new terms into our artistic textbooks- Impressionism, Grand Opera, Romanticism, Realism. The Grand Era inspired people all over the world and, due to the spirit of Parisian preservation, continues to inspire and influence people and places internationally to this day. Visit Paris, and you will not only see Paris as it is in 2009- you will see the Grand Era of 1830-1890 alive and thriving in every breath of the City of Love. Beauty. History. Romance. Paris. The Grand Era - yesterday, today, and forever.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?561887</url></doc>
