<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="562821">
  <docid>562821</docid>
  <title>The Grind</title>
  <year>1992</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Asencio Sutphen, Stacy</actor>
      <role>Dancer (1992-1993)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Campanaro, Anthony</actor>
      <role>Dancer (1995)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Como, Natalie</actor>
      <role>Dancer (1992-1993)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fields, Melissa</actor>
      <role>Dancer (1993-1996)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Flora, Danielle</actor>
      <role>Dancer (1993-1995)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gertz, Brandon Marcel</actor>
      <role>Lead Dancer (1993-1996)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gifford, Kenneth</actor>
      <role>Dancer (1992-1995)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hernandez, Asia</actor>
      <role>Dancer (1993-1996)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lacko, Danielle</actor>
      <role>Dancer (1992-1996)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mateo, Aileen</actor>
      <role>Dancer (1992-1994 - 1995-1996)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nies, Eric</actor>
      <role>Himself/Host</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pierrelouis, Rich</actor>
      <role>Dancer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stark, Ian (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wiggins, Anthony (I)</actor>
      <role>Dancer (1992-1996)</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>After Club MTV was canceled in 1992, it was replaced by "The Grind" which was a more hip hop oriented dance show than Club MTV. Several dancers from Club MTV later moved on to this show. The music played was rap, R&amp;B, hip hop and occasionally alternative. The show was first apart of Hangin w/MTV and was hosted by Eric Nies before it turned into it's own show and was called "The Grind" in the fall of 1992. The Grind would also have several outdoor tapings during the summer months instead of only during Spring Break.. The show was taped at several different resorts ranging from Lake Havasu, Miami, Hawaii, and Las Vegas. Eric Nies left the show as host in 1995 and was replaced by various special guest hosts. In 1996 the show was revamped and stopped playing mainstream music and opted for underground dance, house, and club music. The show lasted until 1997 and after months of runreuns was once again revamped greatly and all the regular dancers from 1992-1996 were no longer featured. It was shortly let go from MTV's lineup in late 1997 and no other similar dance show has since aired on MTV.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?562821</url></doc>
