<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="564743">
  <docid>564743</docid>
  <title>The Hollow Tree</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Stuart-Pontier, Zachary</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">G</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">4 October 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">28</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Steward, Patrick (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Renfro, Beth</producer>
    <producer>Steward, Patrick (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Steward, Patrick (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Sheffer, Jonathan</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barnett, Bill (II)</actor>
      <role>Mr. Von Vitter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bryan, Ashley (II)</actor>
      <role>Diana</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Courtney, Alex (I)</actor>
      <role>Wolfincrass</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grant, Carson</actor>
      <role>Basil</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hyman, Bari</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Von Vitter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jahnke, Justin</actor>
      <role>Timmy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Uczkowski, Dariusz M.</actor>
      <role>David Wolfincrass</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Uczkowski, Jan</actor>
      <role>Timmy</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The Hollow Tree is the touching story of a boy finding his way in life by listening to a tale about a brother and sister who lose their way in a haunted forest. Timothy runs away from home after refusing to move away. He stumbles upon an old bookshop, finding the mysterious and eccentric shopkeeper Wolfincrass. Every person has a book which is only meant for them, says Wolfincrass, who sets about finding Timothy's story. What he finds is The Hollow Tree and he leads Timothy into a world beyond his wildest imagination, following the story of orphaned brother and sister Lizzy and David, and their quest to find Home. Lizzy and David, along with their trusty beagle, Henry, escape from the Thornwall Orphanage for Uncommonly Regrettable Children and the vile clutches of Madam Stagmire. They find themselves lost in Odin Forest, where they are not alone; mysterious and sinister wolves are chasing them on their journey through the forest. Just when Lizzy and David have reached their most desperate moment of need, they find the Hollow Tree. But the forest isn't done with the pair as they press on in their pursuit of Home. With Wolfincrass' guidance, Timothy learns about his own quest for Home, and more about his mysterious benefactor.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?564743</url></doc>
