<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="566031">
  <docid>566031</docid>
  <title>The Immigrants</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bonilla, Andre</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">29 April 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">13</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Thomas, Glenn (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Geller, Jacob</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Thomas, Glenn (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Farris, Kyle</actor>
      <role>William Sina</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gould, Geoffrey</actor>
      <role>Jasper Cuthbert</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Latzer, Josh</actor>
      <role>Soda Jerk</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tucker, Jim (IX)</actor>
      <role>Harold Brandstetter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Varga, Richard</actor>
      <role>Jonathan Ryder</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In the late 21st Century, the United States has been transformed into an oppressive, totalitarian regime bent on the total submission of its citizens who, out of desperation, continually search for new and clever ways of escaping their plight and to seek a better place in which to live out their lives. It is a dark time of mind control and genetically engineered telepathics. The most innovative means by which the dissidents have found to escape, is through a portal in time, traveling to a chosen era when/where freedom actually meant something to its leaders. With the help of the Resistance movement, the "immigrants" secretly slip out of their home-time and settle in different parts of American history in order to live out their lives peacefully. The government becomes alerted to their operation and sends the secret police, the "Peacekeepers" to intercept and annihilate them. Our story begins when a mother and her young son enter a pharmacy in 1947 New York to fill a prescription. Little do we realize that the course of history is about to change drastically in the next few hours. She is Mia Sina, an unassuming immigrant from 2059 who has brought her son with her and seeks her contact in this year. Mia is greeted by the pharmacist, Dr. Cuthbert and is later horrified to discover that he is an agent from her own time...a Peacekeeper. She is caught and under duress, reveals her true motives: she is actually an agent from the Resistance, on a mission to change history...to stop the Socialists at its inception. However, things are never quite what they appear to be as mother and son work together to free themselves and complete the mission.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?566031</url></doc>
