<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="566345">
  <docid>566345</docid>
  <title>The Industry</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Durnford, Bridget</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>country-music</keyword>
    <keyword>series</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">4 July 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">184</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Cairns, Richard</director>
    <director>Durnford, Bridget</director>
    <director>Lehmann, Lars</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bowman, Rob (V)</writer>
    <writer>Lehmann, Lars</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Follows the new career of country music artist Aaron Lines, and probes what it takes to be a "star" in the music industry. Interviews with major country stars, managers, record company executives, publicists, media consultants, producers and others involved in the music business provide a look. Part 1 - THE SIGNING begins with an unsigned act and chronicles the A&amp;R process up until the signing by the artist of a major recording contract. We talk to record company executives as they prepare to offer contracts to a new artist, and we artist as they contemplate their future, and what the support of a major record label will mean, and the responsibilities involved. We will also discuss this phase of career development with established managers, artists and other music industry veterans. Part 2 - THE STUDIO picks up from signing - through the writing process and to the completion of the recorded CD. We are behind the scenes as the artist and the record label work through the music selection and choosing of a producer. We watch the dynamic and stress filled recording process happens. We will talk with well known record producers and engineers about working with a new artist, and talk to established artists about their first experiences in the studio. Part 3 - THE PUBLICITY MACHINE tells the story of the marketing and selling of the new artist and their debut CD. From the perspective of the artist, record company, marketing people, and any "image" testing that is done will be followed. We talk with well known artists about the process of packaging and marketing, as well as image consultants and media trainers. There are a lot of pitfalls to avoid, and stories of good experiences as well. We watch record company executives and the artist work to create a "buzz", hoping to translate their energy into radio and video airplay, and eventually, sales of the "product" as the CD is released to retail outlets. Part 4 - THE BIG DEBUT is the work that happens after strategy has been set. We watch the artist prepare for and go through their first tour with record company support, all of the promotion, radio visits, charting, and other work that need to be done to make a new release a success. Established artists will comment on the process as we watch the new artist go through a hectic schedule of working all day and night to impress radio across North America and their audience. We will follow and document the record company and managements reactions and strategies in this most important phase. A lot of money has been spent to this point, and now it is "make or break". Will the artist connect with the audience? Will they be able to sell records in sufficient numbers to validate the record company's faith in their "star" quality?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?566345</url></doc>
