<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="568477">
  <docid>568477</docid>
  <title>The King's Procession</title>
  <year>1902</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>ceremony</keyword>
    <keyword>king</keyword>
    <keyword>king-edward-vii</keyword>
    <keyword>royalty</keyword>
    <keyword>royal-family</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">30 August 1902</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
<plot>Motion picture films of the coronation of King Edward VII, which took place on August 9th, 1902, were ready for delivery from our factory at Orange, N. J., on the 18th the Monday, next following. A cablegram from our special photographers in London on August 9th, 1902, advised us that they had secured the complete pictures on that day, that the pictures were sent to Queenstown, and placed on board the fast steamship "Umbria" of the Cunard Line, Sailing Sunday, August 10th, 1902. Thus we were enabled to receive the coronation films in America at least three days in advance of mail matter which was posted in London on the day of the coronation. Remember we had the exclusive right of kinetographing the ceremonies at Westminister Abbey, and our pictures were not only the first to arrive in America, but they were the only authentic views. ORDER OF THE PROCESSION. An Office, Headquarters Staff (Lt.-Col. J. S. Cowans, D.A.Q.M.G.) Advanced Guard of Sovereign's Escort (1st Life Guards.) The King's Barge Master and twelve Watermen. Dress Carriages and Pairs conveying the Household of their Majesties. FIRST CARRIAGE. The Hon. Sidney Greville, C.V.O., Groom-in-Waiting, and two Maids of Honour. SECOND CARRIAGE. Lord Knollys, G.C.V.O., Private Secretary to the King. General the Right Hon. Sir D.M. Probyn, V.C., G.C.V.O., Keeper of the Privy Purse. Viscount Valentia, C.B., M.V.O., Comptroller of the Household. Victor Cavendish, Esq., M.P., Treasurer of the Household. THIRD CARRIAGE. The Viscount Colville of Culross, K.T., G.C.V.O., Lord Chamberlain to the Queen. General Lord Chelmsford, G.C.B., Gold Stick-in-Waiting. Admiral Sir M. Culme-Seymour, Bt., G.C.B., Vice-Admiral of the United Kingdom. The Hon. Charlotte Knollys, Woman of the Bedchamber. FOURTH CARRIAGE. The Viscount Churchill, K.C.V.O., the Acting Lord Chamberlain. The Earl of Pembroke and Montgomery, G.C.V.O., the Lord Steward. The Lady of the Bedchamber. the Duchess of Buccleuch, Mistress of the Robes. Personal Staff to the Commander-in-Chief, viz: Major W. H. Sherston, D.S.O., Major Hon. G. J. Goschen, Captain Hon. H. Dawney, D.S.O., Captain Lord Fitzmaurice. Brevet Lieut.-Colonel H. Streatfield. The Aides-de-Camp to the King. General Viscount Kitchener. HEADQUARTERS STAFF OF THE ARMY. Field-Marshal Right Hon. the Earl Roberts, V.C., K.G., K.P., Commander-in-Chief, His Majesty's Marshalmen. Twenty-five Yeomen of the Guard.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?568477</url></doc>
