<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="568759">
  <docid>568759</docid>
  <title>The Label</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Fox, Ariel (IV)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>label</keyword>
    <keyword>rap</keyword>
    <keyword>hip-hop</keyword>
    <keyword>gangsta</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">R</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">8 May 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">110</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Silva, Nick</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ezra, Issac</producer>
    <producer>Kafka, Chaim</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Miller, Yves</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dash, Nick</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hines, Mo</actor>
      <role>Co-Defendent</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jett, Jason</actor>
      <role>Rick Kozar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Patel, Hash</actor>
      <role>Hash - Club Promoter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Silva, Nick</actor>
      <role>Big Mack Money</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A murdered federal witness, a dirty cop, allegations of money laundering, extortion and fraud. Just another day in the life at the label. Watch it all dramatically unfold, as the hip-hop cops launch an investigation and discover that the man they are chasing is the CEO of a hip-hop record label. Nick Silva stars as "Big" Mack "Money", the CEO of Sinsistar Records. Mack and his sexy and deadly Lieutenant, Star (Fia Roan) make a name for themselves by saturating the streets with underground rap and "keeping it gangsta." The Label's extraordinary sales numbers soon catch the eye of Suncoast Records A&amp;R Rep, Rick Kozar (brilliantly played by Jason Jett), who inks Mack to a multi-million dollar distribution deal. The label's quick rise to the top also attracts the interest from local and federal law enforcement and a secret federal hip-hop task force launches an investigation. They work night and day to monitor and infiltrate Mack's organization. Rising to superstar hip-hop status has its good days and its bad. Fake players and snitches clamor to take Sinistar Records out. Haters and feds try to play Mack. They're all about to learn a hard lesson: "He aint' the one." "The Label," is a startling behind -the-scens expose' of the hip-hop industry that keeps it krunk, gangster, and is definitely ballin' out of control.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?568759</url></doc>
