<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="569255">
  <docid>569255</docid>
  <title>The Last Chapter</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Farias, Paco</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>plot-twist</keyword>
    <keyword>intrigue</keyword>
    <keyword>greed</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby SR</soundmix>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">9 August 2005</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">11 November 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">10</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Horn, Douglas</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Siner, Joseph</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Siner, Jason</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Schloemer, Martin</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bernardy, Gil</actor>
      <role>TJ</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Donahue, Jamie</actor>
      <role>Rebecca</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Heyborne, Kirby</actor>
      <role>Jonathan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Siner, Jason</actor>
      <role>Artie</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Jonathan, a workaholic writer, is feverishly typing away at his computer, when his wife Rebecca pleads that they need to take a vacation. He brushes her off, reminding her that he has a deadline to meet and must finish his novel. Any further argument between the two is interrupted by a knock at the door. It's Artie, Jonathan's brother, a drifter who looks like he's been roughed up a bit. The brothers obviously are not comfortable with each other, and as soon as Rebecca leaves the room, an argument erupts between them. Artie begs Jonathan to pay off a huge gambling debt with the money he heard Jonathan just received for an advance on the novel. This is obviously not Artie's first financial misfortune and Jonathan balks at the huge sum Artie is asking him to fork over. Suddenly, as Jonathan tries to get Artie to leave, TJ bursts into the room holding Rebecca at gunpoint. The mean-looking thug states he's there to get the money Artie owes his boss. A scuffle ensues. Artie points a gun at Jonathan, Rebecca is dragged from the room by TJ, and everything goes down hill from there. However, all is not what it seems, as everyone involved in this violent affair has their own secret. These secrets are what very quickly bring about an end to this chaotic night, and for some, a very tragic last chapter...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?569255</url></doc>
