<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="569583">
  <docid>569583</docid>
  <title>The Last Man Club</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>veteran</keyword>
    <keyword>wwii</keyword>
    <keyword>hero</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Brinkman, Bo</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Mead, Gary R.</producer>
    <producer>Manchester, Bunnie</producer>
    <producer>LaRocco, Russell</producer>
    <producer>Yamin, Calvin</producer>
    <producer>D'Orazio, Gina</producer>
    <producer>Schwenker, Ken</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Brinkman, Bo</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Durning, Charles</actor>
      <role>John 'Eagle Eye' Pennell</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Discarded and forgotten, Pete Williams is living out his days in an old soldiers home in Galveston, Texas. Knowing his end is near, he puts out the call to his old comrade, John "Eagle Eye" Pennell. Eagle is facing his own living hell 3,000 miles away in New Jersey. He has become an inconvenient obstacle to his work-a-holic son, and lost all remaining freedoms, except the valued time he spends with his grandson. Now even that joy will be stripped away as his son prepares to place him in a nursing home. Imprisoned and depressed Pete's letter gives Eagle rekindled spirit. Stripped of his driving privileges for years, and with failing eye sight, Eagle steals away in his late wife's old Lincoln and heads cross-country to Pete's rescue. Enroute, Eagle reluctantly comes to the aid of Romy, a sassy moll who has just stolen 600 her life. Romy jumps on board with Eagle, and takes command, as the pair rescue each other in a tense and action-packed scene. Romy dispenses orders like a drill sergeant as they scramble southwest to round up the last two surviving members of Eagle's WWII, B-17 bomber crew. The ragtag crew battle their way to Galveston, with the mob and authorities in close pursuit, and an uncertain destiny awaiting them.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?569583</url></doc>
