<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="569771">
  <docid>569771</docid>
  <title>The Last Roundup</title>
  <year>1943</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>elevator</keyword>
    <keyword>airplane</keyword>
    <keyword>skeleton</keyword>
    <keyword>beer-barrel</keyword>
    <keyword>wwii</keyword>
    <keyword>gandy-goose</keyword>
    <keyword>william-tell-overture</keyword>
    <keyword>artillery</keyword>
    <keyword>slingshot</keyword>
    <keyword>cemetery</keyword>
    <keyword>germany</keyword>
    <keyword>hitler</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">15 March 1943</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">6</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Davis, Mannie</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Terry, Paul (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Foster, John (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Scheib, Philip A.</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Gandy Goose is helping test artillery by putting an apple on his head (to a swinging version of the William Tell Overture). The first shell is spot on. He backs up against a tree, and this shell comes in low, sending Gandy through a whole line of trees. The "dud" explodes, and sends both Gandy and his sergeant rocketing into the air. They land in a haystack; when all the insects greet them with "Heil", they figure out they're in Germany, conveniently near a piglike Hitler and his monkey, Mussolini. Our heroes cause mischief, first by lighting a map Hitler holding on fire, then by using a slingshot to hit Mussolini with a rock. They open fire, and Hitler ducks behind his desk to fire back with cannons. The continued attack sends the dictators to the elevator, and our heroes follow in the next car (down, up, and sideways). Throughout the mansion, whereever the dictators go, our heroes are there to greet them with a variety of guns. Finally, they are cornered in a storage cellar; our heroes send barrels of beer after the dictators, then blow the place up, escaping on an airplane with one of the barrels. The dictators land in a cemetery, where the skeletons pop out of the ground with "Heil" and our heroes hoist mugs of beer.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?569771</url></doc>
