<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="572148">
  <docid>572148</docid>
  <title>The Long Ranger</title>
  <year>1987</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adult</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>sex</keyword>
    <keyword>hardcore</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">X</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <directors>
    <director>Robertson, Joseph F.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Robertson, Joseph F.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Sayer, Steve (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Butler, Jerry (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Curtis, Tami Lee</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harris, Brandon (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Keisha (I)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Savage, Herschel</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Despite the absence of masked men and silver bullets, this hearty, good-natured film is actually a vehicle for the talented ladies who star. Charmer Cyndie Summers owns a vacation hotel catering to lonely women in search of men. Having had the misfortune of catching her husband, Herschel Savage, in bed with one of the resort's boarders, she handily evicts him and arbitrarily bans all men from the premises. The horny, desperate women staying at the hotel are faced with a dilemma. With no available men they must resort to each other's affections while exchanging lusty tales of sexual conquest to warm their long nights. Rocki Rio, Sheri St. Claire and Tami Lee Curtis amuse each other with an over sized ball vibrator pleasuring each others bodies into intense rapture! Sitting on the patio in the cool of the evening, the delectable Rocki Rio (Played by Keisha) envisions herself as the woman cavorting with Herschel while Sheri St. Claire regales of how she seduced her cowboy stud (Jerry Butler) in the garden and rode him hard. Next up, the delightful blonde temptress Tami Lee Curtis reincarnates a vigorous 3-way sex triad she once had with Rocki and the generously endowed Brandon Harris. Meanwhile, a repentant Herschel confronts wife Cyndee while bathing and pleads for her forgiveness subsequently joining her in the suds for a frothy climax.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?572148</url></doc>
