<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="573273">
  <docid>573273</docid>
  <title>The Mad, the Bad &amp; the Ugly</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Duffield, Benjamin</editor>
    <editor>Fortin, Guillaume (I)</editor>
    <editor>Ilkow, Annie</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>French</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">31 March 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Duffield, Benjamin</director>
    <director>Gagnon, Philippe (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Nadeau, Jacques</producer>
    <producer>Normandeau, Josette D.</producer>
    <producer>Birla, Abhish S.</producer>
    <producer>Normandeau, Josette D.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Kalina, Jon</writer>
    <writer>Lepage, Jean-François</writer>
    <writer>Normandeau, Josette D.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Lemay, Alexis</composer>
    <composer>Motard, Michèle</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arcand, Bernard</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barney, Darin</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brown, Timothy Leo</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hirsch, Pierro</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kalina, Jon</actor>
      <role>Himself - Narrator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Krupa, Mark Antony</actor>
      <role>Mad Bad Ugly Driver</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Monderman, Hans</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Saad, Gad</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Thiffault, Pierre</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wiesenthal, David L.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The state of the urban roads seems to be getting worse and worse. Although a large part of the problem is the marketing of automobiles where the perception of the open road rarely matches reality, bad drivers are the major cause of the problem. Three main types make up the bulk of bad drivers: the reckless driver, generally the typical alpha-male aged 18 to 26, who sees himself as king of the road who wants the thrill with little regard for the risk, either to himself or others; the careless driver, often doing other things while driving such as speaking on a cell phone, who acts without thinking; and the mad driver, whose day to day stress is transferred to his/her driving behavior. As these types are inherent in people and unlikely to change, other factors need to change to deal with these problems. Three different trends are emerging: having greater enforcement of regulations and more stringent penalties for breaking the regulations; having smart technologies take the human factor out of mechanized mobility; and the old-fashioned idea of the shared road space, which removes all traffic regulations in urban areas to force drivers to pay more attention to all else happening around them, whether it be the actions of other drivers, cyclists or pedestrians. Each of these three trends has its positive and negative aspects.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?573273</url></doc>
