<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="573466">
  <docid>573466</docid>
  <title>The Magic Sword</title>
  <year>1901</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>witch</keyword>
    <keyword>rescue</keyword>
    <keyword>knight</keyword>
    <keyword>sword</keyword>
    <keyword>male-female-relationship</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">1901</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">May 1902</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">2</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Booth, Walter R.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Paul, Robert W.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Booth, Walter R.</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>On the roof of an ancient palace appear a young Knight and his lady. While they are making love an ugly old witch appears and is rather troublesome. The Knight commands her to leave, and when about to force her away she sits on her broom and rises to the moon. After disappearing she causes various hob-goblins to haunt the pair, the last of them stealing away the lady while the Knight's back is turned. The Knight, frantic with grief, is suddenly confronted by a Fairy, who presents him with a magical sword, and tells him that he can use it to regain the young woman. He suddenly disappears from the scene and is next shown in the witch's cave, where he sees his lady. He recovers her and as he is about to lead her away the witch appears, and snatching the sword from the scabbard attempts to strike the pair, when the good Fairy appears and stops her. The young Knight and lady are then wedded and the wedding repast is served. At the end of the dinner the Fairy is again shown, and taking the sword mysteriously disappears. Very mystifying.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?573466</url></doc>
