<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="574247">
  <docid>574247</docid>
  <title>The Making of Daniel Boone</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Trahan, Mike</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>director</keyword>
    <keyword>alamo</keyword>
    <keyword>expert</keyword>
    <keyword>producer</keyword>
    <keyword>screenwriter</keyword>
    <keyword>mockumentary</keyword>
    <keyword>frontier</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">9 February 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">88</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Wilkins, Randall D.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Brown, Clancy (I)</producer>
    <producer>Hancock, Edward (I)</producer>
    <producer>Wilkins, Randall D.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Wilkins, Randall D.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Humecke, Tony</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Alexander, Kirk (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brown, Clancy (I)</actor>
      <role>Allan Kenton</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Burch, Jesse (I)</actor>
      <role>Max</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Da Silva, Goreti</actor>
      <role>Sheila Parks</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Doctor, Gina</actor>
      <role>Stacey</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gegenhuber, John</actor>
      <role>Benjamin Logan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Goren, Jay</actor>
      <role>Josh Katz</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Janosi, Peter</actor>
      <role>Alex Mckee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Robinson, Andrew (I)</actor>
      <role>Timothy Flint</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Best-selling author and noted history professor Allan Kenton, is realizing a dream. His recent biography on the life of Daniel Boone is being made into a major motion picture. Long wary of Hollywood's idea of historical accuracy, he has avoided selling off the rights until he can be convinced someone will do justice to his book and history. Producer Timothy Flint, convinces him he's just the man to bring the truth to life. Little does Allan know, Flint, has nothing of the sort in mind and has involved the author directly in the film only at the insistence of the actor he's seeking for the role of Boone, John Steel. As a documentary crew follows Allan during the pre-production of the film, despite constant reassurances from associate producer Allison Crawford, it becomes obvious he has made a very, very bad choice. Timothy's efforts to keep the truth from Allan are made even more complicated by the screenwriter Benjamin Logan, who continuously mixes up Daniel Boone with Davy Crockett; and by the new director, Max, who stresses the importance of not being 'constrained by historical facts.' Allan begins to see the proverbial writing-on-the-wall and starts to see his reputation in the academic world disintegrating before his eyes. Based on a number of real events the writer experienced in over 15 years in the film industry, The Making of Daniel Boone is an insider's look into the making of a big-budget historical film.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?574247</url></doc>
