<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="574207">
  <docid>574207</docid>
  <title>The Making of 'Triumph of the Spirit'</title>
  <year>1990</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Pollack, Dean</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>1980s</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-short</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">April 1990</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Lewis, Tom (III)</director>
    <director>Pollack, Dean</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kopelson, Evan</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dafoe, Willem</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kopelson, Arnold</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Loggia, Robert</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Olmos, Edward James</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Young, Robert M. (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In the dead of winter of 1989, a small contingent of filmmakers and movie stars trekked deep into communist Poland to the infamous Auschwitz/Birkenau Death camp and began filming the first ever Hollywood movie to be made on this hallowed ground. Starring Oscar winner Willem Dafoe along with Robert Loggia and Edward James Olmos, "Triumph of the Spirit" is the true story of Greek boxing champion Salamo Arouch's survival of the Holocaust. By boxing for the entertainment of the brutal SS officers who were his captors he was allowed to live while his losing opponents perished. Not merely a behind-the-scenes look into the nuts and bolts of film making, "The Making of 'Triumph of the Spirit'" takes you on a fascinating excursion with this dedicated yet displaced group of filmmakers. Struggling not only with long hours, sub-zero temperatures and isolation from the rest of the world, the cast and crew must daily cope with accurately and painfully recreating life in this most notorious of concentration camps. As they confront one of history's darkest periods with a camera, lights and movie magic, they also must take a journey within themselves, one that could never be scripted.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?574207</url></doc>
