<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="574647">
  <docid>574647</docid>
  <title>The Man Who Met Himself</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="France">20 May 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">9</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Crowe, Ben (IV)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Crowe, Ben (IV)</producer>
    <producer>Taneja, Preti</producer>
    <producer>Brown, James (XXV)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Crowe, Ben (IV)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Bartlett, Oliver</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brown, James (XXV)</actor>
      <role>The Client</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Crowe, Dan</actor>
      <role>Austin Peterson, Private Eye</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Donovan, Lucy (II)</actor>
      <role>Rachel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harrison, Siubhan</actor>
      <role>Faye</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hawkins, Silas</actor>
      <role>Mr. Maker</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lathan, Jennie</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Maker</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Trestain, Richard</actor>
      <role>Officer Bell</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wontner, Tom</actor>
      <role>Michael</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A mysterious call, a photograph of a man and a private detective compelled by the one case that has finally got to him. One stark but brilliant day in London, Austin Peterson takes a job from an anonymous client, a demand he knows he should refuse. He uses the feelings of the woman who loves him to get information. But this only raises more questions than it answers, leading Petersen deeper into the maze. He discovers that the man in the photograph committed suicide 4 years before, and haunted by the unanswered questions, he subjects the dead man's family and friends to his investigation. He finds a mother and father with an idealised view of their beloved son that is in sharp contrast to the memories of his devastated ex lover and friends. What happened to Stephen Maker? Did he fake his own death, or do doppelgangers really exist? Petersen concludes his report but cannot close the case. Desperate, he retraces his steps to the café where he started the investigation, and realises that he has been used to bear witness to the working out of a disturbed plan. One suicide is never the end of the story.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?574647</url></doc>
