<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="574649">
  <docid>574649</docid>
  <title>The Man Who Might Have Been: An Inquiry Into the Life and Death of Herbert Norman</title>
  <year>1999</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kazala, David</editor>
  </editors>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>death-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="France">19 January 1999</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Canada">7 October 1999</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">98</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Kramer, John (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Klinck, Elizabeth</producer>
    <producer>Flahive, Gerry</producer>
    <producer>Lore, Louise</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Kramer, John (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Korven, Mark</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Blanch, Frank</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Curwin, Derek</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dyck, Ernest</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ellwand, Greg</actor>
      <role>Herbert Norman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mininni, Lisa</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>O'Neill, Michael (IX)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Welsh, Kenneth</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>On April 4, 1957, Herbert Norman, the Canadian ambassador to Egypt, leapt to his death from a Cairo rooftop. During his remarkable life, Norman helped set the course of post-war Japan and played a key role during the Suez crisis. But with all of his talents and achievements, there was something haunting Herbert Norman and following him to every corner of the globe: the accusation that he was a Soviet spy. This documentary takes us back to a time when the Cold War was heating up and when the mere accusation of communist sympathies could destroy a man's career. Using de-classified documents, interviews with key players and dramatizations filmed around the world, the film reconstructs the ordeal that Norman endured for seven long years, as a US Senate subcommittee relentlessly probed his past beliefs and current loyalties. During his meteoric rise and fall, Norman crossed paths with some of the greatest personalities of his time: Nobel-prize winning Canadian diplomat and politician Lester B. Pearson; FBI director J. Edgar Hoover, whose organization had an 800-page security file on Norman; General Douglas MacArthur, to whom Norman was a trusted aide; and charismatic Egyptian leader Gamel Abdul Nasser.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?574649</url></doc>
