<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="576982">
  <docid>576982</docid>
  <title>The Missing Stories</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Rubin, Steven L.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">19 January 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">71</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Cade, Matthew</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Rubin, Steven L.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Cade, Matthew</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Baker Jr., Michael J.</actor>
      <role>Gary</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cade, Matthew</actor>
      <role>Dave</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Camp, Nina M.</actor>
      <role>Jen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Giordano, Anthony (III)</actor>
      <role>Charles</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jacobs, Cindy</actor>
      <role>Zoe</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"I like that feeling of just being here, but I'm afraid of stepping in that direction." Dave, a young man in his mid twenties, wanders alone along Ocean Parkway; connecting only to the world seen through the lens of a video camera. Currently he is at a cross roads in his life due to the tragic death of his mother. In the midst of this he meets a young woman who, not unlike himself, shares his feelings of isolation. As a victim of mental illness- she too is trapped and unable to move forward in her life. Together, they struggle to make sense of the world, which surrounds them, and mark their journey of self-discovery while making a documentary film about Dave's dysfunctional family. What starts out as a way to connect to something tangible instead opens up a Pandora's box of secrets, truths and unavoidable heartache. Dave's family which comprises of his schizophrenic father Charles, his angry older sister Jen, and family friend Gary- unwittingly allow him to come to terms with where he is now and how he chooses to live his life from there after.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?576982</url></doc>
