<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="578772">
  <docid>578772</docid>
  <title>The New Adventures of Black Beauty</title>
  <year>1990</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">9 April 1990</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">25</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Crome, John</director>
    <director>Millar, Catherine</director>
    <director>Smith, Mike (IX)</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Catran, Ken</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>King, Denis</composer>
    <composer>Neal, Chris (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bradshaw, David (I)</actor>
      <role>Mr. Coates</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Burgess, Christian</actor>
      <role>Nigel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Burkhard, Gedeon</actor>
      <role>Manfred</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chitham, Claire</actor>
      <role>Isambard</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dorning, Stacy</actor>
      <role>Dr. Jenny Denning</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dorning, Stacy</actor>
      <role>Jenny</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hurst, Michael (I)</actor>
      <role>Kurt</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kerr, Bill (I)</actor>
      <role>Samuel Burton</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lucas, William (I)</actor>
      <role>Doctor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lucas, William (I)</actor>
      <role>Dr. James Gordon</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McWilliams, Amber</actor>
      <role>Victoria 'Vicky' Denning</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mitchell, Tyler (I)</actor>
      <role>Kathy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Robertt, Andrew</actor>
      <role>Constable Carmondy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Treves, Frederick</actor>
      <role>Lord Fordham</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Jenny Denning, the girl who experienced numerous adventures with the stallion Black Beauty in the first series, has grown up in the meantime. She has married Nigel, who boarded a ship bound for New Zealand shortly after their wedding, in order to prepare everything for his wife's arrival. But he never gets there. The ship is missing. Jenny, the young vet, who hates nothing more than sitting around doing nothing, decides to travel to New Zealand with Vicky. She finds it very hard to say good-bye to her father, Dr. Gordon, and to her beloved horse Black Beauty. She is confident that Nigel has succeeded in making his way to New Zealand against all odds. Weeks later, when Jenny and Vicky arrive at the farm in the south of New Zealand, they discover to their dismay that it is deserted. Neither the manager, who was supposed to look after the cattle and the fields, nor any living creature whatsoever can be found. But the young vet and her step-daughter do not give up easily. They turn up their sleeves and work to make themselves at home. They get some unexpected assistance from a young German called Manfred, who had secretly moved into the stables, believing the farm to be deserted. Vicky and Jenny like him immediately. He pitches in with a will and makes himself useful in many ways. However, Vicky is astonished to discover that Manfred does not ride. On the contrary, he is terribly afraid of horses. But he is a talented tinkerer who keeps inventing new original gadgets such as a flying machine. By and by, the two women settle down. One day, they find a beautiful black stallion who will allow nobody but Vicky to ride him. The horse reminds Jenny of her beloved horse back in England, so she christens it Black Beauty.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?578772</url></doc>
