<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="578972">
  <docid>578972</docid>
  <title>The New McCarthyism</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Guerrero, Geoffrey</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>political-thriller</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">25</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Guerrero, Geoffrey</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Guerrero, Geoffrey</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Guerrero, Geoffrey</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barker, Pete</actor>
      <role>Melvin Johnson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Baxter, Diahnna Nicole</actor>
      <role>Sofia Jones</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Guerrero, Geoffrey</actor>
      <role>Jobe Gomez</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Huntley, Mark (I)</actor>
      <role>Tom Shultz</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>As the War on Terror rages on, the government re-institutes old methods from the McCarthy Era and CO-INTEL PRO days to fight terrorism on the home front and expedite the process of capturing enemy combatants. Playing a key role in a covert agency's plan to combat terrorism, Jobe Gomez plants falsified and fabricated evidence into suspected terrorist's homes. Meanwhile, his girlfriend Maribel has begun to catch on to his double-life, and she demands to know the truth. However, nothing will stand in Gomez's way from remaining loyal to his father's short-lived legacy and serving his country with the utmost dignity. One day after Mel and Tom, his superior officers', reward him for his excellent service, he discovers that his father was part of the Contras efforts in Nicaragua in the 1980's during the Iran-Contra Scandal - helping to supply weapons and material support to overthrow the Sandinista Regime. When Jobe's loyalty is put into question, he must make a critical decision and do what he thinks is right. But things are not always right in this world and sometimes your closest friends can be your worst enemies. In the Global War on Terror, old habits die hard.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?578972</url></doc>
