<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="579826">
  <docid>579826</docid>
  <title>The Oak Park Story</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Soe, Valerie</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">20 August 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Soe, Valerie</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Lum, Grande</producer>
    <producer>Soe, Valerie</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Jeung, Russell</writer>
    <writer>Soe, Valerie</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>This documentary tells the story of a broad, multiethnic coalition--undocumented residents from Mexico, a European American minister, Cambodian refugees who had survived the Killing Fields, city officials, college students and others--at the Oak Park apartments in Oakland, CA who in 2000 won an historic settlement of almost one million dollars against their landlord, one of the worst of the "dirty dozen" of landlords in Oakland. Not only did this coalition win monetary damages for forty-four households, but they also forced the landlord to sell the building to two non-profit organizations. Since that time, the tenants have moved into brand new apartments that are permanently affordable, The Oak Park Story, a 60-minute documentary tracing the stories of this coalition of activists, will profile immigrants overcoming tremendous odds, both here and in their native countries. It will look at multiethnic coalitions, innovative community organizing, and revitalized spiritual traditions, recounting the journey of a group of neighbors that changed their neighborhood and made a home for themselves.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?579826</url></doc>
