<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="579901">
  <docid>579901</docid>
  <title>The Ocean Ranger Disaster</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Stewart, Mike (III)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">1 January 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Rowley, Christopher</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Lint, David</producer>
    <producer>Armstrong, Jane (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Gzowski, Mick</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>This new 60-minute documentary, filmed in Newfoundland in the fall of 2001, chronicles the worst offshore drilling accident in North American history. The documentary is tentatively scheduled to premiere in early 2002, ahead of the 20th anniversary of the disaster. The Ocean Ranger sank on Feb. 15, 1982. Part of the Network's expanded slate of documentaries and one of the first recipients of CTV's new BCE-CTV Benefits Package, The Ocean Ranger Disaster is the heart-wrenching story of a disaster that devastated Newfoundland, and shocked the world. In the early morning hours of February 15, 1982, the Ocean Ranger, a giant oil-drilling rig faltered and sank. All 84 crew members were lost. Now 20 years later, using state-of-the-art advances in animation, CineNova has re-created the events of that night. By blending filmed re-enactments, cutting-edge computer graphic technology, poignant interviews and contemporary archival material, The Ocean Ranger Disaster tells the complete story of the startling chain of events that resulted in tragedy. It not only recalls what happened that day but also takes us out "on deck" to experience the disaster first-hand. What really happened that fateful night? How could a seemingly indestructible rig sink? "By exploring the causes of this tragedy, this film is an acknowledgment of the heroic deeds of those who tried their best to save the men of Ocean Ranger, and a tribute to those lives lost and those left behind," said Bob Culbert, CTV's Vice President of Documentaries. "Hopefully, this commemoration will keep the memory of the brave men of Ocean Ranger alive - both among those people who shared in their mourning 20 years ago and among those who have come since and will continue to go to sea in search of oil," said David Lint, chairman and CEO of CineNova Productions, Inc. "We're grateful for the warm reception from the families and people of Newfoundland. Their assistance was indispensable to the telling of the story." Like the Titanic, the Ocean Ranger was the biggest of its kind - 25,000 tons with a deck bigger than two football fields - touted as an unsinkable oil rig and designed to drill in seas too treacherous for others. And like the Titanic, Ocean Ranger challenged the sea in one of the most dangerous areas on earth - the North Atlantic.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?579901</url></doc>
