<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="579948">
  <docid>579948</docid>
  <title>The Off Hours</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Griffiths, Megan (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Griffiths, Megan (I)</producer>
    <producer>Jakupcak, Mischa</producer>
    <producer>Leavitt, Lacey</producer>
    <producer>Saez, Joy</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Griffiths, Megan (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Quinn, Aidan (I)</actor>
      <role>Stu</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Working the night shift at a diner alongside the highway, Francine doesn't spend much time considering what else her life could hold in store. She serves coffee to her regulars, chats with the truckers who pass through, and supports her burn-out brother and his band. Men have always offered Francine a distraction from the monotony, but over time her numerous relationships have earned Francine a reputation she can't escape. &lt;br&gt;Francine's boss Stu is in a similar rut, trying to keep the diner afloat in the face of dwindling business while struggling to connect with his estranged daughter, who he hasn't spent much time with since his divorce. Stu's penchant for heavy drinking has destroyed every relationship he's had, but has also fueled his only truly satisfying outlet-painting. Stu fills his days with visits to Jelena, the town's unlikely local call girl, and keeps his problems at a distance thanks to the ever-present whiskey in his coffee mug. &lt;br&gt;Across the parking lot from the diner, Jelena sets up camp at the Laundromat each night, making her living doing laundry for the people in her apartment building. She supplements her earnings with the occasional dalliance with a truck-driver or local regular, sending regular payments across the Atlantic to support the Serbian son she hasn't seen in years. &lt;br&gt;Awake when everyone else is asleep, these original and unrelenting characters are standing still as traffic is whipping by at 70mph. Just off exit number 127, a few blocks from the off-ramp, they live and work in the stillness of night. Folding laundry, pouring coffee, drinking failures away, never quite surfacing into the waking hours. Within the small, insignificant gestures, through the loneliness and isolation, they struggle to find inspiration in the passing moments of their lives.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?579948</url></doc>
