<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="580372">
  <docid>580372</docid>
  <title>The One Who Wears Red</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Coker, Heather</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>dance</keyword>
    <keyword>choreography</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">25 April 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">51</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="USA">20</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Coker, Heather</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>McBride, Walker</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Levy, Marc (VII)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Berg, Scott (III)</actor>
      <role>Hank</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brown, Pete (IV)</actor>
      <role>Clark</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Coates, Ricky</actor>
      <role>Fashion Expert</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Coker, Heather</actor>
      <role>Teacher</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Davis, Maureen (II)</actor>
      <role>Dr. Flavia</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>DeChellis, Lisa</actor>
      <role>Receptionist</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Delovino, Joey</actor>
      <role>Chauffeur</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Detor, Martha</actor>
      <role>Betty</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hurst, Jake</actor>
      <role>Waiter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kirshman, Armand</actor>
      <role>Sammy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lyons, Deirdre V.</actor>
      <role>Flavia the Freak</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Martinez, Matthew (V)</actor>
      <role>Delivery Man</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nakia, Jermel</actor>
      <role>Barry "Soothing Voice" Braithewaite</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Flavia is a woman who plays a dozen different roles in life. She is a mother, receptionist, delivery man, cleaning lady, chauffeur and nurse to her friends and family members. To her husband alone, she is sex object, his mother, the perfect proper wife and the fashion expert dressing her husband for work each day. She is the ying and yang student and teacher dichotomy depending upon her knowledge and experience with any given situation. Like most women, Flavia has a system to order her multitasked life. Reaching her 40th birthday, Flavia begins to question who she truly is, and her inability to find a quick answer builds to an inevitable meltdown. Friends and family members notice a shift in their typically dependable and always appropriate Flavia. With good intentions, but limited understanding, her loved ones rally around only making the pressure and frustration worse. There is no face Flavia can put on to avoid the questions, concerned looks and smothering attempts at comfort from the people in her life. Flavia must find the strength to step aside from her duties as a wife, woman and everywoman to find who she is to herself. The One Who Wears Red is a slice of the fictitious life of Flavia. Her internal monologue is told through narration and visualized through dance. All of the roles originating in her own mind exist as different people played by other men, women and adolescents. The appropriate persona surfaces when the corresponding task or duty calls him or her to service. Try keeping in order twelve personas and their array of corresponding duties; then, you will have walked a mile in Flavia's shoes.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?580372</url></doc>
