<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="581158">
  <docid>581158</docid>
  <title>The Pact</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Sweden</country>
  </countries>
  <producers>
    <producer>Sjöman, Anders</producer>
    <producer>Carlström, Björn (I)</producer>
    <producer>Janérus, Per</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Carlström, Björn (I)</writer>
    <writer>Sjöberg, Jonathan</writer>
    <writer>Sylvén, Henrik</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Jamie, 19 year's old and a freshman at a small mid western college, is haunted by visions of demons and bloody victims. These nightmares grow in intensity every night. She seeks help at the local hospital - only to find four other college students with her exact visions. They conclude that the visions are an omen: something bad is about to happen. Scared of what that might be, they form a pact, promising to always be by each other's side. The next night one of them is found dead. The others shared a dream showing the killer: a demon trying to cross over to our world. It needs a body to possess and they have all been picked as suitable candidates. If you refuse the demon it will kill you. Before anyone can find a solution another group member is found dead. Jamie dissolves the group and leaves town, leaving behind Chris and Aaron, the pact's remaining surviving members. The weak and scared Chris doesn't dare oppose the demon when he seeks her out, and she is possessed. Jamie, trying to relax on a beach somewhere, is again haunted by visions. She sees the suffering of Chris. She sees Aaron, who also fled town, rush back to help Chris. But worse - the Demon talks to her in the visions. Telling her that Jamie is the one he wants and won't give up until she is possessed. Terrorized, Jamie still returns to face the demon and save her friends.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?581158</url></doc>
