<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="581278">
  <docid>581278</docid>
  <title>The Palomino Club</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bayerl, Brian</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>happiness</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">8 March 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">10</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Gittlin, David</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Gittlin, David</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Gittlin, David</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Bias, Steven</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Elfman, Howard</actor>
      <role>Harold Mogelefsky</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gonzalez, Daniel (XV)</actor>
      <role>Ed Cornwall Jr.</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mena, Chaz</actor>
      <role>The Emcee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Murillo, Renier J.</actor>
      <role>Drag Queen Comedian</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sottilare, Andy</actor>
      <role>Joshua Rubin</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Joshua Rubin has escaped a dismal existence as a septic chemicals salesman and now ardently pursues his dream of becoming a successful stand-up comedian. Things are looking up romantically as well. Joshua is waking up to the fact that the love of his life was right under his nose in the form of his best friend and co-worker, Helen Windsor, a shy, intense, career-oriented woman in her late twenties. It looks like the only obstacles that stand in Joshua's way are the emotional scars he carries courtesy of a hyper critical father, Milton Rubin, who died when Joshua was a teenager. The persona of Milton Rubin haunts Joshua on a daily basis. But Joshua can handle it. He is supremely self-confident. If he took the time to think about it, which he wouldn't, his motto might be; "Full speed ahead and damn the torpedoes." Even though Joshua has quit his high-paying job, sold his expensive apartment, works at a minimum wage job by day and for nothing at night to make a name in the uncertain entertainment world, Joshua has never been happier. Until he finds out Helen faints whenever a man tries to kiss her. Then Joshua discovers the comedy club he has bought into as a partner is haunted by a real, live ghost.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?581278</url></doc>
