<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="581383">
  <docid>581383</docid>
  <title>The Parallel</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Smith, Damien (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">R</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">11 May 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Piandaryan, Jack</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Nazarian, Lucy</producer>
    <producer>Piandaryan, Jack</producer>
    <producer>Jones, Brennon (I)</producer>
    <producer>Schwartz, Brian (IV)</producer>
    <producer>Whitmarsh, Christine</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Piandaryan, Jack</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Newman, P. Daniel</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Altman, Christian</actor>
      <role>Slam Lyricist</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anglin, Chriss</actor>
      <role>Mr. Valentine</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brown, Steve Ben</actor>
      <role>Donald Fitzgerald</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carlisle, Elwood</actor>
      <role>Bum</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Christopher, Damon</actor>
      <role>Harvard Recruiter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ferrick, Adam</actor>
      <role>Jim</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fraga, Grace</actor>
      <role>Detective 1</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gordon, Darla</actor>
      <role>Margie Brooks</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hart, Taylor Gerard</actor>
      <role>Danny Fitzgerald</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jones, Gaetano</actor>
      <role>Bob</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kotek, Elliot V.</actor>
      <role>Big John</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pierce, Robert (II)</actor>
      <role>Detective Quigley</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Robert, John</actor>
      <role>Doctor/drunk/bar guy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ross, L.G.</actor>
      <role>Father McKenna</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Swarthout, Jeff</actor>
      <role>Choorba</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Williams, John Anthony</actor>
      <role>Warden</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>If nobody acknowledges our existence - how do we know we exist? Our existence is acknowledged in two different places; two different times, at once; is it possible to live a parallel existence? High school senior Danny Fitzgerald certainly didn't think so. The town's golden boy with the charmed life and golden girlfriend, Lynn, is about to graduate. On the night of his graduation, however, Danny's life is forever changed by a chance encounter with a Gypsy who startles him with an alarming reality - your life is not pre-destined to follow a certain path just because you want it to; your choices determine your life. In a moment of intoxicated arrogance, Danny gives in to a night of forbidden passion with Lynn's best friend and dangerous vixen, Margie. That is the last that Danny Fitzgerald remembers. Upon waking, Danny has a new reality - and he has no idea how he got there. 39 years old, living a dead end life with a now bitter and vengeful Margie, Danny frantically navigates through a bleak world that he doesn't understand, desperately trying to get back to that night with Lynn and the Gypsy. The people around him assure him that this life is his new reality. The rest is his imagination. But Danny still believes it's a dream and fights to get back. As things progress in this new existence, it suddenly occurs to Danny that this might not be a dream - he may have dreamed being a contented teenager, poised for great success in life. Are either of these a dream, or has Danny's life actually divided into two parallel existences - age 17 and 39? And if so, will he be able to regain the power of choice that was taken away from him, and choose his own path in life?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?581383</url></doc>
