<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="582339">
  <docid>582339</docid>
  <title>The PhanDom Menace</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Tonkin, Craig E.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>fan-club</keyword>
    <keyword>star-wars</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Australia">M</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">62</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Holt, Warwick</director>
    <director>Tonkin, Craig E.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Holt, Warwick</producer>
    <producer>Tonkin, Craig E.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Holt, Warwick</writer>
    <writer>Tonkin, Craig E.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Evans, James (III)</composer>
    <composer>Evans, Martin (V)</composer>
    <composer>Harrington, Brett</composer>
    <composer>Holt, Martin</composer>
    <composer>Holt, Warwick</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brennan, Chris (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fletcher, Karen</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maxwell, Darren</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Morrissey, Shane</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The PhanDom Menace presents the definitive look at the most devoted fans on the planet. Follow the lives of Australia's most passionate Star Wars fans as the moment they've waited 16 years for is suddenly upon them. See the amazing costumes, trivia soaked brains, vast collections and unconditional dedication that make these fans a breed apart. Be stunned by the shockwaves that echo through the Star Wars fan community at the dawn of its new prequel era. The PhanDom Menace revels in Star Walking's national conventions - complete with international guest representatives from Lucasfilm and cast members of Episode 1, elaborate costume pageants (including the George Lucas approved $10,000 'Vader'), swap-meets, an extraordinary film festival and art exhibit. It also eavesdrops on committee meetings where members strategise and officially begin the countdown to the eagerly anticipated, spine-tingling midnight premiere screening of Episode 1. Through childhood and adolescent reflection on the Star Wars trilogy, rooms of collectibles, the planned ritual repeat viewings and the compelling range of reaction to the new installment, we meet fans of all sorts: film-makers, artists, toy-makers, costumers, authors, and, of course, the management, all devoting their considerable passion to a celebration of the biggest pop culture phenomenon of all time.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?582339</url></doc>
