<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="584237">
  <docid>584237</docid>
  <title>The Private Public</title>
  <year>2000</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Olson, Brian (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">R</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Altman, Dana</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Calek, Chad</producer>
    <producer>Altman, Dana</producer>
    <producer>Holstein, Justin</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Calek, Chad</writer>
    <writer>Holstein, Justin</writer>
  </writers>
  <othercrew>
    <credit>
      <name>Lee, John Michael (I)</name>
      <job/>
    </credit>
  </othercrew>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bingham, Traci</actor>
      <role>Laina Brookhart</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brockley, Ross</actor>
      <role>Professor Hass</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brown, Cory (II)</actor>
      <role>Nate Wilson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Burns, David (II)</actor>
      <role>Zeke Lareau</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Calek, Brian</actor>
      <role>Brian Camel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cornwell, Jason (I)</actor>
      <role>Auggie Jacobs</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lynch, Kelly (II)</actor>
      <role>Maddy Nielsen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moore, Michael (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Naessens, Glen</actor>
      <role>Cameron Martin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Smith, Curt (I)</actor>
      <role>Professor Roger Powell</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Thomas, Woogie (I)</actor>
      <role>Thomas Woogly</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vallier, Robb</actor>
      <role>Auggie's Roomate Brix</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Zeke Lareau and Auggie Jacobs are two college seniors who have never met. Both are only a semester away from graduation, or so they think. During a night out on the town, a bar scuffle breaks out and mistakenly lands them in the county jail. After spending the night in cells joined by a window, they discover that although their personalities are night and day in comparison, they both share personal desires for Auggie's extremely liberated ex-girlfriend, Laina, as well as a desire for the truth. Zeke and Auggie soon find themselves engulfed in local stardom after teaming up in film class for a locally broadcasted mini-documentary that reveals Laina's lesbian life style and Zeke and Auggie's unique interests in her. But that stardom soon places Zeke and Auggie in the greatest struggle of their lives when their second documentary, which exposes a nationally acclaimed professor as a sexual offender, is met by opposition from the university, as well as the local authorities. Facing expulsion from the university and possible charges from local authorities, Auggie and Zeke, as well as mid-life crisis advocate Professor Roger Powell, are faced with the question of whether to gain by subsiding, or accept whatever consequences that may come from doing the right thing.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?584237</url></doc>
