<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="584907">
  <docid>584907</docid>
  <title>The Queen of Scarves</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Mystery</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>title-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Levenberg, Eric</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Taylor, Randolph</producer>
    <producer>Gordon, Michael Z.</producer>
    <producer>Levenberg, Eric</producer>
    <producer>Schreiner, Reinhard</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Levenberg, Eric</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Beeftink, Herman</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Jan Nash, a professor of fine arts, is having a novel semester. His mystery student, Johanna, never comes to class, yet is doing the best work. Her "computer art piece", housed in a Mac G-5, draped by black scarves, just appeared in class one week-end. Meanwhile, in the dead of night, a beautiful succubus, "The Queen of Scarves" is on the prowl. She ties black scarves around the neck of her men/prey. With Jan, she releases the scarf before he is asphyxiated. Unfortunately for two of Jan's students, Jolt and Ethan, she releases the scarves after they die. Lieutenant Billingsley runs down the evidence, which is scant. There are no fingerprints or DNA evidence at the crime scenes. He initially suspects, Nicole (Ethan's girlfriend) then Jan, and then Johanna, who does not even appear to exist. Jan dodges Billingsley, yet confides in Warren, his drinking buddy, and a professor of psychology. He believes Jan has conjured up the succubus archetype form his unconscious. In other words, he believes Jan has lost his mind. One night, Jan dreams of another life in ancient Bohemia. In this life, Warren is a cruel king, The Queen of Scarves, is his queen and Jan is a priest. To escape from her cruel husband the queen summons the town alchemist, who helps her transform into a succubus. Back in the 21st Century, The Queen of Scarves visits Warren to exact her revenge. Then she confronts Billingsley and Jan is a shocking finale likely to bend our notions of good and evil.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?584907</url></doc>
