<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="586425">
  <docid>586425</docid>
  <title>The Restoration of the Priesthood</title>
  <year>1982</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>latter-day-saints</keyword>
    <keyword>gospel</keyword>
    <keyword>immortality</keyword>
    <keyword>lds-film</keyword>
    <keyword>mormon</keyword>
    <keyword>baptism</keyword>
    <keyword>mormonism</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1982</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">20</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Newbold, Bruce</actor>
      <role>Oliver Cowdery</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The power to represent God in carrying out some of His most sacred work was given to men such as Adam, Abraham, Moses, and Aaron. John used this authority when he baptized Jesus. Christ conferred it upon his twelve apostles, with Peter, James and John holding the keys to this priesthood authority after His return to The Father. Upon the passing of the apostles, there was a great apostasy and this authority was not on earth for many, many centuries. In the Spring of 1829, Joseph Smith asks Oliver Cowdery to act as scribe as Joseph translates the writings of some ancient people in America that was written upon plates of gold. Coming upon a passage concerning baptism for the remission of sins, they pray to learn its meaning. John the Baptist appears, and confers the Priesthood of Aaron upon them. Using this authority, Joseph baptizes Oliver, and then Oliver baptizes Joseph. They then repeat this order and ordain each other to The Aaronic Priesthood. Peter, James, and John appear later to confer The Melchizedek Priesthood. The Book of Mormon is published on March 26, 1830, and then on April 6th Joseph and Oliver use their authority to organize the restored church of Jesus Christ and ordain each other as elders of the church (Joseph as 1st Elder, and Oliver as 2nd Elder).</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?586425</url></doc>
