<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="587209">
  <docid>587209</docid>
  <title>The River of Copsa Mica</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Uzilevsky, Ryan</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>roma</keyword>
    <keyword>gypsies</keyword>
    <keyword>factory</keyword>
    <keyword>ritual</keyword>
    <keyword>transylvania</keyword>
    <keyword>environmentalism</keyword>
    <keyword>gypsy</keyword>
    <keyword>fire-dance</keyword>
    <keyword>magical</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">6 June 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Uzilevsky, Ryan</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bacharach, Mitch</producer>
    <producer>Highbridge, Dustin</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Harkins, Kevin</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Abel, Chris (I)</actor>
      <role>Villiger</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Albrecht, Rob</actor>
      <role>Soldier</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Botwick, Aaron</actor>
      <role>Soldier</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Buckly, Charles</actor>
      <role>Desmond</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>DiSalvatore, James</actor>
      <role>Anton</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Henriksen, Drew</actor>
      <role>Villager/Druid</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Highbridge, Dustin</actor>
      <role>Soldier</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hristov, Hristo (IV)</actor>
      <role>Nicoli</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mesiano, Joseph</actor>
      <role>Sig</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stanton, Sawyer</actor>
      <role>Young Sig</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Trocola, Tom</actor>
      <role>Villager</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Uzilevsky, Ryan</actor>
      <role>Soldier</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>As the war in Europe raged on around them, the community in young Sig's farming village spoke of giant machines destroying entire cities just beyond the horizon.  Until one day the machine landed in their backyard. The government built an iron foundry for war production near the village, and the villagers  were quick to take up work there. For some joining the war effort was the path to a Utopian future of industry and nationalism. It was too early for them to know that by becoming a component of the industrial war machine, they would be setting an extreme course in their history that would devastate the quality of life in Copsa Mica for many generations to come. In the film these events are recounted by a former citizen of Copsa Mica named Sig. He speaks of his childhood when he wanted to escape the dark shadow of the new factory. He ventured into the woods in search of a group of Gypsies. The Gypsies where known  to perform a mystic Pagan ritual portraying the past, present, and future of the human relationship to the natural world. In a twist of fate Sig becomes a part of their ceremony, and accidentally causes its violent destruction. Sig lives on to see this experience as the foreshadowing of an apocalyptic future for his country, and becomes determined to change its course. And today, he may have his chance. But can he convince the others? And will this emotional unearthing turn the tide for peace, or for war?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?587209</url></doc>
