<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="588437">
  <docid>588437</docid>
  <title>The Same Side of Rejection Street</title>
  <year>2000</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>friendship</keyword>
    <keyword>redemption</keyword>
    <keyword>outcast</keyword>
    <keyword>honesty</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Collins, S.G.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Cook, Jennet</producer>
    <producer>Lanoue, Mark</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Collins, S.G.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Lysinger, Liz</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ball, Karen</actor>
      <role>Catherine DeMeo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dubrovsky, Ben</actor>
      <role>Executive</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Henderson, Michael (I)</actor>
      <role>Winston Bayne</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McCain, Terry</actor>
      <role>Man with Chicken Fajita</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Young, George (II)</actor>
      <role>Terrence</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>What's it about? It's about two complete strangers one vagrant, one middle class who realize they're both social outcasts, and discover in each other a kind of personal redemption. Imagine two people who should really just pass each other in the street and not look back. She's a reformed telemarketer with self-esteem problems. He's an eloquent crazy man with a mysterious past. She's looking for a job. He isn't. She has a place to live. He doesn't. She has deep conflicts with her parents. he's never met his. She's white. He's black. Why are they reaching out to each other? Maybe what draws them together is that they are both, in their own ways, abandoned. They seem to find a purpose for each other. and together they go on a day's journey through the city, their lives, their beliefs, sorrows and fears. They even begin to trust each other a little. At the same time, we wonder where he's leading her. She is meanwhile being stalked by the one man who really loves her an accordion-wielding software engineer, who cost her her last job because he wouldn't leave her alone...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?588437</url></doc>
