<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="588960">
  <docid>588960</docid>
  <title>The Screaming Skull</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Harrod, James</editor>
    <editor>Thorpe, Ashley</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>gothic</keyword>
    <keyword>surrealism</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">29 November 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">10</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Thorpe, Ashley</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hawkins, Jonas</producer>
    <producer>Mitchell, Stuart (VII)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Thorpe, Ashley</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Grierson, Mick</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Berry, Ed</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Spencer Penraddon returns from the 1st World War to his ancestral home. His sister has succumbed to the blight that has cursed the family since the hall was erected in the 17th century...and symbol of the family curse is the mysterious 'Screaming Skull'. Legend has it that the skull belonged to the loyal slave of 18th century Magistrate Azariah Penraddon. Upon his death the slave wished his remains to be returned to the West Indies. But for reasons unknown Azariah did not grant the slave's final wish and his remains were interred on the edge of the family plot. It was soon after that the disturbances began... If moved the skull was believed to emit terrifying screams and terrible commotions would sound through the house. As a consequence few have dared to disturb it for fear of the terrors it will unleash. Spencer however, already reeling from the horrors of the Western front, wishes to be free of the house and its ghosts. But the ghosts of Penraddon hall are not ready to be put to rest. As Spencer walks the halls labyrinthine corridors, he is assaulted by horrors; spectres of the past...and a grim epiphany. that perhaps the deepest parts of our hearts really are inherited.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?588960</url></doc>
