<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="589360">
  <docid>589360</docid>
  <title>The Secret KGB Sex Files</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>acronym-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>kgb</keyword>
    <keyword>russia</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Hungary">21 May 2006</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">18 September 2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">88</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>McKenzie, David (III)</director>
    <director>Peterson, John R.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Romanovich, James</producer>
    <producer>McKenzie, David (III)</producer>
    <producer>Moore, Christian (IV)</producer>
    <producer>Peterson, John R.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Goldman, Dan (II)</writer>
    <writer>Ross, John (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Ross, John (II)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bin Laden, Osama</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gerasimov, Genadi I.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Helmich, Joseph</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kalugin, Oleg</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lunev, Stanislav</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moore, Roger (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself - Host</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The KGB was, for 50 years, the most effective intelligence agency the world had ever seen. The key to its success was a ruthless skill for using money, sex and blackmail as tools to entice foreigners to betray their countries and hand over secret information. In this two hour program, that could only be produced with the end of the Cold War, we enter the never-before seen and carefully guarded vaults of the worlds most feared organization, the KGB. In this program we reveal the inner working of the KGB. The use of the "Honey Trap" which is, in intelligence circles, the use of women in sexual situations to snare victims and obtain secret information. How did the KGB identify U.S. Marines who worked at the U.S. Embassy and target them, leading to compromise and in the case of marine Lonetree, to a 30 year prison sentence. We see secret footage of the bumbling FBI agent selling out his country for sex in a car, and the CIA officer who lived a lavish lifestyle at the cost of agents lives. See the amazing use of hidden cameras and the footage that reveals seduction, passion and sexual conduct all used to destabilize enemy governments. We still have only a glimpse of the secret KGB files and we may never know the full extent of the information contained in the KGB vaults but in the KGB Sex Files you get the closet look ever at the Russian State secrets. Hosted by Roger Moore.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?589360</url></doc>
