<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="589784">
  <docid>589784</docid>
  <title>The Separation on State Street</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Pfaendtner, Michael</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>wicca</keyword>
    <keyword>atheist</keyword>
    <keyword>dungeon</keyword>
    <keyword>first-amendment</keyword>
    <keyword>culture-war</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 December 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">94</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>St. Mary, Robert</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Pfaendtner, Michael</producer>
    <producer>St. Mary, Robert</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>St. Mary, Robert</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Gregory, Troy</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anonka</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The rural village of Caro in Michigan's Thumb had never seen anything like Anonka's Witch Museum -- a curiosity shop that sold crystals, herbs, books and other tools of the magical trade. "Anonka's" stood out because it sold those nick-nacks with a message -- delivered to those with enough courage to "Brave the Dungeon" -- a memorial and commentary on the witch hunts of the Middle Ages and how to make sense of, and learn from, them in the 21st Century. After almost two years in business, the controversy started when four law students asked Anonka a question -- "Why is there a nativity scene on the courthouse lawn?" When Anonka decided to find out the answer she felt pressured by the local government's hostile reaction to her question. When she started to protest for the display's removal many of her neighbors decided to protest for her removal. "The Separation on State Street" follows Anonka and her family down a long, rough legal road where their fight for Constitutional rights, understanding and dialogue scrapes hard against the larger community that does not share her beliefs.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?589784</url></doc>
