<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="590430">
  <docid>590430</docid>
  <title>The Ship That Wouldn't Die</title>
  <year>1945</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>War</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>News</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>wwii</keyword>
    <keyword>narration</keyword>
    <keyword>medal-of-honor</keyword>
    <keyword>military</keyword>
    <keyword>newsreel</keyword>
    <keyword>aircraft-carrier</keyword>
    <keyword>navy</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">8</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Abbott, G.P.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gehres, Leslie</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kennedy, John B.</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lepore, Frank</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Masters, F.W.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Novack, S.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>O'Callahan, Joseph</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Turner, James W.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>On March 19, 1945, the aircraft carrier USS Franklin, one of a group of ships off the coast of Kobe, Japan, was attacked by a Japanese bomber. The plane scored direct hits with two large bombs. This newsreel, shot by US Navy photographers, shows what happened on the Franklin after the attack. The Franklin was heavily laden with bombs, rockets, and fuel-loaded aircraft. For about 24 hours, the ship's armaments exploded. These explosions caused great damage to the ship and the deaths of over 800 crewmen. Over 250 additional personnel were injured. There were many acts of heroism performed. Several ships came to the Franklin's aid, some to fight the fires that all but gutted the ship, others to transport survivors. Miraculously, the ship stayed afloat and was able to move under her own power. After undergoing a cleanup at Pearl Harbor, she made the voyage through the Panama Canal to the Brooklyn Navy Yard for repairs. Father (Lieutenant Commander) 'Joseph O'Callahan' (qv), the ship's chaplain, was awarded the Medal of Honor for his actions.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?590430</url></doc>
