<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="591867">
  <docid>591867</docid>
  <title>The Soldier's Return</title>
  <year>1902</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">January 1903</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Williamson, James (I)</director>
  </directors>
<plot>If you are seeking a Feature Film we can recommend this to fill the bill in every particular. The picture is full of sentiment and will actually cause tears to flow before the end is reached. A Soldier of the British army after being decorated returns to the little village which he left when a boy and immediately wends his way to his old home expecting to find his old mother with whom he expected to live for the remainder of his life. To his astonishment and pain, he learns from a neighbor that his mother, too poor to pay her rent, had been sent to the County Institution. He inquires the way there and on being informed goes hither instantly and demands to see his mother. She appears and they fall into each other's arms, the mother wiping away her tears. The brave soldier tells his mother that she must leave the place at once and commands her to come with him, which she does. The picture again changes showing the old lady seated in the doorway of their old home knitting, while her son plants flowers before the house. He rises and lighting his pipe proceeds to plant more flowers when he enters the house and returns with a cup of hot tea which the old lady apparently enjoys. Thus the picture ends. This is a complete story without words and we do not hesitate in saying that no matter where it is shown, it will appeal to old and young alike and will move any audience to tears. No expense has been spared to make this film perfect in every respect. Wonderfully beautiful.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?591867</url></doc>
