<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="594481">
  <docid>594481</docid>
  <title>The Swamp Critters of Lost Lagoon</title>
  <year>1995</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>swamp</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1996</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Peeler, Dan</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Goldsboro, Bobby</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Goldsboro, Bobby</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Goldsboro, Bobby</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Demetrius, James</actor>
      <role>Critter Cast</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Goldsboro, Bobby</actor>
      <role>All Characters</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Goldsboro, Bobby</actor>
      <role>All characters</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Goldsboro, Bobby</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Goldsboro, Dianne</actor>
      <role>Critter Cast - Ima Dilla</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hitch, Joe</actor>
      <role>Critter Cast</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maddux, Jeff</actor>
      <role>Critter Cast</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rose, Charlie (V)</actor>
      <role>Critter Cast - Billy Bob Possum</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Each music-filled episode of "The Swamp Critters Of Lost Lagoon" centers around the antics and problems faced by critter cast Billy Bob Possum, frog Ribbit E. Lee, armadillo Ima Dilla, Joe Raccoon, Big Al Gator and Gumbo The Fiddler Crab. These live-action, costumed characters, the members of 'The Swamp Critters Band', live and play music in their critter-town of Lost Lagoon. Their frequent co-star is Phinneas Phatrat, the resident bad-boy. As they experience everyday life, the critters learn about values, virtues, emotions and issues including friendship, charity, kindness, acceptance of differences, conservation and pollution. Along the way, they are introduced to a variety of musical styles such as blues, cajun, classical, country, disco, dixieland, jazz and rock 'n' roll. Each half-hour episode features as many as 5 songs. In their adventures, the stars of the show are joined by many critter guests including boar Bobby Q., groundhog T. Bone Willie, Granny Muskrat, Melvis Weasley, Bonnie and the Bunnies and Arnold The Worminator. The cast consists primarily of costumed actors with animatronic heads, interspersed with some puppets. All of the characters are voiced by 'Bobby Goldsboro' (qv). This wholesome series is designed for children 2 to 8. However, with a Bobby Goldsboro soundtrack and clever and witty dialogue, the show can be entertaining to adults as well.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?594481</url></doc>
