<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="594558">
  <docid>594558</docid>
  <title>The Swim Team</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Crosby, Amber</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>swim</keyword>
    <keyword>nostalgia</keyword>
    <keyword>swimming</keyword>
    <keyword>elderly</keyword>
    <keyword>memory</keyword>
    <keyword>team</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">25 September 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">17</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Crosby, Amber</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Garrett, Kyle</producer>
    <producer>Spencer, Savannah</producer>
    <producer>Crosby, Amber</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>July, Miranda</writer>
    <writer>Seamer, George</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barron, Remi</actor>
      <role>Jack Jack</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Burnham, Seth</actor>
      <role>Ex-Boyfriend</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Garrett, Haley</actor>
      <role>Girl in Car</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grenier, Carolyn</actor>
      <role>Elizabeth</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kraetsch, Carolyn</actor>
      <role>Kelda</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In her early twenties, Mona finds herself living in the tiny town of Belvedere with no direction and nothing to do. Her days consist of long, boring hours gazing out her window at the barren landscape, lying to her mother about how busy her life is, visiting the small market down the road and avoiding eye contact with the three elderly people who run it, Elizabeth, Kelda and Jack Jack, the only other people within miles. While visiting the market one afternoon Mona overhears the three elderly shop owners arguing about how they have never learned to swim and complaining that there isn't even a suitable body of water anywhere near the town of Belvedere. Speaking to them for the first time, Mona claims that she can teach them and they don't even need a body of water. Using three large bowls, a kitchen floor and a lot of imagination the swim lessons begin. As Elizabeth, Kelda and Jack Jack eagerly follow Mona's every direction they become lithe, agile swimmers, young again in the waters of their minds. These weekly swim lessons give Mona direction and she, too, is transformed, becoming a strong, purposeful coach. Later in life, when Mona again finds herself without direction, wandering through the empty rooms of her apartment after a painful break-up, the memory of Belvedere comes back to her. She is reminded of her time with Elizabeth, Kelda and Jack Jack and the feeling of swimming without water. Based on the short story by Miranda July, the film reminds us that sometimes it's the things we've forgotten that haven't forgotten us.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?594558</url></doc>
