<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="594839">
  <docid>594839</docid>
  <title>The Talk: Coming to Terms with Sex in America</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Boudreaux, John Henry</editor>
    <editor>Farrell, Brenna</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">97</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Boudreaux, John Henry</director>
    <director>Farrell, Brenna</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Boudreaux, Frank (II)</producer>
    <producer>Hale, Enrico</producer>
    <producer>Boudreaux, John Henry</producer>
    <producer>Farrell, Brenna</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Boudreaux, John Henry</writer>
    <writer>Farrell, Brenna</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Four decades after the Sexual Revolution, sex is no longer hidden behind closed doors. But that doesn't mean it's an open topic at dinner tables across the country. Many of us find it as hard as ever to talk meaningfully about sex...especially to those who are most meaningful to us. In THE TALK, forty-five ordinary Americans struggle to get at the heart of this enduring difficulty. A father regrets he couldn't speak openly with his daughter. A new mother hopes sex will be less stigmatized for her son than it was for her. A sixty-year-old man wishes he'd had more sexual partners in his youth, while a fifteen-year-old girl pledges to remain abstinent until marriage. What's really at stake here? Filmmakers Brenna Farrell and John Henry Boudreaux traveled the country asking friends, family, and a few others they met along the way, to try to explain what sex means to their lives. This uniquely intimate documentary clears the way for a sometimes humorous, sometimes gut-wrenching conversation about the real consequences of sex. THE TALK proves we still have a lot to talk about.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?594839</url></doc>
