<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="594824">
  <docid>594824</docid>
  <title>The Tales of Moondale Haven Presents: George the Head</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Nicholson, Will (I)</editor>
    <editor>Weems, T.G.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">20 January 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Nicholson, Will (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kribs, Jeff</producer>
    <producer>Perez, Rick (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Kribs, Jeff</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Machado, Roy</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kribs, Jeff</actor>
      <role>Flavelious Frederick Farkleby</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>George has everything a boy could want; parents who loves him, a pixie who watches over him, loads of toys, and a sparkling personality. The only thing he doesn't have is a body. Not that that ever bothered him, though. He can roll as fast as anyone can run, and he has his own customized mode of transportation, The GeorgeBoard! But when he asks his dream girl Polly Anna out on a date, everything changes. After being turned down because he's just a head, George begins to question whether or not he's as happy as he thinks is. So when Mother Moondale, the resident pixie of Moondale Haven, offers to grant him a wish to give him happiness, she's quite sure what that wish will be. When it's something quite different, a valuable lesson is learned by everyone in town! Come on in and enjoy the show as George learns about the importance of individuality with all of his friends in Moondale Haven, a most special and unusual place! Includes six original songs, and a most splendid lesson indeed.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?594824</url></doc>
