<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="595033">
  <docid>595033</docid>
  <title>The Teachings of Jon</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Boyer, Max Logan</editor>
    <editor>Owensby, Jennifer</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>down-syndrome</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">TV-G</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2 April 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">57</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Owensby, Jennifer</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Owensby, Jennifer</producer>
    <producer>Sanza, John</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Alexander, Cherish</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>"The Teachings of Jon" is an insightful, soul-touching and funny documentary about the filmmaker's brother Jon, a 40-yr old man, severely and profoundly affected by Down syndrome. He has an IQ of 20, doesn't talk and earns less than $13.00 a year. Although Jon may never accomplish much in this world, he has an important purpose here; to teach. "The Teachings of Jon" follows the journey of a family, and how the "family secret" locked away in an institution for the first 7 years of his life became the powerful silent teacher of kindness and reverence. This documentary shows what it's really like to take care of someone like Jon in heart-warming detail. Jon's parents, a psychiatrist and psychotherapist share how having Jon catalyzed a complete change of values and how he taught them about good mental health. The siblings share what it was like growing up with a brother with severe mental retardation; how they had to learn how to communicate with him and the affect he has had on all of their lives. Though the story is told in a unique cinematic light-hearted style, "The Teachings of Jon" ponders the serious questions of how we value other human beings and what is truly important in life.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?595033</url></doc>
