<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="596125">
  <docid>596125</docid>
  <title>The Timebank: An Economy for Everyone</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>society</keyword>
    <keyword>economy</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>German</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Ecuador">18 November 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Germany">12 August 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Ireland">12 September 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
<plot>Are you doing a job you really like? Have you ever heard of people feeling useless? Do you know the people in your neighborhood? Do you feel integrated in a community or are you a lonely person? Is a growing economy based on good work or more a result of fiscal policy and speculators' decisions? In today's economy driven world these questions gain more and more importance. After achieving political equality - at least in theory through a modern constitution - we recognize that real freedom is determined through economic independence. But how to reach it? "The Timebank - an economy for everyone" describes little "self-made" economies, founded by ordinary people exclusively for ordinary people. In these economies, everyone has the opportunity to do jobs he or she likes. Nobody has to feel useless. People get to know the people living around them and become part of their community. And these economies only grow on the base of needed, well-done services. Social innovation, known to very few people, although spread all over the world. It is about emotions, longings, and hidden power, which all human beings have. Even if those feelings/conditions are to a large extent covered up by our pre-planned, busy daily lives. Whether one believes in the documented system's sustainability or not, the convincing comments made by the protagonists touch all our hearts and reveal new perspectives on lifestyle, dignity, and the value of human skills.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?596125</url></doc>
