<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="597288">
  <docid>597288</docid>
  <title>The Trunk</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Watson, Richard L.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>job</keyword>
    <keyword>trunk</keyword>
    <keyword>mobster</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">19 October 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">10</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Cisneros, Christian</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Cisneros, Christian</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Watson, Richard L.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Horne, Aaron (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harper, Jason (IV)</actor>
      <role>Danny</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pulido, Juan Carlos (II)</actor>
      <role>Guy in the Trunk</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ripke, Maurice</actor>
      <role>Bobby</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>What would you do if the man you looked up to and idolized your entire life turned out not to be quite what you thought he was? Would you still follow the path he had put before you, even if it meant taking the life of a trusted friend, or would you go against the life your father had lead and risk it all to save your friend and yourself? Danny started his day like every other day, making the rounds; collecting money that was owed to his employer, doing the thing his father had taught him his entire life. With his partner Bobby in the passenger seat, still showing him the ropes, Danny soon gets a crash course in the dangerous world his father had failed to tell him about. With Danny's friend now tied up in the back seat and his head full of contradictions and confusion, he must decide what direction his life will now take. Will he continue on the path that has lead him to this crossroad, walking the thin red line between felonies and misdemeanors, or will he delve head on into the underworld that consumed his father and is now forcing him to make the decision of a lifetime.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?597288</url></doc>
