<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="598261">
  <docid>598261</docid>
  <title>The Unknown War</title>
  <year>1978</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>soviet-union</keyword>
    <keyword>tv-mini-series</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Soviet Union</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">22 June 1978</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">1040</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Kleinerman, Isaac</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kleinerman, Isaac</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lancaster, Burt</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Sprawling, 20-part documentary history in film of the World War II conflict between Nazi Germany and the Soviet Union. Companion book, The Unknown War, written by NYT reporter Harrison Salisbury. Each episode is about 52 minutes, similar in format to The World at War. The footage was edited from over 3.5 million feet of film taken by Soviet camera crews from the first day of the war, 22 June 1941, to the soviet entry in Berlin in May 1945. Most of these films have never been seen outside this documentary series. Narrated by Burt Lancaster. Chapters: 1. June 22, 1941; 2. The Battle for Moscow; 3. The Siege of Leningrad; 4. To the East; 5. The Defense of Stalingrad; 6. Survival at Stalingrad; 7. The World's Greatest Tank Battle-Kursk; 8. War in the Arctic; 9. War in the Air; 10. Partisans: The Guerilla War; 11. Battle of the Seas; 12. Battle of the Caucasus; 13. Liberation of Ukraine; 14. Liberation of Byelorussia; 15. From the Balkans to Vienna; 16. The Liberation of Poland; 17. The Allies; 18. The Battle of Berlin; 19. The Last Battle of the Unknown War; 20. A Soldier of the Unknown War.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?598261</url></doc>
