<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="599963">
  <docid>599963</docid>
  <title>The Warrior King</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Hrycyk, Nick</editor>
    <editor>Sturm, Robert A.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>kosova</keyword>
    <keyword>albanian</keyword>
    <keyword>albania</keyword>
    <keyword>medieval</keyword>
    <keyword>warrior</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Albania">April 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">96</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Gjonaj, Nik</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Gjelaj, Nua</producer>
    <producer>Gjonaj, Nik</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Gjelaj, Nua</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carey, Peter (II)</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gojcaj, Anton</actor>
      <role>Gjergj Kastrioti - Scanderbeg</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lulgjuraj, Zef</actor>
      <role>Marin Barleti</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In a time long ago, amidst the warring civilizations of East and West, the dream of universal empire is looming on the eastern horizon, for the house of Osman has awakened. Without mercy the Ottoman Empire devours peoples and nations. A warrior shall rise and a fiercely independent people will break the chains of slavery and sacrifice everything for freedom. Torn from his family and country a young prince is dragged into the court of the crescent. Raised in the Sultan's palace and destined to be the most brilliant commander of his time. Stripped of his Christian name and compelled to accept Islam, Sultan Murad II would give him the name that the world shall forever know him by, Scanderbeg. This name will strike terror to his enemies and give hope to a world on the brink of oblivion. Upon a moment of truth, a fateful decision, Scanderbeg and his loyal warriors return to Albania, their fatherland and the faith of Christ. Uniting the Albanian warrior race against the Ottoman Colossus. Forsaken, betrayed, murdered and enslaved for over a quarter of a century, Scanderbeg and his people suffered their Passion. Leaving their nation in ruins, the Albanian resistance saved Western Civilization from Ottoman Conquest. Spared from obscurity, this heroic tale was chronicled by an Albanian Catholic monk, Marin Barleti, who witnessed the sunset of the Age of Scanderbeg. One man's destiny became a nation's epic struggle for freedom. Glory has a terrible price.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?599963</url></doc>
