<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="600405">
  <docid>600405</docid>
  <title>The Wedding Race</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Lai, Chow Chi</editor>
    <editor>Lo, Jason (I)</editor>
    <editor>Lok, Pui Ching</editor>
    <editor>Wai Suk Fan, Manda (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Reality-TV</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>australia</keyword>
    <keyword>queensland</keyword>
    <keyword>siemens-mobile</keyword>
    <keyword>coca-cola</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Mandarin</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="China">8 March 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="China">44</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Lau, Ken (I)</director>
    <director>Lee, David Y.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Lau, Ken (I)</producer>
    <producer>Lee, David Y.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Lau, Ken (I)</writer>
    <writer>Lee, David Y.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Hui, Clarence</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chen Jian, Jim</actor>
      <role>Orange Male Contestant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chen Jing, Jean</actor>
      <role>Red Female Contestant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chen Xin Tian, Terry</actor>
      <role>Green Male Contestant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gang, Garry Cheng</actor>
      <role>Host</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Huang Jie Rui, Michael</actor>
      <role>Yellow Male Contestant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lei Tao, Charles</actor>
      <role>Red Male Contestant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Liang, Angel</actor>
      <role>Yellow Female Contestant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Liu Yan, Rachael</actor>
      <role>Green Female Contestant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lu Min, Kitty</actor>
      <role>Black Female Contestant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Luo Gang, Ken</actor>
      <role>Black Male Contestant</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Five couples were each given colors to represent their team - Team Green, Team Orange, Team Black, Team Red and Team Orange. During the competitions, the couples were split between the males and the females, with each contestant competing only against their own sex, and their points accumulating as the total team score. The competitions the contestants participated in included skydiving, hang gliding, bungee jumping, swimming with sharks, ATV quad-bike racing, jet-skiing, race-car driving, white water rafting, rap jumping and a variety of other dangerous and exciting events. Most of the contestants had never tried any of the extreme sports, and though beginners, had to perform as professionals not only to win the contests, but for their own safety! During each episode, the show also includes a "Penalty Round" in which the partners of the losing contestants for that episode get punished! Therefore, if the male of the Red team lost on one day, the female on the Red team was the one that had to do the hardship! These difficult and embarrassing punishments were often performed in public, and truly tested the love and commitment of the couples! However, it also provided more motivation for each contestant to win, so that they didn't have to see their loved ones suffer, or feel their scorn! Providing more motivation to win, the winners of each episode's competitions were also given opportunities to secure more points in that episode's "Bonus Round". These rounds consisted of very difficult brain-teasers and trivia games to be completed successfully in a very short amount of time. No doubt, it gave each round's winner enormous pressure to not only accumulate more points, but to not waste that day's effort in achieving the winning score!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?600405</url></doc>
