<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="605862">
  <docid>605862</docid>
  <title>Three Queens: An International Rendezvous</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Marshall, Robert Neal</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">27 November 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">75</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Marshall, Robert Neal</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Marshall, Robert Neal</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>On 13th January 2008 all three Cunard ocean liners, the Queen Mary 2, the Queen Elizabeth 2 and the new Queen Victoria (on her Maiden Transatlantic voyage) all met for one historic rendezvous in New York Harbor. On 22nd April all three ships met for the only time in Cunard's home port of Southampton. On 16th October 2008 the QE2 made her emotional final New York farewell departure and last Transatlantic crossing in tandem with the QM2 shortly before retiring in Dubai as a floating hotel. In Southampton board QM2 for a once in a lifetime event up the Solent to salute QE2 and Queen Victoria. From Queen Mary 2 follow QE2 with Queen Victoria behind into New York Harbor. See QE2 and Queen Victoria side by side at the Manhattan piers. Enjoy a close up water level view of the grand fireworks parade as all three Queens sail past the Statue of Liberty and out to sea. Experience the excitement from QM2 as QE2 makes a stirring final departure from New York with her regal 39 foot paying off pennant flying in the breeze. Sail in tandem across the Atlantic with QE2 and share a powerful mid-ocean horn salute between the two Cunarders with tons of magnificent ship to ship video footage of the QE2! Head down the Solent for a close up look at QE2 as she makes one of her next to last departures from Southampton and see QM2 sail away, never again to pass the QE2. Bonus Features include: QE2 Interior Tour - Cabins, Public Rooms, Stairwells, Spa, Magnificent Ship Models of Cunard Mauretania and Caronia, Memorabilia and More. See Builder's Plate from original Queen Elizabeth! Wreath Ceremony over Titanic site from Aft Deck of QE2 on 14th April 2008, 96th Anniversary of Sinking.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?605862</url></doc>
