<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="606282">
  <docid>606282</docid>
  <title>Throttle</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <editors>
    <editor>Morgenthaler, Peder</editor>
    <editor>Seale, James (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>parking-garage</keyword>
    <keyword>underground</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Portugal">M/16</certificate>
    <certificate country="UK">15</certificate>
    <certificate country="USA">R</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2 August 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Seale, James (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Loudis, Kristin</producer>
    <producer>Aron, Zachary</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Elman, Neil</writer>
    <writer>Seale, James (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Acree, Neal</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arca, Jefferson</actor>
      <role>Victor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Beisner, Michelle</actor>
      <role>Rebecca</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gillen, Tom</actor>
      <role>Man in Valiant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grundy, Chris</actor>
      <role>Lead Officer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Locane, Amy</actor>
      <role>Molly Weaver</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McCouch, Grayson</actor>
      <role>Tom Weaver</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mundell, Dan</actor>
      <role>Eddie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Paul, Adrian (I)</actor>
      <role>Gavin Matheson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sirchia, Gary</actor>
      <role>Repo Man</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Valdez, Daniel Jay</actor>
      <role>Police Officer</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Every day, millions of people descend into underground parking garages, get into their cars and drive to the safety of their homes. But tonight, five levels down in a deserted corporate parking structure, financial analyst Tom Weaver won't be going home. After finishing a late night business deal, Tom arrives at section E5 of the garage only to discover his car won't start. Worse yet, the elevators are shut down and every stairwell has been locked. Trapped in the bowels of the garage, Tom realizes he's not alone. Something else is down here. Watching. Waiting. A monstrous 6000 lb Truck whose driver sits hidden behind a veil of tinted glass. A lethal killer with only one agenda: Not letting Tom get out alive. Over the next six hours, a terrifying game of cat and mouse ensues, testing Tom's will to survive and rattling his sanity. He must outwit his pursuer while trying to figure out who wants him dead: Has his business partner Gavin turned on him and could his wife Molly part of the plan? Or is it simply a case of extreme road rage after he cut someone off earlier in the day? As he fights his way to the surface, discovering horrifying new clues on each level of the garage, Tom realizes the Truck Driver is playing for keeps. Either he outsmarts the mysterious killer behind the wheel... or he won't live to see the light of day. E5 is an unrelenting paranoid suspense thriller that turns an everyday situation into a terrifying nightmare. Parking your car will never be the same again.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?606282</url></doc>
