<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="608440">
  <docid>608440</docid>
  <title>Time Machine</title>
  <year>1985</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Game-Show</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>non-fiction</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Darley, Chris</director>
    <director>Marcione, James</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Davidson, John (II)</actor>
      <role>Host</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>O'Donnell, Charlie (I)</actor>
      <role>Announcer</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In "Time Machine," contestants competed to answer questions about popular culture and recent (usually post-World War II) history. A series of rounds, each with different contestants, could see the contestants answer questions about newsmaking events, identifying events from a specific decade and sports and entertainment. The winners from each of those rounds competed against a returning champion in a Q&amp;A-type quiz. The winner of that round played a bonus round. Two different bonus games were used during the show's run. Early in the series, host Davidson read a list of items all tied to a specific year (e.g., "West Side Story," Chevrolet Impala Super Sport introduced, "I Fall to Pieces" by Patsy Cline, Peace Corps started and Roger Maris' 61st home run); if the contestant correctly identified the year (in this case, 1961), he/she won a bonus prize. Later in the run, a specific year was given (e.g., 1959) and up to four questions relating to whether a certain event happened before or after that year were read (e.g., Vietnam War started, correct answer, before); four correct answers won the player a new car, while an incorrect answer before then stopped the game.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?608440</url></doc>
