<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="608668">
  <docid>608668</docid>
  <title>Timecollapse</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Mangan, Patrick (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">28 April 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">32</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Lavin, Samantha</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>D'Alesandro, Joseph</producer>
    <producer>Goodman, Ellen (I)</producer>
    <producer>Monaco, Gerri</producer>
    <producer>D'Alesandro, Joseph</producer>
    <producer>Lavin, Samantha</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Lavin, Samantha</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>O'Shea, Rosie (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barlow, Barrymore</actor>
      <role>Steve</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Careccia, Maryfrances</actor>
      <role>Lucy Monaco</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Decker, Cathy (I)</actor>
      <role>Zulo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Essig, Ellyn</actor>
      <role>Toni Ann</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hart, Steven</actor>
      <role>Dr. Lawrence</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lee, Matthew (I)</actor>
      <role>Dante</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Lucy is a wannabe writer who hides behind a dead end job in her hometown. When her girlfriend decides to move away and Lucy can't find the courage to go with her, she winds up in bed with her best friend from high school, Dante. She receives a letter of acceptance to a writer's fellowship across the country, which she burns. Lucy tries to forget about Tracy, and continue her friendship with Dante, leaving the affair behind, but to no avail when she discovers she is pregnant. Continuing with her thankless delivery job she meets a lawyer whose snobby exterior softens as she comes on to Lucy after fixing her car which has broken down in the corporate office park. Dante, meanwhile, decides to pull the Catholic, Italian guilt thing and insists Lucy keep the baby. Lucy walks away from him, deciding to take time to make this decision for herself. After taking a look at the people around her and examining her life's choices, Lucy decides that it would be unfair to give up this baby just because she didn't do what she wanted to with her own life. After a month, Dante comes to see Lucy to find out what she has decided. She tells him, and they go to the sonogram appointment together. The doctor delivers the news that this has been a false pregnancy, one in which the embryo never develops. In the heat of the moment Dante blames Lucy saying, "You never wanted this baby. The whole time your poison thoughts were running through it! How could anything grow in that?" But this time, Lucy, instead of thinking of herself first is able to comfort Dante and forgive his momentary rage. In the end, we go back to a bedroom, one we saw in the very first scene and realize that this story was actually being told by Lucy to Jess, the lawyer she's been seeing, two weeks before Lucy is scheduled to leave for the writing fellowship.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?608668</url></doc>
