<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="611331">
  <docid>611331</docid>
  <title>Toki Does New York</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Woodhouse, Tim</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>New Zealand</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="New Zealand">2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">51</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Salmon, Dan</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Christie, Natasha</producer>
    <producer>Salmon, Dan</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Town, Jed</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lee, Hye Rim</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>TOKI a 3D bunny-girl is the sexually complex subject of beautiful and disturbing video art. Her creator, Hye Rim Lee is not yet a household name in New Zealand, but she should be. Hye Rim is intent on being the next Jeff Koons and is arguably one of New Zealand's most successful artists. Already represented by the most important gallery in Asia, Kukjegallery, this year she's taken on the West. In 2008 Hye Rim's works have exhibited in Berlin, Wellington, Auckland, Shanghai, Seoul, Sydney, Spain and New York City. TOKI Does New York partners the bubbly, vivacious and driven Hye Rim and her uber-sexy creation Toki as they open a 'make or break' solo-show at the Max Lang gallery in New York's art capital, Chelsea. And to add to the pressure Hye Rim transforms herself into Toki for a live performance with underground musician Jed Town. TOKI Does New York gives the audience an exclusive inside view of the New York art scene, and through Hye Rim, we learn what it takes to make it in one of the toughest art cities of the world.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?611331</url></doc>
