<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="612108">
  <docid>612108</docid>
  <title>Tomorrow Will Never Come</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bauer, Matt (IV)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">20 May 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">15</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>McInerney, Michael (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Barrio, Chris</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>McInerney, Michael (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Krey, Terence</actor>
      <role>Phoenix Renatus</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Tomorrow Will Never Come is a story we've all lived. A story that follows a man who's gone beyond the end of the chain, who's made the wrong turn a hundred miles ago. In the twilight hours when you cannot sleep, you wander your house and wonder about all the bad things, what choices you could've had made better - what choices you could have made and where they'd bring you. This is the exact kind of night that plagues main character Phoenix Renatus - the loneliness, the desperation, the cry for absolution from it all. Out of patience and time to sleep for the next day of work, Phoenix showers and wonders about all the useless things in his life. When he discovers the book he once wrote at a better time in his life, he becomes inspired to try to make an effort to escape the mundanity of the existence he's created for himself - he tries to get his book published. Phoenix calls in and quits his job and escapes his cold, boxed in apartment, first grabbing a pack of cigarettes from the drawer. He wanders the city on his way to the publisher and thinks about the things no one else challenges themselves to. He settles underneath a bridge in a break in his journey to smoke a cigarette and from behind the bridge emerges a girl who has an avid interest in his book. As she takes it from him and begins to read, both become strangely aware of the parallels between the reality they're living and the fiction Phoenix crafted years before.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?612108</url></doc>
