<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="613569">
  <docid>613569</docid>
  <title>Torpedo Attack on Port Arthur</title>
  <year>1904</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>War</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">March 1904</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
<plot>We are the first in the field with a wonderfully accurate and realistic series showing the highly exciting conflicts between the Russians and Japanese. These films will be the most wonderful money earners of the century. The people of America are greatly excited over the doings of the little brown fellow and the big giant with whiskers. The battles are just far enough away to make business good in this country without causing the awful hardships of war. No war series offers the highly picturesque coloring and exciting action. Both sides are fierce and desperate fighters and the background of strange huts and villages is entrancing in the extreme. It is a series of motion war pictures that will live for years after peace follows death and carnage, and the accuracy and thrilling features can not be questioned. We are admirably situated for getting out the successive films of this series with the utmost promptness. With several correspondents in the field, arrangements for the reception of first copies of foreign made films, night-and-day arrangements here for getting out the positives, nobody can compete with us. Besides, we have on our staff a former naval expert who is thoroughly familiar with all the locations in the far East that will come under the focus of public vision during the war. His assistance and advice will be invaluable to assist in establishing the accuracy of details in our reproductions of the most thrilling and yet-to-be famous films. No series of war films has ever drawn the money that our new reproductions of the Japan-Russian struggles will. This, the first of the battles, is one of the fiercest engagements fought. The Japanese Torpedo Boats crept quite close to the Russian ships before they were discovered. Each of the Japanese boats discharged torpedoes, three of which took effect, striking the Battleships "Csarevitch" and "Retvizan" and the Cruiser "Pallada." The Russians had been surprised. Notwithstanding the continuous fire from the Russian Forts and Fleet, the Japanese Torpedo Boats escaped, but had left death and destruction behind. This picture shows the harbor at Port Arthur, the Russian Battleships, "Csarevitch" and Retvizan" and the Cruiser "Pallada" at the entrance. The Japanese Torpedo Boats are seen approaching to within striking distance. Suddenly a well directed torpedo is seen to explode under the Russian Cruiser "Pallada" and carnage and blood fills the air. It is awful in its reality and chills pass through the frame of the spectator as it slowly sinks. This is the first stroke of the bells of war and we are the first in the market with the film. It is wonderful in every respect.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?613569</url></doc>
