<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="614785">
  <docid>614785</docid>
  <title>Tower House</title>
  <year>1962</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Ansari, Nisar Ahmad</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Malhotra, J.C.</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Ravi (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ajit (I)</actor>
      <role>Suresh Kumar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ansari, Nisar Ahmad</actor>
      <role>Ranjeet</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Banerjee, S.N. (I)</actor>
      <role>Seth Durgadas</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhagwan, Master</actor>
      <role>Ajay</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Devi, Pratima</actor>
      <role>Suresh's Mother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Madhumati</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Mystery surrounds the ruins of an old tower house, where at select nights, a woman comes out wailing a song, amidst people committing suicide by throwing themselves off the tower. The police investigate this, but are baffled, and unable to solve this mystery. The woman is Seth Durgadas' late wife. The police interview Seth Durgadas but nothing comes of it. In the meantime, Ranjeet (N.A. Ansari) rescues Sabita (Shakila), the only daughter of Seth Durgadas from the clutches of a tiger, and himself is disfigured for life. Out of pity, Durgadas appoints him manager of his organization and wealth, and soon a greedy Ranjeet starts showing his true colors, which ultimately result in the murder of Durgadas, and the prime suspect is none other than Suresh Kumar (Ajit), the man who Sabita loves. Sabita changes her mind, and Suresh disappears from their lives, apparently on the run. Ranjeet plots and schemes to drive Sabita mad, so that he can take over her wealth. Will Ranjeet succeed? What is the secret of the Tower House?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?614785</url></doc>
