<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="618297">
  <docid>618297</docid>
  <title>Trip: Remix Your Experience</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>pop-music</keyword>
    <keyword>experimental</keyword>
    <keyword>collage</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>German</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Japan">1 May 2005</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Germany">18 May 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="France">20 May 2006</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">15 April 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">74</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Otto, Frank (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kohler-Adams, Bernt</producer>
    <producer>Otto, Frank (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Kohler-Adams, Bernt</writer>
    <writer>Otto, Frank (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kohler-Adams, Bernt</composer>
    <composer>Otto, Frank (II)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fröhlich, Andreas (I)</actor>
      <role>Speaker (segment "Track 2: Subway Story")</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>TRIP is the filming of music. Back in 2001, Frank Otto and Bernt Köhler-Adams developed the basic idea for a song that was to become the driving force behind an extraordinary synthesis of the arts. The two musicians realized very quickly that the final result was going to differ fundamentally from the structure of other songs and ended up being over 74 minutes long. Frank Otto and Bernt Köhler-Adams shared their visions with 12 more musician friends. Each of them used their instruments, their voices and their hearts to add yet another color to the whole. One track - one take. And then the pictures came. Over the 4 years that followed, 33 film-makers staged their own cinematic interpretations of the original work of music. "element" became "TRIP". Whether as an art performance (ARTWORK), underwater film (SEAMUSIC), journey around the world (PLAYING PLANET) or collage of short films (TRACK 2) - the film-makers of "TRIP" selected the widest range of stylistic tools to visualize the music. In the end, those tools merged together to form a magical ecstasy of images. The creative freedom displayed by the musicians, actors, actresses and film-makers who collaborated on the project, combined with the ongoing inspiration provided by the project's many friends, have marked and shaped "TRIP" over and over again anew to this very day.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?618297</url></doc>
