<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="619076">
  <docid>619076</docid>
  <title>Troubadours</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">107</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Galassi, Adam</director>
    <director>Galassi, Tom (II)</director>
    <director>Snyder, Tom (VI)</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Galassi, Adam</writer>
    <writer>Snyder, Tom (VI)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>McCarthy, Tom (XVI)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barnes, Craig (IV)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Blair, Ed (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Estill, Gabe</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fess, Chad</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Galassi, Tom (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Marcotte, David</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sullivan, Matthew Napier</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zielinski, Patrick</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>After parting ways with his girlfriend, unemployed drummer, Art finds himself broke, bitter, and on the verge of a breakdown. He leaves the big city and returns home to work for his father on the family farm. There he navigates a new field of possibilities and disappointments, meeting new friends and renewing bonds with old ones. Art s quest to quiet his anxieties and discover where he belongs is a universal one as old as storytelling itself. It s the search for life s meaning and a place in this world. Brothers Tom and Adam Galassi collaborated with close friend Tom Snyder for the trio s directorial debut. They set their coming-of-age tale in downstate Illinois, effectively capturing the heart and flavor of the real Midwest in this award-winning indie film. The soundtrack features the combination of an original score by Tom McCarthy and music featuring My Morning Jacket, Devil in a Woodpile, South San Gabriel, &amp; Centromatic. Route 66 Film Festival, Best Feature River s Edge Film Festival, Avery Crouse Award Big Muddy Film Festival, Official Selection Show-Me Missouri International Film Festival, Official Selection</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?619076</url></doc>
