<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="619149">
  <docid>619149</docid>
  <title>Trouble for Two</title>
  <year>1994</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adult</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>sex</keyword>
    <keyword>bondage</keyword>
    <keyword>hardcore</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kane, Sharon</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Majors, Bill</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Terri has heard about Bill Major's reputation and has traveled cross country to train under him and learn true slavery. She is naive about what is to occur but is eager to learn. After a somewhat terrifying ordeal of being spread on a cross, stripped, and teased Terri is told that Master Majors is going to have his slave Sharon begin training her. Terri is clad in a sexy rubber outfit with a leash tied to severe nipple clamps and finds herself pulled by the Master's assistant, Sharon. Sharon ties her to a table, teases her and delights in placing tight clips on her breasts. When Master Majors walks in and discovers his slave is having "too much fun", he punishes the two by tying them together in some erotic positions. The two girls are forced to savor each others' bodies and the application of Master Major's whip. Mistress Jennifer is called in to assist in the training and she is all too eager to drip hot candle wax onto Terri's breasts. She and Master Majors entertain themselves by watching the two whimper, beg and bargain as birthday candles placed on their nipples are allowed to burn down close to the skin. The two are the left alone, bound together in a most uncomfortable position with the leg of one bound to the breast of the other! Terri works herself loose and takes her revenge on Sharon with the very same clips she was tormented with earlier. The story ends with Master Majors ordering the two of them to present their bottoms and proceeding to perform a fast, furious, and forceful simultaneous spankings.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?619149</url></doc>
