<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="619619">
  <docid>619619</docid>
  <title>Truffe</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Comeau, Richard (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>French</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Netherlands">17 April 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Czech Republic">15 August 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Canada">22 August 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Nguyen, Kim (IV)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Nguyen, Kim (IV)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Nguyen, Kim (IV)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Babin, Karim</actor>
      <role>Premier vendeur de truffes</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bonnier, Céline</actor>
      <role>Alice</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bourdage, Jean-Robert</actor>
      <role>Le client affamé</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dupuis, Roy</actor>
      <role>Charles</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lapointe, Jean (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lebeau, Pierre</actor>
      <role>M. Tremblay</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Verreault, Jean-Nicolas</actor>
      <role>Électricien</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In a near and uneasy future, global warming has had an unexpected impact on the city of Montreal. Very suddenly, the ground of the Hochelaga-Maisonneuve district has begun sprouting vast quantities of precious, pricey truffles. They are an immediate sensation worldwide with gourmands, bringing prosperity to Montrealers. When a fur-stole factory sets up shop in the neighbourhood, no one doubts that it's a front for a greedy corporation seeking a monopoly over the valuable truffles. Before long, the earth begins to give up the last of its riches and poverty returns to the working class. The enigmatic company does have one challenger - Charles (Dupuis), an independent truffle - hunter with an exceptional sense of smell, permitting him to make great hauls of truffles. Ready to do anything to block the competition, the company sets in motion furious diabolical plots to undo Charles and his companion Alice (Bonnier). Alone again the powerful organization, the couple can count on none but themselves to survive...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?619619</url></doc>
