<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="619755">
  <docid>619755</docid>
  <title>Truth &amp; Treason</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>History</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>nazi-resistance</keyword>
    <keyword>nazi-germany</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Whitaker, Matt</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Molen, Gerald R.</producer>
    <producer>Urie, Peter</producer>
    <producer>Kendall, Russ</producer>
    <producer>Merrill, Micah W.</producer>
    <producer>Whitaker, Matt</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Vincent, Ethan</writer>
    <writer>Whitaker, Matt</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>King, Jamie Thomas</actor>
      <role>Karl-Heinz Schnibbe</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Osment, Haley Joel</actor>
      <role>Helmuth Hübener</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>von Sydow, Max (I)</actor>
      <role>Franz Fikeis</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>: 1941, Hamburg Germany. A loyal Hitler Youth listens quietly to an illegal short-wave radio -- BBC broadcasts denouncing Hitler's war machine. Fueled by the nightly broadcasts, young Helmuth Hübener is convinced that Hitler is not the savior of the people but in fact the seducer. The final blow comes when his good friend Salomon, a Jew, is thrust into a concentration camp. Standing in the ransacked chaos of Salomon's empty home, Helmuth decides he must do something. He turns to the only weapon he knows: the written word. Overnight, hand-typed fliers on deep red parchment appear on the streets of Hamburg. "Hitler is a Murderer! He is the guilty one!" Within days he recruits his two best friends. By cover of night, the three boys disperse fliers that rage against Hitler and the Nazi regime. For the boys, it is just the beginning. For the Gestapo, it is high treason. Agent Erich Müssener begins a relentless pursuit of those behind the treasonous fliers. Nearly a year later, he finally apprehends the perpetrators and is stunned to discover that it was all carried out by three teenage boys. The prisoners are dragged before Hitler's highest court, the Blood Tribunal, where they are convicted of high treason. Helmuth's friends are sentenced to years in a Nazi prison camp. For Helmuth, the sentence is death by guillotine. He would become the youngest resistance fighter to pay for his beliefs with his life. He was 17. Truth and Treason is the inspiring story of three young men who take a stand for truth against the greatest tyrant in history.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?619755</url></doc>
