<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="619895">
  <docid>619895</docid>
  <title>Trzech Kumpli</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Ciodyk, Robert</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Polish</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Poland</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Poland">19 July 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Poland">107</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Ferens, Anna</director>
    <director>Stankiewicz, Ewa</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Stankiewicz, Ewa</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Buda, Mariusz</actor>
      <role>Staszek</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Poniedzialek, Andrzej</actor>
      <role>Leszek</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wachuda, Wojciech</actor>
      <role>Bronek</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>They met as students and they became very good friends. Young, handsome, popular among women. Individuals with strong personalities. They all opposed the hypocrisy, injustice and humiliation that were so closely linked to the communist system. They infected other people with freedom. They studied in the 70ies - during the times of strong censorship and ruthless secret police actions. Staszek, Leszek and Bronek. Outstanding minds. No surprise that after almost twenty years they became publicists and co-founders of nationwide daily newspapers: Leslaw Maleszka became an editor in "Gazeta Wyborcza", Bronislaw Wildstein in "Rzeczpospolita" and Stanislaw Pyjas... If he was alive, maybe he would also be a journalist or a poet - that's what his friends say. He died as a student, probably killed by the Secret Police. His murderers have never been sentenced. The authors of the feature documentary "Three Buddies" try to learn the truth about Pyjas' death. They hear many lies and mutually exclusive accounts, meet the never interrogated witnesses, talk with the former Secret Police officers. They also speak to Leslaw Maleszka. Today we already know that he was one of those who informed on Pyjas, his friend.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?619895</url></doc>
