<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="620525">
  <docid>620525</docid>
  <title>Tucker</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Jacobsen, Michael (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>premature-birth</keyword>
    <keyword>aging-disorder</keyword>
    <keyword>fish-out-of-water</keyword>
    <keyword>student-film</keyword>
    <keyword>mother-son-relationship</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">10</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Marashi, Zia</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Jacobsen, Michael (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Peebles, Andrew</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chamberlain, Chaz</actor>
      <role>Adult Tucker</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chipiuk, McKenzie</actor>
      <role>Stacy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dales, Nathan</actor>
      <role>Jim</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fex, Andre</actor>
      <role>Senior Tucker</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hempseed, Shane</actor>
      <role>Drew</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Omaid, Shaun</actor>
      <role>Officer Jack</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Porteous, Nicholas</actor>
      <role>Young Adult Tucker</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>After a fight with her mother, Sara has one last chance to prove she's responsible enough to be left home alone. Within that time Sara finds herself faced with an unplanned pregnancy, only it's a little more complicated: as within minutes she has passed through all her trimesters and before she knows it a child is born! After the father skips town Sara is left alone to raise her son, Tucker, who seems to be aging faster then she can keep track of. By the first hour Tucker is already entering puberty and has fallen for the first girl he sees ditching his mom and exploring the world outside her bedroom. Easily Tucker has become the life of the party. Sara tracks down her son, who now looks much older than Sara, and has an argument over how irresponsible he has become. Its only when the party turns on Tucker and throws him out that Sara comes to understand parenthood, and makes a decision to make amends to her child who she realizes she loves very much. When police come to break up the party, they make things worse by attempting to arrest Sara. Tucker makes a sacrifice and goes in her place. Sara watches helpless as her child, now an 80-year-old man is taken away. In the closing scenes life has returned to normal and the entire night seems like a dream. Or was it?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?620525</url></doc>
