<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="620913">
  <docid>620913</docid>
  <title>Tune Mera Dil Le Liyaa</title>
  <year>2000</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Bhalla, B.B.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bhalla, Bharat B.</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Sharma, Kishore (II)</composer>
    <composer>Sharma, Mahesh (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Birbal</actor>
      <role>Suleiman (Raja's chauffeur)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chandran, Sudha</actor>
      <role>Rani (Veeru's girlfriend)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Denzongpa, Danny</actor>
      <role>Raja Sahab</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kambikar, Madhu</actor>
      <role>Madhu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Annu</actor>
      <role>K.K.'s assistant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Shakti (I)</actor>
      <role>K.K. (Kishan Kanhaiya)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Manmauji</actor>
      <role>Rani's admirer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mathur, Jaya</actor>
      <role>Kiran Mehra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nagrath, Anil</actor>
      <role>Principal Mehra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Roy, Rahul</actor>
      <role>Vijay</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shah, Naseeruddin</actor>
      <role>Veeru</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Raja Saheb lives a wealthy life-style together with his wife, Madhu, and her brother, Veeru. Both Madhu and Raja have been heart-broken several times when they have had miscarriages. Now Madhu is pregnant again and Raja is reluctant to send her to any hospital. She does give birth to a baby boy, but tragically passes away. Raja and Veeru undertake to look after the child, who they name, Vijay. Raja pampers and spoils him to the point of smothering him with his love and devotion, so much so when Vijay grows up he has mental capacity of a child, and is nicknamed "Left Right" by collegians. Then one day Vijay meets Janam and everything changes for him, both fall in love with each other, and Vijay stands up for himself and becomes a man. When the time comes to get married to Janam, Raja opposes this marriage as he wants Vijay to get married to Principal Mehra's daughter, Kiran. Vijay, who is unable to get Janam out of his mind, goes to meet her, and that's when he gets the shock of his life - for Janam is not who she claims to be - but is actually a prostitute by the name of Reshma.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?620913</url></doc>
