<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="621953">
  <docid>621953</docid>
  <title>Twilight Blind</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bradway, Nicholas Rubino</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Mystery</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">7 August 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">32</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Bradway, Nicholas Rubino</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bradway, Caitlen Rubino</producer>
    <producer>Bradway, William</producer>
    <producer>Bradway, Nicholas Rubino</producer>
    <producer>Rubino, Jane</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bradway, Nicholas Rubino</writer>
    <writer>Rubino, Jane</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Baum, Steven (II)</actor>
      <role>Friend #1</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brecker, Robin</actor>
      <role>Father Mike</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rico, Joseph</actor>
      <role>Friend #2</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Unsworth, Nathan</actor>
      <role>Ben</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Ben is no different from any other kid - summer job, afternoons at the beach, hanging out with his friends, and if he's late for work, or forgets a promise, or tells himself that tomorrow is soon enough, well....he's no different from any other kid. One morning starts of pretty much like the one before - Ben jumps out of bed, late for work, rushes to his job at a local restaurant, hurries in with a ready apology and finds the restaurant vacant. The power is out, the grill is cold, the phone is dead. He recalls, with some relief, that there was an important farewell Mass that day and hurries to church. The church is silent and vacant. The stores, the streets, the playgrounds, the beach are empty. Confusion turns to desperation, and to dread. Ben returns to a dark, empty house. In his room, he finds a video recorder with an old tape of a party. He curls up on his bed, watching the images of his family and friends until the battery dies. Ben jumps out of bed, late for work, rushes to his job at a local restaurant. It's a day exactly like every other day. But is this day the day after a frightening dream, or the day before....?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?621953</url></doc>
