<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="630763">
  <docid>630763</docid>
  <title>Ungebrochen</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Höhn, Jolanka</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>German</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Germany">30 May 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Slovakia">6 September 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Poland">17 November 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Switzerland">17 September 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">6 February 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Denmark">16 March 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Germany">6</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Höhn, Jolanka</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Volmar, Axel</producer>
    <producer>Höhn, Jolanka</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Höhn, Jolanka</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hoehn, Wolfgang</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Wolfgang, in his fifties now, grew up in the former GDR. He studied external trade in Berlin and after his diploma worked for 17 years at TechnoCommerz, a company specialized in machine trade for the delivery industry. With the fall of the wall, he has to change professions and becomes an insurance salesman. First employed with a German insurance firm, then he starts his own company and manages to make ends meet for a couple of years. But when his company goes bankrupt, Wolfgang is able to find different jobs, but no fixed employment. In 2001, he sees no other choice but to register himself unemployed for the first time. Not until 2005, his job agent offers him a so-called One-Euro-Job at a Berlin school library, which he gladly accepts. Working with children and daily contact to his colleagues allow him to reintegrate fully into society and also give him the feeling of being useful. Against great odds (the fall of the wall and the consequences derived) Wolfgang does not seem to have lost his courage to face life. Seventeen years after the German Reunification the portrait provides a very personal insight into his life.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?630763</url></doc>
