<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="631270">
  <docid>631270</docid>
  <title>Unlocking the Heart of Adoption</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Ganz, Sheila</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>adoption</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">14 November 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">40</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="USA">56</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Ganz, Sheila</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ganz, Sheila</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Ganz, Sheila</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Watkins, Mary</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>The 56 minute documentary "Unlocking the Heart of Adoption" chronicles filmmaker, Sheila Ganz's journey as a birthmother, and reveals the personal stories of adoptees, birthparents and adoptive parents. These stories span 70 years, beginning with ALICE, a birthmother whose child was adopted out without her consent in 1922; RON, an adoptee who uncovered the truth after his parents died when he was 36; and, PHYLLIS and ALISON, birth and adoptive mothers of twin boys born in 1991. Phyllis chose Alison and her husband as parents for her sons in an open adoption. We also meet DEBBIE - Japanese American, PAUL - Filipino American and MARTIN - African American, all adopted into families of other ethnicities. Difficult and touching moments ensue between Martin and his white father, HAL. These and other stories provide a window into the lifelong process of adoption - bridging the gap between birth and adoptive families. Transracial adoptions, issues of closed records, historical perspective and the personal story of the filmmaker - who was raped at age 20 and unwillingly relinquishing her daughter - make this film the most comprehensive to date. The filmmaker's extraordinary rapport with her subjects affords a view into the innermost feelings, fears and joys of the adoption triad.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?631270</url></doc>
