<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="631284">
  <docid>631284</docid>
  <title>Unmada</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Gomez, Georgiana</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="France">1 February 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">19</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Sanchez, Nancy (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Sanjay (II)</producer>
    <producer>Patel, Mitesh</producer>
    <producer>Sanchez, Gladys</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Sanchez, Gladys</writer>
    <writer>Sanchez, Nancy (III)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Niu, Dana</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Iskander, John</actor>
      <role>Farooqui</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Malil, Shelley</actor>
      <role>Ajit</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McMahon, Lorie</actor>
      <role>Homeless Girl</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mhatre, Amol</actor>
      <role>Iswar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Naicker, Sashen</actor>
      <role>Rao</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Patel, Mitesh</actor>
      <role>Akash</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Thiara, Kiki</actor>
      <role>Girl in the Tent</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Brothers, Akash and Iswar, of the "Shudra" caste (Farmer caste), are being chased across an Indian marketplace. They have stolen jewelry from a Brahman caste family and end up in an alley where three "untouchables" hide from society. The hatred between the two castes is felt, but no one can leave, aware of the consequences if they do. That night, Ajit, the oldest of the untouchables, tells Akash about a treasure map he found and the myth attached to it. Fascinated by the myth of a girl who offers anyone unimaginable wealth and power for the return of her map, the brothers fight the untouchables for the map. Akash kills Ajit and steals the map. Akash and Iswar cross a desert in search of the treasure. After a vicious sandstorm, Akash is lured by a girl's chant and discovers she is the one spoken about in the myth. The girl invites Akash into her tent and offers him the treasure. Before he can claim the treasure, she warns Akash he will have to turn against his brother for it, as only one man can truly possess it. Akash rejects the girl's offer. Iswar sees that Akash still has the map and steals it from him. Iswar decides to claim the treasure for himself and kills Akash. When Iswar goes back to the tent, the girl is gone. He opens the box and finds it empty. It was all a myth after all. Iswar dies next to his brother.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?631284</url></doc>
