<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="631583">
  <docid>631583</docid>
  <title>Unseen to Be Seen</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Narayana, J.V.L.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Musical</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>religion</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>hindu</keyword>
    <keyword>pilgrimage</keyword>
    <keyword>temple</keyword>
    <keyword>experimental-film</keyword>
    <keyword>architecture</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Telugu</language>
    <language>Kannada</language>
    <language>Hindi</language>
    <language>Tamil</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">31 July 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="India">42</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Narayana, J.V.L.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Vaka, Rambabu</producer>
    <producer>Narendra, T.</producer>
    <producer>Prasad, K. Hanumath</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Neela, Jayakumar</composer>
  </composers>
  <othercrew>
    <credit>
      <name>Krishna, A. Murali</name>
      <job/>
    </credit>
  </othercrew>
<plot>Tirumala, the holy abode of Sri Venkateshwara, who self manifested to redeem sins of his devotees and to protect one and all, is the holiest place on the earth. Adisesha, the holy serpent spread its hoods as cushions in the form of Seshachala, Garudachala, Venkatachala, Narayanachala, Anjanachala, Vrishabhachala, and Vrishachala hills in order to serve the Maha Vishnu. The ever-effulgent and merciful Sri Venkateshwara is truly the Kaliyugavarada, who fulfills the desires of all his devotees from Tirumala Hills. The Tirumala, is as sacred as the vedas and is composed of Saligramas. It sheds light and peace to all those who take refugee under Lord Sri Venkateshwara's name. The Tirumala Temple is always abuzz with full of religious activities with Nityotsava, Pakshotsava, Masotsava and Samvatsrotsavas sevas being conducted through out the year. Revered by millions of devotees from all over the world. The Tirumala Temple was built by emperor Tondaman. However, in the course of time, the temple was renovated many times with worship and other rituals began to be conducted regularly. This is the temple renovated by great kings and emperors with their grants and offerings. This is the sacred temple which was praised by many musicians and composers with their devotional renderings. Come, Let us visit, this sacred shrine to experience devotional ecstasy and seek divine grace.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?631583</url></doc>
