<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="631525">
  <docid>631525</docid>
  <title>Unrivaled</title>
  <year>2010</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>title-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">6 December 2010</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Sonoda, Warren P.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bursteen, Alan B.</producer>
    <producer>Echavarria, Hector</producer>
    <producer>Wertlieb, Stan</producer>
    <producer>Bekerman, Daniel (I)</producer>
    <producer>Brooker, Barry</producer>
    <producer>Buckley, Sean (III)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bode, Brad</writer>
    <writer>Echavarria, Hector</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arce, Pedro Miguel</actor>
      <role>Big Eddie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Campbell, Nicholas (I)</actor>
      <role>Raphael</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Echavarria, Hector</actor>
      <role>Ringo Duran</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Evans, Rashad</actor>
      <role>Christopher Holland</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fong, Tig</actor>
      <role>Razer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ganderton, Monique</actor>
      <role>Gracie Duran</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Griffin, Forrest</actor>
      <role>Gregor Popoff.</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Herring, Heath</actor>
      <role>Demoledoe</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hubbard, Ashleigh</actor>
      <role>Pepper</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jardine, Keith</actor>
      <role>Stone</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Machida, Ryoto</actor>
      <role>Kamikaze</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Madley, Jordan</actor>
      <role>Kara</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nappo, Tony</actor>
      <role>Ref Dangelo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rogers, James Preston</actor>
      <role>Sandor 'Fingers' Duarte</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Yaffee, Steven</actor>
      <role>Link</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The best fighter in the world works two jobs and supports his sister. The only problem... he doesn't know he's the best. Ringo Duran, the son of Gracie Duran, a famous Argentinian kick boxer, works two jobs to make ends meet. His passion, full contact fighting. His goal, fulfill a lifelong dream of becoming a professional fighter. Ringo has put off attempts at a professional career for so long he has nearly succumbed to age. When the Extreme Cage Fighting(ECF) league, the preeminent full contact fighting promoters, announce a competition to select the best undiscovered fighter, Ringo's friends urge him to join. Ringo, once again, claims he is not ready. Even KARA, Ringo's love interest, pushes him to join, but Ringo resists. Seeing his skill and desire to become a professional she surprises him with a last minute visit to the ECF: Undiscovered registration. Eight fighters will be selected. Thousands submit and the chances of making the cut are slim. One day, at Ringo's local training gym, the ECF owner and current heavyweight champion enter the gym followed by a camera crew. Christopher watches Ringo practicing. Christopher, aware of Ringo's mother, chats with Ringo and ends up putting on the gloves for a quick spar. Ringo knocks him down as the cameras roll and it ends up on sports news shows across the nation. Will he fulfill his life long dream and continue his mothers legacy?  Will he be the best fighter in the world?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?631525</url></doc>
