<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="631953">
  <docid>631953</docid>
  <title>Untethered</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Hensley, Robert (IV)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>rescue</keyword>
    <keyword>chain</keyword>
    <keyword>animal-welfare</keyword>
    <keyword>dog</keyword>
    <keyword>legislation</keyword>
    <keyword>ordinance</keyword>
    <keyword>north-carolina</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">39</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Hensley, Lori</director>
    <director>Hensley, Robert (IV)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hensley, Lori</producer>
    <producer>Hensley, Robert (IV)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Hensley, Robert (IV)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arrington, Amanda</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arrington, Casey</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hensley, Lori</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hensley, Robert (IV)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In 2006, Amanda and Casey Arrington moved from Texas to Durham, North Carolina, where they started a group called Coalition to Unchain Dogs. The purpose of the group, in the long term, was to advocate for the passage of legislation banning or restricting the practice of chaining. In the short term, the group would provide free fences, free spay/neuter, and free basic veterinary care for chained dogs in the community, so that the dogs could have room to run and be free from their chains. This short documentary follows the experience of the Coalition through two of the group's volunteers, Robert and Lori Hensley, as they and the Arringtons rescue Fluffy, a dog severely injured by an embedded tether. Fluffy's story serves as a frame for the Coalition's work and an illustration of the challenges the group has to overcome. The film documents Amanda's skills at building trust with Durham's community members, the deliberations and questions the Arringtons and Hensleys wrestle with during their rescue of Fluffy, and the successful community organizing efforts of the Coalition that culminate in the passage of an ordinance banning the chaining of dogs in Durham.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?631953</url></doc>
