<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="633427">
  <docid>633427</docid>
  <title>Urban Rescuers</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Navia, Andrés (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">40</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Navia, Andrés (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Fredsti, Dana</producer>
    <producer>Corda, Nikki</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Corda, Nikki</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Adams, Tree</composer>
    <composer>Oldman, Kurt</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Metropole, Christi</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Astonishingly, nearly 4 million stray or feral cats inhabit the streets, parks, back alleys and backyards of Los Angeles County, and they are reproducing at an alarming rate. The current solution is round-up and kill. But is there a better way? Urban Rescuers profiles a group of fiercely dedicated animal welfare crusaders in Los Angeles who skirt the law in order to rescue feral cats from the certain death they face upon landing in animal shelters. The methodology involves a controversial solution for feral cats known as "TNR" (trap, neuter, return), which calls for sterilizing these animals and then allowing them to live out their lives in the wild. As the TNR process is revealed, passionate and surprising arguments on both sides of the issue are heard from the heads of PETA (People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals), the Feral Cat Alliance, the Los Angeles SPCA, and the Los Angeles Department of Animal Regulation, among others. The documentary shows that TNR is legal in other communities where it works efficiently, within the system. As we investigate, Los Angeles officials are asked to adopt the policy. Urban Rescuers is a thought-provoking journey of ethics, featuring big personalities and stunning footage of feral cats in our community.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?633427</url></doc>
