<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="634951">
  <docid>634951</docid>
  <title>Vachan</title>
  <year>1955</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Shrikhande, R.V.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">1955</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Rishi, Raj</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Goel, Devendra</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Sharma, Mukhram</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Chandra (IX)</composer>
    <composer>Ravi (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Babboo</actor>
      <role>Young Kishore</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bali, Geeta</actor>
      <role>Kamla - Dinanath's daughter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Balraj (III)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brij (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Rajendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Kishore</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Neroo</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Prem, S.K.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, Madan (I)</actor>
      <role>Laxmidas</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Radhakrishan</actor>
      <role>Kashiram 'Munshi'</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rajdeep (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tiwari, Ramayan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Kamla lives a poor lifestyle in a small town in Uttar Pradesh, India, along with her widowed dad, Dinanath, who works as an Accountant with Sarpanch Journal, and two younger brothers, college-going Kumar, and school-going 12 year old brother, Kishore. Dinanath's main aim is to get Kamla married to her lover, wealthy Prem, and ensure that Kumar and Kishore get a proper college education. When Dinanath's eyesight becomes very weak, he starts making errors, and loses his job. He does manage to persuade his employer, Laxmidas, to hire Kumar once he gets his degree in Arts. On the day of the results, Kumar has an accident and passes away, a devastated Dinanath bangs his head, injures himself, is hospitalized, recovers but loses his vision completely. As a result, Kamla's wedding is canceled, Prem reluctantly gets married to Shyama; while Kamla gets a job and starts to look after her dad and Kishore. Years pass by, Kishore has grown up, graduates, gets a job, gets married to Tara, the niece of Kashiram, Prem's Munshi. The family settles down to a fairly harmonious relationship which is shattered when Kishore and Tara accuse Kamla of stealing household items, resulting in Kamla and her dad moving out of the house. Kamla and her dad live a near-destitute life, and Kamla gets a job to look after an ailing Shyama, while Prem is away. Watch what happens when Shyama finds out that she has hired her husband's ex-lover, and the very woman she suspects is still having an affair with him.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?634951</url></doc>
