<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="635011">
  <docid>635011</docid>
  <title>Vadim's Story: Summer in Siberia</title>
  <year>1999</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Adult</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Russian</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">15 December 1999</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">110</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Arefyev, Andrey</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Eisenlohr, David</producer>
    <producer>Arefyev, Andrey</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Alekseev, Sergey (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Antsiferov, Danil</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Baranov, Alexander</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Burtsev, Maxim</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Butorin, Anton</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dorofeev, Nickolai</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kotov, Andrey (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Krutzev, Nickolai</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maxim (V)</actor>
      <role>Vadim's younger brother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maximenko, Alexey</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Petrichenko, Vadim</actor>
      <role>Vadim</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pustynnikov, Andrey</actor>
      <role>Andrey</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tarasov, Sergey (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Volokitin, Andrey</actor>
      <role>Himself - twin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Volokitin, Sergey</actor>
      <role>Himself - twin</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Siberia - For most people the very word conjures up bleak images of wind-swept frozen tundra and a dreary existence best endured indoors. Few would ever picture it as a land decorated by lush forests, crystal clear lakes and sun-bronzed lads romping in the buff. So when the short summer does arrive, the Siberian people embrace it warmly, and no more so than the handsome young boys of Vadim's Story. From its intriguing shots of foggy mountains and quaint old wooden houses, you know you're not in America. With the first glimpse of eighteen-year-old Vadim as he awakens to a spectacular sunny day - you may just think you're in heaven. Vadim is the central star of this simple slice-of-life tale and his ability to cast a seductive spell over the viewer is magical. He shares his morning shower with us and introduces us to his little brother and their new-found puppy. Then he's off to join more than a dozen other teenage hopefuls at an audition for an American video production. Finally, Vadim makes his way to glistening Lake Arakhlei - where he joins his closest comrade, Andrey, for a holiday of intimate adolescent play and naturism. In these exquisitely photographed scenes we are treated to a stunning symphony of skin, sand and sun that resonates with a subtle nuance of eroticism that will leave you breathless and wanting more.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?635011</url></doc>
