<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="635106">
  <docid>635106</docid>
  <title>Vahinichi Maya</title>
  <year>1985</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Marathi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">1985</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Sohoni, Kumar</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Deshmukh, Geeta V.</producer>
    <producer>Sohoni, Kumar</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Mohile, Anil</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ashalata</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Deshmukh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Berde, Ravindra</actor>
      <role>Dinu Deshmukh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhatkar, Ramesh</actor>
      <role>Yogesh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chavan, Vijay (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deo, Ajinkya</actor>
      <role>Dr. Rajesh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kubal, Alka</actor>
      <role>Madhavi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kulkarni, Ashok</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lad, Kavita</actor>
      <role>Priya Deshmukh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shirsekar, Shashikant</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Rajesh studies in a medical college and lives a middle-class life with his elder, crippled brother, Yogesh, his Bhabhi, Madhavi, who is a devotee of Bhagwan Shri Sai Baba, and a trusted servant, Ramu. Yogesh is employed as an Accountant and continues to work despite of his disability so that Rajesh could become a doctor and fulfill his dreams. Madhavi gets pregnant but due to an internal womb injury is unable and will never conceive. Then after passing his exams, Rajesh gets married to his wealthy sweetheart, Priya Deshmukh, much to the displeasure of her mom, as she would have liked her to get married to someone really wealthy. Her efforts to get Rajesh to come and live in their spacious bungalow, and open his own dispensary are all in vain. But she does get some new furniture for Priya, which does not auger well with Madhavi and Yogesh. Yogesh quits his job on Rajesh' and Priya's insistence. When Priya gets pregnant, Ramu informs Rajesh that Madhavi has stolen Priya's gold ear-rings. Rajesh does not believe this, but when Madhavi poisons a glass of milk meant for Priya, he confronts her, gets her to admit that it was indeed she who had stolen the ear-rings as well as poisoned the milk, then he and Priya move out and go to live with the Deshmukhs. With no income coming in, Yogesh starts working as a peon with Sainath Constructions. After Priya gives birth to a baby boy, Rajesh decides to forgive Madhavi and decides to let him see his son - not knowing that he is opening up a Pandora's box that will only result in more bitterness, acrimony, and create even more misunderstandings as well as a death in the family.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?635106</url></doc>
