<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="635219">
  <docid>635219</docid>
  <title>Vakuum</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Behrens, Inge</editor>
    <editor>Hørnes, Geir</editor>
    <editor>Schmoll, Kathrin</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>salesman</keyword>
    <keyword>vacuum-cleaner</keyword>
    <keyword>widow</keyword>
    <keyword>bird</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Norwegian</language>
    <language>German</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
    <country>Norway</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Sweden">September 2005</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Germany">26 June 2004</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Norway">15 October 2004</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">13</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Grampp, Thomas</director>
    <director>Øie, Pål</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Grampp, Thomas</writer>
    <writer>Lange, Cosima</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Pesek, Julian</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Busch, Fabian (I)</actor>
      <role>Mick</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mues, Wanja</actor>
      <role>Sandro</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Norström, Tomas</actor>
      <role>Salesman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pan, Michael</actor>
      <role>Nestor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>von der Meden, Andreas</actor>
      <role>Philemon</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>It is the year 2024. 27-year old Mick works for Singen Industries, the market leader in information technology. One day his job as an engineer brings him to a HIVE. This enormous, completely sterile building provides a living- and workspace for people whose malfunctioning immune systems would make a life in the outside world impossible. When Mick works on the outside of the massive glass façade, the unbelievable happens: Lilia, his childhood sweetheart, who had been thought dead, enters the room behind the window, and long forgotten feelings come back. Although divided by the strong insulating glass, in the moments together they find happiness as never experienced before. When Lilia's only friend inside the HIVE mysteriously disappears, the darker side of Singen Industries' technological achievements becomes apparent. Now Lilia is in great danger. To save her, Mick needs to enter the forbidden zone of the heart of the HIVE. But even his mere presence inside the HIVE's carefully balanced system puts Lilia's life at risk. Taking her out of there would mean to kill her. And yet - in a world where everything is ruled by cold technology, life itself may be the only thing you ultimately cannot lose.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?635219</url></doc>
