<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="636985">
  <docid>636985</docid>
  <title>Veer Ghatotkach</title>
  <year>1970</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">1970</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Soni, Shantilal</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Roy, Dilip (II)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chatterjee, Sulochana</actor>
      <role>Subhadra - Kanhaiya's sister</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chhaya, Laxmi</actor>
      <role>Surekha - Balram's daughter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kesri, Bharat</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Raj (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mahipal</actor>
      <role>Bhagwan Shri Kishan/Kanhaiya</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Meenakshi (IV)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pahelwan, Chandgiram</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Radheshyam (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vyas, B.M.</actor>
      <role>Vidur - Subhadra's guardian</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Before the epic battle between the Kauravs and the Pandavs, the five brothers, Arjun, Bhim, Sahdev, Nakul, and Yudhister are in exile, bereft of all their worldly wealth along with their Draupadi, their wife. While hunting in the forest Bhim comes to the rescue of a maiden named Hidamba, marries her, and goes back to re-join his brothers. Hidamba gives birth to a son, names him Ghatotkach, who is born with special magical powers which are mainly to protect the forest and the animals that dwell in it. Ghatotkach would face off enemies like Duryodhan, his uncle Shakuni on one hand, as well as his half-brother, Abhimanyu, the son of Arjun; his very own biological father, Bhim, as well as face the might of Bhagwan Shri Kishan. Ghatotkach would then come to the aid of Abhimanyu, who is in love with Surekha, the daughter of Balram (Kishan's brother), and would like to marry her. Bhagwan Shri Kishan has already given his blessings to this couple, however, Balram wants Surekha to marry Duryodhan's son, Lakhsman. Hilarious chaos follows when Ghatotkach, Abhimanyu and Bhagwan Shri Kishan get together to try and convince Balram that this alliance is not suitable in the long run.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?636985</url></doc>
