<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="637043">
  <docid>637043</docid>
  <title>Veetho Vastha</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Telugu</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">7 March 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Kumar, K. Ajay</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Rattan, Sudarshan K.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Aggarwal, Rajan</writer>
    <writer>Kumar, K. Ajay</writer>
    <writer>Sudershan, Pandit</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Chandra, Suresh (II)</composer>
    <composer>Srilekha, M.M.</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brahmanandam</actor>
      <role>Elderly College Student</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kant, Shashi</actor>
      <role>Arjun Choudhuri</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Suman (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Arjun Choudhuri lives a wealthy lifestyle along with his dad, and mom, in a small town in India. His dad is very generous, and is friendly with fellow-villager, Vishwanath, who is the father of Asha. Arjun's dad and Vishwanath agree to get Arjun and Asha married when they are older. Shortly thereafter the Choudhuri family's factory catches fire, they become penniless, are forced to move out, and live a poor lifestyle. Vishwanath gets rich, decides to break off all relations with the Choudhuri family, and his brother, Shankar, assaults Arjun's dad, leaving him paralyzed and mentally unstable. Years later Arjun and Asha have grown up, attend the same college, and fall in love with each other. Arjun breaks off all relations with Asha when he finds who she really is, but his dad intervenes, goes to Vishwanath, who humiliates him. When Vishwanath finds out that Asha is determined to marry Arjun, he changes his mind, and decides to arrange a grand marriage. Arjun decides to travel to Haridwar to find a cure for his ailing father, and when he returns nothing is the same anymore - his dad had assaulted Asha and had attempted to kill Vishwanath, and has been institutionalized. The question remains why did Arjun's dad assault Asha and attempt to kill Vishwanath even after the reconciliation between the two families?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?637043</url></doc>
