<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="637363">
  <docid>637363</docid>
  <title>Velocity</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">20 July 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Jensen, Jeff (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Schwartz, Cary (I)</producer>
    <producer>Pompian, Paul</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Jensen, Jeff (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Connery, Jason (I)</actor>
      <role>Mic</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Korikova, Elena</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Soderblom, Nick</actor>
      <role>Iliya</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Lance King is the newest arrival to the MotoGP Championship racing series. His team is owned by a racing legend but is struggling to remain competitive against the deep-pocketed manufacturer teams. They search for money from new sponsors to no avail until someone approaches them and buys the team. The new team owner, Anna Zykov, is an intelligent and well prepared beautiful young woman who's father owns the Russian oil company, Venture Petroleum. Her arrival boosts the team in the MotoGP standings and Anna and Lance become a hot and glamorous couple within the paddock and out of it. Totally unbeknownst to Anna, her father also happens to be the head of the Russian Mafia. When he is arrested and all of his assets are frozen, Anna, Lance and his brother, Cameron, go to Moscow to "borrow" the cash out of her father's safe to keep the team going. Although racing motorcycles at the highest level in the world is a big part of the story, "Velocity" is much more than just a movie about the MotoGP scene. "VELOCITY" is the first dramatic feature film to be allowed inside the world of MotoGP racing . It is endorsed and produced in cooperation with Dorna Sports SL, the rights holder to the sport that 5.1 Billion people per year watch on television and attend during seventeen different events on five continents.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?637363</url></doc>
