<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="638832">
  <docid>638832</docid>
  <title>Vespro siciliano</title>
  <year>1949</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>civil-war</keyword>
    <keyword>sicily</keyword>
    <keyword>revolution</keyword>
    <keyword>french</keyword>
    <keyword>love</keyword>
    <keyword>palermo-italy</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Italian</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="France">89</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Pastina, Giorgio</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Masetti, Enzo</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barclay, Steve (I)</actor>
      <role>Cap. Droet</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Berti, Marina</actor>
      <role>Laura</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Calamai, Clara</actor>
      <role>Elena Di Caltabellotta</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ferzetti, Gabriele</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lupi, Roldano</actor>
      <role>Giovanni Da Procida</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Muller, Paul (I)</actor>
      <role>Carlo D'angio'</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Randi, Ermanno</actor>
      <role>Ruggero</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Silvani, Aldo</actor>
      <role>Tommaso</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tamberlani, Carlo</actor>
      <role>Abate Di Santo Spirito</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tieri, Aroldo</actor>
      <role>Governatore Di Palermo</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A story from the historic uprising of 1282 known as the War of the Sicilian Vespers (since it began during the evening prayer service of vespers on Easter Monday of that year). Sicily is in a state of unrest under the French rule of Charles of Anjou. Elena di Paterno is betrothed to Salerno gentleman Giovanni da Procida, but she is being forced by the wishes of King Charles to marry the Governor of Palermo. Giovanni returns from exile and from behind the scenes plans a revolt. Pursued by the Governor's men-at-arms under the command of Captain Droet, Giovanni takes refuge in the home of Tommaso, a miller. Captain Droet, meanwhile, meets Laura, the miller's beautiful daughter, with whom he falls in love. But Laura intends to marry a local fisherman, so with the help of both the Abbott of the Church of the Holy Ghost and the Governor's wife, she seeks to hasten the wedding. To thwart her plans Droet lays a trap for the miller who is arrested as a rebel. Tommaso is then fatally wounded in a battle between the French and the rebels. During the marriage celebrations for Laura and the fisherman, Droet attempts to seize the bride by force, but the groom rushes in to stop him. This is the spark that ignites the fire of revolt and all the people rise up. Giovanni comes down from the mountain with his men. The Governor tries to flee, but Elena calls on the people to smite him, though she herself is struck down with her detested husband. Laura is re-united with her beloved, and Sicily is liberated. By the end of the uprising some eight thousand Frenchmen have been put to death.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?638832</url></doc>
