<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="641556">
  <docid>641556</docid>
  <title>Virtuality</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Peverley, Lance</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">20 August 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">9</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Peverley, Lance</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Roberds, Michael</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Telford, Keira Michelle</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Olexson, Mark</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Allan, Stephanie</actor>
      <role>Teenage Girl</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cowley, Norma</actor>
      <role>Old Woman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Denis, Natasha</actor>
      <role>Natacia</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Holloway, Melissa (I)</actor>
      <role>Business Woman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jacobsen, A.J.</actor>
      <role>Spirit Guide</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Sony's Brain Ray just got patented. See how such technology works - in Virtuality. 95 % of us daydream. How actively? How beautifully? Well.. Virtuality is a newly invented technology - a dreammaking technique that involves electromagnetic brain stimulation followed by computerized infusion of media. Virtuality is intended to help users get through reality, making reality easier to take. As far as they can switch it off - the dreammaking that is. Which isn't always easy.. This is what Lyn, a digital artist - both a dream-weaver and a rather un-apologetic dreamer herself, discovers. She feels both her creative and personal life have hit "frozen". She can't move to the big city where "the weird stuff" that she does would be appreciated because her Marc has to stay - as his Virtuality is taking off very successfully. Marc knows well all that Lyn is, and loves her, however is too busy and a bit selfish to respond to her needs. Lyn, Virtuality style, is brought back to life in the alternate reality of a dream world, which comes to existence through her fascination with how William Paltrow made his dream reality - leaving behind a very promising career in international law to cover a humanitarian mission in Kenya as a journalist. Her fascination grows into love. Reality superimposes her dream world as she heads to meet her cool and gorgeous free Will in reality - that brings her the insecure and plain restrained Billie. A used to feasting on all the endorphins produced by the act of dreaming brain makes the addict feed it more and more - by alternating or painfully splicing the two worlds of dream and reality.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?641556</url></doc>
