<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="641709">
  <docid>641709</docid>
  <title>Vishwas</title>
  <year>1969</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Glaad, B.S.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Kashyap, Keval P.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Khatri, J.N.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Jeffries, David (IV)</writer>
    <writer>Katyal, Brij</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Shah, Anandji Veerji</composer>
    <composer>Shah, Kalyanji Veerji</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anil (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bawra, Gulshan</actor>
      <role>Pyarelal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhushan, Bharat (I)</actor>
      <role>Ramnath Kapoor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dhanraj</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dhawan, Krishan</actor>
      <role>Prem</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dulari (I)</actor>
      <role>Ram's Mausi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jeetendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Ravi R. Kapoor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kaushal, Kamini</actor>
      <role>Neena R. Kapoor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Manmohan (I)</actor>
      <role>Mohan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mehmood Jr.</actor>
      <role>Munsaf</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mehra, Raj</actor>
      <role>Neena's dad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nath, Rajendra</actor>
      <role>Nandlal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Roy, Kanu</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sen, Asit (I)</actor>
      <role>Sewak Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shribhagwan (I)</actor>
      <role>Dhara Singh</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Neena lives a poor lifestyle along with her parents. Her marriage is arranged with a wealthy male, but the marriage could not take place as her parents are unable to provide enough dowry. Ramnath Kapoor steps in, gets married to Neena and she re-locates to live a poor lifestyle with him. She is overly ambitious and superficial, and starts to live a parallel life. Even after the birth of a son, Ravi, she continues to enjoy her life, and neglects both her husband and son. Then one day she steals a necklace and lets Ramnath take the blame, and as a result he is arrested and imprisoned. When Ramnath returns, there is no trace of Neena, and he undertakes to look after Ravi on his own. 15 years later Ravi has grown up, and is a Forest Ranger in Uttar Pradesh. Neena, who is wealthy, and has taken crime as a career, finds out and wants Ravi to move in with her, but he turns her down. Then romance enters Ravi's life in the shape and form of Radha, who lives a wealthy lifestyle in Delhi. Both fall in love with each other, Ravi introduces her to his dad, who instantly approves. Then Ravi is invited to visit Delhi to meet Radha's aunt, and it is here that Ravi will come to know Radha's aunt is none other than Neena herself, and he will find out that Radha was merely an attractive bait to lure him and force him to live with his biological mother.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?641709</url></doc>
