<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="642539">
  <docid>642539</docid>
  <title>Vivre le piano</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Anderegg, Jann</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>pianist</keyword>
    <keyword>rachmaninov</keyword>
    <keyword>liszt</keyword>
    <keyword>azerbaijan</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>French</language>
    <language>Russian</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Switzerland</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="France">22 January 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Switzerland">10 January 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Switzerland">62</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Jent, Joël Louis</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kessler, Sewa</producer>
    <producer>Jent, Joël Louis</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Jent, Joël Louis</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Alieva, Adilia</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bochkova, Irina</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Byers, David (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Flyarkovsky, Aleksandr</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Adilia Alieva, born in Baku, Azerbaijan is an extraordinary pianist. At the age of six she recorded her first radio performances and at the age of seven she performed Beethoven's Piano Concerto No. 1 on stage, conducted by Leo Ginzburg. As a fifteen-year-old she was picked as one of the Soviet Union's child prodigies and was taught by the pianist Henry Neuhaus in Moscow. She led the life of a classical artist in the crisis-ridden Soviet Union until she didn't return from touring Switzerland. She left her home and family behind to build a new life in the West. VIVRE LE PIANO tells stories from this playful person's life, depicts her longings, dreams and experiences and accompanies her on her journey back to Russia after seventeen years, where she reunites with her sister and is faced with a new Moscow, which seems to have changed drastically. Adilia provides a deep insight into her world behind her piano playing and narrates with a Russian simplicity which she hasn't lost over the years.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?642539</url></doc>
