<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="643595">
  <docid>643595</docid>
  <title>Voodoo Girls</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Pansittivorakul, Thunska</editor>
    <editor>Saengprachatanaruk, Mitree</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Thai</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Thailand</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Singapore">R(A)</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Singapore">18 April 2003</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">27 June 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">79</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Pansittivorakul, Thunska</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pansittivorakul, Thunska</actor>
      <role>Poon</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>VOODOO GIRLS challenges Thailand's social taboos as filmmaker THUNSKA PANSITTIVORAKUL and his circle of college friends, talk openly about sex, gossiping and teasing each other as they discuss their past and present partners. Loaded with sexual innuendo, random objects and gestures assume new meaning, rendering even an artist's wooden mannequin a playful sexual energy. Roger Garcia Documentary in a form of home video, telling a story of the lives of 3 girl friends through a personal point of view. Director's Note At the end of last year I reveal a secret to my close friend. The next day she called me and told me that she was going to England. Personally, I hate being film on camera. That's why I don't have any picture of me with my friends. This scared me and this fear made me film these events immediately during the time that was left without worrying about how the film will turn out. When I was editing the film, I felt like I was putting the jigsaw pieces of memory together. When I finished it, I saw a curse in our fate. It was a curse that made us laugh in order to forget our pain of love, journey and memories... Thunska</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?643595</url></doc>
