<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="643553">
  <docid>643553</docid>
  <title>Von einem der auszog...</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Heinzel, Sebastian</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>German</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Germany">1 November 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Poland">18 November 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Germany">32</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Heinzel, Sebastian</director>
    <director>Karalic, Benjamin</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Heinzel, Sebastian</producer>
    <producer>Karalic, Benjamin</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Karalic, Benjamin</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Heck, Christian</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hintersehr, Dieter</actor>
      <role>Jäger</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Löllmann, Lars</actor>
      <role>Mann im Wald</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A 31-year-old former student of social sciences is trying to survive in the woods for four years. Without any belongings and health insurance he discovers the forests of Southern Germany - not so much looking for food but rather on the search for a deeper understanding of life. With the help of a local hunter a student film team traces him down. The filmmakers enter a parallel world, where everything, which makes our life comfortable, is worth northing. It becomes quite a troublesome journey, on which their never answered questions turn out to be their heaviest luggage. The hunter supports the helpless film students with their project. Partly, because he has already opened the hunting season on the trouble maker. When it comes to the unavoidable dispute, the woodsman accuses the filmmakers to betray him. But despite all the misunderstandings and arguments the people in front and behind the camera come closer to each other than they would have expected in the beginning. Shooting suddenly stops when the stranger disappears in the depths of the Black Forest.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?643553</url></doc>
