<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="644666">
  <docid>644666</docid>
  <title>Vyzov</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Mystery</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Russian</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Russia</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Russia">27 February 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Artamonov, Anatoli</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Karataev, Sergei</producer>
    <producer>Urushev, Oleg</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khirivskaya, Evgeniya</actor>
      <role>Natasha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nazarov, Dmitri (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shutov, Aleksei</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>LIKE A SLAVE The main characters find themselves in a provincial town of Ozersk driven there by a number of cult murders,which happened within a few months, and left the entire town paralyzed with horror. On the bodies of all victims recovered by detectives there were found pieces of jewelry from the indigenous Scythian burial ground.A sinister rumor began circulating among Ozersk's citizens claiming that allegedly the Scythian burial had come to life. These mysterious circumstances have drawn the main characters into the whirlpool of incredible events. THE REFLECTIONS Belogorsk - a small provincial town is shaken by the series of unexplainable suicides. All the victims happened to be powerful businesspeople, bankers and models from a local agency. The investigation conducted by Moscowdetectives revealed that long before taking their lives all the suicide victims were closely connected with each other. Now it's up to our detectives to uncover why this close-knit group of highly successful people started suddenly settle the score with their own lives.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?644666</url></doc>
