<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="645103">
  <docid>645103</docid>
  <title>WCW Bash at the Beach</title>
  <year>1997</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Sport</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>bash-at-the-beach</keyword>
    <keyword>wwe</keyword>
    <keyword>wcw</keyword>
    <keyword>nwo</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">28 October 1997</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">180</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Banos Jr., Juan</actor>
      <role>Lizmark Jr</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mendoza Jr., Rey</actor>
      <role>Villano IV</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Hollywood Hogan and Dennis Rodman are out to crash the bash for World Championship Wrestling at this beach. Lex Luger and The Giant team up to battle the nWo's dream team of Hogan and Rodman in a tag team match of epic proportions. The nWo is also out to celebrate their one year anniversary, but WCW will attempt to stop the celebration. Scott Hall and Randy Savage with Miss Elizabeth of the nWo will battle WCW's Diamond Dallas Page and a mystery partner. DDP has hinted for weeks of whom the partner will be. With WCW being the hottest wrestling company in the world, it could be anyone! "Living Legend" Larry Zbyszko and Sting appear to be two of the favorites to take DDP up on his offer. Will it be one of them or someone else, and whoever it is, will it be enough to stop Savage and Hall? "Rowdy" Roddy Piper and Ric Flair were friends a month ago battling the nWo as a tag team, but several conflicts have changed that relationship. Flair will battle Piper at the Bash in Daytona. Kevin Sullivan and Chris Benoit have been at each other's throats for over a year, but at the Bash it will end once and for all. Chris Benoit will face Kevin Sullivan in a Career Ending Match! All of that plus much more action from the hottest Superstars of World Championship Wrestling. This year's Bash at the Beach has one of the biggest cards in WCW History. Don't miss it!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?645103</url></doc>
