<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="645577">
  <docid>645577</docid>
  <title>Waaris</title>
  <year>1988</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">6 May 1988</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Peepat, Ravindra</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Cheema, Joga Singh</producer>
    <producer>Gill, Baldev</producer>
    <producer>Yograj, Swarn</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Khanna, Jagdish</composer>
    <composer>Singh, Uttam</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Babbar, Raj</actor>
      <role>Bhinder</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bahadur, Rana Jung</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bala, Shashi</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gill, Avtar</actor>
      <role>Dara D. Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Javed (I)</actor>
      <role>Chhote D. Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kharbanda, Kulbhushan</actor>
      <role>Gajjan K. Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kiran, Raj</actor>
      <role>Shravan G. Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Pradeep</actor>
      <role>Kishan Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pal, Amrit</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pandey, Sudhir</actor>
      <role>Thade D. Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, Amrish</actor>
      <role>Dulla K. Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tiwari, Ramesh</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Wealthy, widowed Kishan Singh lives in his palatial house with his two sons, Dulla and Gajjan. He has made a will distributing what's in the house equally between them, but has willed his vast land to Gajjan only, as he is displeased with Dulla. An enraged Dulla confronts his father, an argument leads to fisticuffs, and Kishan is killed. Dulla is arrested, and sentenced to 16 years in jail, leaving his 3 sons (Thade, Dara and Chhote) dependent on Gajjan. Years later, Gajjan's only son, Shravan, has come of age, meets and falls in love with Paramjeet alias Paro, who comes from a very poor family, consisting of her widowed mother, and a younger sister, Shibo. His father approves of Paro and soon both are married. Dulla gets released from prison and also joins in the festivities. Barely had the young couple completed the religious rituals, Shravan is killed, leaving Paro a widow and completely devastating Gajjan. Dulla now wants one of his sons to marry Paro, who will give birth to the new heir, but Gajjan and Paro refuse. Dulla declares himself the owner of the land, as there is no heir. Paro decides to teach Dulla a lesson by getting Gajjan re-married. But the question remains - who will marry an elderly Gajjan? Or is Paro herself readying herself to marrying her father-in-law?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?645577</url></doc>
