<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="645833">
  <docid>645833</docid>
  <title>Wait 'Til Your Father Gets Home</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Australia">2 June 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">25</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Wilson, Martin (III)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Smith, Angie (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Guthrie, Brendon</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Ledger, James</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dorsey, Mike</actor>
      <role>Alf Phillips</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hewitt, Luke</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kennedy, Deborah (I)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Langrishe, Barry</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lord, Tamblyn</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Morrison, Kyle (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This is the story of Seth Selwyn: A simple, thirty-year-old man who is having a great deal of difficulty dealing with the death of his beloved father. Unfortunately, Seth's Mum is having just as much difficulty dealing with her son. Little wonder. Over thirty years, Mum came to rely upon Dad's infinite patience as a buffer between her delicate psyche and Seth's painfully literal way of looking at the world. But now that Dad is gone, the cracks are beginning to appear. And there driving in a wedge is Dad's younger brother Frank , Shire president, bowls club supremo and faded town Romeo, with his constant advice to "Have the mad bastard put away." Seth may be simple, but he's far from stupid. He knows Uncle Frank is turning the screws, even if he has no idea why. And he hears Mum crying herself to sleep every other night But most of all, he knows none of this would be happening if Dad was still around. So, with a little help from Jesus, a heavy-duty battery and a set of jump leads, Seth is planning a surprise family reunion.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?645833</url></doc>
