<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="645930">
  <docid>645930</docid>
  <title>Waiting for Godot on the Edge of Chinatown</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Moss, Natan</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>waiting-for-godot</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">23 April 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">17</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Moss, Natan</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Moss, Natan</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Westlake, Christopher</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Backus, Karl</actor>
      <role>Mulray</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>When Serena Cross walks into his San Fernando office on a cold rainy evening, Mulray thinks his waiting might finally be over. In truth, it has only just begun. She has more sex appeal than Betty Grable, but behind her sultry eyes and fishnet stocking lies a secret as deep and dark as a scorned lover's heart. For the hardened Mulray, with more than 20 years as a private investigator, it's going to take more than a sexy dame and a crazy story to pull one over on him..or will it? The mystery gets murkier for Mulray when a couple of plainclothes detectives become interested in the case. Mr. Cross, Serena's estranged husband with a secret of his own, spends most of his time waiting in a field for someone he calls Godot. Who is Godot - a dealer, a pimp, another lowlife or salvation for the human condition? Is Mr. Cross truly her husband or is that simply the way things are done in their family? Is the experienced Private Eye being led by lust, arrogance or someone's diabolical plan? Sometimes to solve a mystery the only thing you can do is wait.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?645930</url></doc>
