<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="649295">
  <docid>649295</docid>
  <title>Weary Willie's Wiles</title>
  <year>1903</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">1903</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">May 1903</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
<plot>A rather hungry looking tramp is seen entering a kitchen. On the table he sees chicken, ham and numerous other good things to eat. Not satisfied with these, he looks in the closet, and finds a bottle of wine and a loaf of bread. Taking out his handkerchief, he proceeds to wrap up all the good things and take them away to some secluded spot, where he can satisfy his hunger and thirst without being annoyed. Suddenly he hears a noise. Someone has discovered him. Throwing his bundle one side, he jumps for the closet and closes himself in it. A policeman now enters and after looking around for the tramp, his eyes rest on the closet door. As he opens it, the tramp jumps out, and nearly blinds and smothers him with a panful of flour. Weary Willie now pushes the "cop" into the closet and locks him there. He then makes his escape with the bundle. The "cop" soon knocks down the closet door, and as he crawls out into the kitchen, presents a very ludicrous appearance. He is bound to catch the thief, however, and rushes out the door. Here the scene changes to an open field, with a house in the background, and an old coat and hat placed on sticks as a scarecrow, in the foreground. The tramp comes along in great haste and seeing the scarecrow, decides to take its place. He hurriedly dons the old coat and hat, and after tossing the sticks on which they were placed, on the ground, he stretches out his arms and stands perfectly still. The policeman now comes toward the camera on a run, and not seeing the sticks on the ground, falls over them. He gets up very quickly, more mad than hurt, and proceeds to find the tramp. The tramp now sits down to enjoy his meal. The scene again changes, and next we see Weary Willie stretched full length on the grass, after "filling in" and enjoying a smoke from a stump of a cigar.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?649295</url></doc>
