<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="649315">
  <docid>649315</docid>
  <title>Weather Untamed</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Adams, Dean (V)</editor>
    <editor>Dargin, Gavin</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>weather</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">2004</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Canada">February 2003</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">47.5</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Triffo, Chris</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Lesiuk, Dana</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>De Lucas, Pablo</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Not your everyday weather report; prepare for a severe weather watch. Look into the eye of the storm as we meet Canada's most notorious and eccentric character, our weather , whose antics provide a fascination as vast as the land it controls. As the obsession with the subject grows, are the extremes expanding as well? The five episodes investigate this question through weather's hottest (and coldest) topics: What happens when its pressure builds up ... its wild windy flurry of activities ... and the violent temper of its temperatures....above all, clouded in mystery by its skies, veiled in secrecy by its fog, ephemerally illuminated by its lightning. Full of surprises, don't take this personality for granted. Most Importantly, when talking about Canadian weather, never say never. Filmed throughout the Never-Never Land of Canada, where pigs do fly and Hull freezes over, this five-part series reveals unbelievable, yet historical events. Ruling both with an iron first and a helpful hand, weather has its hand in making almost anything possible. Ultimately, for all its accomplishments, Canada remains under the thumb of its chaotic climate.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?649315</url></doc>
