<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="649429">
  <docid>649429</docid>
  <title>Wedding Day</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kang, Olivia</editor>
    <editor>Luong, May May</editor>
    <editor>Sng, Tania</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>bride</keyword>
    <keyword>las-vegas</keyword>
    <keyword>singapore</keyword>
    <keyword>wedding</keyword>
    <keyword>elvis</keyword>
    <keyword>paris</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>French</language>
    <language>Mandarin</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">7 June 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">21</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Schmoeller, David</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Schmoeller, David</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Baley, Virko</composer>
    <composer>Spadoni, Michael</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Alnaif, Abdul</actor>
      <role>Taxi Driver</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bomar, Dana</actor>
      <role>Angelina</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Caballero, Nick</actor>
      <role>Adrian</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chaar, Fish</actor>
      <role>Jin Hao</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Charvoz, Axelle</actor>
      <role>Michelle</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Corpening, Majidah</actor>
      <role>Daughter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Corpening, Nicole</actor>
      <role>Mother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gandy, Terri</actor>
      <role>Waitress</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Huimin, Chan</actor>
      <role>Kay</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Labadens, Mara</actor>
      <role>Catherine</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Leung, Kim</actor>
      <role>Wedding Guest</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Thompson, John W.</actor>
      <role>Elvis</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Thompson, Mike (VIII)</actor>
      <role>Homeless Man</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>WEDDING DAY tells the story of three brides: one in Las Vegas, one in Paris and one in Singapore. Each bride is in her wedding dress and something unexpected has happened. All three stories are intercut - advancing to the surprise ending of each segment. In Las Vegas, the first shot we see is a crying bride running out of an Elvis Wedding Chapel. She has been "left-at-the-altar" by her no-show fiancée and has decided to march down the strip to find a replacement husband for her Elvis wedding. She is followed by the Best Man, not happy to be the one to rescue her from herself. The Paris story starts with the bride standing under a picture-postcard shot of the Eiffel Tower - telling us her wedding day was the happiest day of her life. As we follow her through the streets of Paris, we begin to see this is not going to be a happy story. She ends up at a cemetery where we learn her fiancée had died four years ago - three days before the wedding. They buried him on her wedding day - and she wore her wedding dress to the funeral and has returned every anniversary since - in her wedding dress. A surprise ending comes after a conversation with a passing woman who is able to help the bride move behind her mourning period. The Singapore story tells a more light-hearted and amusing story of a bride hurrying to her wedding accompanied by her child-hood best friend who is trying to talk her out of the marriage. The friend is convinced the bride is too good for the groom. But, at every turn, the bride comes back with the simple fact that: "she loves him and he loves her." The Singapore segment has a surprise twist at the end when the bride asks her fiancée to do something very special - as a show of his love for her - and true to her claims, he proves his love- in a very surprising way. The story comes full circle, ending with the Las Vegas bride sitting in a restaurant with the Best Man, who has offered to marry her - "not for real" - so that she can have her Elvis Wedding. It is a noble gesture and shows how close these two have grown during this humorous, harrowing night on the strip. The bride has given up on her Elvis wedding so the Best Man casually suggests an "elopement." The final image of these two slightly holding hands - while looking at the menu's - hints of new-found love.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?649429</url></doc>
