<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="650320">
  <docid>650320</docid>
  <title>Welt der Wunder - Mystica</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>tv-mini-series</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>German</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Germany">14 April 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Germany">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Hess, Ariane</director>
    <director>Matsa, Luisa</director>
    <director>Mirbach, Frank</director>
    <director>Schmitt, Sebastian</director>
    <director>Stiefenhofer, Christian</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Hess, Ariane</writer>
    <writer>Matsa, Luisa</writer>
    <writer>Schmitt, Sebastian</writer>
    <writer>Stiefenhofer, Christian</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hey, Hendrik</actor>
      <role>Host</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Secret societies, conspiracies, intrigues and murder: World's history is full of ancient myths, well-guarded secrets and unsolved enigmas. Since best-selling authors like Dan Brown or Thomas Gifford thrill millions of readers with their popular novels the public interest in the mysterious chapters of our past is aroused. In this four-part documentary-series Welt der Wunder (World of Wonder) and Mineworks Film take the audience on a fascinating journey into the most obscure and adventurous times of the past. Each episode of the series sheds light on historical myths that have been present in mankind's collective memory for ages: Find out why holy relics have been so important for Christendom that bloody wars were waged to gain them. Get to know the origins of legendary objects like the Holy Grail or the Ark of the Covenant. Is it true that secret societies like the Illuminati or the Knights Templar are still in existence and planning world domination? What kind of power do magic symbols, signs and numbers have? The truth behind these myths lead us into the world of sensational historical stories that are more hair-raising and shadowy than any novelist could ever imagine. Along with elaborate historical drama-scenes shot on location in Germany, France, Italy, Belgium and Israel MYSTICA features original documents and interviews with leading scholars. The appealing combination of historical re-enactment-scenes with more than 150 actors, excellent visual effects and cutting-edge HDTV technology creates an informative and intoxicating experience that sets new standards in the field of Docu-fiction.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?650320</url></doc>
