<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="651180">
  <docid>651180</docid>
  <title>Wet Dreamz of Genie</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Junito</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adult</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>sex</keyword>
    <keyword>homosexual</keyword>
    <keyword>hardcore</keyword>
    <keyword>latino</keyword>
    <keyword>foot-fetish</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">X</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">7 July 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">164</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Junito</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Junito</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Junito</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Junito</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cole, Josh (IV)</actor>
      <role>Mr. Fumando</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cruz, Anthony (II)</actor>
      <role>Genie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>DeAngelis, Viviana</actor>
      <role>Greta/Genie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>DeAngelo, Viviana</actor>
      <role>Greta"/"Jeannie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Escobar, Benji</actor>
      <role>Nicky</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Junito</actor>
      <role>Maj. Antonio Nalgado</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Santiago, Dimitri</actor>
      <role>Maj. Rog Helio</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sergio (X)</actor>
      <role>Harem Boy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Serrano, Tony (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vega, Enrico (II)</actor>
      <role>Prince Jabbaar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>de la Cruz, Junior</actor>
      <role>Dr. Bocudo</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Once upon a time, there lived a handsome and horny Prince who possessed mystical powers beyond your wildest dreams. He fell in love with his favorite slave boy and granted him the gifts of magic and immortality. However, the sexy slave boy did not return his affections. This enraged the Prince, who then condemned him to live for eternity trapped in a bottle at the bottom of the sea. 2000 years later, Air Force major Antonio Nalgado and his best friend Rog discover the magical bottle when it washes ashore. Opening it unleashes a supernatural world of cum-gushing magic, decadence and the passion of an age-old grudge into the 21st Century. Already, the uniformed studs lead hectic lives complicated by a meddling boss whose carnal desire for Rog threatens their careers and their friendship, and a hot, young, nosy next-door neighbor with an insatiable appetite for voyeurism, public exhibitionism and an improper attraction to his own stepfather. Their world is turned upside down as they try to adjust to a new and enchanted way of life with a horse-hung, accommodating, though sometimes mischievous Genie and the jealous wrath of his evil ex-master who will stop at nothing to take him back. From carefree sex on the beach to the terrors of dungeon torture, Wet Dreamz of Genie is a non-stop magic carpet ride of horny, hardcore ass pounding, cock swallowing and foot sucking action. Cum along on a fun-filled, kinky, sex-soaked comedy fantasy!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?651180</url></doc>
