<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="651945">
  <docid>651945</docid>
  <title>What They Want</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>literary-adaptation</keyword>
    <keyword>based-on-novel</keyword>
    <keyword>black-film</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">28 March 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Heiman, David</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Malki, James</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Heiman, David</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Nelson, David (XXV)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barouh, Bram</actor>
      <role>Casey</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gillespie, Brian (I)</actor>
      <role>David Gibbs</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sabath, Bruce</actor>
      <role>Henry</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Terrance Mitchell had no plan at all to ever settle down. For what? Being single was freedom, where relationships were bonding. Nor did he have any plans for a family; what, with snotty-nosed kids running around, cramping his style, and eating for free? To hell with all of that. Terrance loved his life as is. He was a well-traveled, good looking, male model in an industry full of insatiable and insecure women. Beautiful women. Women who adored him. He liked it that way. And he had become accustomed to it. Then it happened. One of his beautiful women fell over the coockoo's nest and shattered his peace of mind. From then on, Terrance could never again lead the blind mice with his flute without feeling guilty about it. He realized that women had a purpose for him. They had dreams and aspirations that included his participation. Of course, a man in his position, constantly surrounded by beautiful women, would know this already. But just because he knew what women wanted didn't mean he was capable or willing to give it to them. Nevertheless, Terrance felt inspired to try.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?651945</url></doc>
