<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="652366">
  <docid>652366</docid>
  <title>What's Your Neighbor Cooking?</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>del Rosario Jr., Luis L.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">26</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>del Rosario, Ricardo</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>del Rosario Jr., Luis L.</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Forster, Benjamin</actor>
      <role>Charles Wright</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kalisz, Michelle</actor>
      <role>Jessica Poriskova</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Karnovsky, Daliya</actor>
      <role>Paula Stringholder</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Taub, Josh</actor>
      <role>Jim Schwartz</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Jim Schwartz finds himself in a quandary. Small in stature but enough bravado to fill a room. Jim finds his way to becoming the next celebrity on the Food-network channel. His prospect of possibly working with his celebrity "idol" Bobby Flay is suddenly sacked by a call from his agent. His quest of celebrity-ism is in jeopardy unless he, with humility, calls back a small production company where he'll host a cooking show called, "What's Your Neighbor Cooking?" which he coincidentally, unabashedly turned down just a few days ago. Bandido Entertainment with some reluctance hires Jim to host their new show. After a shaky start they move forward with the production and shoot the pilot episode of "What's Your Neighbor Cooking?" Jim struggles with the idea of the show and butts heads with the Producer and Director. Jim and his co-host Jessica must scour the neighborhoods of New York; follow the smells from the halls and corridors of apartment buildings, knock on the door and find out what they are cooking inside. Each episode we'll find Jim and Jessica in precarious situations. Jim struggles with each shoot. His heart and mind is still with Bobby and the Foodnetwork. He feels inadequate at times and believes that he is being upstaged by his attractive young, inexperience co-host. Jim is enamored by her greenness and coddles her as she gains confidence with each episode. Jim misconstrues her appreciation and is smitten. Jim Schwartz will stop at nothing to realize his dream of becoming the Food Network's next shining star. We'll follow Jim episode after episode as he climbs his way to the top of the Food Chain.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?652366</url></doc>
