<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="652507">
  <docid>652507</docid>
  <title>Whatever Turns You On</title>
  <year>1979</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">16 October 1979</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Darby, Geoffrey</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Price, Roger Damon</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Baillon, Marc</actor>
      <role>Marc</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brooks, Alma Faye</actor>
      <role>Musical Guest</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Buzzi, Ruth</actor>
      <role>Miss Take/Miss Fit/Other Various</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gebert, Jono</actor>
      <role>Jono</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Helal, Rodney</actor>
      <role>Rodney</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kevin Page Band, The</actor>
      <role>Musical Guest</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lye, Les</actor>
      <role>All Male adult characters</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McGlade, Christine</actor>
      <role>Christine</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mitchell, Elizabeth (II)</actor>
      <role>Elizabeth</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Patton, Mike (I)</actor>
      <role>Crew Person</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Schenk, Kevin</actor>
      <role>Kevin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Somers, Kevin</actor>
      <role>Kevin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Thomas, Ian (I)</actor>
      <role>Musical Guest</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Trooper (I)</actor>
      <role>Musical Guest</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Webster, Max</actor>
      <role>Musical Guest</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Due to the success of a local Saturday morning TV show titled "You Can't Do That On Television" which only aired in Ottawa on CJOH-TV in early 1979 as it had a cast of kids acting in comedy skits and adult actor Les Lye playing the adult roles. It prompted the creators Roger Price and Geoffrey Darby to air a prime-time TV series shown all across Canada. First a pilot episode aired on Saturday Morning on May 12, 1979 as they hired Ruth Buzzi to play the female adult roles as well it had a musical guest by Vancouver rock band Trooper. The pilot was a success so in the fall starting on September 18, 1979 the series aired every Tuesday night at 7:30 on CTV as 16 episodes were purchased. The skits had certain topics like Union Fees, Fan Letters/Summer Camp and Superstitions and Educational Programming and like it's sister show it was about kids being kids. There were also musical guests by Canadian bands like Ian Thomas, Max Webster, Cooper Brothers and Alma Faye. Because the series appealed to kids 11 and under it was an odd combination as kids couldn't related to rock bands and didn't know who Ruth Buzzi was. Not only that, a prime time slot wasn't right for a series like that. After the 12th episode in December of 1979 the series was canceled but however, it's sister show You Can't Do That On Television re-aired in early 1981 on Saturday mornings airing nationwide and used some of the characters that were fresh off of the other series which became popular for the show. Whatever Turns You On did however re-aired in reruns when a Canadian station YTV became new to the public in 1988 but sadly it only aired for one season.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?652507</url></doc>
