<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="652950">
  <docid>652950</docid>
  <title>When Kim &amp; Aggie Went to Hospital</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">30 August 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">48</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Copley, Paul</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>MacKenzie, Aggie</actor>
      <role>Presenter</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Kim and Aggie travel to Ealing, West London, to look at the standards of cleanliness and issues of hygiene facing Britain's hospitals. Ealing Hospital has been publicly criticized in the past for its levels of sanitation. But during the last 18 months the hospital's Chief Executive, Fiona Wise, has worked tirelessly to raise standards of cleanliness. Over three months, the hospital opened its doors to the scrupulously clean Kim and Aggie, allowing them free rein to visit all departments to examine cleanliness levels and tackle any problems in their own unique style. Kim spends time with the cleaning staff, finding out what an average day's work involves and how the hospital divides up and manages the mammoth task of keeping things clean, while Aggie delves deeper to see what bacteria could be located, with the help of an independent microbiologist. And some of what they found shocked even them! They uncovered clinical waste left lying in corridors, staff having to deal with sometimes chaotic and filthy patients and, most shockingly of all, something very nasty in a supposedly super clean, super sterilized MRSA isolation ward. When Kim and Aggie Went to Hospital explores what every hospital in the country - staff, patients and visitors - could and should be doing to make them safer and healthier places.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?652950</url></doc>
