<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="654657">
  <docid>654657</docid>
  <title>White Man's Burden</title>
  <year>2010</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <directors>
    <director>Busby, Douglas</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Nemeth, Stephen</producer>
    <producer>Woldenberg, John</producer>
    <producer>Harvey, Amanda</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Easterly, William</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bennett, Diane (II)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Danilovich, Ambassador John</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Drayton, Bill</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Duggan, William</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Easterly, William</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kuraishi, Mari</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Whittle, Dennis</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This is a full-length feature documentary about the second tragedy of the world's poor. The first tragedy is, that in a world of abundance, 3 billion people live on under $2 per day and live in extreme poverty. The second is: The World's Poor are still dying not only because of the world's indifference to their plight, but also because of the ineffective efforts by the people and agencies who 'do care'. The West has spent 2.3 trillion dollars in aid to the World's Poor in the past 60 years and the poor still do not have simple life sustaining materials, which include clean drinking water, food, bed nets and simple lifesaving medicines. This documentary will concentrate on the issue of transferring power from the Planners in the offices to the Searchers who are on the ground finding pragmatic answers to this bigger tragedy. Bypassing bad governments and placing money in the right programs so it reaches the poor. This documentary will shift conventional thinking about aid and help transfer funding to transparent and 'accountable' non-profits and Searchers whom are discovering piecemeal solutions to helping the poor and providing feedback from poor. Thus White Man's Burden explores one of the most relevant questions of our time: How does Western foreign aid waste not, so the poor can want not?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?654657</url></doc>
