<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="656081">
  <docid>656081</docid>
  <title>Wide Awake</title>
  <year>2011</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>based-on-comic</keyword>
    <keyword>drugs</keyword>
    <keyword>numerology</keyword>
    <keyword>sleep</keyword>
    <keyword>end-of-the-world</keyword>
    <keyword>dream</keyword>
    <keyword>messenger</keyword>
    <keyword>nightmare</keyword>
    <keyword>h.p.-lovecraft</keyword>
    <keyword>dreamscape</keyword>
    <keyword>armageddon</keyword>
    <keyword>nightmare-becomes-reality</keyword>
    <keyword>based-on-graphic-novel</keyword>
    <keyword>monster</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <producers>
    <producer>Feliciano, Jarrod</producer>
    <producer>Novkovic, Mirjana</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Feliciano, Jarrod</writer>
    <writer>Novkovic, Mirjana</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>If she had her way, Amanda Carter would never sleep again. Sleep leads to dreams, and more often than not, Amanda's dreams can be lethal. Since childhood, she has battled nightmares-a vast array of terrifying monsters-which she has slowly realized aren't just figments of her imagination. If Amanda doesn't finish them off before she wakes up, the horrors from her dreams get loose in the physical world and it's her job to clean up the mess. As a result, she lives a wired life in an apartment full of coffee pots and alarm clocks, doing everything she can to fight off the inevitable. H.P. Lovecraft once experienced a similar condition, but he chose to face his horrific visions through a cracked mirror of transcription and interpretation; Amanda fights the only way she knows how - tooth and nail, blood and bone. Her wars are waged in the Dreamlands. She has special abilities there, the limits of which remain unknown. For now, she can create an arsenal of weapons, exert a degree of control over her surroundings and occasionally perform physical feats that are quite a bit beyond normal. Amanda's main adversary is a terrifying figure called the Messenger, the new avatar of ancient, evil gods, trapped for centuries behind the steadily weakening barrier of the Dreamlands. Amanda's ability to bring dreams to life may be the key to unlocking the ancient prison that traps his masters, He is watching and waiting, minding the portal between the Dreamlands and Earth, waiting for the time when Amanda dreams the End of All Worlds...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?656081</url></doc>
