<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="658268">
  <docid>658268</docid>
  <title>Winning Lines</title>
  <year>2000</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Game-Show</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>futuristic-sets</keyword>
    <keyword>contestant-elimination</keyword>
    <keyword>gimmicks</keyword>
    <keyword>non-fiction</keyword>
    <keyword>remake</keyword>
    <keyword>quiz-show</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">8 January 2000</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Yukich, James</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Clark, Dick (I)</producer>
    <producer>Smith, Paul (X)</producer>
    <producer>Stanley, David G.</producer>
    <producer>Stone, Scott A.</producer>
    <producer>Champion, Gregg (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Page, Lisa (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Strachan, Keith</composer>
    <composer>Strachan, Matthew</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Clark, Dick (I)</actor>
      <role>Host</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Game show where in the first round 49 contestants (numbered 1 to 49) are whittled down to six in the first round, where Dick Clark asks them mathematical word problems, such as, "What is the number of Brady kids added to the number of Backstreet Boys?". In the second round, the six survivors face off in a sudden death round where the answers are the numbers of the finalists (e.g., if contestant #14 is still playing, a question may have 14 as an answer). The round works like this: Dick Clark asks a question. Once one of the players thinks they know the answer, they must lock-in with an answer. If they are right and it's someone else's number, the player with that number is out. If they are right and it's their number, then that contestant stays in the game. But if they're wrong, they're out. The winner goes on to play the Wonderwall, where he/she can win one million dollars by answering 20 questions in three minutes. If the Wonderwall player misses three questions, or doesn't bail out when time runs out, he/she loses all of the Wonderwall earnings. In addition, a home viewer can win $50,000 in a phone contest. The numbers in that contest were made up from the end digits of the 6 finalists (e.g. contestant #14 would add a "4") and the end digit of the Wonderwall contestant's last correct answer.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?658268</url></doc>
