<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="658353">
  <docid>658353</docid>
  <title>Winter Draws On</title>
  <year>1948</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>screen-song</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">19 March 1948</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">7</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Kneitel, Seymour</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Buchwald, Sam</producer>
    <producer>Kneitel, Seymour</producer>
    <producer>Sparber, Izzy</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bourne, Larz</writer>
    <writer>Turner, Bill (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Sharples, Winston</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Beck, Jackson (I)</actor>
      <role>Buzzy the Crow, Southern Gentleman Statue</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mercer, Jack</actor>
      <role>Jailbird, Little Chick</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>As winter approaches, a variety of birds fly south to see a warmer climate. We see them packing their suitcases and carrying them in their claws; a bird nest is propelled by a balloon, the mother sets her eight chicks as if they're billiard balls, while a jailbird is stuck in prison. Meanwhile, a soon-to-be father duck paces back and forth while his wife indicates that their egg has not yet hatched. We continue to see a variety of birds flying south, one hitching a ride on a plane, and a parakeet taking his entire cage with him. Another inspection by the prospective duck parents with a match indicates that the egg is not ready - the youngster inside draws the shade down. The migration continues. By the time we come back to the duck couple it is already winter with snow on the ground. The egg refuses to hatch, so the prospective father puts one end of the match in the egg and lights the other end. The egg bursts open and the junior duck is seen hoping up and down with a burnt toe. Junior keeps jumping up and down as the mother duck invites the audience to sing "Alabamy Bound." In the final moments, the birds are seen passing over the Mason-Dixon Line where the weather is instantly warmer. A statue of a Southern gentleman (dates 1812-1888) looks up, dons an umbrella, and mutters: "Hm. It's those consarned Yankees again!"</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?658353</url></doc>
