<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="659438">
  <docid>659438</docid>
  <title>Wo de ming xing</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Shen, Bin (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Biography</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Mandarin</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="China">17 May 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="China">27</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Pelino, Mike</producer>
    <producer>Goodman, Jonathan P.</producer>
    <producer>Lynch, Joseph R.</producer>
    <producer>Wu, Fei (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lian, Jie</actor>
      <role>Herself - Host</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Celebrity exists in all walks of life. From stage to screen, basketball court to race track, individuals that achieve great success and accomplishment elevate themselves to a status that most of us can barely imagine. Who are these people that gain such notoriety? What is it that makes them who they are? How did they achieve all that they have? Who are the people that helped them reach their goals? My Celebrity, will help audiences gain a deeper understanding of these interesting personalities. Today in China, countless number of entertainment and celebrity gossip magazines and television shows talk about every aspect of celebrity life. Each source brings its own view of who these people are and what they are all about. Writers and editors have their own view of celebrities and readers and viewers are subjected to those opinions. The only way to truly understand these celebrities is to hear their stories straight from the source. My Celebrity takes an in-depth look at the lives and careers of China's top stars. These individuals who's movies we watch, music we listen to and style we imitate are much more than the surface we see. Celebrity life can appear glamorous and exciting. But as songs have deeper meanings than just a pleasant sound, so do the lives and emotions of the stars that sing them. Throughout the My Celebrity series, audiences will experience what it means and what it takes to be in the public eye. From professional success to personal heartbreak, this series will allow audiences the opportunity to see a side of these superstars they have never imagined. Interviews with family, friends, co-stars and the superstars themselves will narrate these amazing stories. Mothers and fathers reveal their lives as children. Intimate details of life before stardom and the first signs of something special will leave the audience with a new understanding of where they began. Friends will make us laugh and cry with their personal tales of love and loss. Co-stars and career mentors will tell stories of the highs and lows of super stardom. My Celebrity: This is who they really are</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?659438</url></doc>
