<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="659605">
  <docid>659605</docid>
  <title>Woh Tera Naam Tha</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Jaiswal</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">U</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="India">150</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Kohli, Sandesh</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Nathani, Farhad</producer>
    <producer>Singhania, Vijaypat</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Chowksey, J.P.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Chopra, Sumeet</composer>
    <composer>Rathod, Roop Kumar</composer>
    <composer>Sen, Sameer</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bajwa, Arjan</actor>
      <role>Akhtar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bedi, Rajat</actor>
      <role>Basharat Ali</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chanana, Gaurav</actor>
      <role>Badruddin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chopra, Prem</actor>
      <role>Kishanlal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kaul, Kanchi (II)</actor>
      <role>Reshma Khan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Javed (I)</actor>
      <role>Ashiq Khan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Parvez, Yunus</actor>
      <role>Pervez</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, Amrish</actor>
      <role>Ustad Samad Khan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Verma, Rajeev</actor>
      <role>Nawab Hyder Ali</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Orphaned at a very young age, Badruddin alias Badru was taken in by the kind-hearted Ustad Samad Khan, a once popular singer in Bhopal, Madhya Pradesh. During one of his shows, Samad found his audience distracted, and taking this as an insult to his art, gave up singing altogether. Badru is attracted to Samad's pretty daughter, Reshma, who also likes him. Badru has another admirer in the beautiful Naseem, but does not reciprocate her love. When Akhtar, a free lance photographer from Delhi, arrives there, Reshma and he instantly fall in love with each other, leaving behind a heartbroken Badru. When Akhtar proposes marriage, Samad angrily rejects him, as he wants Reshma to marry Nawab Hyder Ali's son, Basharat. This anger has repercussins on Samad's health and he is hospitalized. His treatment will cost a lot of money, so Reshma decides to part in a singing competition, which she wins. Samad is treated and returns home to start preparations for Reshma's marriage, and is told to his astonishment that Reshma has already down Basharat's proposal. It is then Basharat decides to take this matter in his own hands, and attends Samad's house, and there is no one who can stop him from forcibly marrying Reshma.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?659605</url></doc>
