<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="659932">
  <docid>659932</docid>
  <title>Woman's Work</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
    <soundmix>Dolby</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">6 June 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Benton, Chad (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Benton, Chad (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bond, Elizabeth</actor>
      <role>Electricity Girl</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carrington, Christopher (II)</actor>
      <role>Mick Sancy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fite, Steve</actor>
      <role>Lawyer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gary, Treisa</actor>
      <role>Janet Sancy/Lady Adrenaline</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Judelle, Jenny</actor>
      <role>Librarian</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rhodes, Ramjasha</actor>
      <role>Mick's Friend</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Russell, Aerick</actor>
      <role>Aerick Sancy</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The rhythmic clink and clatter of household chores. The smack and rattle of the ironing board causes mild-mannered housewife Janet Sancy to catch her iron before it hits the floor. She yells at her son for knocking the ironing board, but soon realizes she's holding the hot end. Dropping it, she sees it did not burn her hand but is now destroying the sweater she was ironing! Later, Janet is informed by The Hall of Super Justice that due to her "heightened adrenaline" she could possibly be a superhero. At first dubious, Janet realizes she could be more than just "mom." Her husband, Mick, does not greet this news with the same enthusiasm. Angered by his attitude, Janet sizzles 'till POOF - she stands in her uniform: golden tiara, a red bodice with yellow flames, white spandex and a long flowing yellow cape. She is Lady Adrenaline. Out to fight crime only finds Lady Adrenaline doing menial tasks: making thugs pick up trash, stopping kids from spray-painting graffiti. There's nothing glorious about it and she's still got to pick up her son from school! Back at home, Janet still has trouble getting Mick to take her seriously as a crime fighter. All he really sees is the sexy spandex. "It's not lingerie, it's my uniform!" she proclaims. Can Janet make everyone understand "there's more to this than the way it looks?" Can Lady Adrenaline achieve real superhero status? Woman's Work shows her juggling both housewife and superhero tasks and fighting for respect from both.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?659932</url></doc>
