<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="661026">
  <docid>661026</docid>
  <title>World War II and Me</title>
  <year>1976</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Holbrooke, Andrew</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>War</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">22</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Lee, Francis (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Lee, Francis (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Lee, Francis (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lee, Francis (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself (narration)</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In 1976, Francis Lee edited footage he shot during the years 1941 to 1945 while an Army combat motion picture cameraman. A pacifist and painter living on New York City's East 10th Street before World War II, Lee initially requested classification as a conscientious objector. Realizing WWII was a war against racism, fascism and totalitarianism, he reconsidered, was classified 1-A and enlisted as an Army cameraman. The film looks back on his growing maturity as he moves closer to combat. Lee calls this a testimonial to "one man's initiation: mine." Scenes of basic training are followed by the 6 June 1944 D-Day landing at Omaha Beach, where his unit suffered a 75% loss, the Liberation of Paris and his visits in Paris with Pablo Picasso. Jonas Mekas commented, "His D-Day footage is so spectacular, so real that I don't think I have ever seen war footage as real, as believable. You know Lee was there and he took it all and you know it was a hell. His Paris liberation footage is about equally spectacular." The film concludes with Lee's return to East 10th Street at the war's end.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?661026</url></doc>
