<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="661147">
  <docid>661147</docid>
  <title>World's Deadliest Storms</title>
  <year>1998</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Dalzell, Chris</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">18 November 1998</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <producers>
    <producer>Nash, Bruce</producer>
    <producer>Bishop, Brad (I)</producer>
    <producer>Miller, Michael (XI)</producer>
    <producer>Tetrick, Michael</producer>
    <producer>Young, Brent (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Boone, Dave</writer>
    <writer>Nash, Bruce</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Clement, Shawn K.</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Tornadoes, hail storms, floods and blizzards - real people tell their stories of their desperate struggles against the elements. Using interviews along with stunning 'caught on camera' footage, this program features people who showed amazing courage and bravery in the face of some of the century's greatest natural disasters. A mudslide in Banks, Idaho completely swallows a town of 740 people. A 170 km/h (90 mph) hail storm shoots a barrage of baseball-sized snowballs into a county fair in Fort Worth, Texas, attacking 10,000 unprotected and unprepared people. A storm in Fort Smith, Arkansas, destroys the power and phone lines, leaving the town without a warning system for the deadly twister about to decimate hundreds of homes. Blinded by storms and battered by winds, giant ships are tossed about as an immense tidal wave explodes upon a small Korean harbor village. A powerful flood in Oregon swallows up everything in its path, including two men who are trying to outrun it in their pickup truck.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?661147</url></doc>
