<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="661365">
  <docid>661365</docid>
  <title>Woven Ways</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>La Morte, Gloria</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>coal</keyword>
    <keyword>mining</keyword>
    <keyword>uranium</keyword>
    <keyword>navajo-indian</keyword>
    <keyword>weaving</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">5 March 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">50</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Krapf, Linda Helm</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Krapf, Linda Helm</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Eggert, Scott</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Woven Ways interweaves the intimate stories of five Navajo families, the land and livestock that sustain their culture and economy, and the environmental issues that threaten their health and well-being. Told in their words, with no narration, Woven Ways is a testimonial to Navajo beauty and hope in the face of grave injustice. Deadly uranium mining and dirty coal power pose serious problems for all who live on the Reservation. Decades of uranium mining is directly responsible for thousands of cancer deaths among Navajo miners, and has contaminated the land, air, and water for hundreds of square miles. Our nation's thirst for nuclear power has re-invigorated interest in its fuel: uranium. As a result, new mining is slated for the Navajo communities of Crownpoint, Church Rock and Mt. Taylor, one of four sacred mountains. The proposed Desert Rock Power Plant would be the third coal burning plant in the San Juan Valley, home to two plants listed among the dirtiest in the nation. If built, Desert Rock will add 12.7 million tons of CO2 and other Woven Ways interweaves the intimate stories of five Navajo families, the land and livestock that sustain their culture and economy, and the environmental issues that threaten their health and well-being. Told in their toxins into the atmosphere each year, and will drain 2,700 gallons of water every minute from the arid ecosystem. While more than 20,000 Navajos are without electricity, they live with all the negative health and environmental impacts of these projects. Woven Ways chronicles each family's steady resolve to hold on to what remains sacred - the land, the air, the water; not for themselves, but for generations that will come.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?661365</url></doc>
