<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="662597">
  <docid>662597</docid>
  <title>Xian doujiang</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Chen, Po-wen</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Mandarin</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Taiwan</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Taiwan">GP</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Taiwan">2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Wang, Ming-Tai</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hsu, Li-Kong</producer>
    <producer>Yeh, Ju Fen</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Wang, Ming-Tai</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Chen, Tai-Hsiang</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chen, Tai-Hsiang</actor>
      <role>Ah-shiang</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fan, Wing</actor>
      <role>Chi-wen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Huang, Phoebe</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ma, Chih-Hsiang</actor>
      <role>Ming-hsien</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Back in the 1980's, passing the college entrance exam was every high school student's only hope for the future. Yet for Chi-wen and Ming-hsien, it is not a road of their own choice. Gradually they rebel against it. The spicy soy chowder is their favorite breakfast. They like to watch the ingredients being mixed and swirled together forming a soup that tastes otherworldly, which seems to mimic the future they long for. Ming-hsien is in love with Jing-fen, a girl with whom he shouldn't be involved. She already has a boyfriend, Ah-shiang, who performs at a local pub. Ming-hsien's love for her is unconditional and he agrees to help Jing-fen on a money making scheme. All she wants is to have enough money to buy a new guitar for Ah-shiang. Ming-hsien decides not to take the exam. As Chi-wen follow suite to stand by his friend, he looses his girlfriend as well as his focus in life. Coincidentally, he witnesses a mysterious woman who lives downstairs being threatened by a gangster. The hero in Chi-wen is awaken and he wants to save the woman from harms way.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?662597</url></doc>
