<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="663180">
  <docid>663180</docid>
  <title>Y Lleill</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Williams, Geraint</editor>
    <editor>Williams, Tristan</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>wales</keyword>
    <keyword>music</keyword>
    <keyword>ankst</keyword>
    <keyword>lleill</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Welsh</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="UK">15</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">11 November 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">88</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Williams, Emyr Glyn</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Williams, Emyr Glyn</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Williams, Emyr Glyn</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Green, Rhian</actor>
      <role>Pati</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hughes, Morfudd</actor>
      <role>Mam</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Reynolds, John (XXIX)</actor>
      <role>Rob</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Roberts, Iwan (II)</actor>
      <role>Paul</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sion, Rhodri</actor>
      <role>Dyf</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>'Y LEILL' is a bi-lingual film about music and other less important things. The lives of a group of young aimless musicians ( Y LLEILL ) are examined as they play two concerts over a wintry weekend. The importance of music to the individuals and the society they exist in is examined in the film as music is played , recorded , stolen , attacked and censored . As 'Y LLEILL' play their music the hypocrisy and deceit that exists between the young characters and the resistance to their music that exists in the wider Welsh society is revealed . Manipulative guitarist and singer Pati ( Rhian Green ) starts the film by stealing the records she can't afford and sets Y LLEILL on a collision course with the established order. Meanwhile lead singer Rob ( John Reynolds ) is a different kind of thief who blindly follows his desires oblivious to family and friends. These fragile relationships are set to explode on stage as the band edge towards one last truly 'revolutionary' performance .'Y LLEILL' is Ankstmusik's first attempt at independently producing a commercial cinematic film. Y LEILL was made with the express intention of trying to find an audience for 'Welsh cinema' and to prove that it is possible to produce small scale films that can engage with such an audience.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?663180</url></doc>
