<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="663448">
  <docid>663448</docid>
  <title>Yaaran Naal Baharaan</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Punjabi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="UK">U</certificate>
    <certificate country="Australia">PG</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Singh, Manmohan</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Gill, Amrik</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kumar, Jaidev</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Babbar, Juhi</actor>
      <role>Harmaan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Babbar, Raj</actor>
      <role>Navdeep</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Guggi, Gurpreet</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kher, Anupam</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shergill, Jimmy</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This film shows the college life of students, their hostel life, the way they enjoy themselves in the college and the hard work they put in for their studies. This film tells a story of young hearts seeing each other and falling in love; this falling in love makes their life so different and beautiful. Navdeep, the son of an Army major, sees a girl, Harmaan, and falls in love with her. In time, she also starts liking him. There are lots of good moments between both of them while Navdeep tries to convince her for his love. Both start to dream of a happy life together. But problems arise when they think of taking their parent's consent before going any further. Harmaan's father is a typical Punjabi father with a big ego who does not appreciate the idea of his daughter selecting a groom herself. It's the same case with the Army Major - he has given Navdeep all the freedom in life, but cannot accept the fact that his son has chosen a girl for himself. He thinks it is his duty and right to find a girl for his son. Now both Navdeep and Harmaan are in a dilemma: neither can they go against their parents, nor can they live without each other. How they convince their parents about their relationship without hurting their sentiments is the rest of the story.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?663448</url></doc>
