<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="663563">
  <docid>663563</docid>
  <title>Yahtzee</title>
  <year>1988</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Game-Show</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>non-fiction</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">21 March 1988</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hovis, Larry</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hovis, Larry</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Marshall, Peter (I)</actor>
      <role>Host</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Two teams of three contestants competed with 5 celebrities. Host Marshall introduced six numbered questions, and the captain of one of the teams chose one. The question would be read to the celebrities, and they'd write their answers. Each contestant would then face one celebrity and try to guess their answer. After each celebrity's answer was guessed, right or not, the opposing team chose one of the five remaining questions and play continued. When each team had a chance, the one who scored more matches (or a tiebreaker, which was a buzz-in question between the captains) rolled five dice. The dice were regular, except for the fact that one number on each side was replaced by a "WILD," which could become any other number on the table. If a Yahtzee (five of a kind, with or w/o "WILD"s) was rolled, that team won the game. Otherwise, the captain chose some numbers to hold aside for later. Round two was played the same. If the team that won Round One won Round 2, they got to build on their held numbers by rolling all five dice again (A major difference from the board game.) If a Yahtzee was established, that team won. Otherwise, Round Three was played. Round 3 had a few differences. The winning team got two rolls instead of one, and the dice could be passed to the other team as well. Whichever team was closer to a Yahtzee after this round won. If there was a tie, a regular tiebreaker was played for the match. Two different bonus games were used in the show's nine month run. In the first, a new sequence of matching was played. For each match, the team got a roll, with a guarantee of one. Then the team was shown the "YAHTZEE" letters. Each letter had a money amount. Four had $5,000, two had $10,000, and one had $25,000. After the pick, the dice were brought out. If Yahtzee was made in the first roll, the team won $100,000. Otherwise if a Yahtzee could be made within the earned rolls, the chosen amount was won. In the second, the only difference was that 5 "WILD"s had to come up for $100,000.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?663563</url></doc>
