<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="664091">
  <docid>664091</docid>
  <title>Yaqui Drums</title>
  <year>1956</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Pierson, Carl</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Western</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="West Germany">12</certificate>
    <certificate country="Finland">K-16</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Japan">29 April 1958</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Finland">9 May 1958</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">14 October 1956</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">71</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Yarbrough, Jean</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Broidy, William F.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Beauchamp, D.D.</writer>
    <writer>Pagano, Jo</writer>
    <writer>Peil, Paul Leslie</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kay, Edward J.</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cameron, Rod</actor>
      <role>Webb Dunham</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Castle, Mary</actor>
      <role>Linda Quigg</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Collins, G. Pat</actor>
      <role>Bartender</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fierro, Paul</actor>
      <role>Leader</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Frederick, John (II)</actor>
      <role>Hostler</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gabourie, Fred (II)</actor>
      <role>First Henchman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gorss, Sol</actor>
      <role>Second Henchman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hutton, Robert (I)</actor>
      <role>Lute Quigg</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kerr, Donald (I)</actor>
      <role>Saloon Piano Player</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Naish, J. Carrol</actor>
      <role>Yacqi Jack</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pyle, Denver</actor>
      <role>Gang Leader Lefty</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Richards, Keith (I)</actor>
      <role>Prescott</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Roberts, Roy (I)</actor>
      <role>Matt Quigg</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Walker, Ray (I)</actor>
      <role>Sheriff</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Mexican bandit Yaqui Jack (J. Carroll Naish) and his men hold up a stage coach, kill the driver and guard and are robbing the passengers, ranch owner Matt Quigg (Roy Roberts), his son Lute (Robert Hutton) and Linda (Mary Castle), when they in turn are ambushed by Lefty (Denver Pyle) and his gang. Yaqui Jack is shot but escapes and reaches the camp of Webb Dunham (Rod Cameron), who treats his wounds. They separate with Webb going to the ranch of his brother who has been murdered. Suspicion turns on Matt, who claims title to the brother's ranch, and has Webb brutally beaten after ordering him from the property. Webb goes to Matt's saloon, where Linda sings, and she and Webb had been in love in California. Webb retaliates against Matt for his beating, and Matt hires Lefty to kill Webb. Lefty, waiting in Webb's cabin to ambush him, is overpowered by Yaqui Jack who has returned to help the man who aided him, and asks Webb to join him and his friends in their fight to free Mexico. Matt, Lute, Linda and Lefty and the sheriff (Ray Walker) are kidnapped by Yaqui Indians, as is Webb, who shot a Yaqui grabbing Linda. They are taken across the border to be held for ransom, where Lefty confesses to Webb that he had killed Webb's brother on Matt's orders. Lute, with no intentions of returning, persuades his father to let him go across the border to get the ransom money but Linda, whom he had married the night before, refuses to go with him. Matt learns of the intended deceit deceit, and accidently kills Lute. Yaqui Jack is killed as he dfies the Mexican Army authorities who escort Webb, Linda, the sheriff and the now-demented Matt back across the border.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?664091</url></doc>
