<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="664594">
  <docid>664594</docid>
  <title>Yeh Kaisi Mohabbat</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Musical</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">31 May 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Kapur, Dinkar</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Handa, Vinit</producer>
    <producer>Kotwani, Ashok</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Kapoor, Y.N.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Chowta, Sandeep</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Babajee, Viveka</actor>
      <role>Priya Thakral</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deeksha</actor>
      <role>Tina</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hingoo, Dinesh</actor>
      <role>Gurkha Bahadur</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Sharad S.</actor>
      <role>Rahul Thakral</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Krishna (I)</actor>
      <role>Vicky</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lever, Johnny</actor>
      <role>Paaji</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mehmood Jr.</actor>
      <role>Bhaaji</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rishi, Mukesh</actor>
      <role>Asst. Comm. of Police</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Srivastav, Anjan</actor>
      <role>Ratanlal (Tina's dad)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tijori, Deepak</actor>
      <role>Vijay Pal</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Yeh Kaisi Mohabbat (YKM) is a romantic thriller. It deals with a whole lot of fun, romance and suspense. It is story of an innocent boy Vicky. The plot involves an innocent poor boy, who is a happy go lucky, always trying to live a stylish life. He is always in search of a rich girl with a view to live a luxurious life with her money. He lives in a motor garage with his six friends. the friends always help him with his requirements. One of the friends is a dress designer and provides him the artist's clothes and imported cars are provided to him to enjoy life. The boy falls in love with a rich girl, Tina. He presents himself to be a rich boy, fool her and romance with her. He saves a rich man (Rahul Thakral) from the goons, who offers him a job. The boy gets a shock when he comes to know that the job involves spying Rahul's wife. He is again shocked to see the wife, she is Tina. He is confused. Priya is a glamorous woman and has high standards of living. She has an emotional bond with a Casino owner (Vijay Pal). Paaji is a millionaire sardarji who believes in distributing &amp; spending lavishly his wealth on his friends. Does the hero succeed love? Does Krishna achieve his love? Where does the high standards take Priya? Who is murdered &amp; who is the murderer... Forms the crux of the film.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?664594</url></doc>
