<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="666456">
  <docid>666456</docid>
  <title>You Must Be This Tall: The Story of Rocky Point Park</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Cawthorn, Harry</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>History</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>rocky</keyword>
    <keyword>park</keyword>
    <keyword>amusement-park</keyword>
    <keyword>roller-coaster</keyword>
    <keyword>point</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">14 September 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">81</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="USA">81</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Bettencourt, David</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bettencourt, David</producer>
    <producer>Bettencourt, David</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bailey, Walter (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cianci, Buddy</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ferla Jr., Vincent</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>LaCross, George</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rinn, Ken</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This film documents the long history of Rocky Point Park, an amusement park and shore dinner hall situated along the coast of the Narragansett Bay. For over 150 years, New Englanders flocked to the spot, for a game of Sunday baseball, for a picnic, for a rock-n-roll concert, or to ride on the Tilt-a-Whirl . Then, in 1996, the park closed. With its rides sold off, the park sits as a ghost town, scheduled for demolition and primed for the construction of condominiums. The story of Rocky Point Park will be told entirely by the people who lived there, who worked there, and who spent every waking moment of every summer at the park. We have collected found footage, family photographs, and memorabilia from the park. Along with a couple of local still photographers, we have shot extensively inside the ruined buildings and on the hallowed grounds of the former amusement park. From Babe Ruth to George Bush, from the first presidential phone call to a devastating hurricane, You Must Be This Tall hopes to capture all the fond memories left behind at Rocky Point, leaving future generations with a visually-stimulating reminder of the way things were.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?666456</url></doc>
