<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="667532">
  <docid>667532</docid>
  <title>Your Humble Serpent</title>
  <year>1996</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Rhine, Gary</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>indigenous</keyword>
    <keyword>native-american</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">70</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Rhine, Gary</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Rhine, Gary</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Brown, Hayna</writer>
    <writer>Cousineau, Phil</writer>
    <writer>Rhine, Gary</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brown, Hayna</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In this portrait of a contemporary American Indian leader, the late Reuben Snake speaks out on ecology, sacredness, intuitive thinking and "The Rebrowning of America". As Reuben grew up, his elders taught him that a leader is a servant to the people. Reuben lived his life true to that teaching, serving his country as a Green Beret, his tribe as Winnebago Tribal Chairman, and all his Indian people as President of The National Congress Of American Indians. When the U. S. Supreme Court denied 1st Amendment religious liberty to the sacramental use of Peyote for his Native American Church, Reuben arose to the challange. Creating The Native American Religious Freedom Project and producing an award winning documentary film titled THE PEYOTE ROAD; Ancient Religion In Contemporary Crisis, his efforts resulted in passage of The 1994 Amendment to The American Indian Religious Freedom Act. Combining Mr. Snake's storytelling with interviews of friends and relatives, Your Humble Serpent is an enlightening and inspiring look at a modern day American Indian leader and role model.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?667532</url></doc>
