<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="668262">
  <docid>668262</docid>
  <title>Yurisai</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kaneko, Naoki (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Japanese</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Japan</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Japan">19 July 2004</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="UK">September 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Czech Republic">4 April 2005</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Italy">28 September 2002</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">20 June 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">100</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Hamano, Sachi</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Yamazaki, Kuninori</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Curtis, Mickey</actor>
      <role>Terujiro Miyoshi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hara, Chisako</actor>
      <role>Atsuko Namiki</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Meguro, Sachiko</actor>
      <role>Nene Totsuka</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Delightful romantic complications are stirred up with the arrival of a 75-year-old Casanova, Mr. Miyoshi, at a senior citizens' apartment building. Mrs. Miyano and her five other apartment mates, who range in age from 69 to 91, find their lives forever transformed by his flattery and sexual attentions. Dauntlessly they break out of their shells, reclaiming their own desires. Lily Festival is a humorous and subversive erotic fantasy in which Mrs. Miyano, having found her desire, is now confronting the possibilities of lesbian love for the first time. Lily Festival portrays the lively reawakening of older women who have been shackled by both oppression of women and discrimination against the elderly # these women are definitely not cute old ladies. Director Sachi Hamano has released over 300 low-budget adult films portraying sexuality from women's perspectives. Funding for Lily Festival was provided in part by donations from more than 12,000 women from all over Japan who support Hamano's filmmaking. High production values, great acting and an engaging story make Lily Festival such a delight. If you are looking for granny-on-granny action, be patient # this romantic comedy unfolds in the most lovely and unexpected ways. Lily Festival celebrates golden girls who are bold and overflowing with energy and who find that there is sex after 60.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?668262</url></doc>
