<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="668992">
  <docid>668992</docid>
  <title>Zakhmi Sher</title>
  <year>1984</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Dasari, Narayana Rao</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Sharma, Pradeep (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kudalkar, Laxmikant Shantaram</composer>
    <composer>Sharma, Pyarelal Ramprasad</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhardwaj, Brahm</actor>
      <role>Judge</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhushan, Bharat (I)</actor>
      <role>Judge</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Das, Leena</actor>
      <role>Dancer/Singer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Haksar, Rajan</actor>
      <role>Inspector Malhotra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hattangadi, Rohini</actor>
      <role>Annapoorna Singh (Vijay's mom)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jayasudha (I)</actor>
      <role>Anandi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jeetendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Major Vijay Kumar Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jeevan (I)</actor>
      <role>Advocate Ramnath</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jeevan, Bhushan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Joshi, Renu</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapadia, Dimple</actor>
      <role>Advocate Anu Gupta</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Shakti (I)</actor>
      <role>Arsonist</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khote, Viju</actor>
      <role>Inspector Shankerlal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Kiran (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Malini, Madhu</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mehra, Vinod</actor>
      <role>Police Inspector</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Phule, Nilu</actor>
      <role>Lala (Anandi's dad)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, Amrish</actor>
      <role>Swami Kashinath Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shivpuri, Om</actor>
      <role>Gupta</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sudhir (I)</actor>
      <role>Raghunath Rai</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tiwari, Ramayan</actor>
      <role>Dharam Raj Singh (Drunk driver)</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Honest and diligent Major Vijay Kumar Singh is called back from active duty to attend to the funeral of his mother. He declines as he has to be present on the front as well as inspire others. When he returns home, he grieves for his mother, and sets about finding a suitable groom for his unmarried sister. He finds out that Reshmi is in love with a male, and he goes to talk to this male's father. The father, Lala, agrees to the marriage, provided Vijay marries his mentally retarded daughter, Anandi. Vijay instantly refuses, but when he finds out that his sister is pregnant, he agrees to marry Anandi. Then circumstances force him to be a witness in two crimes - one an arson set deliberately, and the other about a drunk driver who crushes some people asleep on a city footpath. In both the cases, the Judge dismisses the matters. Confused and hurt by a system that is unable to punish the guilty, he ponders on what is going to happen to his country. Then he comes to know that his mother did not die but was murdered and he sets out to find the person(s) responsible for this. Vijay does not trust the police now, and knows that they will let the guilty go unpunished, and sets out to hunt them down one by one - until he comes across the male who actually killed his mother - none other than a holy man named Swami Kashinath Singh - a man who claims to be his biological father, and a man who claims that killing his wife was a mistake. What will Vijay next action be? Will he be objective enough to punish his father for this heinous crime, or will emotion overwhelm him from making any decision.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?668992</url></doc>
