<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="669115">
  <docid>669115</docid>
  <title>Zamane Se Kya Darna</title>
  <year>1994</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="UK">PG</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">172</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Raj, Bobby</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Goel, Shyam</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Chitragupth, Anand</composer>
    <composer>Chitragupth, Milind</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dutt, Sanjay</actor>
      <role>Vikram 'Vicky' V. Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grover, Gulshan</actor>
      <role>Bhairav</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hingoo, Dinesh</actor>
      <role>Chelaramani</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Shakti (I)</actor>
      <role>Shakti G. Singh/Vicky V. Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lagoo, Reema</actor>
      <role>Shalini 'Shaloo' V. Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lever, Johnny</actor>
      <role>Pickpocket</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Manik, Roma</actor>
      <role>Gauri</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maruti, Guddi</actor>
      <role>Guddi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Murad, Raza</actor>
      <role>Gajendra Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nath, Alok</actor>
      <role>Virendra Singh/Sardar Rajpal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rindani, Shiva</actor>
      <role>Gypsy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rohera, Ghanshyam</actor>
      <role>Dhania</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sethi, Ram P.</actor>
      <role>Pyarelal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sudhir (I)</actor>
      <role>Gambler</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Virendra Singh lives wealthy lifestyle in Bommbay, India, along with his wife, Shalini, and son, Vikram. He gambles on Diwali, loses all his money, borrows a large amount from his friend, Gajendra Singh, ends up losing this too, and returns home along with Gajendra and his brother to try and repay as much as he can. When Gajendra's brother attempts to molest Shalini, Virendra's kills him and flees. He boards a bus which meets with an accident, leaving only two survivors - himself and a young heiress named Anju. He adopts her, looks after her estate and assumes a new name, Sardar Rajpal, and becomes wealthy over time. Years later Anju has grown up and finds out about her foster father's tragic story and decides to try and re-unite this family. She posts two advertisements in Bombay's newspapers, to hire an Estate Manager, as well as asking for the whereabouts of Shalini and Vikram. Little does she know that she has opened up a Pandora's box for the advertisements were read by none other than Gajendra and his son, Shakti, who are well aware that Virendra's wife and son had both perished in a fire that engulfed their residence on that very night - and now they are poised to re-enter Virendra's life - with Shakti re-naming himself Vikram with a view of marrying Anju, inheriting her wealth and then the duo plan to kill Virendra to avenge the death of their brother and uncle respectively.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?669115</url></doc>
