<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="672478">
  <docid>672478</docid>
  <title>Zulm Ka Badla</title>
  <year>1985</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Rajput, Shyam</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Prasad, K.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Singh, Swaran (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Sharma, Om Prakash (I)</composer>
    <composer>Sonik, Master</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ameeta (I)</actor>
      <role>Devout Muslim</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Babbar, Minoo</actor>
      <role>Young Geeta</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bunty, Master</actor>
      <role>Young Anil Verma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chandrashekhar</actor>
      <role>Colonel Rajesh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Denzongpa, Danny</actor>
      <role>Shambhu/Bunty</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Haksar, Rajan</actor>
      <role>Pinto</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hingoo, Dinesh</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Irani, Manik</actor>
      <role>Sangram's victim</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jagdeep</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Shakti (I)</actor>
      <role>Jagdish Kumar 'JK'/Sangram Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kiran, Shashi (I)</actor>
      <role>Police Inspector</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kundan (I)</actor>
      <role>Police Inspector</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mehra, Neelam</actor>
      <role>Bijli</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pannu</actor>
      <role>Rana</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Raj, Jagdish</actor>
      <role>Inspector/D.I.G. Verma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rajesh, Master</actor>
      <role>Young Bunty</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Roshan, Rakesh</actor>
      <role>Inspector Anil Verma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Thakkar, Deviyaani</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Verma</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Young and attractive Geeta lives a fairly wealthy lifestyle along with her mom - Savitri, dad - Colonel Rajesh, and brother - Bunty. The family decide to have a get together with the Verma family, which consists of Police Inspector Verma, his wife, and son, Anil. When the Vermas get to Rajesh's residence, they find the house in flames, a traumatized Geeta, the charred remains of her parents, and Bunty missing. Verma takes Geeta home, adopts her, and does not her know that her parents were brutally murdered for fear of traumatizing her even more. Years later Anil has grown up and is now a Police Inspector, while his dad is the D.I.G.. Anil and Geeta fall in love and get married. Then Anil is assigned the murder case of an underworld gangster, Rana. Before he could even conclude his investigation, another gangster, Pinto, is killed. Both Anil and his dad suspect that Geeta may have had a hand in their killing but are unable to prove anything yet decide to keep an eye on her. Geeta subsequently gets pregnant followed by the brutal killing of another gangster, Jagdish Kumar. Anil and his dad confront Geeta but she manages to escape, dons the disguise of a nun, calls herself Mrs. D'Sa, and decides to hunt down the final killer of her family - Sangram Singh. Now visibly pregnant she must now confront a hit-man named Shambhu as well as be on the run from her husband, her father-in-law, the entire Police Force, as well as locate the elusive Sangram, who is believed to be in jail for another murder. The question remains who will assist Geeta, and how will she finally avenge the death of her parents?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?672478</url></doc>
