<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="672402">
  <docid>672402</docid>
  <title>Zugaim dama</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Avitsur, Daniel</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>idf</keyword>
    <keyword>poker</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hebrew</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Israel</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Israel">10 July 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Italy">12 October 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Israel">31</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="default">31</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Giladi, Nitzan</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Cohen, Tsachi</producer>
    <producer>Leshem, Yoav</producer>
    <producer>Zini, Levi</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Katsiri, Roy</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Asaf, Ro'i</actor>
      <role>Green</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Balanga, Oren</actor>
      <role>Dudu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nahari, Ofir</actor>
      <role>Mano</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"Zugaim Dama" ["Queens Up"] is a story about an unequal match in a tough male environment. Somewhere around the northern boundaries of Israel, in an adjutancy office of a quite sleepy military base, on an especially wintry Saturday night - three "desk-jockeys" who remain on weekend duty - are playing Poker. In the course of the poker game it turns out who is weak, who's even weaker and who's the weakest among three: Green, the NCO (non-commissioned officer) who is only three months before his release from the army, has a weakness for money, and poker is the best way he knows to earn it. Dudu, the cook, is about to sign standing army just like his father; He has a weakness for paternal figures, that's why he hangs after Green. And the weakest soldier of the base, Mano, the gate-keeper, has an artificial eye, and he's just came out of basic training, so he's an easy prey for everyone. After a few rounds of poker, Mano confesses that he can't pay the money he owes, so Green makes him a twisted offer: if Mano can't bet on money, why couldn't he bet on his glass-eye. From now on the card game becomes nerve-racking, until the one-eyed rifle-armed Mano turns from a prey into a predator. This movie is about a little nightmarish army.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?672402</url></doc>
