<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="006677">
  <docid>006677</docid>
  <title>7-Eleven zhi lian</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Liao, Ching-Song</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>nail-polish</keyword>
    <keyword>low-fat-milk</keyword>
    <keyword>self-referential</keyword>
    <keyword>convenience-store</keyword>
    <keyword>interview</keyword>
    <keyword>intertitle</keyword>
    <keyword>cashier</keyword>
    <keyword>homecoming</keyword>
    <keyword>jealousy</keyword>
    <keyword>surveillance-camera</keyword>
    <keyword>mentor</keyword>
    <keyword>film-director</keyword>
    <keyword>love-triangle</keyword>
    <keyword>flashback</keyword>
    <keyword>raincoat</keyword>
    <keyword>documentary-filmmaking</keyword>
    <keyword>kimono</keyword>
    <keyword>convict</keyword>
    <keyword>geisha</keyword>
    <keyword>sex</keyword>
    <keyword>taiwanese</keyword>
    <keyword>7-eleven</keyword>
    <keyword>based-on-story</keyword>
    <keyword>secret-admirer</keyword>
    <keyword>train</keyword>
    <keyword>rice-ball</keyword>
    <keyword>japanese</keyword>
    <keyword>fake-custom</keyword>
    <keyword>kyoto-japan</keyword>
    <keyword>number-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
    <language>Japanese</language>
    <language>Mandarin</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Taiwan</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Singapore">27 April 2003</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="France">13 March 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">97</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Teng, Yung-Shing</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Huang, Pin-Yuan</actor>
      <role>Mr. Tsai</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ko, Huan-Ju</actor>
      <role>Hsiao Feng</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Miao, Julius Jay</actor>
      <role>Hsiao Pan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wu, Ke-Chun</actor>
      <role>A Chih</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Mr Tsai makes his living doing creative work. He writes songs and lyrics, pens novels and makes documentaries. Usually, he works at night and sleep during the day. Every morning, after finishing work and before retiring, he goes to the 7-11 at the street corner et purchase milk and rice balls for breakfast. He lives a routine and disciplined life. One day, he breaks his piggy bank by mistake. He looks at the pile of coppers and wonders what he can do to dispose of them. A breakfast costs 32 dollars... that'll last him a good five weeks ! Hsiao Feng, the 7-11 shop assistant, becomes intrigued by the strange customer- this young man who comes in every morning at 10:30 carrying the same combination of small change. Hsiao Feng has just got out of a relationship. The boyfriend, Hsiao Pan, is a good-for-nothing, a bum. When he's not fantasizing getrich- quick schemes, he's getting into trouble with the triads. When he gets put into the can, Hsiao Feng runs away. She gets herself a job at the 7-11, hoping to settle down into a more simple life. At the shop, she sells things and watches drama series on TV. Mr Tsai's arrival gives her something to look forward to in her otherwise uninspired existence. The TV drama series, Raincoat, is extremely popular. It tells the story of a graduate student who's not particularly fond of Japan falling in love with a retired Geisha who's come to Taiwan to study Chinese. They exchange language lessons for four months, and before woman leaves, she follows Japanese convention by presenting the man with a raincoat as token of her feelings. A woman is also expressing her feelings for Mr Tsai in some special ways. For the past few months he has been interviewing a Japanese Geisha. Her name is Kikuliu and she's not an ordinary Geisha. She only enters the profession after graduating from university studying psychology; and she speaks English. The interviews release the emotions behind her heavily powdered face. Before she leaves, she expresses her feelings for Tsai with her eyes. Meanwhile, Hsiao Pan has located Hsiao Feng. One more time, She finds herself caught up in a tumultuous relationship. She wants to escape, and leaves her phone number for someone to give to Mr Tsai...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?006677</url></doc>
