<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="006870">
  <docid>006870</docid>
  <title>8 Simple Rules for Banging My Teenage Daughter 2</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adult</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>hardcore</keyword>
    <keyword>sex</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">31 October 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">141</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Curtis, Stoney</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Commings, T.J.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Curtis, Stoney</actor>
      <role>Interviewer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Emerald (I)</actor>
      <role>Candi's Mom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jayden, Jocelyn</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Love, Alexis (I)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lynn, Vanessa</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lyons, Scott (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Talon (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Taylor, Steve (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Five scenes. First up, a former porn-star brings her daughter in to do her first scene, but overprotective mom has a list of conditions. Yeah, the premise is ridiculous, but it beats no setup at all, and we find out if the actress can deliver a line other than, "Faster, faster. Deeper, deeper." Once mom leaves the room, daughter ends up breaking most of the rules. Next, another porn shoot. This girl has a list from her parents that she and her partner mostly ignore. The next scene takes place at home. Another porn-star mom, interrupts teenage daughter and shirtless guy in his thirties, hanging out on her bed. She sizes up the situation and sets the ground rules for their encounter and heads out to a bar. Again, not much adherence to the rules laid out. Bad parenting continues as we return to the porn studio where dad offers up his daughter as long as they abide by his rules and make the check out to him. While the scene is shot, dad's out shopping for hi-def TVs, so once again the rules go out the window. Another scene of a girl with a list from a camera-shy mom, and we're done.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?006870</url></doc>
