<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="006999">
  <docid>006999</docid>
  <title>8: The Mormon Proposition</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bayerl, Brian</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>mormon</keyword>
    <keyword>digit-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>gay-marriage</keyword>
    <keyword>equal-rights</keyword>
    <keyword>number-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>gay-rights</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Argentina">80</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="USA">80</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Cowan, Reed</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bastian, Bruce</producer>
    <producer>Cowan, Reed</producer>
    <producer>Greenstreet, Steven</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Cowan, Reed</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Greer, Nicholas</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Black, Dustin Lance</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In 2009, thousands of LGBT citizens are denied almost 200 civil rights their straight, married counterparts enjoy through civil marriage. Some states have signaled progress. But amid the progress, The Mormon Church, with its front-group THE NATIONAL ORGANIZATION FOR MARRIAGE, has been coordinating, financing and leading the effort to stop the advancement of marriage equality for more than three decades. As an organization worth hundreds of billions of dollars, the Mormon Church has been able to wage this war in secret. Not until the California Fair Political Practices Commission launched an investigation into the Mormon's involvement in Proposition 8, did the secrets of the Mormon effort become a matter of record. Through never-before seen documents, recordings &amp; insider-interviews, 8: THE MORMON PROPOSITION, exposes the efforts of the Mormon Church and its members to halt nearly every piece of LGBT legislation on the desks of lawmakers from Hawaii to New York. 8: THE MORMON PROPOSITION makes these efforts a matter of record and challenges viewers to demand more of government officials in requiring religions more transparency in their efforts to influence public policy. Emmy-award winning journalist and documentary filmmaker Reed Cowan is a former Mormon who served a two-year mission door-to-door for the Mormon Church. His access to high-level Mormons &amp; Mormon communications on the matter, coupled with his OUT status as a gay man and father of two adopted sons has provided a compelling and at times shocking look at the Mormon way of doing business against LGBT people.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?006999</url></doc>
