<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="006938">
  <docid>006938</docid>
  <title>800 Fantasy Lane</title>
  <year>1979</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Sherman, Joe (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adult</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>hardcore</keyword>
    <keyword>sex</keyword>
    <keyword>address-as-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Argentina">X</certificate>
    <certificate country="USA">X</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Japan">26 January 1980</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">82</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="USA">76</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Svetlana (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Svetlana (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Svetlana (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anderson, Chris (III)</actor>
      <role>Karen/Hot Tub Girl #1</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Colberg, Alan</actor>
      <role>Hubert Fielder</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cousteau, Desiree</actor>
      <role>Girl in Wheelbarrow</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Davis, June (III)</actor>
      <role>Tennis Girl in White Top</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>De Leeuw, Lisa</actor>
      <role>Victoria/The Leopard</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gillis, Jamie</actor>
      <role>Vic Derges</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grady, Sam</actor>
      <role>John Poster</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moonshine, Don</actor>
      <role>Cab Driver</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Two lowly gas pump attendants pose as oil magnates in order to gain entry into the exclusive Hollywood Star Realty ... where the real estate agents are gorgeous, sexy starlets! Met at the airport by 4 eager agents, the counterfeit tycoons are whisked away to tour an upscale mansion hidden in the Hollywood hills at 800 Fantasy Lane. And what a tour it is! The opulent mansion is filled with a bevy of beauties who go out of their way to make the schemers receptive to their pitch. Touring the expansive house, the boys observe half naked girls lounging poolside and walking the halls, while in one room they peek in on 2 lovelies crawling all over each other. Left alone in their room, the boys are anxious to get in on the action. A buxom, fresh-faced woman arrives and quickly checks out our entrepreneur's assets. Playing hard-to-get clients, the boys feign boredom and request to see another property. A luxurious beach house is the setting for an incredible threesome between one woman and the enthusiastic agents. Later, the girl-girl contact with crashing waves as backdrop is stimulating beyond description! Returning to the mansion, one man hears a commotion in the basement and stumbles onto a kinky dungeon scene where the women take him beyond the limits of sensuality. Later, after a lively game of nude-tennis, the provocative agents pull out all the stops in a free-for-all sex rite climaxed by a fantastical ballet with an enormous erupting penis as centerpiece.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?006938</url></doc>
