<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="007589">
  <docid>007589</docid>
  <title>A Belly Full of Dreams</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Prasad, A. Sreekar</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Telugu</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby SR</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">1 June 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="India">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Rao, Prakash (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Thambidorai, Viren</producer>
    <producer>Daggubati, Rana</producer>
    <producer>Raghavendra Rao, K.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bharavi, J.K.</writer>
    <writer>Rao, Prakash (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>R.P., Patnaik</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Sai (I)</actor>
      <role>Ramu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Shiva (II)</actor>
      <role>Chotu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Naresh, E.V.V.</actor>
      <role>Babu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>S.P., Balasubramaniam</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"A Belly full of Dreams" is about Ramu, a boy of 9 had a simple dream of going to school. As with everything in his life, he invested the dream in the belly of the puppet Narrator Know-it-all. Know-it-all, knowing it all, realized that the dream would lie wasted if he didn't talk about it and so began the fable of Ramu - a rag picker who carries the burden of supporting a lazy father, a sickly mother and a life not facilitating his immediate fundamental right - EDUCATION! As the narrative alternates between the puppet world and the real world, we follow Ramu in his travails, exploring both his physical and emotional journeys as he confronts a corrupt system that is threatening to destroy the Nation. Bruised and battered he struggled, but never gave up-his will so strong that it broke the universe from its slumber. The universe conspired to help and sends forth a tooth fairy; to unleash her magic, to set right a broken System and to revive the sagging Belly of the puppet Know-it-all. A magic so beautiful, that it made true the little boy's dream.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?007589</url></doc>
