<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="009409">
  <docid>009409</docid>
  <title>A Day in the Life</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bush, Dan (I)</editor>
    <editor>McReynolds, Michael</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>War</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>soldier</keyword>
    <keyword>future</keyword>
    <keyword>kubrickian</keyword>
    <keyword>german</keyword>
    <keyword>death</keyword>
    <keyword>dying</keyword>
    <keyword>love</keyword>
    <keyword>museum</keyword>
    <keyword>the-beatles</keyword>
    <keyword>meta-story</keyword>
    <keyword>experimental-film</keyword>
    <keyword>photographer</keyword>
    <keyword>boredom</keyword>
    <keyword>office</keyword>
    <keyword>atlanta-georgia</keyword>
    <keyword>1960s</keyword>
    <keyword>2021</keyword>
    <keyword>memory</keyword>
    <keyword>twenty-something</keyword>
    <keyword>wwii</keyword>
    <keyword>space</keyword>
    <keyword>existentialism</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">19 August 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">76</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Bush, Dan (I)</director>
    <director>Coe, Judson</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Weiss, Alexis (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Noveck, Willie</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>A soldier lies in a battlefield dying from a gunshot wound: Legs paralyzed, situation futile. As he fades in and out of consciousness, he reflects on all he has left to live for. The shrill sounds of an air-raid siren pierce the air. A man twenty years later lies awake in bed ignoring the shrill sound of his alarm clock. As he gets up, makes coffee, catches a bus and marches to the office, he reflects on a life left unfulfilled. Inspired by the Beatles' song of the same name, A Day in the Life highlights the forgotten moments and fleeting fantasies that fill the hours. Surreal imagery and sound effects provide the soundtrack to two days existing in separate time periods, creating a lyrical language that challenges the audience to follow two men reaching their own personal front-line. follow each as he reaches his personal front line - the father on his final day on the battlefield, the son each day at his office. In both, we will observe the forgotten moments and the fleeting fantasies that fill the seconds of each day. Beneath a fragile facade we see regret over a life unfulfilled, the hope for legacy and the dream of a greater human condition.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?009409</url></doc>
