<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="010197">
  <docid>010197</docid>
  <title>A Father's Rights</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Blanton, Chris</editor>
    <editor>Fuqua, Miles</editor>
    <editor>Parks, Carson</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>three-word-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 June 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">110</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Blanton, Chris</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Buchanan, Jim (III)</producer>
    <producer>Carlson, Karen (I)</producer>
    <producer>Shiflet, Jason</producer>
    <producer>Fain, William (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Blanton, Chris</writer>
    <writer>Fain, William (II)</writer>
    <writer>Itson, Matthew</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Mains, Rolin R.</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Allen, Deborah (I)</actor>
      <role>Gail Walker</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Apidgian, Mike</actor>
      <role>Jack Benson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bruce, Ed (I)</actor>
      <role>Senator Edwards</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carlson, Karen (I)</actor>
      <role>Ms. Little</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Collie, Mark</actor>
      <role>Det. Eddie Roberts</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Darling, Sarah (II)</actor>
      <role>Receptionist</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Davis, Robbie (II)</actor>
      <role>Seth Ryder</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Holley, John (I)</actor>
      <role>Travis</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Knapp Jr., Frank</actor>
      <role>Judge Phillips</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Miller, Jeff (XXXIV)</actor>
      <role>Lawyer for State</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Russell, Allen (II)</actor>
      <role>Jury Foreman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Soul, Jon (II)</actor>
      <role>Doctor Pondillo</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"A Father's Rights" is based upon a real life story. It depicts the situation of an unwed father and his child's struggle with the legal system predominant in American society today. It is meant to expose the system that treats children differently across this country and the world: a system that needs to change. We should all be looking at and working for one thing, getting equal rights for our children. It should not matter if a child is born out of wedlock. It's not the child's fault, and that child should have the same rights as a child from a happily married couple. Stop the fighting over who gets custody and what he/she receives for the privilege of raising that child. The system that all of us face as parents, and/or grandparents is broken. No matter if you are mother, father, or grandparent, we all must acknowledge this basic fact. Thousands of emails have been received over the past year about this project asking for help, or parents telling their own horror stories with the system. One major problem is that fathers, mothers, and grandparents all seem to be fighting for their own rights. We should all be able to come together and fight for our children's rights. The right to be treated equally, no matter if their parents are married, were married, or never married. If that goal is obtained, then a lot of the problems in the system will go away. This movie was made to bring attention to and educate the public about a corrupt system that is not taking care of the future: making sure children are well taken care of</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?010197</url></doc>
