<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="010552">
  <docid>010552</docid>
  <title>A Foreign Kiss in Times Square</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Sanders Alcántara, Gisela</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Colombia">6 October 2003</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">12 November 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">14</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Lea Higby, Josie</director>
    <director>Reyes, Wilson</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Young, Koren</producer>
    <producer>Lea Higby, Josie</producer>
    <producer>Reyes, Wilson</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Coorey, Adam</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Haule, Kristin</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Robinson, Scott Michael</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tatlock Jr., Norman</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Young, Koren</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Its 11:59pm on New Years Eve and revelers from all over the world fill Times Square, New York, the biggest party on earth. Millions more watch the great, colorful ball drop on television in the comfort of their own homes while the majority of native New Yorkers avoid the festivities all together and travel instead to local clubs or out of town family events. This documentary follows three young adults who travel to New York for their first time to attend the party. Kristin, a mathematics major living in Berkeley, California, brings her shy boyfriend. Norm, an Air Force instructor from Georgia, meets his friend Scott, a programmer from Florida, desperately hoping to meet a few hot girls. As the three of them spend twelve hours in below freezing temperatures, unable to reach the bathrooms and waiting for the ball to drop, they meet many friendly and some estranged revelers from around the world. Although many can turn their televisions on every year to witness the events, this documentary shows the reality of the party from the street, rather than from the fancy party rooms high above. Filmed by three revelers intrigued with their own experience from the year before, the documentary asks the question "is the travel and expense worth the experience?" Norm and Scott begin to think it is as they meet some cute girls from England. For these revelers, their first time in Times Square is filled with anticipation, excitement, disappointment, and the question; "will I get a midnight kiss?"</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?010552</url></doc>
