<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="014780">
  <docid>014780</docid>
  <title>A Power Sun</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>black-panther-party</keyword>
    <keyword>assata-shakur</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">14 October 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>McGhee, Dawn</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Joseph, Jamal</producer>
    <producer>McGhee, Dawn</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>McGhee, Dawn</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hall, Irma P.</actor>
      <role>Eartha Kahn</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Olugabala, Mutulu</actor>
      <role>Sun</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wiseman, Omar</actor>
      <role>Cinque Kahn</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Clark Edward Squire, aka Sundiata Acoli was reared in a small town in Texas, worked as a Computer Analyst for NASA with astronaut Neil Armstrong, and became known as one of the loyalist activists during the Civil Rights Movement and beyond. With a home front war brewing, a movement allegiance to educating and liberating the oppressed was the goal. Former Black Panther Party (herein BPP) member and current prisoner, Sundiata Acoli shares his story via vocal narration and dramatic re-enactments about his journey through the BPP and the Liberation Movement in America. A POWER SUN tells of a courageous man, who served as the Party's Lt. of Finance, and blatant cover-ups by a government who turned its back on justice. It explores many aspects of the BPP Movement in New York with direct accounts from former members, including the states' longest and most expensive criminal trial to date. Acoli joins his family and friends in this docu-film of his life from childhood to his current struggles as a prisoner, along with direct accounts, historical context and critical perspectives. The film's plot is navigated by the conversation between a grandmother, Eartha "Mama Earth" Kahn, and grandson, Cinque Kahn, as "Mama Earth" teaches Cinque about the BPP NY Chapter using a unique game of chess on a recreational park set. As Cinque learns chess, a by-stander in the park, Sun, listens to the instructions and applies the lessons to his life. An exploration of Acoli's life is revisited. The audience experiences the surreal life of Acoli, as well as learning the art of chess.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?014780</url></doc>
