<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="015210">
  <docid>015210</docid>
  <title>A Really Intimate Portrait... of a Complete Unknown</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">6 September 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">28</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Alpert, Danielle</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Alpert, Danielle</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bucatinsky, Dan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sepenuk, Pete</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Williams, Chris (XII)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Lifetime Television's Intimate Portrait is a landmark series that has provided the viewer with a closer look at many amazing women who have changed our lives. This groundbreaking show has spotlighted everyone from Golda Meir and Ruth Bader Ginsburg to Loni Anderson. But the day Lauralee Bell got an Intimate Portrait, somebody stood up, and shouted, "who the fuck is Lauralee Bell, and why does she get an Intimate Portrait?" That person was Dani Alpert. Apparently, all it takes is a couple of credits to be the subject of an Intimate Portrait. That being the case, Dani didn't see any reason why she didn't have one. She'd done stuff. The only problem was convincing Lifetime. Dani decided not to bother. She would write, shoot, star, and edit her Intimate Portrait by herself. She had some concerns along the way. Would her accomplishments, obstacles and drama, be less interesting to viewers than if she was actually known? She didn't know, and she didn't care. She'd let the viewer decide. If Lifetime was going to persist in producing Intimate Portraits of the lesser known, then Dani was going to take it a step further, and produce an Intimate Portrait of a complete unknown. She felt that the subject of an Intimate Portrait should have to earn their portrait? The Portrait loses meaning and significance if they're handed out willy nilly. It's not unlike Britney Spears getting a star on the Hollywood walk of Fame. There were artists who spent lifetimes working in the business before they were honored with a star. They weren't 19 and wearing a thong. If there are no rules then any woman, like Dani, who has ever done anything, qualifies them to be an Intimate Portrait subject. Just like Dani.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?015210</url></doc>
