<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="015850">
  <docid>015850</docid>
  <title>A Seven Mile Drive</title>
  <year>2011</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>South Africa</country>
    <country>UK</country>
    <country>Hungary</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">2011</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <producers>
    <producer>Owen, Russell (II)</producer>
    <producer>Thompson, Andy (VIII)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Owen, Russell (II)</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Famed the world over for her extraordinary abilities, Yvonne Green had become America's foremost trusted psychic medium. Her gift had secured her book deals, television contracts and endorsements. But her phenomenal career disintegrates following a malicious, organised campaign by an over-ambitious tabloid journalist. To add to her woes, a devastated Yvonne has to battle through a bitter divorce that sees her lose custody of two beloved children. Distraught, broken and relying on prescription drugs, she sells up and heads to the Welsh valleys, following her estranged husband to the remote village of Trefriw. Desperate to be near the kids she buys the only property available, a seven-mile drive away through a vast, deserted pine forest nestled deep within the mountains. However, it isn't long before she learns of the sinister back-story to this ruggedly beautiful landscape. A spate of sudden disappearances is coupled with a disturbing legend that stretches back to the dark ages; the legend of 'a demonic beast sent from hell to collect and ferry across souls of impure mind'. Initially dismissive of local folklore, Yvonne puts all her energy into building a new life for herself, escaping her fame and trying desperately to reconnect with her children. Emotional, isolated and lonely, Yvonne begins to spiral slowly into depression until she happens across her only neighbour, John Wood, a reclusive, elderly cattle farmer, who has lived alone for nearly twenty years since the disappearance of his wife and son. Intrigued by him and grateful for his ignorance of her fame, Yvonne attempts a friendship. Soon, however, she becomes uneasy around the peculiar old man. His sharp mind and over enthusiastic interest in her children begin to disturb her. Frightened and hounded by visions of the dead, she turns to her abandoned gift, opening her mind and listening to warnings from the troubled entities desperately trying to communicate with her. What she learns petrifies her. Stunned with terror, the truth behind the disappearance of John Wood's son and countless others is revealed to her. Panicked and in shock, Yvonne races off in a desperate attempt to save her children. But the 'legend' of the forest is one step ahead of her.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?015850</url></doc>
