<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="016089">
  <docid>016089</docid>
  <title>A Skin, a Night</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Moon, Vincent</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>concert</keyword>
    <keyword>music-scene</keyword>
    <keyword>rock</keyword>
    <keyword>semi-documentary</keyword>
    <keyword>band</keyword>
    <keyword>live</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">26 May 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Denmark">25 April 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">63</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="default">63</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Moon, Vincent</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Perrier, Alexandre</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Berninger, Matt (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dessner, Aaron</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dessner, Bryce</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Devendorf, Bryan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Devendorf, Scott</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Newsome, Padma</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Seeking the right lyrics, notes, sounds, instruments to express yourself is not easy. It's even harder if a whole group of artists is looking into a sea of good ideas. A communion with the spectator is going to appear. The National is a band from New York that runs away from everything to create a new album. This creation was shot by the French artist Vincent Moon in a film called A skin, A Night. The story of this band starts inside the studio. During the first steps the director follows The National as they create the new songs while searching for a new kind of sound. The film shows how one of New York's bands works also dark places in the artist's heart and soul. You will see the creative process: how they work, how it grows from a simple guitar riff to a whole song. A Skin, A Night is about music, creation and external things that an artist absorbs before he goes inside the studio also how it affects the result. Away from all distractions in order to leave the ideas coming together back and forward. A Skin, A night is a ticket to follow "The National" on a long journey that ends with the release of their last album "Boxer". It's about the questions they are asking themselves during these sessions. It was the first time they work this way, all together, in the same studio, with everybody giving ideas and opinions. You will see how they feel while recording this way. This film will make you see through the eyes of the band and understand what made them to create this album this way. But this is not only about The National, it's also about how difficult it is for any artist or any band to be themselves.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?016089</url></doc>
