<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="016000">
  <docid>016000</docid>
  <title>A Silent Whistle</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">12</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Kyle, Russell</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Church, Jacqui</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ellison, Christopher</actor>
      <role>Brian Bevan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Malone, Martin (II)</actor>
      <role>Michael Conway</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Spencer, Jonathan (II)</actor>
      <role>Carlton Dean</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>After an organized hit takes a turn for the worst, only one of three men can be held responsible. Throughout the aftermath of this monumental error, each of these men plot and scheme to shift the blame and prevent themselves from being killed for something they have potentially not done. The one problem and only question that cannot escape all three is...who has blown the whistle on who? Brian Bevan, an infamous and invisible drug lord hires Irishman Michael Conway to take out his associate, Carlton Dean, who he claims has been double crossing him for over 3 months. However, when a routine killing doesn't go according to Bevan's plans and Conway finds himself in a situation beyond his control, who will have the cunning to out smart the other, who will have the daring to make the first move and who will more importantly remain alive. A Silent Whistle follows the twists and turns of three men caught up in a situation that cannot be swept under the carpet or ignored. If someone is going to say something, it's perhaps best they say nothing at all.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?016000</url></doc>
