<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="016156">
  <docid>016156</docid>
  <title>A Small Domain</title>
  <year>1996</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Dorn, Dody</editor>
    <editor>Sjogren, Britta</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">January 1996</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">18</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Sjogren, Britta</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Sjogren, Britta</producer>
    <producer>Sperling, Andrea</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Sjogren, Britta</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Leyh, Blake</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gasteyer, Ana</actor>
      <role>Mother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hayes, Beatrice</actor>
      <role>Woman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kuntz, Rebecca Guadalupe</actor>
      <role>Baby</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sjogren, Lance</actor>
      <role>Clerk</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Once upon a time, there was a 95-year-old kleptomaniac. One morning, she woke up, drank her coffee and watered her plants as usual, and went to the mall. There she stole some things she needed: a coil for a ball-point pen and some nice new shears. That night she thought about her dead husband, because the next day was their anniversary. Early the next day, she cut the stalks of all her sunflowers and put them in a jar. Then she took an old brown bottle of poison from the cupboard and put it out on the counter -- just so she wouldn't forget. She needed to go shopping again, so she went to the supermarket and stole some more stuff -- then she had to wait for the bus. A curious thing happened at the bus-stop. A mother asked her to watch her baby, and left. The baby was crying, but the old woman knew who it really was, so she when the bus came, she took the baby home with her. That afternoon she made the cake, and poured all the poison from the old brown bottle into the batter. Then she and the baby waited for the cake to bake.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?016156</url></doc>
