<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="016461">
  <docid>016461</docid>
  <title>A Star Close to Home</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Goldschmidt, Katie</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Musical</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-short</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">4 November 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">13.5</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Goldschmidt, Katie</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Sobol, Gianna</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Goldschmidt, Katie</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Raimi, Daniel</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Elmaleh, Sarah</actor>
      <role>Blanche</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Flanagan, Laura (I)</actor>
      <role>Mama</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Goldschmidt, Jessica</actor>
      <role>Irene Norland/Jessica North</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Helfer, Ian</actor>
      <role>Gerry</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Popper, Ben</actor>
      <role>Jeff</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>It's the opening night of a new musical show, and a fresh, young ingénue waits nervously in the wings. This will be her first ever appearance center stage, and she has a lot to prove. As the overture ends and the first number begins, Jessica North relives the adversity she has had to face thus far. Memories of her disapproving mother, an egotistical leading man, and a dismissive director surge through her mind as her confidence wanes. Frantically, she scans the audience for a familiar, supportive face. Seeing none, Jessica prepares for her entrance, while her mother arrives at the last minute. Overwhelmed by her anxiety, and shocked by her mother's sudden appearance, Jessica bungles her entrance, bringing the show crashing to a halt. With the director livid, the leading man smug, and the audience outraged, Mama turns to leave, but Jessica finally takes a stand. An impromptu tap dance brings them all around, including Mama, who is drawn on stage to see for herself the joys of song and dance. Mother and daughter re-unite as the entire theater joins in the final refrain; reminding us to always follow our heart and let those we love do the same.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?016461</url></doc>
