<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="017648">
  <docid>017648</docid>
  <title>A Union in Wait</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Berndt, Thomas (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>wake-forest</keyword>
    <keyword>same-sex-union</keyword>
    <keyword>lesbian</keyword>
    <keyword>gay-activism</keyword>
    <keyword>gay-marriage</keyword>
    <keyword>lesbian-interest</keyword>
    <keyword>gay-interest</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">3 June 2001</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Italy">12 April 2001</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Germany">20 October 2001</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">12 April 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">45</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Butler, Ryan</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Butler, Ryan</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Schuler, Jason (I)</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>In May of 1981 Wendy Scott would meet a new co-worker named Susan Parker. Their new friendship would quickly transform into something more special. A Union In Wait takes a very personal look at Susan Parker and Wendy Scott's relationship and the controversy that would make their private life anything but private. Susan Parker and Wendy Scott are members of Wake Forest Baptist Church. In 1997 the couple decided they wanted to have a union ceremony in Wake Forest University's Wait Chapel, but the university told them no. Susan Parker, Wendy Scott, their church, and many others joined together to fight the school's decision in what would become a controversy that divided a community in North Carolina and made national headlines. A Union In Wait includes interviews with Andrew Sullivan, Barney Frank, Robert Knight, Jimmy Creech, Fred Phelps, Candace Gingrich, Wake Forest University students, and local ministers. Also included is footage from the Millennium March on Washington, attended by over eight hundred thousand gay activists.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?017648</url></doc>
