<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="017709">
  <docid>017709</docid>
  <title>A Very Cool Christmas</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Broom, Ness</editor>
    <editor>Tourneur, Paul</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>vancouver-british-columbia</keyword>
    <keyword>gratitude</keyword>
    <keyword>respect</keyword>
    <keyword>teenage-girl</keyword>
    <keyword>growing-up</keyword>
    <keyword>gay-parent</keyword>
    <keyword>christmas</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="UK">U</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Hungary">26 December 2006</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Canada">2004</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">20 December 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Irvin, Sam (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Colichman, Paul</producer>
    <producer>Kamens, Stanton W.</producer>
    <producer>Shavick, James (I)</producer>
    <producer>Shaw, Kirk</producer>
    <producer>Shavick, James (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Gelbart, Michael</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Allen, Peter (VII)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carter, Adrienne (I)</actor>
      <role>Paige</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cook, Preston</actor>
      <role>Tough Kid</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cudmore, Daniel</actor>
      <role>Gym Guy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ferland, Jodelle</actor>
      <role>Alexa</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gash, Mark (II)</actor>
      <role>Salesman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gelbart, Michael</actor>
      <role>Chuck</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hamilton, George (I)</actor>
      <role>Santa Claus</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harrington, Adam (I)</actor>
      <role>Matt</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hope, Barclay</actor>
      <role>Stan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Levy, Barry W.</actor>
      <role>Rob Bothwell</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McDonell, Ryan (I)</actor>
      <role>Anderson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mills, Donna</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Claus</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ohtsji, Kevan</actor>
      <role>Donnie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Scott, Malcolm (IV)</actor>
      <role>Uncle Phil</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Soriano, Marco (I)</actor>
      <role>Eduardo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Whale, Sean (I)</actor>
      <role>Food Server</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Sixteen-year-old Lindsay Deerfield wants absolutely zilch to do with the whole deal, especially hanging out on Christmas with her family. Lindsay's just way Too Cool for Christmas. She'd totally prefer going skiing with her buds and chilling with the wickedest guys in school. But as sometimes happens on Christmas Eve, Lindsay meets a whiskery old chap whose magic stirs up her spirit and transforms her life forever.! With only two shopping days before Christmas, Lindsay gets up the nerve to notify her physically expressive male homosexual parents that her whole class is going skiing on Christmas Day and that she is definitely going too. The Deerfields are not impressed and ask Lindsay to try to be a little less selfish and consider the feelings of others. Lindsay's six-year-old sister Alexis is devastated by the thought of Christmas without her sister, but for Lindsay, Christmas at home is so been there done that! -- nothing can change her mind. Lindsay -- and her best friend Paige -- decide to visit the mall to check out this year's Santa and maybe have a laugh, at his expense of course. It may be extremely uncool to visit Santa, but a free candy cane is -- a free candy cane. Lindsay immediately insults the old man's taste in clothes and his excessive size. Despite this, Santa requests Lindsay's assistance in changing his look telling her he absolutely needs a makeover. You see, the tinsel in his marriage to Mrs. C has lost some glitter over the years and well just maybe...a new image would brighten up the long dark days of a North Pole winter. Moved by the man's sincerity, Lindsay gets the Claus a new do, designer suit, and a way cool attitude. Impressed by the whole thing, Santa takes Lindsay into his confidence and asks her to help him out on the big night; Christmas Eve. His sleigh won't start (must be the battery again) so he asks Lindsay if he can hitch the reindeer to her convertible for the night! Lindsay checks out the reindeer, the sleigh, and the presents and agrees to do it on ONE condition: Santa guarantees Lindsay won't be late for the big ski trip Christmas morning. Together the two dash from roof to roof, piling presents under trees and under the noses of all the sleeping little children. Lindsay explodes at Santa for eating too many cookies and offers him carrot sticks as a healthy alternative, but Santa takes it all in stride. When it finally comes down to Lindsay arriving at her own home, there is a surprise in store when Santa asks Lindsay to make this delivery herself. Lindsay enters her home with presents absolutely overflowing in her arms only to come face to face with the true spirit of Christmas.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?017709</url></doc>
