<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="018553">
  <docid>018553</docid>
  <title>A Word from God: Four Principles for Believers</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">7 January 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Lindly, James</director>
  </directors>
<plot>A Word from God is a Christian bible lesson series by James Lindly. These Christian bible studies are designed to enlighten you with God's Word and His everlasting love. In this special edition we will be examining four principles that every believer in Christ should exercise on a daily basis. Implementing these four principles will grow you spiritually and bring blessings into your life that will spill over into the lives others. Four Bible Lessons Covered: Forgiveness: Do you have un-forgiveness in your heart? Do you pray for your enemies? Listen as James Lindly helps us to understand what God wants from us when we feel hurt by others and how forgiving them is the right thing to do. Giving Your Life: What does Jesus want from you and your life? Take a deeper look into what Jesus wants from you and how your submission to Him will lead to a greater fulfillment in your spiritual walk with God. Words for Guidance: Ever wonder what God wants for your life? Do you need some insight for the confusing situations life can sometimes bring? This inspirational message by James Lindly deals with getting guidance from God through His Word while highlighting many strong points about the dangers of falling away from God and His Word. Peace Through Obedience: Do you want more from God? Do you want to give more to God? This inspirational message by James Lindly deals with lining up with God's Word in order to get the full blessings He has in store for you while giving back to God in the process.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?018553</url></doc>
