<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="019643">
  <docid>019643</docid>
  <title>A.D.</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Asher, Jeremy (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>post-apocalyptic</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">7</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>White, Jeff (III)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Rodriguez, Phil (II)</producer>
    <producer>White, Jeff (III)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>White, Jeff (III)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Maleki, Hamidreza</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Decker, Amanda</actor>
      <role>Allison Dawn</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>James, Karen V.</actor>
      <role>Khalia</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Allison Dawn - warrior/missionary of a post-apocalyptic Earth -- crash lands her surface pod somewhere in the freezing sub-Arctic. She is immediately attacked by a pack of hungry mutant wolves, which, she easily dispatches with her ancient Old West-style revolvers. She uses their hides for extra clothing and to build a make-shift snow wigwam. Her presence soon attracts another hostile, this time an aggressive native woman. Allison, an expert shot with her pistols, once again gains the upper-hand. The native woman wakes up next to a campfire in Allison's warm shelter. The gunshot wound on her shoulder has been dressed. After sharing some drink and foreign banter to one another, Allison introduces herself and finds out the native woman's name is Khalia. It seems to be the start of an unlikely friendship. When Allison awakes, Khalia is gone. Allison steps out into the twilight. Khalia stands looking out over a nearby ridge. Allison joins her. Khalia says something in her native tongue. Both women stare out to a descending valley at the deserted ruins of a once great urban metropolis.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?019643</url></doc>
