<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="020295">
  <docid>020295</docid>
  <title>Aaghaaz</title>
  <year>2000</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Reddy, Krishna (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">6 October 2000</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Kuwait">24 October 2000</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Ishwar, Yogesh</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Babu, D. Suresh</producer>
    <producer>Naidu, D. Rama</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Pandey, Kamlesh</writer>
    <writer>Posaani, Krishna Murali</writer>
    <writer>Saini, Nikhil</writer>
    <writer>Upadhyay, Alok</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Malik, Anu</composer>
    <composer>Srilekha, M.M.</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anand, Akshay</actor>
      <role>Harish Patel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Asrani</actor>
      <role>Gullu (Gay)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bedi, Rakesh</actor>
      <role>Dilip Roy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dalvi, Sudhir</actor>
      <role>Pushpa's Father</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grover, Gulshan</actor>
      <role>Sadanand Kutty</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapila, Padmini</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Balraj Nanda</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Sharad S.</actor>
      <role>Laxman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kher, Anupam</actor>
      <role>Balraj Nanda</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khote, Viju</actor>
      <role>Deshpande</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lever, Johnny</actor>
      <role>Rajni Deva</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Namdeo, Govind</actor>
      <role>Karim Khan Toofani</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nath, Alok</actor>
      <role>Ram Charan Shukla</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Parvez, Yunus</actor>
      <role>Dheerajlal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Potdar, Achyut</actor>
      <role>The Judge</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, Rajesh</actor>
      <role>Professor. Pillai</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rajnikanth (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself (a scene from a movie)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rindani, Shiva</actor>
      <role>Suku</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Saxena, Sharat</actor>
      <role>Johnny Handsome Mendoza</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shetty, Sunil (I)</actor>
      <role>Govind Narang</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Srivastav, Anjan</actor>
      <role>The Ordinary Man</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tiwari, Mukesh</actor>
      <role>Danny Mendoza</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Honest, upright, young and handsome Govind Narang falls in love with a young woman named Sudha. But due to circumstances in the occurrence of an unknown pregnancy by a police man, Govind is forced to marry Pushpa, Masterji's daughter, since the police man refuse to marry her. All is well for Govind after the marriage but not with Pushpa and her hot-headed brother Laxman as they learn about Govind's old relationship with Sudha, they trys to throw her out of the village but to no avil as she is now a police officer. When Laxman finds out about Pushpa's infidelity, he poisons her, and she soon passed away. Seeing his wife dead and to wash away his past Govind and his sister, Rattna now relocates to Bombay in an area called Azad Nagar. He soon reaches up with super-star Gitika, and both fell in love. Azad Nagar residents has always been fared by Johnny and his brother Danny Handsome. One day Govind attempts to defend the right of a young woman and he seriously beats up Danny. When Johnny attempts revenge from Govind, he is humiliated, shaved and striped naked on the outskirts of Bombay by Govind and other residents. Johnny soon recruits two foreigners: Sadanana Kutty and Karim Khan Toofani in order to average his humiliation. Govind also attempts to help hawkers and Sole Traders and so befriends a savior, Ram Shevak and decides to build a market for them in order for them to put up there businesses. Soon it was found out that the plot of land and the owner were fakes and Govind gets all the blame and is called a fraud. He goes with the help of Ram Shevak to find out why he is called names and witnessed his sister being raped openly and he himself is beaten up and badly injured infront of the same residents whom he pitied and try to save. The questions remain: Will Govind ever recover to take revenge on his perpetrators? Will he be granted justice by anyone in Azad Nagar?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?020295</url></doc>
