<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="020356">
  <docid>020356</docid>
  <title>Aaj Ka Robin Hood</title>
  <year>1987</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="West Germany">February 1988</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="India">150</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="default">80</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Sinha, Tapan</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Jalan, R.A.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Sinha, Tapan</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Sinha, Tapan</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chatterjee, Anil</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dutt, Utpal</actor>
      <role>Ram S. Jadhav</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ghosh, Robi</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Patekar, Nana</actor>
      <role>Ramdulaare S. Jadhav</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ravi, Master</actor>
      <role>Ramkishan Ram Jadhav</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shah, Satish</actor>
      <role>Ramdas S. Jadhav</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Talwar, Ritesh</actor>
      <role>Tetra Chedi Tushar</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Jatin Chatterjee lives a poor lifestyle in India circa the British rule. He is amongst the thousands who are actively agitating for the British to quit India. One day while on the run from authorities, he takes shelter on a tree and is apprehended by Shyam Jadhav, who takes him under his wing, hides him from the British, educates him, and then subsequently hires him to teach his sons, Ram, Ramdas, and Ramdulaare. Years later all three men have grown up, are married and have children of their own, who are also Jatin's students. While there is no electricity in Jatin's classroom, a poor young boy, Tetra, the son of a farm laborer, Chedi Tushar, manually operates a ceiling fan, educates himself, and impresses everyone with his arithmetical and memorizing skills so much so that Ram Jadhav instructs Jatin to include him as a regular student. Then Ram is asked to contest elections which he does so without much help from his Ramdas, who is comically forgetful, and Ramdulaare, who spends all his time riding his horse and gambling. Watch what happens when Jatin instructs his students about the legendary bandit Robin Hood and the impact this has on everyone in the community.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?020356</url></doc>
