<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="020408">
  <docid>020408</docid>
  <title>Aakhri Khat</title>
  <year>1966</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Rao, Jadav</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">153</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Anand, Chetan</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Anand, Chetan</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Khayyam (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bunty, Master</actor>
      <role>Buntu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chitnis, Manvendra</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Choti, Mohan</actor>
      <role>Bit part</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jehan, Naqi</actor>
      <role>Ladjo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khanna, Rajesh</actor>
      <role>Govind</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Palsikar, Nana</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rao, Maruti (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>It was in scenic Kulu that Govind Bali had first met Lajoo, both fell in love, got married secretly in a temple and parted company. When Lajoo becomes pregnant, her step-mother sells her to a male for 500 Rupees, where she is beaten and thrown out. She goes to Govind, who is on the verge of going to America, who refuses to believe that the child is his. Lajoo writes a letter informing him that she will never see him again. Govind re-locates to Bombay where he starts his own business, and makes a sculptor of Lajoo. She writes to him from Amritsar when she gives birth to Buntu her son. She again writes to him from Delhi when he begins to walk, and yet another letter when he begins to talk. The last two letters that Govind receives inform him that Lajoo and Buntu are now in Bombay, that Lajoo is seriously ill and may not live long. Shortly thereafter Govind goes to the Police, meets with a skeptical Inspector Naik, and a few days later he is asked to identify Lajoo's lifeless body found on the beach. Then the search begins for Buntu, who is only 15 months old, no one know what he looks like, and whether he is still alive or not. How can Govind and the Police ever locate a child, in a city of millions of similar-aged children, and if at all they do, how can they positively identify him as Govind's child?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?020408</url></doc>
