<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="020550">
  <docid>020550</docid>
  <title>Aao Pyaar Karen</title>
  <year>1994</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">25 November 1994</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Peepat, Ravindra</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bokadia, Gautam</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Shrivastava, Adesh</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ali, Somy</actor>
      <role>Sonu S. Rai</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Aparajita</actor>
      <role>Sampat's wife</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arjun (I)</actor>
      <role>Suraj</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bedi, Rakesh</actor>
      <role>Pandit Kashiram</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bharti</actor>
      <role>Anjali</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chopra, Prem</actor>
      <role>Sampat Rai</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grover, Gulshan</actor>
      <role>Maniram</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Saif Ali</actor>
      <role>Raja</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khanna, Mukesh</actor>
      <role>Shankar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kiran, Shashi (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, Rajesh</actor>
      <role>Bakshish</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Subbiraj</actor>
      <role>Anjali's husband</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Talsania, Tiku</actor>
      <role>Tikuram</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Wealthy Suraj lives in a palatial house with his mom, Anjali, and dad. When the time comes for his marriage, his parents find a suitable match for him, but he instead marries a woman from a poor family, antagonizing his parents, who ask him to make a choice between his wife and them. Suraj chooses to stay with his wife, and moves out. Years later, Suraj's dad passes away, leaving his wife alone to look after the business and the vast estate, and making her promise that she will never welcome Suraj, his wife, nor any of their children in this house. Suraj and is wife tragically pass away due to an accident, leaving behind a son named Raja. One day Anjali receives a telegram informing her of Raja coming to settle down with her. She instructs her employees not to let Raja inside the house, so Raja pitches a tent on her lawn and lives there, hoping one day to win her over and be invited in the house. He does succeed, and Anjali does welcome him with open arms. Since he is of marriageable age, she would like him to marry a beautiful young woman by the name of Sonu Rai, the daughter of wealthy Sampat Rai. But Raja is in love with Chhaya, a servant in their household, which is quite unacceptable to Anjali. Over at Chhaya's house, her brother, Shankar, opposes her marriage with Raja, and would like her to marry Maniram. Looks like history is all set to repeat itself as both Chhaya and Raja have sworn to marry each other and no one else.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?020550</url></doc>
