<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="020586">
  <docid>020586</docid>
  <title>Aaram Haram Aahe!</title>
  <year>1976</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bhosle, Waman B.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Marathi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">1976</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Torne, Kamalakar</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Phadke, Sudhir</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Berde, Roohi</actor>
      <role>Dadu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhagwat, Suresh</actor>
      <role>Sudam</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chavan, Padma</actor>
      <role>Padma 'Pama' Pammi'</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dhumal</actor>
      <role>Jagge</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kale, Asha</actor>
      <role>Sudha Godbhole</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mahajani, Ravindra</actor>
      <role>Mahesh Kuber/Suresh Vichare</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Solanki, Ganesh</actor>
      <role>Chauffeur</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Talvalkar, Sharad</actor>
      <role>Potbhare</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Sudha Godbhole lives a poor lifestyle in Bombay along with her widowed mother and works as a Secretary, earning a salary of Rs.300/- every month. She meets with and falls in love with her neighbor, Suresh Vichare, who works in a Garage as a Motor Mechanic, earns a salary of Rs.200/- every month, and rents a terraced room. Both plan to get married, and Suresh even starts giving her money so that they save for their future children. Then one day Suresh does not return home and jewelry and cash are found stolen from the Godbhole residence, including the cash that Suresh left in their safe-keeping. Sudha and Suresh's friend, Sudam, start to look for him and make inquiries at the garage, and are told that he has not attended work for two days and has taken off with a customer's Impala. Sudha and Sudam eventually do locate Suresh near Bangalore but find that he is now living a wealthy lifestyle by impersonating Mahesh Kuber, an industrialist, and also has a chic girlfriend by the name of Padma. Watch what impact this has on Sudha and Sudam.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?020586</url></doc>
