<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="020567">
  <docid>020567</docid>
  <title>Aap To Aise Na The</title>
  <year>1980</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">5 December 1980</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Sangal, Ambrish</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kumar, Mohan (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Khanna, Usha</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Babbar, Raj</actor>
      <role>Vijay</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dulari (I)</actor>
      <role>Vijay's Mother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kaur, Ranjeeta</actor>
      <role>Varsha Oberoi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumari, Lalita</actor>
      <role>Harnam Kaur J. Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mehmood Jr.</actor>
      <role>Billu J. Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mehra, Raj</actor>
      <role>Police Commissioner</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Parashar, Deepak</actor>
      <role>Vikram Chawla</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, Madan (I)</actor>
      <role>Khanna/Jagjit 'Jaggi' Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shivpuri, Om</actor>
      <role>Oberoi/Michael</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Orphaned at a very young age, Varsha Oberoi, lives a wealthy lifestyle with her paternal uncle, Jain Oberoi, in Bombay, and has traveled world-wide. She is in love with Vijay, a middle-classed young man, who runs a small furniture store, badly in debt, and lives with his widowed mom, a younger brother, Deepu, and sister, Nanhi, who are very friendly with Varsha. Then Vijay is reunited with his childhood friend, Vikram Chawla, who is welcomed with open arms by the entire family. It is then Vijay's life turns around, he starts getting a lot of orders, gets out of debt, is able to buy a jeep to replace his motorbike, and moves to a comfortable bungalow. Then Vijay's life is turned upside down when he finds out that Vikram and Varsha are getting engaged. He meets with Varsha, who flats tells him that she prefers marrying someone richer and wealthier. Angrily he confronts Vikram, who counsels him that Varsha had never really loved him. The question remains, did Varsha really love Vijay, and if so, what compelled her to change her mind?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?020567</url></doc>
