<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="021256">
  <docid>021256</docid>
  <title>Abi Titmuss: A Modern Day Morality Tale</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Dollner, Gary</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">19 May 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Egan, Simon (III)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Wright, Stephen D.</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Borg, Sean</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Leslie, John (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Liddle, Rod</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Abi Titmus was the girlfriend of television presenter John Leslie when he was accused of rape and torn to shreds by the tabloids. She stood by him in the court case until he was found innocent and then she decided to "make something good of this situation" and left her £16k pa nursing job and hired a publicity agent. This got her some nice work (Richard &amp; Judy for one) and the money was coming in nicely - until a tabloid broke a "story" about her having group sex with Leslie and some strangers. She denies it at first but then milks it by getting £50k for a "confession" to a Sunday paper - a confession she says the papers twisted. However, her denials were for naught when a sex tape showing the whole thing hit the internet. However, getting the profits from that film when it was released on dvd, Abi also found herself in demand from the tabloids and men's magazine. Owning half the rights to the photographs is a nice earner for her, along with the publicity do's, the calendars and other deals put her firmly on the A list in the UK but is she a model for others to follow?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?021256</url></doc>
