<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="022072">
  <docid>022072</docid>
  <title>Accidentally Yours</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <producers>
    <producer>Wesley, Michael (II)</producer>
    <producer>Allen, Kent (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Wesley, Michael (II)</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>It was an accident. Clearly it was not his fault, though he did have a couple drinks after work. But why was he on the back road to the Carlson's house anyway? At that hour? With both his own wife and John Carlson out of town? Bill Benedict's affair with Kristin Carlson is nearly as old as his marriage, but not as old as his friendship with her husband, John. John Carlson works for Bill, and Bill seems to take perverse pleasure in sending John away on business so that he can spend time alone with Kristin. On the way over to the Carlson's house one evening, Bill accidentally kills Paula. Paula is the Carlson's older daughter, who was speeding home on her bike in the rain to escape her friend's lecherous stepfather. Bill frantically tries to get Paula to the hospital, but she dies before they arrive. In the heat of the moment, Bill decides that the best thing to do would be to cover up his involvement in Paula's death. Bill waits at his house contemplating what happened. He has spoken with his wife, who is in Las Vegas at a conference, and he has left a message for Kristin telling her that he was sick and unable to meet her. There's time to kill before he'll feel comfortable going out and finding a place to bury Paula. It's nearly 2 a.m. when he hears a crash. Bill thinks someone is breaking into his house. It's Kristin. She's drunk. Hysterical. Violent. Bill doesn't look sick! Maybe he's sleeping with that intern! Maybe she's there right now! Kristin is an emotionally insecure wreck, and Bill's last minute cancellation led to a few too many drinks. As always, Bill is able to push the right buttons. The next afternoon, he is talking with an apologetic, but increasingly worried, Kristin. Paula isn't home yet. Bill is a supportive friend. The Carlson's would be lost without him at this terrible time. The search for Paula yields no results. John starts talking about taking revenge on the wrong man. Bill can't talk John out of his plan, so he anonymously exonerates the prime suspect and brings closure to his friend's ordeal without incriminating himself. Months later, the affair seems over. The healthy grieving continues, but both marriages are stronger than ever. The Carlson's are getting along with their remaining teenage daughter much better. Bridget Benedict is finally pregnant. The sexy intern has been replaced. Kristin has even quit drinking. But will questions about what happened that night be answered or forgotten?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?022072</url></doc>
