<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="022321">
  <docid>022321</docid>
  <title>Achieving the Glow</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>tv-mini-series</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <producers>
    <producer>Senter, Nick</producer>
    <producer>Solomon, Nicole</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mell, Tory</actor>
      <role>Correspondent (featured gamer)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>West, Adam (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself - Host</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A five-part rather tongue-in-cheek series that tries to explain what is 'the Glow' and how do you go about achieving it. Part 1 is called "Achieving the Glow with Gamers". Host Adam West introduces the concept of "The Glow," and real-life gamers explain how they tackle the five steps to elevated gamer consciousness. Featured gamer Tory Mell visits "Crazy Gideon's" to fulfill the first step to Glow achievement: Get the Gear. Part 2 is called "Achieving the Glow with Musicians". Busta Rhymes, Andrew W.K., Soup and Marc 7 from Jurassic 5, John Dolmayan from System of a Down and Robbie Merrill from Godsmack are just some of the musicians who are feelin' The Glow. Also: featured gamer Tory Mell consults with a Feng Shui expert in an effort to master the second step to Glow achievement: Prepare the Environment. Part 3 is called "Achieving the Glow with Actors". Some of the actors working on their inner gamer: Brian Posehn ("Just Shoot Me"), who says he gets ready for gaming by drinking lots of water; Ray Park (Star Wars: Episode I - The Phantom Menace), who likes to situate himself just so in front of the TV; Kadeem Hardison (Biker Boyz), who likes to crank his speakers way up, and Brian Heidik ("Survivor") who says he plays to make other people mad. Stay tuned as featured gamer Tory Mell levels up with fitness guru Tony Little on the Gazelle machine to master the oh-so-important third step to getting that gaming Glow: Prepare the Body and Mind. Part 4 is called "Achieving the Glow with Athletes". The history of "The Glow" is recounted and we discover how athletes strive to Achieve the Glow. The five steps to Glow achievement are discussed in detail. The show follows featured gamer Tory Mell as he tackles the fourth step: Play to Win. Part 5 is called "Achieving the Glow with Game Developers". In which, again, the history of "The Glow" is recounted and we discover how game developers strive to Achieve the Glow. The five steps to Glow achievement are, again, discussed in detail. The show follows featured gamer Tory Mell as he finally reaches the fifth step: Enlightenment.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?022321</url></doc>
