<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="023080">
  <docid>023080</docid>
  <title>Adalat</title>
  <year>1958</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <genres>
    <genre>Musical</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Kalidas (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Mohan, Madan (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Devi, Pratima</actor>
      <role>Nirmala's mom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kaul, Jawahar</actor>
      <role>Barrsiter Rattanlal Roy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Rashid (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Pradeep</actor>
      <role>Barrister Rajindra R. 'Rajen' Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Murad</actor>
      <role>Thakur Ranbir Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pran (I)</actor>
      <role>Pandit Kedarnath/Sharif Ahmed</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Yakub</actor>
      <role>Mirza Saheb</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Nirmala lives with her maternal uncle, his wife, and her widowed mom, studies in an Arts College, has a sweetheart in wealthy Rajinder R. Singh, who she plans to marry. Disagreements flare up at home when her aunt wants her to get married to an uneducated villager, Nirmala refuses to marry, instead gets a job at a Sada Bahar Nurtya Vidyalaya, which turns out to be a front for a brothel, landing her in prison. She gets off with a not guilty verdict, but is turned away from home, and the shock kills her mom. She attempts to find work, but is pursued relentlessly by a pimp, Pandit Kedarnath, who wants her for himself. Nirmala ends up as a Governess with none other than Rajinder's mom, where both lovers get married secretly. Rajinder then leaves for Britain, leaving behind a pregnant Nirmala. When the Singhs find out about her pregnancy and the man responsible, they refuse to believe her and throw her out straight into the arms of Kedarnath. She runs away and takes shelter working as a nurse in a private hospital where she gives birth to a baby boy. Kedarnanth once again shows up here, forcing the Trustees of the hospital to fire her. She flees with her child, and ends up at a brothel where she must accept this profession or see her child starve to death. She manages to smuggle the child to a kind-hearted doctor Renuka Roy. Years later, her son has grown up and is now the Public Prosecutor, and one of the first cases that he is to try is none other than that of Nirmala herself - a prostitute - who is now accused murder.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?023080</url></doc>
