<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="023113">
  <docid>023113</docid>
  <title>Adam &amp; the Allegory of the Forest</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Charles, David (XIV)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">10</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Halsey, Ryan Alan</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Endler, Sebastian</producer>
    <producer>Marin, Alejandro Montoya</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Halsey, Ryan Alan</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Doty Jr., John</actor>
      <role>German Soldier</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Enberg, Kirsi</actor>
      <role>Aniela</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Martel, Simone</actor>
      <role>Adam</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Adam Traugott is a German officer, who in 1945 chooses to desert the German military and the 2nd World War. After weeks of journeying through a foreign wilderness, Adam finds he must revert to a more primal existence in order to survive. He tries to catch a small animal by making a primitive trap. He baits the trap with the last of his rations (rations that he scavenged off another dead soldier), but fails to catch anything. He tries to make a fire using anything he can, but again fails in his attempts. All Adam has to comfort him is a damaged field radio, which he also scavenged. Despite numerous attempts to reach anyone for help, his desperate pleas go unanswered. However, one night Adam is awoken by the radio and upon turning it off he hears voices emanating from a distance. He recognizes them as German soldiers and flees for his life. Adam comes across an old decrepit barn, and in desperation seeks shelter from the approaching soldiers. There he unexpectedly encounters Aniela, a farm wife left to tend the household while her husband and sons are off fighting the in war. Both dare not make a sound as they hear the rogue soldiers scouting around outside. One soldier enters the barn. Adam and Aniela remain silent and hidden. A gunshot rings out as the other soldiers outside try to kill a cow for food, distracting the soldier in the barn. Before Adam escapes he tries to thank Aniela, but she reacts in fear, and Adam sees he is no different than the people outside pillaging her livelihood. Adam runs and leaves Aniela to her fate. Adam struggles on, and eventually reaches the coast of the Adriatic. He has made it out of the forest which has held him captive for so long. He cleans the blood and dirt from his face and hands in the ocean. Suddenly the radio again turns on again, but this time a voice is faintly heard through the static. He rushes to it and soon is able to find the frequency with a British sea vessel relaying a message that the war in Europe has ended. Adam can not understand English. However, to him it doesn't matter, for he has found peace within himself in the fact that he has survived to see another day.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?023113</url></doc>
