<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="023581">
  <docid>023581</docid>
  <title>Adikimeni</title>
  <year>1964</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Greek</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Greece</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">81</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Papakostas, Giorgos (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Papakostas, Giorgos (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Crystal (XVIII)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Galani, Rena</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kedrakas, Nasos</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kourakou, Mariana</actor>
      <role>Angeliki</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lembesi, Niki</actor>
      <role>Lena</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Makris, Orestis</actor>
      <role>Nikolas Andreou</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tzanetis, Panos</actor>
      <role>Singer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Velentzas, Giorgos</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Yannakas, Alkis</actor>
      <role>Alkis</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zambetas, Giorgos</actor>
      <role>Singer</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Angeliki, a beautiful girl with a lovely voice, leaves the orphanage as soon as she comes of age and finds work in a social club. The son of the owner, Alkis, who likes her a great deal, urges her to become a singer. Her first appearance meets with unhoped-for success and, naturally, it's not long before she becomes a star of popular song. One day, however, her friend Lena informs her that an elderly man, Mr. Nikolas, has visited the orphanage looking for a little girl named Angeliki he had left there years ago. Shocked, Angeliki looks for and finds him, reuniting father and daughter at last. In the meantime, she is involved with Aris, but when he comes to ask for her hand in marriage, a drunken Mr. Nikolas sends him off. An accident, however, puts a different spin on things, as Angeliki loses her eyesight, and her father takes her to America for treatment. In the end, the compulsory separation fails to alienate the young couple, and their love proves superior to all obstacles, including that of another woman who threatens to invade Alkis' life and affections.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?023581</url></doc>
