<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="023535">
  <docid>023535</docid>
  <title>Adieu Babylone</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Ferreri, Fabien</editor>
  </editors>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>new-york-city</keyword>
    <keyword>crush</keyword>
    <keyword>pizza-delivery</keyword>
    <keyword>mexico</keyword>
    <keyword>roller-skates</keyword>
    <keyword>journey</keyword>
    <keyword>traveling</keyword>
    <keyword>paris</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>French</language>
    <language>Spanish</language>
    <language>Portuguese</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby SR</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="France">21 February 2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">91</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Frydman, Raphaël</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Cuel, François</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Frydman, Raphaël</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Epaud, Frédéric</actor>
      <role>Pizza manager</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Faventines, Emmanuel</actor>
      <role>Laurel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Frydman, Raphaël</actor>
      <role>Tchang</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Le Besco, Isild</actor>
      <role>Anouk</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Anouk, a sixteen year old Parisian schoolgirl, has a crush on Laurel, a young man she hardly knows and who doesn't know her. Every day she secretly follows him when he goes home from his job. One evening, Laurel leaves France on the spur of the moment and takes the first plane to Brazil. There he decides to travel up north through the continent and plans to travel over land all the way to New York City. But he isn't lucky, his money and luggage get stolen, he gets depressed, and several months later he must abort his journey and returns to Paris in a bad condition. Anouk hears about his story and is shocked, and she decides to take up the journey in Mexico where he stopped and to complete the journey to New York. During her travel she films her adventures with a videocam and mails the videotapes to the recovering Laurel. Laurel becomes intrigued with this young girl he doesn't know, especially when Anouk proposes to him that he'll meet her in New York when she'll reach the end point of the journey.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?023535</url></doc>
