<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="023977">
  <docid>023977</docid>
  <title>Adult Film: A Hollywood Tale</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Florence, Brent</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">105</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Florence, Brent</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bihari, Bryan Laszlo</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Florence, Brent</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Abbott, Bruce (I)</actor>
      <role>President Brad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bender, Cameron</actor>
      <role>Hot Mailman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bergkvist, Megan</actor>
      <role>Melony Harpier</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chen, Camille</actor>
      <role>Pamela Holdsbar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Clement, Rob</actor>
      <role>Gary Birch</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ewell, Dwight</actor>
      <role>Hal Calloway</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Florence, Brent</actor>
      <role>Bill Williams</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Haley, Bret</actor>
      <role>Johnny G</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Holdridge, Alex</actor>
      <role>Foster Bateman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Holiman, Levi</actor>
      <role>Creep Casting Director</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kidd, Courtney (I)</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Benderman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Leffler, Christian</actor>
      <role>Tom Wellread</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Luper, Kenny</actor>
      <role>Armondo Jones</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Young, Vincent (I)</actor>
      <role>Bud Lunger</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>At the age of eighteen, Bill Williams and Armondo Jones made their 23rd short film, a dramatic piece entitled, I Don't' Know, which unexpectedly won the Spirit award in their home town's Arts, Crafts, and Antique festival, and catapulted them into a life changing decision to move to Hollywood, California. They had only one goal, "change the world through motion picture." However, over the thirteen years they have lived in Los Angeles, they have come to realize, securing a movie deal is more difficult than they had imagined. Nameless Studios, a leading producer of soft-core, made-for-television late night movies; Sex is their domain, profit their motive. Their newest project: The Lone Rancher, a "softy" western, period piece, of two lovers on a ranch. As Nameless studios executives meet potential candidates to direct their project, Bill and Armondo fall onto the top of their list, being that they're out of work filmmakers, with talent, drive, and access to a massive, family owned ranch in Northern California. And so the Mature movie making process begins, with commerce on one side and Bill and Armondo on the other, clinging desperately to the only redeeming value The Lone Rancher has to offer them... it's love story. As the production spins out of control, the boys and their crew fight Nameless Studios each step of the way, to protect their vision, and version of their first ever "potentially great," feature film... that contractually must produce scenes of sexual intercourse, every six and a half minutes.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?023977</url></doc>
