<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="024332">
  <docid>024332</docid>
  <title>Adventures of the Quest: Monsters of the Shallows</title>
  <year>2000</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Aiers, Bill</editor>
    <editor>Fitzpatrick, Andrea</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 February 2000</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">45</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Fitzpatrick, Geoff</director>
    <director>Masters, Claire</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hohenacker, Thomas</producer>
    <producer>Borglund, Mikael</producer>
    <producer>Luscombe, John</producer>
    <producer>Rivett, Ron</producer>
    <producer>Wight, Andrew</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wight, Andrew</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Episode 6 - "Monsters of the Shallows" The remote Osa Peninsula of Costa Rica has no roads leading into it and is only accessible by sea or aircraft. This National Park parallels a lost garden of Eden with an abundance of exotic wildlife including howler monkeys, spider monkeys, squirrel monkeys, giant scarlet macaws, toucans, Baird's tapirs, anteaters, peccaries, snakes and crocodiles. The Quest team launched up river and whilst diving and searching under logs, the team found themselves face-to-face with a huge croc! This is the sort of dangerous situation which brings out the best in the well drilled Quest team, and allows scientists the opportunity to get first hand information really close to the action. During one of their many night-time river expeditions, the Quest's visiting crocodile expert was surprised when the crew caught a fully mature Caiman - a relative of the crocodile. This was very unusual because crocodiles and caiman's do not generally co-habit the same environments - because crocodiles eat caiman's!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?024332</url></doc>
