<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="024329">
  <docid>024329</docid>
  <title>Adventures of the Quest: Jungle Cats</title>
  <year>2000</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Aiers, Bill</editor>
    <editor>Fitzpatrick, Andrea</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 February 2000</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">45</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Fitzpatrick, Geoff</director>
    <director>Masters, Claire</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hohenacker, Thomas</producer>
    <producer>Borglund, Mikael</producer>
    <producer>Caulfield, Michael</producer>
    <producer>Rivett, Ron</producer>
    <producer>Wight, Andrew</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wight, Andrew</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Episode 7 - "Jungle Cats" The magnificent jungle cats of Costa Rica are constantly under threat from poachers who snatch them from the wild to be sold as exotic pets. On route to the Galapagos Islands the Quest team assists two feline biologists with one big rescue mission. They have 25 confiscated jungle cats (15 Ocelots, 9 Margays and 1 Jagarundi) that are surviving at their temporary field station near Dominicalito on the west coast of Costa Rica. Their previous station was obliterated by a cyclone, so a philanthropic Danish businessman has built a new facility on Nicoya Peninsula, 250 miles further north. The Quest team's mission was to rescue these cats and transport them to their new home with a minimum of trauma. There is plenty of high-jinx and drama as the Quest sails across the equator towards the Galapagos Islands on yet another rescue mission; this time to save a species of Giant Tortoise from extinction. Utilising the Quest's helicopter, the team has brought new hope to a seriously endangered species.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?024329</url></doc>
