<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="024963">
  <docid>024963</docid>
  <title>Afro Samurai: Flesh and Bone</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Mader, Kenneth</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">24 July 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">9</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Mader, Kenneth</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Brown, Percy 'Spitfire'</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Brown, Percy 'Spitfire'</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Derian, Alan</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brown, Percy 'Spitfire'</actor>
      <role>Afro Samurai</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Johnson, Vaughn (II)</actor>
      <role>Kabuki Warrior #2</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McClure, Christopher 'Jinx'</actor>
      <role>Ninja-Ninja</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nagasawa, Todd</actor>
      <role>Hiro</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Award-winning filmmaker Kenneth Mader delivers the first live action Afro Samurai tribute film starring international action actor Percy "Spitfire" Brown. Shot in a style reminiscent of old Shaw Brothers Samurai movies, the film is a kind of prequel to the original Afro Samurai Anime series. While the wife and brother of a fallen Sword Master (Mina Oba and Todd Nagasawa) mourn his brutal slaying in a nearby village, Afro Samurai (Percy "Spitfire" Brown) arrives to pay his respects and exact revenge on a rival Kabuki Warrior who has been dispatched by his clan leader (Jen Zhao) to finish the job. Complete with appearances by Afro's trusted imaginary sidekick Ninja-Ninja (Christopher "Jinx" McClure) this live action tribute to the popular Anime - the first of its kind - features surprisingly high production values and solid acting performances which culminates in an exciting, action-packed fight sequence punctuated with a rousing original musical score by award-winning composer Alan Derian and special makeup effects by top Hollywood makeup artist James Lacey. Strap in for a fun and crazy ride!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?024963</url></doc>
