<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="025586">
  <docid>025586</docid>
  <title>Against the Race</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Monberg, Nicolaj</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Denmark</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Denmark">1 November 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Denmark">58</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Thomsen, Wadt</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Holst, Carsten</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Dragsted, Morten</writer>
    <writer>Peyk, Nikolaj</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Galia, Lars Top</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kleinschmidt, Jutta</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nissen, Kris</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sainz, Carlos</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This ultimate TV-programme will tell the story of the men and tomboys who live their dream to the fullest. A unique group of people who are willing to take challenges upon them that will bring them on the verge of, and sometimes beyond, their physical and psychological capacities. A film about such a group of people will be of no interest unless it describes something generally human. The Dakar Rally has achieved its mythological status because it speaks to universal human emotions of both the contestants and the audience. Emotions that are rooted in a fascination of the ultimate challenge. A fascination that is recognized by most of us and probably in particular by men. This fascination creates a desire and need it can be difficult to satisfy in modern everyday life and therefore it is fulfilled in front of TV-screens all over the World. The Dakar film will tell the story of some of the people that actually do live the dream. A tale of the people and the experiences that year after year bring them to participate in the journey of 10.000 tough kilometers, stretching through some of the most hostile environments on the planet to the goal in Dakar. A journey that every year pushes them to their utmost and confronts them with themselves and each other, in ways that changes them forever.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?025586</url></doc>
