<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="026493">
  <docid>026493</docid>
  <title>Ahmed, Say Something Funny...</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Vickroy, Thelma</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">29 July 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">80</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Vickroy, Thelma</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Beshid, Fred</producer>
    <producer>Beshid, Susan</producer>
    <producer>Vickroy, Thelma</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ahmed, Ahmed</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Ahmed Ahmed is an Egyptian-born, California-raised, writer, actor, comedian and consummate Hollywood insider who counts the original "Swinger" Vince Vaughn among his best friends. Ahmed's appearance in Vaughn's stand-up comedy documentary The Wild West Show, received rave reviews, with At the Movies with Ebert &amp; Roeper among those recently anointing him "the funniest guy in this movie." Ahmed subsequently made his first appearance on The Tonight Show, after which Jay Leno invited him to sit on the couch - a major milestone in any comic's career. An Arab-American-Muslim immigrant, Ahmed Ahmed uses in-your-face humor as both an offense and a defense to brazenly tease out racial themes. Like most stand-ups, Ahmed has toured the college circuit, but he has also grown and diversified his fan base to include members of cultural centers and synagogues by embarking on a tour with a Rabbi comedian. Ahmed Ahmed is flaunting the stereotypes, putting them on the table to pick on, laugh at and hopefully gain some much needed perspective-and his audiences are eating it up. Ahmed, Say Something Funny is not a performance piece, but rather a portrait-style documentary that tells an intimate, sometimes painful, always funny version of a hot button American immigrant story. Through filmed performances of Ahmed's tour across the United States and intimate family interviews, the film makes us laugh, cry and think by illuminating the seemingly insurmountable challenges of being an Arab American in a post 9/11 America. With Ahmed's career momentum heating up, American audiences have already begun to discover his unique brand of humor, healing and hope.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?026493</url></doc>
