<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="027095">
  <docid>027095</docid>
  <title>Airboss II: Preemptive Strike</title>
  <year>1998</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Howe, Matthew M.</editor>
    <editor>Ingvordsen, J. Christian</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>military</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Germany">16</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Germany">88</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="USA">88</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Ingvordsen, J. Christian</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Duncker, C. Steven</producer>
    <producer>Solomon, Alan M.</producer>
    <producer>Howe, Matthew M.</producer>
    <producer>Ingvordsen, J. Christian</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Howe, Matthew M.</writer>
    <writer>Ingvordsen, J. Christian</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Solomon, Darren (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Christensen, Deborah</actor>
      <role>Lt. Lucy Mitchell</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deen, Bleu</actor>
      <role>Adm. Todd</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ingvordsen, J. Christian</actor>
      <role>James Kelly</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McClelland, Michael</actor>
      <role>Lynch</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McCrae, Scooter</actor>
      <role>Bix Bender</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Watson, Kayle</actor>
      <role>Bone Conn</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zagarino, Frank</actor>
      <role>Frank White</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>High above the Earth, Top Gun pilot turned astronaut, Frank White commands his first Space Shuttle mission. While in orbit, the science team headed by Doctor Bender runs a critical experiment utilizing the unique properties of micro-gravity to cultivate a cure for the Ebola virus, the most lethal pathogen known to the human race. Back on Earth, an accident on the way to de-brief leaves the entire science team dead. Only Dr. Bender has survived. Suspecting foul play, Frank White infiltrates the hospital where Dr. Bender is quarantined, and learns from the critically injured scientist that the accident was arranged. The Ebola in the experimental container had been stolen. Frank takes this information to James Kelly the Deputy Director of Intelligence for the CIA. Immediately after, Frank is nearly killed on a training flight when his unarmed FA-18 is attacked by a mysterious F-15. Frank finds his way to former SEAL team leader Bone Conn. The two uncover a plot to turn the Ebola virus into a chemical weapon of unimaginable destructive power. Millions of innocent lives hang in the balance as the two men and their team of Navy SEALS become locked in a deadly race against time to stop the ultimate terrorist attack.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?027095</url></doc>
