<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="027235">
  <docid>027235</docid>
  <title>Aisling: We Saw a Vision</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Ferguson, David (XIII)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>dance-film</keyword>
    <keyword>poetry</keyword>
    <keyword>garden-of-remembrance</keyword>
    <keyword>dublin-ireland</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">27 June 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">4</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Ferguson, David (XIII)</director>
    <director>Lowry, Miles</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ferguson, David (XIII)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Mac Uistin, Liam</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Lowry, Miles</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ferguson, David (XIII)</actor>
      <role>Man</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Aisling - We Saw A Vision, is inspired by Irish author Liam Mac Uistin's visionary peace poem, this short dance film speaks to all people who value freedom, nature, and the power of transformation. The work suggests how mythology remains in the modern mind; a kind of ancestral symbolism akin to contemporary dance. Background: The Garden of Remembrance was created in Dublin, in 1966, and is so named to honour the people who sacrificed and fought for the independence of the Irish Nation, and who ultimately won their struggle. A contest was created in 1976 to find a poet who could express the appreciation and inspiration of this struggle for freedom. The winner of the contest was Dublin born author Liam Mac Uistin, whose poem "We Saw a Vision" is now written in Irish, French, and English on the stone wall of the monument. The word "aisling" in the Irish language means vision. An aisling poem is a type of poetic form created in the 18th century as a new means of poetry, which could express the hopes and sorrows of the people, free from censorship. Mac Uistin's poem decisively observes the overcoming of obstacles and the creation of a new freedom by standing up to oppression with a vision of peace. The language successfully moves from the past to the present with a message of hope, in a poetic voice that could easily be speaking about contemporary issues.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?027235</url></doc>
