<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="028395">
  <docid>028395</docid>
  <title>Al-boom</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Gomal, Raj</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Arabic</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Oman</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="United Arab Emirates">6 March 2006</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="France">25 November 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">105</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Al-Zadjali, Khaled Abdul Raheem</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Al-Zadjali, Khaled Abdul Raheem</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Ridha, Hani</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Al-Darmaki, Saud</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Al-Zadjali, Isam</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Al-Zadjali, Zakaria</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bahwan, Salem</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mohammad, Talib</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Qader, Zoha</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Za'al, Saleh</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The film takes place in a coastal town where the locals are known for fishing and boat building. As it turns out, work in these two professions has started to decrease. Most young local men have deserted the town and started heading to the capital to look to for work They claim that the sea's fortune has run short and that a container of fish is not enough to fulfill their dreams and ambitions. Sheik Ibrahim, one of the wise and rich men of the town, was a vital catalyst in the migration of the work force. For it is in the sake of his big investments, that everyone talks of but no one seems to know what they are and who are his Omani and foreign partners. He offers people to buy off their old fishing boats, even their old homes which are close to the coast. No one stands in his way but a elder man in his fifties Nokhithah(Captain) Salem "Abu Zahir", who has long relationship with the sea since his childhood. It is said that his son Zahir has gone off to sea on a fishing trip and has not returned This is why he waiting for him while raising, Noor, a girl he has betrothed for Zahir. Abu Zahir insists on fixing old fishing boats. Sheik Ibrahim finds the Nokhithah as an obstacle in his way to achieve his investments. So he starts fighting him by any means, one of which was spreading false rumors about an illegitimate relationship with his son's fiancée Noor; Sheik Ibrahim even raises doubts about the existence of Zahir that everyone heard of but never seen on first hand.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?028395</url></doc>
