<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="029156">
  <docid>029156</docid>
  <title>Alejandra</title>
  <year>1994</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Venezuela</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Venezuela">1994</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">45</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Barrera, Olegario</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Pulido, Jhonny</producer>
    <producer>Faria, Hernando</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Fiallo, Delia</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Alonso, Maria Conchita</actor>
      <role>Alejandra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arenas, Angélica</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Campos, Marcos (I)</actor>
      <role>Guanipa</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Castell, Ana</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gadea Pérez, Eduardo</actor>
      <role>Diógenes</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Herrera, Angélica</actor>
      <role>Rosalba</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Loreto, Félix</actor>
      <role>Porfirio</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Magaz, Esperanza</actor>
      <role>Ileana</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mago, Oswaldo</actor>
      <role>Víctor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Romero, Rafael (III)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Schubert, Jorge</actor>
      <role>Luis Jose</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Xiqués, Raúl</actor>
      <role>Alejandro Antunez</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Alejandra is a beautiful woman who has dedicated her life to the medical profession in an effort to rise above her tormented, humble beginnings and prove to herself and those around her that she can make a contribution to society. After a one-year medical internship in the rural areas of her country, Alejandra returns to her family's working-class neighborhood. She obtains a job at the local hospital, where she confronts the hospital director--the famed surgeon Alejandro Antunez--with the news that she is his illegitimate daughter, determined to prove to him that she did not need him in order to succeed in life. Alejandra's presence has a great impact on Dr. Antunez's life; the daughter he had long-forgotten is now a capable and intelligent physician who sparks a renewed sense of pride in him. Everyone seems to respect the abilities of the young female doctor...except for Dr. Luis Jose Baez, a brilliant young intern who is equally well-known for his male chauvinism and womanizing ways. Alejandra and Luis Jose's growing attraction for each other is masked behind their frequent conflicts, but love blossoms despite themselves. Alejandra gets pregnant. And along comes Morella, Luis Jose's estranged wife, a beautiful older woman whose obsession for him may forever keep Alejandra.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?029156</url></doc>
