<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="029671">
  <docid>029671</docid>
  <title>Ali in Wonderland</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Persian</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">1 November 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">15 January 2010</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Gharavi, Tina</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Drainville, Elaine</producer>
    <producer>Wardlow, Rachel</producer>
    <producer>Baillie, James Richard</producer>
    <producer>Gharavi, Tina</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Gharavi, Tina</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Boutrous, Amir</actor>
      <role>Amir</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Coulson, Christian</actor>
      <role>Tommy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Halls, Nicole</actor>
      <role>Nicole</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Haq, Shiraz</actor>
      <role>Ali</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Henderson, Katherine</actor>
      <role>Immigration Solicitor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hooper, Steven</actor>
      <role>Leigh Hall</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Palmer, Darren (III)</actor>
      <role>Neighbour</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sadeghi, Micsha</actor>
      <role>Nasrine</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>When the world makes no sense, where can anyone begin to live? Nasrine,16, is picked up by the Iranian police riding a motorcycle with a boy. Her family desperate to find her are inconsolable. Once bribes are paid, her Dad decides to send her and her older brother, Ali, 19, to the UK. Nasrine is defiant- she wants to stay; however, the decision is out of her hands. Nasrine wants to find herself and to become a journalist, against her fathers will. Ali resents being sent away from his comfortable life. During the journey, Nasrine begins to understand now she is free, now she can have an adventure. Ali doesn't respond and continues to be resentful. In England, life is not what they expected. They are patronized, treated with hostility, and have a hard time making things work. Nasrine goes to school and Ali finds black market work. Nasrine meets Nicole, a unique tour-de-force from the travelers community. Like her, they are misfits. Ali goes to work in a car wash and eventually a pizza shop and meets men from a variety of backgrounds. Ali tries to assert control over Nasrine, but he is incapable of being strong. Nasrine copes better- she is finding her strength and finding out who she is. Both are on their journey to 'find themselves'. Nasrine falls for Nicole's older brother, a blue-eyed charmer and Ali meets Tommy. Ali is finding it increasingly difficult to cope and continues denying his sexuality. The parents are set to come to the UK, however, this looks uncertain as 9/11 has now happened. Now with relative freedom, Nasrine and Ali both explore their new-found relationships as they are relatively free in the West. They struggle to deal with each other's new personas when Ali is tragically murdered. In the end, Nasrine must decide her own fate- to stay and make her own life or return to Iran where surely she will lose her chance to decide her own future. At the end of the film, Nasrine now much stronger, ventures into a life which is very much in her hands.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?029671</url></doc>
