<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="030357">
  <docid>030357</docid>
  <title>Aljuriya</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Coss, Gabriel</editor>
    <editor>Marrero, Freddie</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>History</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>occupation</keyword>
    <keyword>palestine</keyword>
    <keyword>one-word-title</keyword>
    <keyword>international-affairs</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Puerto Rico</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Cuba">8 December 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">55</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Coss, Gabriel</director>
    <director>Marrero, Freddie</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Chazulle Rivera, Carmen</producer>
    <producer>Marrero, Freddie</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Jiménez, Bairex</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>It's 2002. The streets of New York and Washington are the first scenarios in which citizens express their viewpoints on the Palestine-Israel conflict. Those situations illustrate the climate of incomprehension that prevails in the U.S. regarding this affair. Swiftly the streets of the U.S. become the streets of Palestine, where U.S. Citizens observe, interview and participate in the life of Palestinians in the occupied territories during a period of grand scale military operations by the Israel military forces. One of such operations is that of Jenin refugee camp, where footage from Kevin Skvorak, one of the first cameramen to enter it after the destruction of the center of the camp. By means of observations, situations and interviews with Palestinians, members of the International Solidarity Movement, and Israel Conscientious Objectors Aljuriya weave together a mosaic of the different elements that Palestinians face everyday: checkpoints, curfews, growth of Jewish settlements, and the acts of an occupying force determined to deny their existence as a Nation.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?030357</url></doc>
