<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="030330">
  <docid>030330</docid>
  <title>Alive and Well</title>
  <year>2010</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>based-on-novel</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <directors>
    <director>Rugan, Robert</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bullock, Brian (III)</producer>
    <producer>VanCleave, Darren</producer>
    <producer>Hennessy, Michael (II)</producer>
    <producer>Mayeux, Molly M.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Denton, Bradley</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Heder, Jon</actor>
      <role>Oliver Vale</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The enduring magic of a 1950s rock 'n' roll icon and the visual and emotional excitement of action/sci-fi/fantasy films will be the attractive mix of "Alive and Well." The Film depicts the story of Oliver Vale, a common young man suddenly called to unexpected adventures, when TV screens go blank across the world and the 1950s rock pioneer Buddy Holly is alive again, performing from Ganymede, a moon of Jupiter. In the film's arresting central image, Holly, who died in a plane crash at the height of his fame, returns with all of his legendary stage charisma. He wears his trademark black-framed glasses and plays his Fender Strat electric guitar. Suddenly, the rocker stops and delivers a strange, unexpected message in his sultry Texas accent, that Vale holds the key to the blackout and that he should be "contacted for assistance." This odd manifesto abruptly changes the life of Vale, an average electronic salesman geek in Wichita, Kansas, who suddenly finds himself the target of a high-speed, cross-country chase. In a defining moment, Vale turns from channel surfer to perpetrator number one as he finds himself pursued by space aliens, a fierce cyborg dog, and a ruthless government agent. This does not include the millions of fellow couch potatoes in the world incensed and frantic to get their TV back. In his quest for answers, Vale decides to travel to Lubbock, Texas, Holly's birthplace and the site of his grave, hoping that there he will find the solution to the mysterious TV blackout and the appearance of Buddy Holly.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?030330</url></doc>
