<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="030483">
  <docid>030483</docid>
  <title>All About Reinalda</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <editors>
    <editor>Reeve, Dylan</editor>
  </editors>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="New Zealand">2 June 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">108</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Lambert, Richard (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Lambert, Richard (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Lambert, Richard (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Banks, Christopher (II)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Banks, Christopher (II)</actor>
      <role>Phil Spectacle</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Beyer, Georgina</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Currie, Max</actor>
      <role>Priest</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gay, Lucy</actor>
      <role>Natasha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lambert, Richard (II)</actor>
      <role>Reinalda/Rex</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McKay, Brian (I)</actor>
      <role>Father/Arabian Husband</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McRae, Elizabeth</actor>
      <role>Marge Brasch (Prime Minister)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Whitehead, Christopher</actor>
      <role>Krystal/Callum</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Once upon a time, in a tiny French village, little Reinalda had dreams of a bright future on the stage - being one half of a singing, dancing musical troupe with her father. But her stepmother bitch was to ruin it all. Later in life, Reinalda has achieved fame and fortune - two of the three things she has always desired. Unfortunately the third seems out of reach - the beautiful, seductive Anne Elise. Reinalda fell hopelessly in love with her long red hair and big good-goods during her days as a French panto teacher and now she will stop at nothing, including the highest office in the land, to be with her always. Along the way she must fend off the unwelcome advances of national TV talk-show host Krystal (With A K), her seedy pop svengali Phil Spectacle, and her enigmatic live-in sidekick Dromedary Girl; as well as avoiding detection by Natasha, the bewildered international spy with a penchant for inner monologues, who in turn may just bring Reinalda's mysterious past back to haunt her one final time...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?030483</url></doc>
