<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="030758">
  <docid>030758</docid>
  <title>All Life</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Roth, Malachi</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>hopi</keyword>
    <keyword>native-american</keyword>
    <keyword>environment</keyword>
    <keyword>experimental</keyword>
    <keyword>slave</keyword>
    <keyword>historical</keyword>
    <keyword>jamaica</keyword>
    <keyword>mahatma-gandhi</keyword>
    <keyword>martin-luther-king-jr.</keyword>
    <keyword>africa</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Roth, Malachi</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Roth, Malachi</producer>
    <producer>Sigal, Matthew (II)</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>'All Life' begins with an audio recording of Fountain Hughes, a former slave who after identifying himself declares that his grandfather belonged to Thomas Jefferson. The viewer is then introduced to the Hopi, through stills, archival footage and on-screen text as one of the oldest and most peaceful tribes on the planet. During this scene Ghandi informs us through voice over that 'there is an indefinable mysterious power that pervades everything'. This introduction sets the tone for a film that will lead the viewer toward valuable symbolic and philosophical tools which can be used to generate hope at a time of planetary peril. The images and voices that make up the film all share a common wisdom concerning the preservation of the earth and the just treatment of 'All Life'. Animated ancient symbols are superimposed over stills and archival footage while musical motifs punctuate and highlight the overall message of 'interconnectedness'. Images dominate the first half while voices and sound dominate the second. 'All Life' is, at its core, about all life.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?030758</url></doc>
