<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="030952">
  <docid>030952</docid>
  <title>All Star Blitz</title>
  <year>1985</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Game-Show</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>non-fiction</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">6 December 1985</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Shaw, Jerome</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Conlin, Noreen</producer>
    <producer>Alisi, Art</producer>
    <producer>Greenfield, David (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Lloyd, Rob</writer>
    <writer>Solomon, Alan (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barnes, Priscilla</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Butkus, Dick</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dussault, Nancy</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Eden, Barbara (I)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Farr, Jamie</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Furst, Stephen</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Garland, Beverly (I)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harlan, John</actor>
      <role>Announcer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kazan, Lainie</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Korman, Harvey</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Marshall, Peter (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself / Host</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mitchell, James (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>O'Donnell, Charlie (I)</actor>
      <role>Announcer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Poston, Tom</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Reilly, Charles Nelson</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Weaver, Dennis (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"All-Star Blitz" was the last in a long-line of multi-celebrity games associated with game show producer Merrill Heatter, all which had in some way to do with his by far most successful effort, "The Hollywood Squares." In "All-Star Blitz" (incidentally hosted by "The Hollywood Squares" host Peter Marshall) two contestants, including a returning champion, competed with the help of four celebrities. Behind the celebrities' podiums was a wall of six electronic screens, which contained the words to a familiar phrase. The basic rules were similar to "The Hollywood Squares" (e.g., choose a celebrity, agree or disagree), but with the following changes: 1. When the contestant chose a celebrity, he/she also picked a star in in his/her column to light (i.e., "so-and-so at the bottom"); 2. The celebrity is asked a multiple-choice answer, and generally did not bluff; and 3. If the contestant was correct, he/she continued control of the board, but if not, control passed to the opponent. Whenever four stars around a screen were lit, that screen exposes part of the phrase. At any time, the contestant in control of the board may guess the phrase, always at the risk of losing control if incorrect. The first contestant to solve two puzzles won a prize package worth approximately $4,000 and advanced to the Blitz Bonanza Board. In The Blitz Bonanza, the object was for the contestant to solve one more word puzzle; by spinning a wheel, the contestant could highlight and reveal portions of the puzzle. Up to four spins were allowed, though spins could prove to be unhelpful if they designated an already-highlighted screen. If fewer than four screens were lit, the contestant could either solve the puzzle or trade the prize package already won in the front game (all previous winnings were considered safe) for one more spin. Following the fifth spin, the contestant has 10 seconds to review the puzzle; at the same time, the celebrities write down their guesses as to the correct phrase. At any time during the Blitz Bonanza, a correct guess was worth $10,000 (plus an additional $5,000 for each day not won, up to a maximum $25,000); an incorrect guess at any time stopped the Blitz Bonanza, though he/she could collect $250 per celebrity who guessed the puzzle correctly. Contestants competed until defeated or winning five games, at which point they also won a new car.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?030952</url></doc>
