<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="031342">
  <docid>031342</docid>
  <title>All the Russias</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Eveleigh, Steve</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>russia</keyword>
    <keyword>soviet-union</keyword>
    <keyword>tv-mini-series</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Russian</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">2002</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Finland">10 February 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Gavin, Barrie</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gergiev, Valery</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nikitin, Yevgeni</actor>
      <role>Ruslan</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Beautifully crafted, informative documentary series, exploring the musical history of Russia in a five-part series. Beginning with its origins in ancient chants and folk music, stretching through to radical contemporary composers like Schnittke and Gubaidulina. Maestro Valery Gergiev, the reknown Conductor and Artistic Director of the Kirov Mariinski, presents excerpts from the orchestral and vocal legacy of composers such as Mussorgsky, Borodin, Rimsky-Korsakov, Tchaikovsky, Stravinsky, Prokofiev and Shostakovich with the Stars, Chorus and Orchestra of The Kirov Marriinski Theatre Ballet and Opera Companies. Part 1: Folk Singer"THE LITTLE BIRCH TREE" is filmed largely in the remote countryside this is an evocation of Russia's rural heart. Part 2: Russian Priest "HOLY MOTHER RUSSIA", how has faith and religion influenced music in this pagan and Christian country? Part 3: "DEVILS", What has been the effect of Russia's cycles of tyranny and violence on its musical heritage? Part 4: Dancer "ONCE UPON A TIME", a look at an archetypal form of Russian culture, the fairy-tale. Part 5: Camel and Rider "LOOKING EAST, LOOKING WEST", the cultural and musical impact of Russia's relationship with her neighbours.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?031342</url></doc>
