<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="031559">
  <docid>031559</docid>
  <title>Allah and America</title>
  <year>2010</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Yedalian, Hrag</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>country-name-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>islam</keyword>
    <keyword>religion</keyword>
    <keyword>god</keyword>
    <keyword>post-september-11-2001</keyword>
    <keyword>place-name-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>september-11-2001</keyword>
    <keyword>america</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>muslim</keyword>
    <keyword>muslim-american</keyword>
    <keyword>allah</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Yedalian, Hrag</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Yedalian, Hrag</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Hakopyan, David</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>The tragic attacks of September 11, 2001 changed the identity of our country. Over the last several years, the United States has been involved in two separate wars and an international manhunt for the people behind the most devastating act of terrorism on American soil. During this period, Americans of all political and social backgrounds have engaged in debates dealing with the country's future. And, behind all these debates, and embedded within the countless newspaper editorials and media reports covering the attacks and subsequent events is a fascination with the religion that is under an international spotlight: Islam. A feature length documentary, "Allah and America" chronicles America's relationship with the fourteen hundred year old religion and its adherents. The narratives that color this complicated issue are told through the perspective of those who influence and help shape public opinion and policy. These varying and sometimes contradictory opinions are presented in an unadulterated manner in order to grant audiences the opportunity to draw their own conclusions. At its core, "Allah and America" explores a few simple questions: What are the varied American perspectives about Islam? What considerations shape such public opinion, and how have these beliefs evolved over time? To what degree do these perceptions and opinions correspond to how American and non-American Muslims view themselves and their religion? Are Muslim values compatible with their American counterparts, and what issues, if any, stand in the way of reconciliation between the two? The answers to these questions are offered through candid interviews, compelling images and engaging storytelling. Because the interviewees come from diverse backgrounds, their stories will provide a great deal of insight into these topics and help weave a story about the wide spectrum of thought that exists in our country today. At its essence, therefore, "Allah and America" is a film for all of America.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?031559</url></doc>
