<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="031704">
  <docid>031704</docid>
  <title>Allegra</title>
  <year>2010</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2010</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Mandler, Anthony</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Nicosia, Joseph Mojoe</producer>
    <producer>Clark, Duncan (I)</producer>
    <producer>Listermann, Brad</producer>
    <producer>Mandler, Anthony</producer>
    <producer>Roberts, Gregory David</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Listermann, Brad</writer>
    <writer>Roberts, Gregory David</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>John is a complicated "fixer" with a heart of gold but rough around the edges from a terrible past tragedy. One day Billionaire, Madison Mace, sends him on an urgent mission to Mexico to try and help a mysterious girl get out of the local Tijuana prison. John is about to begin a journey that will change his life forever. This mysterious girl, Allegra, has a past that highlights the harrowing lives of many girls from all over the world today that are kidnapped or sold into child slavery and prostitution. As he dives into her past through meetings with the people that know her, Allegra's life takes on a special meaning for John that has him questioning everything about himself. But with Allegra's life marked for death by the local drug cartel and police corruption all around him, John will be in the middle of a battle and it's his own life that may need saving. In the end he will have to make the tough decisions and take tough action as Allegra's life is on the line and time is fast running out. A gripping action-drama with thriller elements that will inspire faith, challenge the mind and touch hearts daring people to examine the true harrowing stories rolled into this film of the child slavery/prostitution issues that plague the world today. The combination of dramatic thriller elements, action sequences and timely story will deliver a ground breaking film sure to grip audiences and critics alike.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?031704</url></doc>
