<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="032225">
  <docid>032225</docid>
  <title>Almaritsu</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Parquier, Baptiste</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>flying-boat</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>minimalism</keyword>
    <keyword>bubble</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>None</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="France">U</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="France">2 December 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Bosnia and Herzegovina">7 May 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">29</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Montaron, Damien</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Montaron, Damien</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bondil, Fabien</actor>
      <role>Pamphile</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dzogovic, Edina</actor>
      <role>Amaranthe</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Parquier, Jean-Jacques</actor>
      <role>The Father</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Parquier, Philibert</actor>
      <role>Théo</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In a lost town, an unexpected encounter between a grown-up and a child is going to change their slow-moving surroundings. The first is a ten year old boy, the other is three times older. One has to run away to construct himself, while the other has to return to his origins to reconstruct himself. On the deck of an old boat which has run aground, these two Little Princes, lost in the confusion of age and maturity, are searching for ways to relieve the world, the very world which is sinking around them. With their naivety, these two beings give us a lesson in altruism. The result of this quest through imagination is a strange invention. A dreamlike machine which will perturb the life of the town's people, and which will give two free spirits the possibility to make their dream come true. Chaplin was right, our tragedies have the importance we give them. Because everything becomes so beautiful, when the adults finally put on a child smile. Everything is so light when houses begin to float in the sky. And everything becomes so poetic, when both boys finally leave the earth and fly away aboard their big sailboat for a dreamlike journey.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?032225</url></doc>
