<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="032553">
  <docid>032553</docid>
  <title>Alone with the Devil</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bennett, Ryan (III)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Canada">14A</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">25 May 2006</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">20 April 2006</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="France">29 March 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">11</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Braun, Uwe Rafael</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Grieco, John</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Braun, Uwe Rafael</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Braun, Uwe Rafael</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Payne, Charles (II)</actor>
      <role>Blind Willie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Warren, Harold (II)</actor>
      <role>Robert Willis</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Alone with the Devil opens at midnight, on a crossroad in the Deep South, 1936. Using his own blood, blues man Robert Willis signs a deal with the Devil, to play the guitar like no other and have everlasting fame, on the condition that they meet again and surrender his soul to darkness. 5 years later Robert is on death row. He awakens on the last day of his life to the sound of his cell mate, Blind Willie, playing Lyra, Robert's guitar. Robert scolds Blind Willie then laments his own imprisonment, denying culpability to his crimes. The Devil, who is in the guise of Blind Willie, explains to Robert that everyone is responsible for their own fate, and that his actions relate directly to the course of his life. Robert directly shifts the blame for his death sentence on the Devil to whom he sold his soul, not realizing who he is talking to. Displaying the slit wrists of the child molester Blind Willie, the Devil reveals himself as possessing the cell mate's body. Robert is caught off guard, but regains himself and attacks the Devil, questioning the present outcome of their agreement and, why he failed to achieve fame. The Devil responds by clarifying that Robert's fame will come after his death, and not for his music, but for the atrocious murder he committed which landed him on death row. Having clarified Robert's misconstrued ideas about the contract, the Devil relinquishes the body of the dying Blind Willie leaving Robert alone with his thoughts. Blind Willie dies and Robert plays his blues, a song about his deal with the Devil. He realizes that he is to blame for his mistakes. With sunset and the end of his time approaching, Robert makes a last effort to regain his soul by praying to Jesus. He first attempts to deceive and then plead his way to heaven. He does not receive a response. The sun goes down and Robert is left to accept his fate.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?032553</url></doc>
