<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="032500">
  <docid>032500</docid>
  <title>Alone Together</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Stitt, Martin</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Germany">6 May 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">53</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Stitt, Martin</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Lyons, Jake (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Ecclestone, Dan</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ball, Jonathan (I)</actor>
      <role>Gary</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Blake, Rupert</actor>
      <role>Simon</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Garwood, Chris (I)</actor>
      <role>Matt</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>May, George (I)</actor>
      <role>Peter</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The first couple, Naomi and Gary, are a modern day good time couple. During the course of their story Naomi's emotional memories flood back and shatter the moment. Natalie, a young woman supported by her Mother, is helped at a taxi rank by Simon, an out of work estate agent. The story centres on the theme 'one good deed does not always lead to another.' The situation turns tense due to Natalie giving Simon a bogus phone number. She soon discovers that he is not all smiles and kindness. Matt and Susan are both young professionals. Matt lacks confidence with women desperately trying to impress and thereby overcome his internal fears. Susan sees the situation for what it is 'a one night stand' and has come back purely for sex. The situation soon becomes apparent with embarrassing effect. Peter and Anne are an artist and a socialite respectively. Peter cannot believe his luck as he lies post-coital next to Anne, the problem is he just can't understand that she is engaged to be married. Anne is resigned to her destiny as family and friends expect her The four strands have been interwoven driving the stories forward towards resolution and the dawning of a new day. Alone Together explores the theme of different agendas standing in the way of pure physical attraction.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?032500</url></doc>
