<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="034668">
  <docid>034668</docid>
  <title>American Blackout</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Boucicaut, Jean-Philippe</editor>
    <editor>Canning, Liz</editor>
    <editor>Inaba, Ian</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>election</keyword>
    <keyword>african-american</keyword>
    <keyword>voter</keyword>
    <keyword>ohio</keyword>
    <keyword>atlanta-georgia</keyword>
    <keyword>florida</keyword>
    <keyword>democracy</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">22 September 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">92</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Inaba, Ian</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Boucicaut, Jean-Philippe</producer>
    <producer>Marshall, Stephen (III)</producer>
    <producer>King, Anastasia</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Bearden, Michael</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Acey, Taalam</actor>
      <role>Spoken Word Poet</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McKinney, Cynthia</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Chronicles the recurring patterns of disenfranchisement witnessed from 2000 to 2004 while following the story of Georgia Congresswoman Cynthia McKinney, who not only took an active role in investigating these election debacles but also found herself in the middle of one after publicly questioning the Bush Administration about the 9-11 terrorist attacks. Some call Cynthia McKinney a civil rights leader among the ranks of Shirley Chisholm and Malcolm X. Others call her a conspiracy theorist and a 'looney.' American Blackout gains unprecedented access to one of the most controversial and dangerous politicians in America and examines the contemporary tactics used to control our democratic process and silence political dissent. The film features interviews with: US Congressional Representatives, John Lewis, Cynthia McKinney, John Conyers, Bernie Sanders, and Stephanie Tubbs-Jones; former US Civil Rights Commissioner &amp; Dean of UC Berkeley's School of Law, Christopher Edley; BBC journalist Greg Palast; and, Van Jones, Executive Director of the Ella Baker Center.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?034668</url></doc>
