<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="036682">
  <docid>036682</docid>
  <title>An Animated Life: The Phil Roman Story</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Saylors, Kyle</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Saylors, Kenny</director>
    <director>Saylors, Kyle</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Roman, Phil</producer>
    <producer>Saylors, Kenny</producer>
    <producer>Saylors, Kyle</producer>
    <producer>Tuminello, Joel</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hudnut, Rob</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rodriguez, Steves</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Roman, Phil</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vidov, Oleg</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wilder, Lance</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This documentary details the life and career of Phil Roman, the legendary animator who is widely regarded as one of the most influential men in television animation history. You will be moved by this inspirational story of a young artist who had a dream larger than life, who made a brave move to Los Angeles with only $60 in his pocket and, against all odds, became a one of the most respected and beloved figures among animators around the world. In his career he has been nominated for 26 Emmy awards and winner of 6. He has been behind some of the most successful and classic shows and specials in television history, his credits include hits such as "The Simpsons", "King of the Hill", "Garfield and Friends", "How the Grinch Stole Christmas", a dozen Charlie Brown Specials, "Felix the Cat", "Tom and Jerry","The critic" and hundreds of other shows that will be remembered and loved for generations to come. Phil Roman personally navigates this project with stories of his life that will inspire you and encourage you to reach for your dreams. Take this journey with the man that brought to life so many timeless chracters through the years.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?036682</url></doc>
