<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="037491">
  <docid>037491</docid>
  <title>An Uncommon Union: The Life and Love of Sarah and Jonathan Edwards</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 August 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">56</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Jackman, John (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Curtis, Ken (III)</producer>
    <producer>Jackman, John (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Rowe, Maggie (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Johnson, Sara (VI)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bedrossian, Pete</actor>
      <role>Jonathan Edwards</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lewis, Cliff (II)</actor>
      <role>George Whitefield</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Parsons, Jay</actor>
      <role>Dr. Shippen</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This is the story of Edwards and his remarkable wife Sarah as seen through her eyes. Sarah is played by Maggie Rowe, who adapted for the screen her one-person play performed for several years across America. The life of the Edwards makes for an incredible story. Leaders of a prestigious colonial American church parish, they survived the death of children and grandchildren, international fame for spiritual leadership, and local humiliation and public ridicule from opponents. Edwards paved the way for deeper understanding of the ways and working of God in the world that has inspired every generation since, yet he was voted out of his own congregation by resentful agitators. Through it all was his faithful wife Sarah. Mother of 11 children, she supported him through the peaks and valleys, even though she was herself subject to bouts of depression. Edwards is often remembered for his famous sermon, "Sinners in the Hands of an Angry God," delivered in Enfield, Connecticut on July 8, 1741. In this program, however, we see him through the eyes of his beloved wife as a minister whose emphasis was far more on the grace and mercy of God. Through the intimacy of their gentle and faithful love for each other, we are provided penetrating insight into an amazing home and marriage relationship, one that left an incredible legacy in American history, as well as insight into an unusual man who stands among the most influential in all of church history.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?037491</url></doc>
