<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="037727">
  <docid>037727</docid>
  <title>Ana y Manuel</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Doblado, Miguel</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Mexico">26 November 2005</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Spain">12 March 2004</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Italy">23 April 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Spain">11</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Calvo, Manuel (V)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Butragueño, Roberto</producer>
    <producer>Zuazua, Koldo</producer>
    <producer>Calvo, Manuel (V)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Calvo, Manuel (V)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Villalobos, José (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anaya, Elena</actor>
      <role>Ana</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Martín, Diego (I)</actor>
      <role>Manuel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Martín, Ismael (III)</actor>
      <role>Street market pet seller</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>-Spoilers- Ana has just been dumped by her boyfriend Manuel. While living with him, she never wanted to own a pet because she thought it was cruel for the animal and not very hygienic for them. Once she even convinced him to get rid of a turtle that was given to him as a birthday present. But now she has decided to get a puppy, partly as a revenge to him for leaving her and partly to help her forget about him. She names him "Man" because he sees him as half "Manuel" but still twice the man he was. Time goes by and the dog grows up but she can't forget his ex-boyfriend, and she doesn't want the dog anymore. So she plans to give him away, as a Christmas present, to her brother. She leaves him in the car and has dinner with her family but when she comes back to get him, the car's gone and so is the dog. She feels very sad and tries to find Man. Until one day, Manuel shows up at her door with him. He tells Ana the story of how he bought the dog at the market they used to visit when they were together, and how surprised he was the dog lead him there. He also tells her he wants them to get back together.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?037727</url></doc>
