<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="038585">
  <docid>038585</docid>
  <title>Anand Aur Anand</title>
  <year>1984</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>adultery</keyword>
    <keyword>elephant</keyword>
    <keyword>real-life-father-and-son-playing-father-and-son</keyword>
    <keyword>affair</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Anand, Dev</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Anand, Dev</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Burman, Rahul Dev</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anand, Dev</actor>
      <role>Arun Anand</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anand, Suneil</actor>
      <role>Varun Anand</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Babbar, Raj</actor>
      <role>Pratap Singh, Union Leader</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bedi, Rakesh</actor>
      <role>Ravi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Birbal</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Biswajeet</actor>
      <role>Thakur</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gulzar, Rakhee</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Arun Anand</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sudhir (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Arun Anand has been married for several years now, but his wife is unable to conceive. Arun's has an affair with his personal secretary, Kiran, and as a result Kiran gets pregnant. Arun does not want a scandal to upset his wife, so he asks an impotent union leader, Pratap Singh, to marry Kiran, sire the child, and then divorce her, all for a hefty sum of money. Pratap agrees to this arrangement, and soon a boy is born. Pratap then changes his mind about divorcing Kiran, as her son is proof of his virility and manhood, and as such disappears from Arun's life. Years later Kiran's son has grown up and named Varun Singh. Arun finally finds out about them and meets them, but is rejected by Varun, who has come to accept Pratap as his father. There is a confrontation between Pratap and his employer, Thakur, and as a result, Varun is abducted, tied to a tree with four wild elephants who are made to drink alcohol, and after which will go on a drunken and virtually unstoppable rampage - starting with the gory death of the person nearest to them - Varun.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?038585</url></doc>
