<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="040533">
  <docid>040533</docid>
  <title>Angrakshak</title>
  <year>1995</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>abductor</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">17 November 1995</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Pinisetty, Ravi Raja</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kumar, Vivek (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Chitragupth, Anand</composer>
    <composer>Chitragupth, Milind</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Agashe, Mohan</actor>
      <role>Khare</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anand, Mahesh</actor>
      <role>Dancer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bahadur, Rana Jung</actor>
      <role>ACP Jaganpal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bahl, Mohnish</actor>
      <role>Ramesh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhatt, Pooja (I)</actor>
      <role>Priyanka "Priya" Choudhary</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deol, Sunny (I)</actor>
      <role>Ajay</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jaffrey, Saeed</actor>
      <role>Sanghvi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kharbanda, Kulbhushan</actor>
      <role>Satyendra Pal Choudhary</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rami Reddy</actor>
      <role>Vellu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Reddy, Rami (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Priyanka lives a very wealthy lifestyle with her widowed politician father, Satyendra Pal Choudhary, who owes his allegiance to Bharatiya Ekta Party. As Satyendra's popularity rises he fears for his life and that of his daughter's and as a result hires some bodyguards for himself, and one bodyguard named Ajay for Priyanka. With the elections approaching, and Satyendra's growing popularity creates some uncertainty with other political parties, as a result Priyanka is kidnapped and is Ajay seriously wounded and hospitalized. When the news is made public, a wave of sympathy moves in Satyendra's favor and he is sure to win the election. Priyanka's abductors demand two crore rupees, but before Satyendra could respond the police find a body of a young woman, who he identifies as that of Priyanka. A grieving Satyendra is shown on national television before a shocked nation, and he wins the election hands down. What the public do not know is that Ajay is a hit-man for an underworld don named Vellu, Ajay is known for his short-temper, which had resulted in the death of a young man named Ramesh, whose only crime was marrying Ajay's sister, Asha, without his consent. The question remains why would a respectable politician hire a killer as his daughter's bodyguard?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?040533</url></doc>
