<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="040884">
  <docid>040884</docid>
  <title>Animals</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Ingram, James (III)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">7 August 2003</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="France">16 May 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">80</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Alon, Arik</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Porteous, Dougal</producer>
    <producer>O'Rafferty, Sheila</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Alon, Arik</writer>
    <writer>Hurn, Jonnie</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Brignell, Tom</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Andrew, Sheli</actor>
      <role>Jade</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Conway, Paul (IV)</actor>
      <role>Charlie Jentzen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dalton, Caroline (I)</actor>
      <role>Elsa</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hurn, Jonnie</actor>
      <role>James Reynolds</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Porteous, Dougal</actor>
      <role>Nic Robinson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stephens, Vimal</actor>
      <role>DCI Raj Capor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Watts, Charlie (II)</actor>
      <role>DI Bolton</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Animal rights activist Jade is anxious to get Nick Robinson, the marketing director of a pharmaceutical company, to justify their experimentation on animals so she can post the results on her fledgling website www.justice4animals.tv but all attempts at a serious debate are met with contempt. When hard-line activist Charlie convinces Jade he can get the one-on-one she wants, she agrees, unaware of what this will involve. Kidnap. Imprisonment. Torture. Locked in a cage, barely able to move, Nick is finally at Jades mercy as she videos and uploads his arrogant dismissal of her questioning. An anonymous e-mail to the police confirms their intention to keep him caged until all vivisection at the company is halted. It is then that their experiments begin, and these are more than just shampoo in the eyes. As Nick's health deteriorates rapidly, accelerating the sites hit-ratio, his willingness to talk increases, yet Jade is made aware that even if he repents and opposes the tests there will always be others willing to continue the work. Realizing that Charlie has no intention of changing Nick's view of life but to simply end it she breaks anonymity to warn the police, putting her own life at risk to save another.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?040884</url></doc>
