<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="041193">
  <docid>041193</docid>
  <title>Anker werfen</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Tonne, Karen</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>German</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="France">5 September 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Germany">20</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Beck, Markus</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Gräfe-Höft, Verena</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Romberg, Martin</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Le, Aaron Hong</actor>
      <role>Lian</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rott, Matthias</actor>
      <role>Hannes</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sauer, Oliver</actor>
      <role>Jochen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Schad, Stephan</actor>
      <role>Herbert</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zhoungraba, Isaaka</actor>
      <role>Domba</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"Cast Anchor" is a story about a short moment of life of five people. Their path of life is going to cross during one night in the port of Hamburg. At the same time the QM2 leaves the docks. The young Chinese sailor LIAN has only a couple of hours until his Container ship will be departing. On the telephone with his wife he gets to know that he became a father. Far away from home he celebrates the birth of his daughter and gets lost during the celebration ceremony of the QM2. HANNES, a scrap metal thief, meets the African blind passenger DOMBA, who convinces him to drive him to the Asylheim. Domba assumes that his family lives there. Both men make their way through the traffic jam, just to find out that some journeys are never going to end. JOCHEN finishes his last shift work as a customs officer. He has developed cancer and needs to get some serious therapy. But before leaving for the hospital he wants to make peace with his daughter LAURA. They haven't seen each other for eight years. But his egoism and her pride seem to stand in the way of their reconciliation.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?041193</url></doc>
