<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="041128">
  <docid>041128</docid>
  <title>Anjaan</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Mehta, Hansal</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bohraa, Anil S.</producer>
    <producer>Kanungo, Manohar P.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Dube, Sudhanshu</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Shah, Viju</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chahal, Mahek</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gupta, Vipul</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Malik, Aamir Ali</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A 'marital thriller'. A mysterious stranger creates havoc in the lives of a husband and wife, within a few days after he visits their house. Aditya is a film-maker whose last two films have failed miserably. He is currently working on a script which for him is almost like a final attempt at glory. His failures have created a rift in his relationship with Meneka, his wife. While the marriage is not really on the rocks, Meneka does feel neglected and lonely. Her attempts at understanding Aditya are usually met with a snub. She misses the caring, loving and passionate Aditya for whom she had forfeited her successful modeling career. The arrival of a stranger, Shoaib, into the house soon turns into an exploration of morality and momentary temptation. The disarming, mysterious Shoaib opens up vistas that were till now taboo for Meneka. He charms her, he angers her and in the process he provokes her innermost thoughts and desires. Who is this dangerously charming stranger? Will his presence rock the very institution that Meneka has been clinging to? And what will Aditya who has been so engrossed in his own professional failures do when he realizes the deception that is about to engulf his personal life?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?041128</url></doc>
