<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="042077">
  <docid>042077</docid>
  <title>Another Part of Me</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Abreu, Christopher</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">8 April 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">5</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Abreu, Christopher</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Abreu, Christopher</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Abreu, Christopher</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Shipkowski, Sarah</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Davis, Kendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Girl Walking</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Garcia, Jace</actor>
      <role>Boy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Garcia, Veronica (III)</actor>
      <role>Witch/Mother/Storyteller</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gramlich, Aaron</actor>
      <role>Extra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Guzman, Ivan</actor>
      <role>Teenager</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hurst, Emily</actor>
      <role>Extra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Merreighn, Quentin</actor>
      <role>Younger Brother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Schurenberg, Kramer</actor>
      <role>Extra</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>'Another Part of Me' is the emotional tale about a young man who must survive the wrath of his mother. This young man's world often seems cruel and unjust, where he rarely has a voice. However, through the example of his little brother, he discovers the joys that life brings and the strength to go on. Every morning he awakens to the same life from the same nightmares. His mother, with a bucket at hand, greets him with a nice cold splash of reality and yells her demands for the day. The only thing he looks forward to is the smile on his little brother's face. Everyday he tolerates the same routine, seemingly unaffected by its hardships, until it is suddenly broken. He realizes what no one else has; he does have a choice. His younger brother is his sole reason for existence. So, when his brother's life is threatened, he finds the courage to stand up for himself and reclaim what he's lost; his childhood. He must find his voice while still growing up, taking charge of his life, and securing his own destiny. He must now decide if he's going to make the right choice to better his life, or allow it to continue on its path of self-depreciation. Will his mother have the last laugh? Or will it be the mysterious villain that haunts his dreams? Will he be able to save the troubled boy inside? Or will his younger brother have the same fate as him?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?042077</url></doc>
