<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="043047">
  <docid>043047</docid>
  <title>Anywhere But Fear</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Hendra (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>war-victim</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>displaced-person</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Indonesian</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Indonesia</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Indonesia">SU</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Indonesia">29 November 2004</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Philippines">8 October 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Indonesia">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Tumenggung, Adeline</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Sudrijanta</producer>
    <producer>Tumenggung, Adeline</producer>
    <producer>Tumenggung, Adeline</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>One afternoon, Suryani and her fellow villagers were forced to leave their homes to a camp by TNI (Indonesian Military). Her husband, Mawardi decided to stay and worked in his garden. When TNI cleaned up the village, he was arrested, charged to be a GAM (Gerakan Aceh Merdeka, Free Aceh Movement) member. According to this couple, Mawardi is just an ordinary civilian. But the TNI forcedly asked him to confess that he is truly a GAM member. During military operation of the Martial Law, Suryani and many people in Aceh have been suffering from many faces of violence: forced displacement and looting, torture, forced disappearances, arbitrary detention, restrictions on freedom of movement, restrictions on economic activity, and recruiting civilians to join militia. Violence has been circling all over territory of Aceh. GAM strongholds areas are of course become the most affected by violence. Many people have left Aceh because of violence but people who have no other choice but to stay in Aceh, must challenge such violence as Suryani does. Violence has generated fear. For civilians like Suryani, it doesn't matter whether their villages were 'clean' or not. Living at home or at camp, following TNI or GAM, for them it is anywhere but fear</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?043047</url></doc>
