<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="043136">
  <docid>043136</docid>
  <title>Aoki densetsu shoot!</title>
  <year>1993</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Sport</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>based-on-comic</keyword>
    <keyword>punctuation-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>anime</keyword>
    <keyword>soccer</keyword>
    <keyword>championship</keyword>
    <keyword>schoolgirl</keyword>
    <keyword>love-triangle</keyword>
    <keyword>male-female-relationship</keyword>
    <keyword>exclamation-point-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>team</keyword>
    <keyword>high-school</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Japanese</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Japan</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Japan">7 November 1993</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Nishio, Daisuke</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Horikawa, Kazumasa</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Gôdo, Kazuhiko</writer>
    <writer>Ohshima, Tsukasa</writer>
    <writer>Takegami, Junki</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Honma, Yûsuke</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Toshihiko Tanaka decided to go to Kakegawa high school after graduating from junior high, along with Kazuhiro Hiramatsu and Kenji Shiraishi, the other two members of the Golden Trio in Kakenjshi Junior High football team. Although there are some problems at the beginning, the new players finally fit the team well And after being trained by the team's junior caption Yoshiharu Kubo. A year before, freshman player Kubo led the two-month-old team to the quarterfinal in the highly competitive Shizuoka province tournament single handedly. The new team needs to rebuild itself before the National Tournament in summer, without their leader Kubo. Assistant caption Atsushi Kamiya remains strong and shows great leadership to replace the caption spot, and new comer Keigo Mahori fulfills Kubo's mid-field position. This totally break team inherits the spirit of Kubo and again aims for the national championship. Toshihiko, who takes Kubo's number 10 jersey, now needs to endeavor for his skill in order to reach their goal, but at the same time Toshihiko needs to strive for his girl, Kazumi Endo, against Kazuhiro, to be in danger the friendship between they two to reach the Endo's love.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?043136</url></doc>
