<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="043376">
  <docid>043376</docid>
  <title>Apeth</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Talfinger, Laura</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>threesome</keyword>
    <keyword>gay</keyword>
    <keyword>ape</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Indonesia">9 August 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Brazil">15 November 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="UK">12 December 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="France">16 May 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">8</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Charlton, James Martin</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Charlton, James Martin</producer>
    <producer>Kelleher, Andy (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Charlton, James Martin</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Hyde, John (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Billington, Stephen</actor>
      <role>Sven</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cooke, Caroline Burns</actor>
      <role>Pierrot's Mother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hayes, Tom (V)</actor>
      <role>Ape</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Herrera, Pietro</actor>
      <role>Pierrot</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Sven is looking at a coffee table book of El Greco reproductions. He is fascinated by one picture in particular - Allegory, Boy Lighting Candle in Company of Ape and Fool (Fábula). He lays the book aside and drifts into a reverie. Later, he is on his computer, and receives an email from a sexual partner, asking if their meet tonight is still on. Sven replies that it is. He touches himself sensually. A car drives past London zoo. In a block of flats on a run-down council estate, a woman scrubs her dirty washing. The mobile phone beside her receives a text. Before she can check it, her son Pierrot barges into the kitchen and violently wrests it from her hands. He checks the text - it's from Sven, inviting him round tonight. Pierrot is cocky and over-excited at this, and rubs his glee in the face of his long-suffering mother. At London zoo, an Ape leaves via the main exit and runs into the street. Later that evening at Sven's, Pierrot and his host smoke dope and enjoy the sexual tension. Pierrot tries to look at the El Greco book but Sven forbids him, instead providing him with lurid pornography. The doorbell chimes, and Sven lets the Ape in. The three of them smoke dope, watch DVDs of gorillas frolicking and begin to grope each other in wild abandon...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?043376</url></doc>
