<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="043444">
  <docid>043444</docid>
  <title>Apna Sapna Money Money</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Jain, Chirag</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Musical</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Sivan, Sangeeth</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Pillai, Prem</producer>
    <producer>Farooqui, Raju</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Sivan, Sangeeth</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Chakraborty, Pritam</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Darling, Bobby</actor>
      <role>Bobby Mohabbati</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deshmukh, Ritesh</actor>
      <role>Kishan/Sunaina/Sania/Sarju Maharaj Banaraswale</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gill, Avtar</actor>
      <role>Senior Police Inspector</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jaitley, Celina</actor>
      <role>Sania</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kher, Anupam</actor>
      <role>Satyabol Shashtri</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mitra, Koena</actor>
      <role>Julie Fernandes</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pal, Sunil</actor>
      <role>MataPrasad Henchman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pandey, Chunky</actor>
      <role>Rana Jang Bahadur</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shetty, Sunil (I)</actor>
      <role>Inspector Mane</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shroff, Jackie</actor>
      <role>Carlos</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Talpade, Shreyas</actor>
      <role>Arjun Fernandes</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Yadav, Rajpal</actor>
      <role>Matha Prasad</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Kishan is a young man from Goa whose brain is full of every conceivable trick to make a quick buck. He cons people by slipping into different outfits and by assuming many guises. Julie, is a sexy club dancer with quite a local reputation, but behind her raunchy exterior is a compassionate, kind-hearted woman who goes out of her way to help the needy. Sania Badnaam is a con-woman who uses her sexuality to lure men and leave them penniless later. Beautiful and unwilling to surrender to emotions easily, Sania craves only money and power. Danny Carlos, is a merciless underworld don with wacky fashion sense. He works from Bangkok and operates in India through Sania. Arjun Fernandez, an honorable man who is content making a simple living with whatever money he earns from his garage. He meets the woman of his dreams-Shivani Shastri-on a bed of red hot chillies. She is a simple girl from a Brahmin family, but her subborn, overprotective, and aging father, Pandit Satyabol Shastri, would never let her marry Arjun. It will take a hell of an effort to win her hand from her father. Namdev Mane, an honest cop dedicated to putting criminals behind bars. Some clever criminals who work in disguise have kept him on his toes.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?043444</url></doc>
