<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="043426">
  <docid>043426</docid>
  <title>Apna Bana Ke Dekho</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Telugu</language>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Subhash, K.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kukreja, Raj</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Deva (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deva, Prabhu</actor>
      <role>Jankiraman 'Johny'</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Jankiraman alias Johny is a hoodlum, known to the local police, has been arrested several times, and lives a poor lifestyle in a city in South India along with his widowed mom. His mother and father had a love marriage, but he died a violent death. She kept her Mangalsutra around his photo frame. Once she talked to a parrot astrologer, who predicted great things in Janikiraman's life, as he will soon be associating with rich people, as well as getting married to a very wealthy girl. These predictions come true when Jankiraman introduces her to Sandhya Anand, a pretty young woman, who even comes to visit and eat at their humble dwelling. She and Jankiraman will, however, soon find out that she regards Jankiraman just as a friend and will soon ask him to pick a groom for her from an envelope containing photographs. A broken-hearted Jankiraman is unable to convey his true feelings, and picks the photo of Dhinesh Nallathambi, the only son of a Politician. Sandhya instantly approves of Jankiraman's choice, and an engagement party takes place. Shortly thereafter Jankiraman's life spirals out of control as his mother passes away, and he gets into a confrontation with a hoodlum named Sadhaa - and it is during this confrontation that will lead to even more changes in his life.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?043426</url></doc>
