<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="044327">
  <docid>044327</docid>
  <title>Ar-Men</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Manya, Aurélien</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>French</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby SR</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">21 July 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="France">14</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Auffret, Gilles</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ramonet, Axel</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Auffret, Gilles</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Goanec, Michaël</actor>
      <role>Damien's Father</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Goanec, Nonna</actor>
      <role>Damien</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kerhom, Jean-Marc</actor>
      <role>The Fisherman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Le Corre, Guy</actor>
      <role>The Regular</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Le Meur, Morgane</actor>
      <role>The Waitress</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Damien, seventeen, sets out to see the lighthouse he's dreamed about forever: Ar-Men, the gate to the Atlantic high seas. To do so, he convinces Marine, the bartender of his regular bar, to introduce him to Jean-Marc, a fisherman who needs a sailor. Though his father is very reserved about his son's plans, Damien sets sail for a inshore fishing trip, keeping his true motives a secret from Jean-Marc. It's dark when the voyage begins and at dusk, all of the coastal marks have vanished. The only thing that remains is the sea, the great desert. Soon, Jean-Marc prepares his equipment: weighted poles are thrown like javelins overboard; dozens of nets dive into the water - hundreds of yards of ropes and thousands of miles of mesh. Damien, who keeps looking at the horizon, suddenly doubts their destination. When he asks Jean-Marc whether or not they go to Ar-Men, the answer is a firm no. As the weather changes, Damien now becomes seasick, so Jean-Marc has to pull the nets back in on his own. However, Damien has a sudden burst of energy and helps to sort out the different species of fish. When back in the harbor, he even unloads the crates as if he's done it his whole life. Before leaving each other, Jean-Marc explains to Damien that Ar-Men is not in his fishing range, that only ships aiming the Irish Sea pass through it, and that it's always on work purposes. It seems that Damien has changed, because this is likely the first time he truly listens to someone. His share of fish is probably not the only thing he gained on his journey.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?044327</url></doc>
