<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="045521">
  <docid>045521</docid>
  <title>Arly Hanks</title>
  <year>1993</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>based-on-novel</keyword>
    <keyword>threat</keyword>
    <keyword>mayor</keyword>
    <keyword>gas-station</keyword>
    <keyword>divorce</keyword>
    <keyword>small-town</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Sanford, Arlene</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Fitzgerald, Pam</producer>
    <producer>Clark, Sean (III)</producer>
    <producer>Sander, Ian (I)</producer>
    <producer>Sanford, Arlene</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Clark, Sean (IV)</writer>
    <writer>Hess, Joan Angela</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bergen, Polly</actor>
      <role>Ruby Bee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cole, Olivia</actor>
      <role>Estelle</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Darbo, Patrika</actor>
      <role>Dahlia O'Neill</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jackson, Kate (I)</actor>
      <role>Arly hanks</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McCullough, Julie</actor>
      <role>Jay-Lee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McKinnon, Ray</actor>
      <role>Hobert Middleton</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Page, Harrison</actor>
      <role>Larry-Joe</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Perlman, Ron</actor>
      <role>Jim-Bob Buchanan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Scheine, Raynor</actor>
      <role>Raz Buchanan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stevens, Chambers</actor>
      <role>Kevin</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The small town of Maggody, population 775, Stump County, Arkansas, has a new Police Chief - Arly Hanks, who has returned home from New York City after a messy divorce, her former husband having been shamefully found in bed with a foot model. A high number of the inhabitants of Maggody carry the surname of Buchanan, which does tend to lead to a certain amount of confusion amongst visitors, especially as the most prominent member of this prolific and devious clan is Jim-Bob Buchana,, gas-station owner and larger-than-life Mayor of Maggody. But Maggody is under threat. A strip-mining company is trying to set up business just outside town, and while Jim-Bob is a slippery character, his heart is in the right place - after a fashion. He and his two cronies, car salesman Hobert and teacher Larry-Joe begin to scheme and plot to prevent the company claiming the land. And so Jim-Bob approaches the delightfully scatty, good-hearted but beautiful Jay-Lee, a lady with a weakness for male company - any male company. Jim-Bob appeals to her sense of honor by telling her that she has to distract the company representative long enough for him to miss filing the claim, and then the town would be safe. But things go dreadfully wrong when poor Jay-Lee turns up dead. Jim-Bob and his two friends kidnap the poor mining representative Drake, and it takes all of Arly's deductive skills to solve the murder, involving - among other things - Withers, an escaped convict with a sugar buzz, a missing-presumed-dead hound dog, a skunk, and a desperate Drake in a dress.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?045521</url></doc>
