<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="045768">
  <docid>045768</docid>
  <title>Army Men: Green Rogue</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>VideoGame</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>army-men</keyword>
    <keyword>video-game</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">T</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">20 March 2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <composers>
    <composer>Fish, Ron</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cummings, Jim (I)</actor>
      <role>Sarge, Grimm/Omega Soldier/All of the soldiers</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The Green Army is creating a supersoldier, created by the spliced DNA of Sarge's Heroes. The supersoldier is code-named "Omega Soldier." A computer Mr. X created that idea. Colonel Grimm was hesitant about the project, but had no choice. Doing so will put the Bravo Company Commandos out for a week or two. While attempting to transport Omega Soldier for training while he is in a capsule, the Tan Army led by General Plastro sent in attack choppers and attacked the Green Army choppers including the one with Omega Soldier on it. Omega Soldier is now behind enemy lines. Omega Soldier must battle through all the Tan Army with the weapons he can muster plus using a genetic special attack called Bio-Strike, in order to retrieve back to a Green Army base. He will not be alone at some times, since some other Green Army soldiers are caught in the firefight, too. Unfortunately, they have to return back to a base by escaping the battlefield. With Bravo Company temporarily out of commision, Omega Soldier is the last line of assault and defense for the Green Army, will he stop the Tan Army? You can prevent the Tan Army from winning the war with this new commando. Too much like a Terminator-like soldier, huh? Just because he is just a created machine does not mean he is invincible.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?045768</url></doc>
