<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="045866">
  <docid>045866</docid>
  <title>Aron's Big Adventure</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Altmark, Aron</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">5 May 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Altmark, Aron</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Altmark, Aron</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Over the space of four months, Aron documents his travels throughout the land of Israel and a side trip to Poland to discover how both places are part of who he is today. Along the way, he meets many interesting characters--from Jews to Palestinians to Poles--and sees all the beauty the Middle East has to offer--from the Negev Desert to the war-torn north of Israel. Along the way, he gains a new perspective on Israel's importance to all peoples of the world and a new understanding of Israel's importance in his life. As he hikes, backpacks, runs, eats, crisscrossing every square inch of Israel, Aron films the land, people, and cultures he experiences. From up close and personal encounters with camels to celebrating religious holidays to walking in the footsteps of biblical ancestors, and even walking through the gas chambers of Auschwitz, Aron paints a vivid and personal picture of the Jewish homeland. Through the eyes of one Jewish American teen, Aron's Big Adventure presents a different side to a region often plagued with conflict and turmoil, and provides an alternative viewpoint on the Middle East. He shows the beauty and harmony that does exist, surpassing religious and cultural differences, and provides an optimistic contrast to the common impressions of the Middle East.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?045866</url></doc>
