<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="046231">
  <docid>046231</docid>
  <title>Arroz con mango</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Frias, Juana</editor>
  </editors>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">5 April 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">101</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Frias, Juana</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Frias, Juana</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Crespo, Asela</writer>
    <writer>Frias, Juana</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chamberlain, Robb</actor>
      <role>Steve Meckler</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Diaz, Eddie (I)</actor>
      <role>Eduardo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Espalter, Denisse</actor>
      <role>Maggie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hernandez, Ivan (I)</actor>
      <role>Mateo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Memo (II)</actor>
      <role>Musico</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rodríguez, Carlos (III)</actor>
      <role>Yayo</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>'Arroz con Mango' is a Spanish phrase which means 'What a mess!' And that's what you get when sampling the wonderful idiosyncrasies in this love story on espresso. Maggie is a young Cuban-American freelance writer who takes an eye opening trip back to her roots and meets a young enchanting native, Mateo. Her short visit awakens a romance that cannot go outside the Island. She returns to Miami to her career driven City Commissioner boyfriend, Steve, an overbearing father who's a little too overprotective of her and his bakery, plus a group of nutty relatives from politically incorrect Tio Julian down to the romantically pursued delivery man Conrado. Maggie finds that life can take many unexpected turns as she discovers Mateo has risked a dangerous trip at sea and he has made it to Miami. The quest is hope and the passions that drive us in this search. Arroz con Mango is a light romantic comedy about people and their drives. Entwined with Maggie's search for hope, the film explores her interaction with her family and friends. Maggie's father, Yayo, runs a successful bakery, Steve is a politician, Elena is a fashion designer, Ms. Al seeks love, Conrado is a bashful deliveryman, and Mateo is looking for a chance in life. These diverse motivations come together creating a big problemo. And what a mess!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?046231</url></doc>
