<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="048191">
  <docid>048191</docid>
  <title>Askar fi el-mu'askar</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Merhi, Khaled</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Arabic</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Egypt">8 August 2003</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Kuwait">28 January 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Kuwait">100</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Yasin, Muhammad</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Abdullah, Ahmad (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Maher, Nabil Ali</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Abdallah, Salah</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>El Kedwany, Maged</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Henedi, Mohamed</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hosny, Hassan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Leqa'</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Mohamed Henedy plays the role of a native soldier called "Khedr El Gebaly" who is so kind and naïve, he is in love with a girl who lives in the same village called "Saadeya" played by Lekaa El Khomaisy and he wants to marry her. "Khedr" meets another native kind man "Metwaly El Zanaty" played by Maged El Kedwany, in along train journey to their home village. They became friends. Metwaly El Zanaty's uncle "Salem El Zanaty" -played by Fayek Azab- as well as his mother keep forcing Metwaly to take revenge for his father as he was killed by one of "El Gebaly's" family members; "Hasanein El Gebaly" -played by Hassan Hosny. They want Metwaly to kill the son of "Hasanein El Gebaly"; on the other hand Metwaly is totally against the idea of revenge; we also get to know that his uncle is pushing him to do this so that he would get killed and then he can merge Metwaly's land with his own. Finally Metawly submits to the pressures of his mother and uncle and decides to join the army when knowing that the son of "Hasanein El Gebaly" is volunteering. So again both Khedr El Gebaly and Metwaly El Zanaty meet in the army and their relationship becomes stronger each day until they both discover the Khedr's father is the one who killed Metwaly's father, accordingly Metwaly must kill Khedr to take revenge.. suspense begins. The remaining events of the movie display Khedr's escape with his bride Saadeya from his friend Metwaly who follows them everywhere. In this escape journey Khedr leaves his village heading to Cairo to hide in the house of his uncle Hassan Kolonia -played by Salah Abdulla- who lives with a dancer. Hassan Kolonia used to be a history teacher but he quits teaching to work in a nightclub to gain more money. At the end and after a long chase Metwaly El Zanaty and his mother understand the wicked plot of his uncle Salem El Zanaty who is caught by the police, thus Khedr's soul is rescued, he's finally able to begin his life with his bride and they were able to enjoy their wedding night which they were never able to enjoy during the runaway journey.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?048191</url></doc>
