<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="048275">
  <docid>048275</docid>
  <title>Asmaan Se Ooncha</title>
  <year>1989</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Kumar, Mehul</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kumar, Sujit (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Roshan, Rajesh</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ajitesh</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Amrapurkar, Sadashiv</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Babbar, Raj</actor>
      <role>D.S.P. Inspector Ranjit Malik</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cola, Coca</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dalvi, Sudhir</actor>
      <role>Inspector Malik</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>David, Sheela</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Govinda</actor>
      <role>Vikram Malik (Vicky)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hingoo, Dinesh</actor>
      <role>Parsi car-driver</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jeetendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Krishen/King</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Dev (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Sujit (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mathur, Jaya</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mohan, Mac</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Negi, Master Bunty</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Raj, Jagdish</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Raj, K.K.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Saxena, Pradeep</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Kishan, who lives with his sister, Reshmi, runs a Gas Station in Srinagar. One day while returning home he hears cries of help from a woman in a jeep. He chases and overtakes the jeep, and rescues the woman from four hoodlums. He finds out that the woman is Anita, who has run away from her cruel uncle who wanted to sell her for a large sum of money. Kishan permits her to live with them, and soon both fall in love with each other. Then their lives are turned upside down when Naag Raj, one of the hoodlums who had attempted to molest Anita, returns and sexually assaults Reshmi. When Kishan comes to her rescue, he ends up killing one of the men, and setting fire to the Gas Station, while Naag Raj absconds. The Police arrest Kishan and he is sent to prison for several years. A pregnant Anita attempts to kill herself, but is rescued by Delhi-based Police Inspector Ranjit Malik, who subsequently marries her and allows her to give birth to a baby boy, Vikrant alias Vicky. Years later Vicky has grown up and has fallen in love with a lovely young woman named Sonam, who he rescued from a molester named Prem Raj. Ranjit gets transferred to Bombay to nab an underworld Don by the name of King. Vicky is recruited as a Police Inspector with Bombay Police. One night Anita wakes up to see a man pointing a gun at Ranjit, she is shocked to see that the man is none other than her former lover, Kishan. The question remains why does Kishan want to kill Ranjit, and what impact Kishan's arrival will have on Anita?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?048275</url></doc>
