<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="051469">
  <docid>051469</docid>
  <title>Aur Pappu Pass Ho Gaya</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">20 April 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Soni, S.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Srivastava, Amit (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Chopra, Ravi (II)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Abhishek, Krishna</actor>
      <role>Pappu/Prince of Trikamgarh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bedi, Narendra (II)</actor>
      <role>Sardar Tara Singh/Raja of Trikamgarh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Goswami, K.K.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kamle, Shradha</actor>
      <role>Baby/Rajkumari Devi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kanawat, Rahul</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Mushtaq</actor>
      <role>Pathan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kharbanda, Sikander</actor>
      <role>Biloo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nath, Alok</actor>
      <role>Pappu's dad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shroff, Jackie</actor>
      <role>Sudhakar 'Sudhabhai' Chauhan</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Day-dreamer Pappu lives a poor lifestyle with his mom and dad in a village in India. In order to better his prospects, he re-locates to Bombay and finds a job as a mechanic in Sardar Tara Singh's garage. He meets with and falls in love with Kiran Chauhan, who is the sister of dreaded gangster, Sudhakar Chauhan, and lives a very wealthy lifestyle surrounded by bodyguards. Pappu feigns that he is really a runaway Prince of Trikamgarh, worms his way into Kiran's heart and also wins over Sudhakar and their grandmother. When Sudhakar asks Pappu to bring his father to finalize the marriage, he asks Tara to be his dad, to which he agrees, and in this way fool Sudhakar and Kiran. When Tara borrows money from Pathan in order to enable Pappu live a princely lifestyle, they are unable to re-pay this debt, but help comes unexpectedly from the real Raja of Trikamgarh, who also travels to finalize his son's marriage - much to Pappu's surprise. Things spiral out of control when Pappu's real father and mother also decide to pay their son a visit!!!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?051469</url></doc>
