<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="051482">
  <docid>051482</docid>
  <title>Aura, IL</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Hasegawa-Johnson, Yu</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Japanese</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">PG-13</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">15 September 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">97</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Hasegawa-Johnson, Yu</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Christian, Robin</producer>
    <producer>Dobbs, Anita Roy</producer>
    <producer>Vidanagamage, Rita</producer>
    <producer>Hasegawa, Akira (II)</producer>
    <producer>Hasegawa, Akira (II)</producer>
    <producer>Hasegawa-Johnson, Mark</producer>
    <producer>Hasegawa-Johnson, Yu</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Hasegawa-Johnson, Yu</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barrie, Avalon</actor>
      <role>Crystal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dobbs, Anita Roy</actor>
      <role>Clair MacGregor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Golden, Aaron</actor>
      <role>Kevin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kearns, Anne Shapland</actor>
      <role>Brenda</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Van Eman, Jason</actor>
      <role>Scott</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wasiyo, Khaitsa</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Xu, Troy</actor>
      <role>Ryan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Yang, Brian</actor>
      <role>Chris</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>'I have to prove to Daddy that Mommy's still alive!" Ryan (8) keeps pestering his big sister, until finally she buys him a bus ticket. He doesn't want his father to remarry. His father is on a business trip; in the vast cornfields of Central Illinois, Ryan has only 4 days to find the evidence. In St. Louis, Crystal (17) fails to kill herself, again. Her father is absent from her life; she can't understand her mother. Crystal wants to die beautifully, like a princess. In Chicago, Scott (27) is diagnosed with cancer. He has treatments and his doctor says he's now cured. But the fear of his own death prevents him from proposing to his girlfriend. In Aura, IL, Eliora writes. An 80-year old Holocaust survivor who lost her husband years ago. She waits for God to take her too. Her mind is fading, and, as her everyday task, her habit from the dark past returns to her. Ryan's encounter with Crystal and Scott. Their accidental visit to Eliora's house. Endless cornfields. The sunset. The books. Would near-death experiences of Crystal, Scott, and Eliora make them perfect mentors for Ryan? Suppose you knew the date of your death; would that solve anything? An award-winning director. (CINE Golden Eagle Award) An award-winning script. (Moondance International Film Festival Screenplay Competition) An award-winning writer. (Writer's Digest Writing Competition; Robert Boit Manuscript Competition; Richard Rudy Memorial Grant; R. Boit Writing Prize; Gaia Award, Moondance Screenplay Competition) and A heart-warming story. The 80 year-old Eliora is played by Holocaust survivor Maria Szapszewicz. This is the debut film for Avalon Barrie and Troy Xu, who, together with Maria Szapszewicz and Scott VanEman ('Regarding Billy'), create intense personal histories that turn the isolation of the prairie into a pathway to life.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?051482</url></doc>
