<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="052061">
  <docid>052061</docid>
  <title>Autopsy 6: Secrets of the Dead</title>
  <year>1999</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Ginsberg, Arthur</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>autopsy</keyword>
    <keyword>nellie-medina</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">October 1999</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">47</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Ginsberg, Arthur</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Medina, Nellie</producer>
    <producer>Nevins, Sheila</producer>
    <producer>Monet, Gaby</producer>
    <producer>Medina, Nellie</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Baden, Michael</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>LeNoir, Tommy</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Von Cosel, Karl</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The sixth installment of HBO's popular series examining six cases in which forensic science has helped detectives track down criminals that might have otherwise gone unpunished. The first story, "The Case of the Severed Hand", delves into why a human hand was thrown in the river even though the owner of the hand had been dead and buried for years. "A Fatal Attraction" tells the bizarre story of Andrew Katrinak whose wife and infant son were murdered by someone from his past. "The Margo Prade Story" reexamines the case of a doctor who was shot to death in her minivan and why she had a partial bite mark on her arm. "The Telltale Imprint" tells of the 1978 bankrobbery by a woman who left her lip print on the bank door as she fled the scene. "The American Dream" begins with the disappearence of a Filipino who was married to a retired Army officer but the plot thickens when it is discovered that he had two other wives disappear or die. "The Strange Obsession of Dr. Carl Von Cosel" is the truely bizarre tale of a doctor in 1931 who was working on a cure for Tuberculosis and fell in love with one of his patients who died. After her funeral, the doctor disappeared, and so did the woman's body.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?052061</url></doc>
