<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="052164">
  <docid>052164</docid>
  <title>Autumn Leaves</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Love, Tina</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>based-on-short-story</keyword>
    <keyword>divorce</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">3 February 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">19</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Love, Tina</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Love, Michael (II)</producer>
    <producer>Love, Tina</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Love, Tina</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Acosta, Rose</actor>
      <role>Susie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brennan, John (XXIII)</actor>
      <role>Tommy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fischer, Josh</actor>
      <role>Ted</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>White, Clay</actor>
      <role>Foster</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Whiting, Peter (II)</actor>
      <role>young Tommy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Yco, Nathan</actor>
      <role>John</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A divorced couple, Foster and Suzie, and their college age sons, John and Tommy, are purging the amassed remnants in the attic of their once family home, which is up for sale. As they toss objects from the small attic balcony into the pickup truck below, emotions are stirred. Suzie is purge-happy while Foster, clings pathetically to the memories of a once happy family life. When Foster discovers the "Wedding Day" video he asks all, "What shall I do with this?" Distraught son Tommy settles the matter, "What's the point of keeping it" and he tosses it into the pickup truck below. Suzie's new fiancé, Ted, arrives with a 6-pack of beer, to encounter the debris that missed the truck bed. Fully immersed in his I-pod shuffle, he picks up the fall out, tossing items into the truck bed, oblivious to the drama playing out on the attic balcony above him between his new love and her ex. BREAK TIME! Suzie escapes. Ted's arrival is perfect timing as Foster's behavior is becoming unbearable to her. As they disperse Foster humors his sons, but soon finds himself alone gazing at a pair of his son's discarded roller blades, recalling a glimpse of the past. Later, a very uncomfortable Foster declines the invite to join the others for a beer and meets up with sullen son Tommy.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?052164</url></doc>
