<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="054089">
  <docid>054089</docid>
  <title>Baap Ka Baap</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Darak, Dilip</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Kothare, Mahesh</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bachhewar, Vidya</producer>
    <producer>Singh, Shobha</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Patil, Vijay (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Amrapurkar, Sadashiv</actor>
      <role>Advocate Raja Waghmare</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Berde, Laxmikant</actor>
      <role>Laxmikant Lokhande</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Berde, Ravindra</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chandorkar, Aarti</actor>
      <role>Gauri Tungare</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jadhav, Bharat (I)</actor>
      <role>Bhiku</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jayant, Nutan</actor>
      <role>Vasanti Waghmare</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kohate, Mahesh</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kothare, Mahesh</actor>
      <role>C.I.D. Inspector Mahesh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lever, Johnny</actor>
      <role>Inspector Pratap Tungare</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Narkar, Avinash</actor>
      <role>Avinash Tiwari</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The Government of India decides to honor five entrepreneurs in a small town called Shrirajpur in Maharashtra, India, which is well publicized all over the country. Then on an Amavas night (no moon) one of the entrepreneurs is brutally strangulated by a rope and killed. The police, especially local Police Inspector Pratap Tungare are baffled. Before the police could even piece together a motive, exactly on the next Amavas the second entrepreneur is killed in a similar fashion. Now even more vigilante, and suspecting more serial killings, the Police, assisted by CID Inspector Mahesh, alert the three remaining entrepreneurs to exert all due caution. Despite of this, no one was able to prevent the third entrepreneur from being killed. Then the police get an anonymous tip, which leads them to the arrest of one Laxmikant Lokhande, a private investigator by profession, who claims that he is innocent, however, has no explanation to offer of the evidence located in his house. The police also arrest a second suspect named Avinash Navre, a press reporter. What the police do not know is that there is also a third culprit at large - a culprit who has been closely working with the police - and who is beyond and above any suspicion.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?054089</url></doc>
