<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="056608">
  <docid>056608</docid>
  <title>Bahay ni Lola 2</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Navarro, Jess</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Tagalog</language>
    <language>Filipino</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Philippines</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Philippines">PG-13</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Philippines">16 March 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Tan, Joven</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Villamar, Helen</producer>
    <producer>Monteverde, Lily Y.</producer>
    <producer>Monteverde-Teo, Roselle</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Castañeda, Manny</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>de Guzman, Von</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chokoleit</actor>
      <role>Glory</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Confiado, Mon</actor>
      <role>Daniel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dantes, Dingdong</actor>
      <role>Rupert</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Eigenmann, Gabby</actor>
      <role>Michael</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Enriquez, Biboy</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fulgar, Kristel</actor>
      <role>Carla</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Karylle</actor>
      <role>Nina</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lapus, John</actor>
      <role>Richie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Paule, Allan</actor>
      <role>Priest</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ramirez, Biboy</actor>
      <role>Andrew</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ventosa, Archie</actor>
      <role>Mr. Mendoza</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Their dream home became a house of horror. Rupert &amp; Nina are a young, recently-married couple who couldn't be happier. He's zooming up the corporate ladder at the ad agency where he works, while she's a glowing lady who's just given birth to a beautiful baby girl. Just when they thought that things couldn't get any better, they are able to purchase a large, recently-renovated house for a price that's too good to be true. But true it is, and Rupert and Nina quickly move in together with some other relatives, including Aunt Belle, Nina's sister Carla, and brother Andrew. They're also joined by their loyal houseboy, Glory. To turn the house into a home, Nina hires flamboyant interior decorator Richie to add more elegant touches to the decades-old house, which could supposedly benefit from good feng shui. But good things seldom last. After they settle into the house, some family members glimpse the restless spirit of a pale old woman in certain rooms late at night. A swarm of flies even invades the living room one evening, as if drawn to some foul presence deep within its walls. Worried by all the alarming occurrences, Nina investigates the house's history, and is told by its previous owner Amelia that the house has a long history of malevolence and violence. Rupert's personality also begins to deteriorate. Not only does he begin to neglect his work, he also becomes obsessed with building a swimming pool beside the house. When the carpenters and workers flee the house, Rupert begins digging to make the pool himself. And what he unleashes from the digging has horrific consequences on his entire family...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?056608</url></doc>
