<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="057577">
  <docid>057577</docid>
  <title>Ball Up</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Sport</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>chicago</keyword>
    <keyword>basketball</keyword>
    <keyword>basketball-player</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <producers>
    <producer>Starkov, Bill</producer>
    <producer>Le, Courtney</producer>
    <producer>Edmonds, Tracey E.</producer>
    <producer>McQuarn, Michael</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>J, a privileged white kid from the affluent suburbs of Chicago, is a talented basketball player with the promise to become a future NBA star. However, after disgracing himself and his father while playing for his college team, he finds himself living on his own and struggling to make ends meet. When he falls behind on his rent and tries to get an advance on his paycheck, he gets into an altercation with his boss that leaves him without a job. After buying himself some time to make his rent, he tries out for the Ball Up street basketball league with the hopes of making the Chicago team and winning some money. J makes the team, though he is definitely the outsider with his proper technique and his straight-laced style of play. At first, his hard-edged teammates chide him and feel he has little to offer, but eventually they realize that they can learn something from his style of play, just as he can learn from theirs. The team goes off on the road to play in a city to city tour and showcase their talents, and J has to leave behind his new love interest, Dana. While on the road, J must face the challenges of playing competitive basketball while also dealing with the unexpected hardships in his new relationship, and he finds himself with much more on the line than he ever could have imagined.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?057577</url></doc>
