<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="057882">
  <docid>057882</docid>
  <title>Baltimore Local</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Douglas, Stephen J.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">13</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Douglas, Stephen J.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Douglas, Stephen J.</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Conny, Julia</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kelly, Robert (XX)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lombardi, Michael (III)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mccroy, Will</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Almost five years ago, three teenagers from the suburbs of Maryland had a plan. Bored with their cookie-cutter surroundings, they began seeking local musicians to perform at a monthly event at the Faith Community Methodist Church of Hamilton, MD. Now, the three are in their twenties, and bring in an average of 450 kids for each show. The bands who frequent the venue have begun to get picked up by major labels. Jaquie, Julia, and Will have provided a safe-haven for the teens in and around Baltimore; an escape from the strip malls and backyards. There's such a community between everyone involved. Bands are seen mingling with fans when not preforming, the fans are seen helping load equipment. Ranked the best local venue in all of Maryland by the Baltimore City Paper in both 2007 and 2008, St. John's Hamilton music venue is no laughing matter. The film documents this venue, and the local music community surrounding it in and around Baltimore. There's truly something interesting about St. John's Hamilton. Growing up in the scene, and attending these shows, friends are found and the process of growing up begins.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?057882</url></doc>
