<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="058976">
  <docid>058976</docid>
  <title>Bara no jujika</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>tv-mini-series</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Japanese</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Japan</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Japan">10 October 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Amami, Yuki</actor>
      <role>Aki Takahata</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Goda, Masashi</actor>
      <role>Junya Ihara</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ishida, Yuriko</actor>
      <role>Sumiko Kudo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Katsumura, Masanobu</actor>
      <role>Jin Kitamura</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mikami, Hiroshi</actor>
      <role>Togo Kudo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tamayama, Tetsuji</actor>
      <role>Kyosuke Kamiya</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tanaka, Hekikai</actor>
      <role>Seiji Takahata</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tayama, Ryousei</actor>
      <role>Mr. Sakoda</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In the prime of his career as a TV ad director, Togo finds himself at a crossroads. His wife Sumiko hasn't given him any children, and because of it his mother Sae berates her mentally for this by giving her baby presents almost everyday, whether she likes it or not. One day he meets a woman called Aki whom he mistakenly takes for a model his right-hand man Kyosuke wanted to meet for another commercial. Aki is really a career woman living with her divorced mother Yuriko and younger sister Masami, who is married and has a daughter of her own. Due to her parents' divorce, as well as a traumatic experience when she was younger, she doesn't trust men at all. Her proposal to Togo, "I don't want a relationship with you, to get married to you, or even you giving me money. All I want is for you to help me have a child," seems shocking to him. But as the problems at home and at work bear down on him, and seeing the danger Aki puts herself in contacting other men who reject her proposal, Togo eventually accepts. Nonetheless, Aki remains stern that he have no contact with her or their child, and before you know it she's flown to New York by herself for graduate study. Four years later... Aki has returned from New York and is now raising Seiji, the child she had with Togo, with help from her friends Hinako, Eri and Junya. Junya has long had a crush on Aki and thus cares for Seiji as his real son. But Togo still has the same problems that led him to Aki in the first place. Sumiko still hasn't given him any children, and the atmosphere in the Kudo house remains as tense as ever. When he sees Aki and Seiji with Junya, he realizes how much he's been missing, and decides to help them out - like it or not, he's still Seiji's father, after all. Aki eventually makes him meet Seiji, and Togo's paternal instinct is awakened, fully throwing himself into, if not caring for him all the time, at least having him always in his heart. Of course, Sumiko finds out about this, and decides to strike back. Family and friends on both sides, seeing the three's attraction as not in their best interests, will conspire to keep Aki, Seiji, and Togo apart...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?058976</url></doc>
