<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="059804">
  <docid>059804</docid>
  <title>Bargain Hunters</title>
  <year>1987</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Game-Show</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>non-fiction</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">6 July 1987</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Shaw, Jerome</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Heatter, Merrill</producer>
    <producer>Alisi, Art</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bryant, Pamela Jean</actor>
      <role>Hostess</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Goss, Dean</actor>
      <role>Announcer (1987)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tomarken, Peter</actor>
      <role>Host</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"Bargain Hunters" was on the short list of game shows which attempted to use elements of the then-relatively new medium of home-shopping network services with those of game shows. Six contestants competed in this "Price is Right" copy, wherein the object was to spot merchandise bargains. Three games were played, with two contestants playing each game: "Bargain Quiz," where contestants had to decide if a merchandise item's price was a bargain and won points based on the number of correct guesses; "Bargain Trap," where the two contestants chose prizes and tried to avoid which among the five was overpriced; and "Bargain Busters," where the contestants were shown three prices to a single item, and won points based on correct choices. The three contestants who won their respective games played the "Super Savers Round," where they were shown seven items of merchandise and had to choose the three that were the best bargains; the one choosing the prices representing the largest total bargain won all seven prizes. Throughout the show, viewers could call a special 1-800 number to order the merchandise items featured as prizes on the show.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?059804</url></doc>
