<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="060655">
  <docid>060655</docid>
  <title>Bastard</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Caro, John</editor>
    <editor>Lee, Michelle (IV)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Israel">3 June 2002</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Canada">24 October 2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">22</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Caro, John</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Caro, John</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Greenberg, Jason (I)</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>"Bastard" is a twenty-three minute documentary on illegitimacy and single mothers. The filmmaker uses his family's experiences and history to confront the negative stereotypes surrounding these topical and controversial issues. Conservative pressure groups, for example, consistently hold lone mothers responsible for a variety of social ills. The project is an experimental and personal piece originating on various film and video formats. Using interviews, archival material and video diaries, "Bastard" is a positive account of one family's healthy development without the presence of a traditional paternal figure. The central figure of the film, Patricia Caro, challanges the widely held prejudice that single mothers are irresponsible and no more than a welfare burden. Additionally, while investigating the identity of his absent father, the filmmaker questions the "common sense" belief that children raised in lone parent households are destined for a life of adversity and criminality. In general, the documentary endeavours to remind the audience that behind the generalisations and judgements passed upon single parent families, there exists a variety of individual stories that deserve to be considered on their own merits.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?060655</url></doc>
