<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="060672">
  <docid>060672</docid>
  <title>Basti</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <genres>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">8 August 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <composers>
    <composer>Sagar, Milind</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Amrapurkar, Sadashiv</actor>
      <role>Kanta</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bari, Liyaqat</actor>
      <role>Natwar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gopal, Brij</actor>
      <role>Inspector Dhamle</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gupta, Rajendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Commissioner Jabbar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kabir, Sanober</actor>
      <role>Madhu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Faisal (I)</actor>
      <role>Satish Kulkarni</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Kader (I)</actor>
      <role>Commentator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kharbanda, Kulbhushan</actor>
      <role>Karanjia</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mishra, Mamta</actor>
      <role>Pinky Kulkarni</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mohan, Ram (I)</actor>
      <role>Usmaan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Muthu, Pramod</actor>
      <role>Minister</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Namdeo, Govind</actor>
      <role>Vinayak Kulkarni (Masterji)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ranjeet</actor>
      <role>Police Commissioner</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Soni, Samir (I)</actor>
      <role>Ramesh Kulkarni (Rama)</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Bombay city's slums are due for an improvement at the hands of builder Karanjia, but a gangster, Kanta, asks for a price that is too high, leading to Karanjia recruiting Ramesh Kulkarni and some of his friends, paying them, and arming them with weapons to fight it out with Kanta's men. This leads to a gang war, and Kanta's men are subdued. Then Kanta gets together with a corrupt Minister and the Police Commissioner,and together they plan Hindu-Muslim riots, which leads to the death of Ramesh. Enraged at this, Ramesh's quiet and soft-spoken brother takes over, and the fight continues. To make matters worse, Satish's unmarried sister gets pregnant, and commits suicide. In a suicide note she indicts the Police Commissioner and the Minister who raped her. Unable to bear the loss of his son daughter, Vinayak, passes away. Satish now has arranged for three funerals in a very short while, and goes about his task of revenge ruthlessly - until he finds out that he is being used as a pawn by Karanjia - and that he is on the hit list of the police, Kanta as well as Karanjia's men - and he has no place to run nor hide.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?060672</url></doc>
