<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="062228">
  <docid>062228</docid>
  <title>Beating the Bunny</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Obremski, Carl</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">3 October 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">24</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Obremski, Carl</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Obremski, Carl</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Obremski, Carl</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Obremski, Carl</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fouse, Shelby</actor>
      <role>Galena</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Guarino, Ruth</actor>
      <role>Ruthie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lineback, Phillip</actor>
      <role>Dad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Obremski, Collin</actor>
      <role>Amos</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Beating the Bunny follows the secret life of Amos, a young man who lives under clerical parents (aka "Pastor's Kid" or "PK"). Behind the cloak of his outwardly Christian life, he suffers from an addiction to porn, shifting back and forth from the thrill of looking at naked beauties to the incredible guilt for doing so. His parents find signs of his problem, from a porno disc accidentally left in the DVD player to little naughty things in his pants pockets. But the pastor and his wife are in denial. "He's a good Christian boy. He wouldn't do anything like that." -Dad Meanwhile, Amos is haunted in his nightmares by a beautiful seductress, who upon luring him into her grasp, morphs into a giant evil pink bunny! Amos wakes up just as his face gets close enough to see the plaque formations on the rabbit's razor-sharp teeth. Watch Amos as he fights the bitter internal war of the pornography snare. You'll laugh at him. You'll cry with him. Then you'll realize that he is you. Accompany him on the nail-biting twists and turns of his adventure in Beating the Bunny.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?062228</url></doc>
