<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="063133">
  <docid>063133</docid>
  <title>Beef: The Series</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Handy, Ri-Karlo</editor>
    <editor>Reed, Gabriel</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">4 October 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">22</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Alton, Peter</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Freedman, Jared</producer>
    <producer>Takahashi, Alisha</producer>
    <producer>Banh, Trinh T.</producer>
    <producer>Jones III, Quincy</producer>
    <producer>Krause, Joshua (I)</producer>
    <producer>Bardach, Adam</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Davis, Miles (I)</composer>
    <composer>Johnson, Kodi</composer>
    <composer>Smith, Terry (X)</composer>
    <composer>Starr, Joe</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cube, Ice</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Davis, DeRay</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dogg, Snoop</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Game, The</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jay-Z</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kishino, Andrew</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>QD3 Entertainment, leaders of the Urban DVD market have partnered up with Black Entertainment Television (BET), to bring you the highly anticipated BEEF The Series. Continuing the tradition of thoughtful, unbiased and entertaining Hip Hop journalism that earned BEEF, BEEF II, and BEEF III critical and popular acclaim, comes BEEF The SERIES. Based on the multi-platinum DVD releases, BEEF The Series will continue to explore Hip Hop's most notorious beefs and resolutions while also diving into the world of sports, politics and entertainment. BEEF The Series is a new half hour show that will provide the ultimate platform for artists and prominent figures to have an open discussion on matters unresolved. With sensational stories abound in the media, BEEF The Series is an outlet where all sides can set the record straight. Through various elements including archival as well as current interviews, we hope to initiate change through dialogue and bring to our audience a greater understanding of this phenomenon. Some of the artists featured in the series will include Oprah, Snoop Dogg, Dave Chappelle, The Game, Jamie Foxx, Ice Cube, Ludacris, Jay-Z, and many more.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?063133</url></doc>
