<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="063498">
  <docid>063498</docid>
  <title>Begravelsen</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Jensen, Birger Møller</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Danish</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Denmark</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Denmark">A</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">25 February 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Denmark">15</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Bækkel, Peter</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Felding, Johanne Stryhn</producer>
    <producer>Potalivo, Christian</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Jensen, Anders Thomas</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kaas, Jeppe</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gabold, Anne-Lise</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hagen Andersen, Asta Esper</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hoffmeyer, Stig</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kaas, Jeppe</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Knop, Joachim</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kronby, Sebastian</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>On a grey winters morning a small family gathers in a church for the funeral of Jesper. Both his mother, father, grandmother, his pregnant widowed wife as well as his brother, sister in law and their son are all waiting in the church while the bells toll solemnly. As the priest begins his sermon, he is suddenly interrupted by sounds of knocking from inside the coffin. The knocking is followed by yelling, and to its great terror the small gathering now realizes that it is Jesper trying to get out. The priest faints and the family is terrified. As Henning, the father, opens the coffin with a crowbar, Jesper pops out, alive and kicking. He is miraculously arisen from the dead! - he announces in excitement to the stunned audience. But to Jespers's surprise his family doesn't quite respond to the miracle with the same enthusiasm as him. It turns out that they were all beginning to move on with their lives, and the fact that Jesper is not dead after all, doesn't really fit into their plans for the future. Actually the family finds Jesper's coming back to life rather rude and they decide to take matters in to their own hands.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?063498</url></doc>
