<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="064122">
  <docid>064122</docid>
  <title>Being Barry</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Davidson, Kayla</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Australia">13 October 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Australia">9</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Davidson, Kayla</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Phillips, Andrew J.</producer>
    <producer>Constantinou, Cleo</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Davidson, Kayla</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Apurado, Elisha</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Clyne, Spencer</actor>
      <role>The Boy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Davidson, Emmanuel (II)</actor>
      <role>The Dominatrix</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Phillips, Andrew J.</actor>
      <role>Barry</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Being Barry is a dark, skewed comedic tale of Australian suburbia. The suburbs you don't see on Australian soap opera or in glossy real estate development brochures. When you hate the soulless grind your life has become, what are the consequences? For yourself and the others around you, life can become a silent hell ... The film opens by introducing our protagonist, Barry. We meet his fish. His plant. His happiness. His wife. We discover his unusual way of dealing with the soulless grind his life has become - and the order of things he seems to both love and hate in equal measure. Barry's wife, desperate for any form of attention resorts to dangerous thoughts and attractions ... until one day it all becomes unglued. She finally takes a dramatic stand to resolve her stale, dreary life. And so does Barry. Shedding his old life like a snake sloughing its skin, Barry emerges transformed. Performing a 360-degree personality-change to rival Madonna, Barry embraces this new life with vigor. New pet. New drink. New ... boyfriend. However, the more things change, the more things stay the same - at least for Barry.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?064122</url></doc>
