<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="066335">
  <docid>066335</docid>
  <title>Best Wishes</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Birnbrower, C. Russel</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>period-piece</keyword>
    <keyword>fantasy-man</keyword>
    <keyword>fable</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">7 October 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">86</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>McClung, Joffre</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>McClung, Joffre</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>McClung, Joffre</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Caldwell, AlanKeith</actor>
      <role>Harry Baker</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carney, Damon (II)</actor>
      <role>Stan Durham/Detective</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McClung, Joffre</actor>
      <role>Peggy Durham</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Peggy Durham is a white middle class housewife with an extraordinary talent for baking. Unfortunately, neither she nor her baking, are appreciated by her husband, Stan. Peggy, however finds comfort in her fantasy life as a Film Noir femme fatale pursued by a sexy, mysterious detective, who more than makes up for what's missing in her marriage. Lucille Baker is a black waitress struggling to make ends meet. Unlike Peggy, Lucille has a wonderful husband, Harry, who not only understands and appreciates her but is always there to listen when she needs to speak her mind, which she does often! The only problem is, he's dead. BEST WISHES is the story about how two birthday wishes, made on the same night in 1958 Texas, bring these two seemingly different women together. And while their friendship, at first, allows them a safe place to be just who they are, it is eventually this friendship - and a strawberry tart - that forces them to confront the truth of who they are not. In the end, it is a story of hope and friendship and the things you can achieve if you are truly willing to have your wishes come true.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?066335</url></doc>
