<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="067543">
  <docid>067543</docid>
  <title>Beyond Purgatory</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Ausburn, Peter</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">15 January 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">6</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Ausburn, Peter</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ausburn, Peter</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ausburn, Peter</actor>
      <role>Interdimensional Traveler</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hatch, Robert (II)</actor>
      <role>Loan Officer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Salazar</actor>
      <role>Jealous Boyfriend</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This film operates on the notion of Purgatory. A young man is off on an early afternoon jog when a stray bullet hits him. The bullet originated from a house in which an altercation was taking place. One man found his friend in bed with his girlfriend. The man being cheated on fires a weapon at his friend. He misses the first time and the bullet goes out the window. This bullet hits the young man who was jogging. The next shot fired hits the friend successfully. The jogger is then seen on an escalator. This escalator is a metaphor for Purgatory. A deceased friend accompanies him on the way down. The jogger blames himself for the death of his friend. Several flashbacks explain that the deceased friend died at a houseboat party the jogger was having. The jogger was with a girl and not monitoring the copious amounts of alcohol his friend and another man at the party were drinking. The other man is a mutual friend of the jogger and the deceased man on the escalator. Another flashback shows the mutual friend blaming the jogger for the man on the escalator's death. The mutual friend (Martell) was drowning and the man on the escalator (Misha) died trying to save Martell's life. Martell maintains that if the host of the party (the jogger) had not been serving alcohol to minors and neglecting his hosting duties i.e., keeping a watchful eye on party-goers, Misha would not have died saving him.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?067543</url></doc>
