<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="067969">
  <docid>067969</docid>
  <title>Bhagwan Parshuram</title>
  <year>1970</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Mistri, Babubhai</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhattacharya, Abhi</actor>
      <role>Parshuram</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gadkar, Jayshree</actor>
      <role>Gayetri</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Helen (I)</actor>
      <role>Dancer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jeevan (I)</actor>
      <role>Bhagwan Shri Narad Muni</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Trilok (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Latkar, Sulochana</actor>
      <role>Renuka</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sapru, D.K.</actor>
      <role>Samrat</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sunder (I)</actor>
      <role>Samrat's employee</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Before Bhagwan Vishnu took an avatar (reincarnation) as Bhagwan Shri Ram, he was Bhagwan Parshuram, a revered sage, who undertook upon himself to stop all warriors and war, if force by necessary. This story depicts the birth of Parshuram, in the home of a sage, and his wife, Reunka. Together they give birth to five sons, with Parshuram being one of them. Their household and Ashram is home to the weary and the hungry, and their provider is Kamdhenu, a cow who is blessed to bestow and fulfill any wish by Renuka. One day the land's Samrat himself attends, and has a feast through Kamdhenu. After the feast the arrogant Samrat wants to buy Kamdhenu, but Renuka will not part with the cow for any amount. The Samrat returns home, angry and swears to avenge this humiliation. The sage is upset with Renuka and suspects her fidelity, and calls upon his sons to behead her. None of the sons is able to carry out this task, but Parshuram does so, thus proving that duty comes before everyone. Bhagwan Shiv is impressed with this, and asks the Sage to restore the life of his wife and his sons, which he does. Parshuram, now armed with an axe, goes on to complete the task his birth was for - to stop all wars. He meets with the Samrat's daughter, Gayetri, and both fall in love. This angers the Samrat, and in rage he kills Gayetri. Parshuram is enraged and strikes the Samrat dead, and carries on with his life of bringing peace on Earth. His next encounter with Gayetri will be when she is re-born as Sita, and is in the process of marrying Bhagwan Shri Ram, none other than another avtar of Bhagwan Vishnu</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?067969</url></doc>
