<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="068032">
  <docid>068032</docid>
  <title>Bhairav</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>witness-for-the-prosecution</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">A</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Prasad, T.L.V.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Siraj, Liyaqat</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Sodhi, Surendra Singh</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Birje, Hemant</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chakraborty, Mithun</actor>
      <role>Bhairav/Rakesh Pandey</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gaud, Jack</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gopal, Brij</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Haldar, Indrani</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Issar, Puneet</actor>
      <role>Jindal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Razak</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Madhura</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Rakesh Pandey belongs to a middle-class family, and is employed. One day when he is returning home from work, he is arrested by the police on the charge of killing a woman in cold-blood. He refutes and denies this charge, but to no avail, as the prosecution produces witness after witness that have actually seen him commit this heinous crime. Ultimately, the court convicts him, and sentences him to several years in jail. After serving his time, Rakesh returns to his family home, and finds that his house has been destroyed in a fire, and his parents killed. Rakesh then finds out that the person behind this outrage is a wealthy industrialist by the name of Jindal. The reason why Jindal chose to destroy and kill all the Pandeys was that the person killed by Rakesh was none other than Jindal's brother. Rakesh vows to avenge this outrage, and assumes the name of Bhairav, not realizing that he has an uphill task, and that all the odds are stacked against him, including the fact that the witness who testified against him is Mrs. Jindal.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?068032</url></doc>
