<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="068009">
  <docid>068009</docid>
  <title>Bhagyawan</title>
  <year>1994</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Rajendran, A.R.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">1994</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Subash, S.K.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Jha, Upendra</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Pandey, Kamlesh</writer>
    <writer>Rathod, Keshav</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Chitragupth, Anand</composer>
    <composer>Chitragupth, Milind</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chaddha, Suraj</actor>
      <role>Kishan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chadha, Ajay</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chawla, Juhi</actor>
      <role>Geeta</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Govinda</actor>
      <role>Inspector Amar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Imran, Master</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Irani, Aruna</actor>
      <role>Renu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kiran, Shashi (I)</actor>
      <role>Alka's Ex</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Komal, Baby</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Kirti</actor>
      <role>Vishwas</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Leo, Peter</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lever, Johnny</actor>
      <role>Jhoney</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Manmauji</actor>
      <role>Havaldar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mansoor (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pran (I)</actor>
      <role>Dhanraj</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pukhraj</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Raj, K.K.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ranjeet</actor>
      <role>Hira</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Romani, Taabish</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Singh, Gurbachchan</actor>
      <role>Rana</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A poor mill worker, Dhanraj, finds out that his sister, Pushpa, is pregnant, and that the man responsible for this is his boss, Hira. He goes there to get him to marry her, only to be told to get his sister an abortion. Unable to bear this shame, she kills herself, and Dhanraj swears to avenge her death. Hira fires Dhanraj, leaving him, his wife, two sons and a daughter destitute and on the verge of starvation. Deciding to kill himself and his family, he takes them on an outing at Chowpatty, and there he mixes poison in some snacks and takes them to his family. On the way, a small boy steals the food. Dhanraj catches up to this boy, and takes the food away from him, and disposes it off. He finds that this small boy has a winning lottery ticket. He rejoices, tells this good news to his family, and adopts the boy, who is now his goodluck charm. Thereafter they live a very comfortable life. Years later, all of Dhanraj's children, Renu, Vishwas, and Kishan have grown up alongwith the boy, Amar, who is now a police inspector. Renu and Vishwas are married, and Amar and Kishan will soon be married too. Kishan gets married to Hira's daughter, and Amar marries a petty thief, Geeta. Things don't go quite well in this household, as money is being embezzled; and then Vishwas' wife blames Amar of sexually molesting her, forcing Amar and Geeta to leave the house. Dhanraj has always considered Amar a goodluck charm for this house, feels vulnerable and open to attacks. And his perceptiveness gives fruit when Vishwas and his wife decide to leave this house and live separately, and it is on the very same day that Dhanraj is arrested for marketing suprious drugs, and the arresting officer is none other than Inspector Amar.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?068009</url></doc>
