<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="068297">
  <docid>068297</docid>
  <title>Bhola Bhala</title>
  <year>1978</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Glaad, B.S.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">U</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">25 April 1978</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Satpal (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Krishna, V. Gopi</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Kalekar, Madhusudan</writer>
    <writer>Pant, Ramesh</writer>
    <writer>Sharma, V.K.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Burman, Rahul Dev</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arora, Harbans Darshan M.</actor>
      <role>Villager with red turban</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Begum, Mumtaz</actor>
      <role>Ram's Mother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chatterjee, Moushumi</actor>
      <role>Renu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chicoo, Master</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deo, Ramesh</actor>
      <role>Thakur Ajit Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dutt, Uma</actor>
      <role>Lala Phoolchand</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gopal, V.</actor>
      <role>Khalifa</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Irani, Aruna</actor>
      <role>Nathu Singh's wife</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jagdeep</actor>
      <role>Tamanchewala</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jankidas</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Pinchoo</actor>
      <role>General Manager of Jeevan Beema Co.</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Satyendra</actor>
      <role>Mr. Kapoor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Kader (I)</actor>
      <role>Nathiya</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khanna, Rajesh</actor>
      <role>Ram Kumar Verma/Nathu 'Nathiya' Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Latkar, Sulochana</actor>
      <role>Renu's Mother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mehra, Raj</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moolchand</actor>
      <role>Seth</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rao, Maruti (II)</actor>
      <role>T.C.</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shelly, Joginder</actor>
      <role>Sambha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Thakkar, Sudhir</actor>
      <role>D.I.G.</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Verma, Deven</actor>
      <role>Babu Khan</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Ram Kumar Verma (Rajesh Khanna) is an honest albeit unsuccessful Insurance Agent. His poor performance and a quick settlement for Renu (Moushumi Chatterjee) and her mom (Sulochana) gets him transferred to Madhya Pradesh. During the train journey he comes across Nathu Singh (also Rajesh Khanna with dubbed voice of Kader Khan), and thinging that Nathu is an emperor of sorts, gets him to insure himself for Rs.5 lakhs, to which Nathu Singh agrees. Ram Verma returns to his company and is heartily congratulated by his Manager (Satyen Kappu) and the General Manager (Pinchoo Kapoor) even throws a party for Ram. Subsequently, the Manager realizes that the person Ram has insured is actually a wanted dacait and thug commonly known as Daku Nathiya, wanted by the police dead or alive. Fearing the collapse of the insurance company, the Manager coerces Ram to return to Madhya Pradesh and get Nathiya to cancel his insurance policy. Ram, in the interest of the insurance company, readily agrees and on the way to meet Nathiya, ends up saving Nathiya's son from a burning house, thus earning Nathiya's and his woman, Champa's (Rekha) gratitude. Ram finds out that Nathiya was otherwise known as Nathu Singh, a honest villager, with a beautiful wife (Aruna Irani), and a son Chander. A rich village lord, Thakur Ajit Singh (Ramesh Deo), rapes and kills Nathu's wife, and as Nathu is unable to get justice, he turns into Nathiya, the dacait. Ram only wants Nathiya to cancel the policy, so that he can return home, and promises not to inform the police. Nathiya agrees to cancel the insurance policy and let Ram return home. But Sambha (Joginder) is not pleased with the favors being showered on Ram and rebels, and forces Nathiya to keep Ram prisoner. When Nathiya is injured, Champa asks Ram to bring in a medical doctor, and Ram brings Renu, and ultimately both Ram and Renu are also held by Sambha, while Nathiya lies unconsicious. Meanwhile the police have launched a dragnet to capture Nathiya dead of alive. Will Ram and Renu return home to Ram's mother and sister, Sarla (Heena Kauser) and his best friend Babu Khan (Deven Verma)? Will Nathiya and Champa survive the police dragnet?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?068297</url></doc>
