<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="068376">
  <docid>068376</docid>
  <title>Bhupathi</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kanusurya, Damodar</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Kannada</language>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Govind, S.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kavya (II)</producer>
    <producer>Kukreja, Mohan</producer>
    <producer>Shreyas (II)</producer>
    <producer>Spurthy</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Govind, S.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Krishna, V. Hari</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ashwath</actor>
      <role>Bhupathi's grandfather</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kishore (XV)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rishi, Mukesh</actor>
      <role>Chief Minister</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tugudeep, Darshan</actor>
      <role>Bhupathi 'Guru Bhai'</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Dr. Anita works in a hospital, lives a wealthy lifestyle in Mumbai, and is the only child of the state Chief Minister, a widower. One day while rescuing a child, she herself is rescued by a male on a motorbike. She finds out that this male is Bhupathi, who lives a wealthy lifestyle in Malad along with his widowed mother, paternal grandfather, sister, Jijaji, and niece. He is also a modern-day Robin Hood, referred to as 'Guru Bhai', and is feared and respected by everyone. Both continue meeting and eventually fall in love with each other. Anita is introduced to the rest of his family and all approve of her. When Bhupathi's grandfather approaches the Chief Minister to let the couple wed, he is humiliated. When Anita persists, he consents to and does meet with Bhupathi but makes it clear that he has always catered to Anita's whims and fancies, like buying her an imported car as well as a pedigreed dog, and wants Bhupathi to be added to his daughter's collection, but Bhupathi rebukes him, and the Chief Minister, together with Bhanuprasad, a member of the opposition political party, assaults Bhupathi's mother and niece, leaving Bhupathi with no choice but to seek vengeance on the Chief Minister, a move that will pit him against the system, and also alienate him from Anita.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?068376</url></doc>
