<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="068530">
  <docid>068530</docid>
  <title>Biale malzenstwo</title>
  <year>1992</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>based-on-play</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Polish</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Poland</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">105</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Lazarkiewicz, Magdalena</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Lazarkiewicz, Magdalena</writer>
    <writer>Rózewicz, Jan</writer>
    <writer>Rózewicz, Tadeusz</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kaczmarek, Jan A.P.</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bista, Henryk</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Borsuk, Danuta</actor>
      <role>Cyganka</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Budzisz-Krzyzanowska, Teresa</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Englert, Jan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fraszynska, Jolanta</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lulek, Tomasz</actor>
      <role>Officer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Opania, Bartosz</actor>
      <role>Beniamin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wójcicki, Jacek</actor>
      <role>Singer</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Evening. Two contemporary teenage girls, Blanca and Pauline, living in an old manor house, are watching a television programme about the sexual life of people and of animals. Surprised by Bianca's father who returns late at night they quickly change channels. The film they see made up of old archive footage, is the beginning of their journey into the past. The same manor house, the same room, the same girls, but in another time. Bianca and Paulina are totally immersed in problems associated with puberty and reaching adulthood. Blanca is sensitive with a "poetic nature," shocked at the role that tradition has mapped out for her, terrified by the marriage which is being planned for her. Marriage with Benjamin - a very immature young man for whom she has no feelings. Pauline is an extrovert, well adapted to face every situation, who accepts ironically the amorous advances made by Grandfather who even at his advanced age can't control the waves of lust that rage in his ancient body. In addition Pauline is jealous about Benjamin, who isn't her beau. Then there's father - a womanizer, and Blanca's mother, unhappy in her maternal role. Then Aunt, widowed too early, in whom there burn untold passions. All these people pay scant attention to Bianca and her phobias which are the result of her great sensitivity and from disturbing experiences she had as a child... Blanca isn't in a position to assume the role that her surroundings have earmarked for her. Her escape into a world of fantasy can't cure her either... Her fears push her towards madness when she comes to realize that she won't be able to fulfill her aim of preserving her purity, that a "marriage blanc" is impossible.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?068530</url></doc>
