<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="069171">
  <docid>069171</docid>
  <title>Big Brother</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>disfigurement</keyword>
    <keyword>beautiful-woman</keyword>
    <keyword>acid-burning</keyword>
    <keyword>acid-attack</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">February 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Dhanoa, Guddu</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Dhanoa, Guddu</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Anand, Anand Raj</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chopra, Priyanka</actor>
      <role>Aarti D. Gandhi/Aarti D. Sharma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Denzongpa, Danny</actor>
      <role>Police Commissioner Kudheshwar Negi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deol, Sunny (I)</actor>
      <role>Devdhar S. 'Deva' Gandhi/Devdhar Sharma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gill, Avtar</actor>
      <role>Advocate Nathani</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jalal, Farida</actor>
      <role>Sitadevi S. Gandhi/Sitadevi S. Sharma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Shahbaaz</actor>
      <role>Rajji Pandey</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Prachi</actor>
      <role>Anjali S. Gandhi/Anjali Sharma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shinde, Sayaji</actor>
      <role>Baburao 'Bhau' Kamble</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>S.P. Sharma lives a middle-class lifestyle in Delhi, India, along with his wife, and son, Devdhar. His wife passes away, and Sharma re-marries Sitadevi when Devdhar is only 3 years of age. Sita cares for him as if he were her own, even after giving birth to a son, Akash, and daughter, Anjali. Now Sharma has passed away, while all 3 children have matured. Devdhar gets married to Aarti. Anjali is seduced by the son of the Home Minister, Manohar Shinde, and has acid thrown on her face, disfiguring her. An enraged Devdhar kills the culprit, abducts a number of men who have raped and burned their daughter-in-laws, and secures enough money to pay for plastic surgery for Anjali, whose face is eventually restored. Devdhar and his men are now feared by everyone in Delhi, so much so that Prime Minister Urmila asks Manohar to tender his resignation, publicly denounce his son, and re-locate to Bombay, which he does. She also asks Police Commissioner Kudheshwar Negi to apprehend the Gandhi family. Before Negi could take any action, Sita and her family re-locate to Bombay, change their last name to Sharma, where Devdhar &amp; his men make a living driving an auto-rickshaw, while Anjali and Akash continue their education. Six years later Negi is now the Police Commissioner of Bombay, while Manohar is now the Deputy Chief Minister - and both are now planning to do away with the entire Gandhi family - with the help of former jailbird, Baburao Kamble alias Bhau, who has several personal scores to settle with Devdhar.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?069171</url></doc>
