<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="071354">
  <docid>071354</docid>
  <title>Bintou in Paris</title>
  <year>1995</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Massiot, Frédéric</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>medicine</keyword>
    <keyword>koran</keyword>
    <keyword>france</keyword>
    <keyword>argument</keyword>
    <keyword>paris-france</keyword>
    <keyword>female-circumcision</keyword>
    <keyword>female-genital-mutilation</keyword>
    <keyword>fear</keyword>
    <keyword>health</keyword>
    <keyword>social-problem</keyword>
    <keyword>parent</keyword>
    <keyword>excision</keyword>
    <keyword>africa</keyword>
    <keyword>women's-studies</keyword>
    <keyword>qur'an</keyword>
    <keyword>gender-roles</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">15</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Johnson, Kirsten (II)</director>
    <director>Pimsleur, Julia</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Pimsleur, Julia</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Johnson, Kirsten (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Hebrail, Jean</composer>
    <composer>Kidjo, Angélique</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>The film concerns female excision which has long been a practice in various African cultures and has taken a variety of forms. In those European countries and more recently in the United States, which has seen a rise in immigration from formerly inaccessible areas of Africa, the term "female genital mutilation" or "excision" and it's practice by newly transplanted Africans within the context of European and American society, culture and law, has become contested ground. Anthropologists, many of whom have long been aware of the practice, are finding themselves in the center of the debate. BINTOU IN PARIS is an excellent introduction to the theme as we are able to understand the complex mix of the pressure to adhere to tradition, while dealing with the desires of a younger generation infused with a sense of female emancipation to conform to the roles and demands of a new culture with new laws and protections. While the film is acted, the inter familial relationships ring true, as do the circumstances the film constructs. The film enhances our understanding of a volatile topic without resorting to horrific images or descriptions.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?071354</url></doc>
