<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="071740">
  <docid>071740</docid>
  <title>Birds of a Feather</title>
  <year>2000</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Tane, Brian</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2000</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">15</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Smith, Terrence (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Smith, Terrence (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Blasso, Jason</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>DeRenzo, Thomas</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cooke, Chris (I)</actor>
      <role>Henry</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Il Grande, Daniela</actor>
      <role>Mary</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McGee, Ted</actor>
      <role>Carl</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Mary is convinced that her husband Henry is trying to kill her! For the last few days he changed a lot and became aggressive, shouting obscenities and menacing her. Mary found comfort in the hands of Carl, the husband of her friend Dolores who happens to be out on vacation. After Henry leaves for god knows where, Mary calls Carl and asks him to come by, which he agreed to do as he was aware that she is frightened. A few minutes later the door bell rings but its not Carl but his wife Dolores. It looks like she decided to come back sooner. Dolores can see that things aren't looking great for Mary but Mary don't wanna say anything. She finally does tell Dolores who's seem kinda surprise that her husband is part of this whole story. Henry then returns who decided to come back and make dinner for Mary and Dolores and to forget about his obnoxious behavior. Carl hasn't made it yet and Mary gets suspicious to where he is. But Dolores assure her that he will be there. He brings dinner home as the meal is a shocking surprise!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?071740</url></doc>
