<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="071906">
  <docid>071906</docid>
  <title>Birthright Israel</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Belman, Mitch</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">26 November 2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">44</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Godfrey, Rena</director>
    <director>Pearl, Leonard</director>
    <director>Szpindel, Isaac</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Godfrey, Rena</producer>
    <producer>Pearl, Leonard</producer>
    <producer>Szpindel, Isaac</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Godfrey, Rena</writer>
    <writer>Pearl, Leonard</writer>
    <writer>Szpindel, Isaac</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>In an unprecedented effort to stem the tide of assimilation and reconnect Jewish young adults to their heritage, the "birthright israel" program was initiated by a group of North American philanthropists in partnership with Jewish communities of the world-wide. This initiative offers Jewish young adults between the ages of 18-26 who have never been to Israel, a free 10 day trips to that country. Participants come from all over the world and from a wide range of religious and cultural Jewish backgrounds. The birthright israel documentary focuses on the Canadian participants in this trip. In 2000 and 2001 more than two thousand Jewish young adults from across Canada traveled to Israel to participate in the birthright Israel program. The participants were taken to see both Israeli and Arab historical landmarks. They experienced the hospitality of the Israeli and Arab people, and participated in programs including interactive lectures, cultural activities and outdoor excursions. 12 Tribes Productions was there to capture the life changing experiences, gained friendships and the spiritual epiphanies encountered by the birthright participants as they came in contact with the different peoples, cultures and histories of Israel for the first time.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?071906</url></doc>
