<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="072754">
  <docid>072754</docid>
  <title>Black Cat</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Canada">14A</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">85</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Rodnunsky, Serge</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Rodnunsky, Serge</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Erickson, Shawna</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jones, Philip (XI)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kurtz, Shaun</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Leon, Stephanie (II)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sandberg, Logan</actor>
      <role>Police Officer</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"Black Cat" is a provocative tale of psychological horror based on the famous short story by Edgar Allan Poe. Detective Eleanor Wyman is investigating Jack in the mysterious disappearance of his wife Mira and son Jonathan. Eleanor probes Jack's tormented mind as he remembers the gaze of the Black Cat and the horror that brought him to bury an Axe in his wife's brain. But in this modern revisiting of the classic tale we ask - is it in fact Jack who has done the deed or some other manifestation of his tormented soul? As Eleanor teases out the bloody tale from Jack under blistering interrogation, she becomes so engrossed in the story that she soon is dazed into believing she is somehow tied into the plot. Eleanor has now lost her barring in her own investigation. Under the spell of the Black Cat she has become the suspect and the detective. She questions her sanity and the violent actions she might take to protect her reputation and sanity. Who knows who is capable of murder when under the curse of the BLACK CAT.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?072754</url></doc>
