<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="073020">
  <docid>073020</docid>
  <title>Black Girl</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Snead, Debra</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>chicago</keyword>
    <keyword>urban-setting</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">7 June 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">27</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Roper, Archie</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Roper, Archie</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Diederich, Collin</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Christopher, Anthony Pierre</actor>
      <role>Ebony's Father</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Davis, Angela (III)</actor>
      <role>Tammy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Polk, Alaysia</actor>
      <role>Ebony</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"Black Girl" is loosely based on a true story of a young inner city girl that comes from a troubled household. The lead character Ebony, is nine years old and is the oldest of three with two younger brothers Kevin and Poo. Ebony's father is dead and her mother Tammy is a drug addict and hardly takes care of her three children. Tammy's addiction has caused her to neglect her children in unimaginable ways. However, there is a person in Ebony life that picks up on her odd behavior at school and wants to understand the root of Ebony's problems. Helen, a school counselor wants to interview and help not only Ebony but the family as well. Like so many other families in this position help does not come in time. Ebony is left to fin for herself and her two younger brothers while her mother ruins any chance of the family become a productive part of society. After Ebony shares too much of her life with the school counselor she is brutally beating by Tammy. In the throws of her anger Tammy realizes that her life is out of control and seeks help. After attending rehab meetings for a while Tammy's past catches up with her just when you think her life is getting better. A tragic tale of violence, gangs, drugs, and neglect happens in a blink of an eye.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?073020</url></doc>
