<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="076380">
  <docid>076380</docid>
  <title>Blue Jean Fantasy</title>
  <year>1998</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adult</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>nudity</keyword>
    <keyword>sexual-fantasy</keyword>
    <keyword>gay-sex</keyword>
    <keyword>sex</keyword>
    <keyword>porn</keyword>
    <keyword>homosexual</keyword>
    <keyword>hardcore</keyword>
    <keyword>erotica</keyword>
    <keyword>gay-interest</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1998</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Alfaro, Ishmael</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Granado, Ernesto (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grand, Max</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A rugged hiker narrates the story of meeting the handsome Bill while exploring a ghost town. After a few beers, despite his attraction to the stranger, he panics when Bill attempts to kiss him. Bill promises to leave a calling card should the hiker ever come back looking for him. Weeks later, the hiker returns and finds Bill s blue jeans - stimulating a series of intense fantasies leading him to accept his sexual identity and search for the jeans owner. Adult star Max Grand stars in the first vignette, where two strangers meet on the cracked plains of the desert and share a bath that sends both into ecstasy! Next, a hunky gardener s employer invites his drenched handyman inside and offers to dry his jeans, while they share a passionate shower. Finally, a dark and tattooed painter seduces his model by transferring the erotic designs on his canvas to the model s bare skin! Each fantasy burns hotter than the last for the hiker - who eventually leaves his own calling card on the jeans and heads out to find the man who awakened his true sexual nature. Each scene will change the way you look at denim forever. Stuff all your stockings with a BLUE JEANS FANTASY!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?076380</url></doc>
