<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="078254">
  <docid>078254</docid>
  <title>Bolsa de huesos y recuerdos</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Salem, Khaled</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>huesos</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Turkey">2 May 2006</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Slovenia">2 September 2005</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="France">27 June 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="France">7</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Ciliberto, Beatriz</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Arellano, Jeronimo</producer>
    <producer>Bieberach, Irina</producer>
    <producer>Ciliberto, Beatriz</producer>
    <producer>Rogero, Elena</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Ciliberto, Beatriz</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Ellis, Nesta Wyn</composer>
    <composer>Snøve, Erik</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cambell, Kate</actor>
      <role>Juliette</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lopez, Marcos (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>del Barco, Mariano</actor>
      <role>Theater Owner</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Alicia 53 years old, is in her dressing room getting ready to give a show, her table is full of make-up a yellow light illuminates her face, her hands are full of age marks. She observes every wrinkle in her face. Someone knocks the door. She exists. Walks thought a long corridor, as in the background we can hear people laughing, and some ambience music. As she gets closer the music invades her ears. Alicia gets on stage; the light separates her from the audience. She takes the microphones and starts to sing, with sadness on her face. The light between her and the audience's dimes down. She returns to her dressing room in a hurry, she stops at the doors as she sees in front of her table a young women getting ready, Alicia looks at her, and then enters grabs a bag with her belongings and exits. Outside the theater, Alicia is sitting on the floor, with her bag, drinking whiskey directly form the bottle. A couple exits the theater; the young women from the dressing room stand in from of Alicia looking at her with disgrace. Alicia stands up and walks away from the theater.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?078254</url></doc>
