<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="079389">
  <docid>079389</docid>
  <title>Boond</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Verma, Sanjay (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Mahshar, Inayat</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Ajmeri, Asad</writer>
    <writer>Khan, Jaanam</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Liyaqat (II)</composer>
    <composer>Prasanna, Rajendara</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Berry, Navin</actor>
      <role>Anha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Berry, Pankaj</actor>
      <role>John</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Birbal</actor>
      <role>Hariya</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dalvi, Sudhir</actor>
      <role>Neelam's maternal uncle</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dhawan, Siddharth</actor>
      <role>Advocate Sagar Saxena</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gupta, Narendra</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Joshi, Mohan</actor>
      <role>Dhanna</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Mushtaq</actor>
      <role>Lallan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kiran, Prema</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kishan, Ravi</actor>
      <role>Vikram 'Vicky' Malhotra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Manmauji</actor>
      <role>Kalwa</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mohit, Ankush</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nagrath, Anil</actor>
      <role>Suryakant Ahuja</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rajda, Mulraj</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rizvi Jarehavi, Javed</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>After the passing of her parents, Mumbai-based Neelam lives a poor lifestyle with her ailing maternal uncle, and is employed as a Typist with Suryakant Ahuja, who wants her for himself. When she refuses, he hires a pimp, Lallan, to coerce her, initially to no avail, but subsequently financial worries, to pay for medicines for her uncle and hospitalized boyfriend, Vikram Malhotra (whose friends gang-raped her), compel her to accept money and become a call-girl. Vikram recovers and relocates to live in London along with his mother, while her uncle passes away. Alone and destitute she is rescued by some slum dwellers and starts to live in a concrete pipe, making a living as a prostitute. She catches the eye of local gangster and extortionist, Anha, and agrees to be his mistress if he stops collecting Haftas from the community. Anha does agree but another extortionist, Dhanna, moves in on this vacated territory. A confrontation ensues and Anha is killed. The Police arrest Neelam for possession of narcotics and a lawyer, Sagar Saxena, impressed by her honesty and literacy, comes to her rescue, and gets her acquitted. She moves in with him and both fall in love with each other. He proposes marriage to her despite of her background, and she accepts. On the day of the marriage she comes across a newspaper article - and it is this article that will separate her from Sagar, and change her life forever.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?079389</url></doc>
