<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="079670">
  <docid>079670</docid>
  <title>Border City Rustlers</title>
  <year>1953</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Currier, Richard C.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Western</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>horse</keyword>
    <keyword>wild-bill-hickok</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">15 November 1953</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>McDonald, Frank (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Broidy, William F.</producer>
    <producer>Barry, Wesley</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Raynor, William (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Alper, Murray</actor>
      <role>Kirby</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bice, Robert (I)</actor>
      <role>Branton</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Devine, Andy (I)</actor>
      <role>Jingles</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Eldredge, George</actor>
      <role>Judge</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Evans, Douglas</actor>
      <role>Grogan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Griffith, Billy (I)</actor>
      <role>Jenkins</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Johns, Larry</actor>
      <role>Collins</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lewis, George J.</actor>
      <role>Ramon</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Madison, Guy</actor>
      <role>Wild Bill Hickok</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pendleton, Steve (I)</actor>
      <role>Larson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Turner, Don (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>von Schiller, Carl</actor>
      <role>Chief Marshal</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In 1953 in the United States, there were more homes without television sets than there were with, so William F. Broidy's Newhall Productions would paste two of the 30-minute episodes of The Wild Bill Hickok TV series together and Allied Artists would sell it as a 60-minute feature to theatres. The first half of "Border City Rustlers" is from an unknown-to-me episode (I was one of the citizens who didn't have a TV set in 1953) in which Wild Bill (Guy Madison) and his deputy Jingles P. Jones (Andy Devine) arrive in Green Springs just after the mayor has been killed in a gun battle. The town's Old Maid, Hepsibah (Isabel Randolph), stirs up the other townswomen and is elected mayor. Wild Bill and Jingles help her prove that the local judge (George Eldredge) is behind the town's reign of terrorism. Wild and Jingles saddle up and ride over to Border City (from the episode called "Border City")to mix it up with a gang of international cattle rustlers where, helped by Consuelo (Gloria Talbot), daughter of a Mexican cattle baron, and her cousin Ramon (George J. Lewis), the two marshals nab cattle buyer Flint Kirby (Murray Alper) as the head of the rustlers. Those of us who didn't have TV sets figured Wild Bill and Jingles were twice as good as the usual western heroes as they only took half the usual time to clean up a situation. No, we really didn't. One didn't have to have a telly to figure out these were on-the-cheap productions. The cast order in the theatre-released films is not the same as that shown on the original TV episodes, as Newhall Productions and/or Allied Artists would crunch both casts together to get the better-known names closer to the top.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?079670</url></doc>
