<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="079785">
  <docid>079785</docid>
  <title>Borealis</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Wolf, Frank (V)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Canada">G</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">19 May 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">20 February 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">63</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Wolf, Frank (V)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Wolf, Frank (V)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Baldwin, Grant</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hokoyama, Taku</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wolf, Frank (V)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>From Portage and Main in downtown Winnipeg to the family cottage near Parry Sound in Ontario, filmmaker Frank Wolf and his inexperienced friend Taku Hokoyama tackle raging rapids and grueling portages on a 3,100 km canoe trip through Canada's Boreal forest in an effort to shed light on the issues now facing the wilderness area. The Boreal Wilderness is a massive swath of forest that lies just north of the Canada-US border. It contains 25 % of the world's remaining ancient forest and is globally significant in its ability to filter water, keep carbon levels in check, and operate as a species habitat. Manitoba and Ontario are home to the largest intact forest area. The remote location has kept it safe for many years, but current interest from the forestry, hydro, and mining industries now threatens the sanctity of the forest. Deeply committed to their mission and message but never didactic, Frank and Taku, with their offbeat sense of humor, provide an intimate look into the current environmental and social issues facing the region. This is not a typical nature documentary, however. Our amiable guides cope with bears, black flies and flat tires in order to educate and entertain us over the course of their 75-day adventure.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?079785</url></doc>
