<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="082105">
  <docid>082105</docid>
  <title>Break the Bank</title>
  <year>1985</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Game-Show</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>non-fiction</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Kline, Richard S.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kline, Richard S.</producer>
    <producer>Cox, Gary (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Lloyd, Rob</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Farago, Joe (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself/Host (1985-1986)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hanks, Michael</actor>
      <role>Himself/Announcer (1985-1986)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rayburn, Gene</actor>
      <role>Himself/Host (1985)</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Two couples competed in a game similar to Super Password. The host would read a question whose answer was a clue to a puzzle. Six clues, each more revealing than the last, were given to the puzzle. Each correct clue earned the winning team more time to use in the bonus round should they reach it. The team to solve two puzzles first played the bizarre bonus round, which involved completing different stunts at different stations to earn Bank Cards. One stunt per week was manned by a celebrity or celebrities. After time expired the team used their bank cards to see if they had found the one special card that would "Break the Bank" which won them a growing jackpot of cash and prizes. The stunt bonus round was eventually replaced and the format changed completely. In the second format, the two couples played the puzzle round for money. The team that solved $2000 worth of puzzles first played a special puzzle round to determine how many bank cards they would take in the vault. Each card was worth a prize, although some cards could forfeit all prizes won to that point. One special card still "Broke the Bank" of cash and prizes.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?082105</url></doc>
