<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="082217">
  <docid>082217</docid>
  <title>Breakin' 'Em In!</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>paddle</keyword>
    <keyword>male-nudity</keyword>
    <keyword>hand</keyword>
    <keyword>hair-brush</keyword>
    <keyword>spanking</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">February 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">58</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anthony (X)</actor>
      <role>Spankee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Black, Rick (II)</actor>
      <role>Spanker</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brian (VII)</actor>
      <role>Spankee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Leroy (VII)</actor>
      <role>Spankee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pookie</actor>
      <role>Spankee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sterne, Jeff (II)</actor>
      <role>Spanker</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Once again, four rascal boys are 'broken in' to a more disciplined life by resounding posterior discipline designed to break their ill will, if not their butt in the agonizing process. First Anthony, who broke in to Jeff Sterne's bedroom, is stripped and bend over the bed for a smashing lesson, hand-spanked red and raw only to find it gets even worse when the hair-brush proves its hardwood is unbreakable however hard and often it hits his holler-sore hide (9:13 min). When Brian loses a coin-flip with his ass literally at stake, Rick Black has him strip to his boxers and bend over the couch for an elaborate hand-spanking, then bares his butt for the next installment and finishes him off stark-naked over the knee (15:40). In the third episode, Pookie (from Boys Will Be Boys, when he went over Jeffs knee) is visiting but physically bumps into Rick Black, who doesn't hesitate to prove he's just as capable of making him as sorry as his gradually bared behind is rendered sore by hand and ping-pong bat which doubles as an effective paddle (17:30). Finally neighborhood boy Leroy who plays peeping Tom all around is caught jerking off in the bushes by Jeff Sterne, who does such a good job heating up his quivering naked arse that the squirt runs off as soon as released, still wearing nothing but his socks (11:52).</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?082217</url></doc>
