<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="082362">
  <docid>082362</docid>
  <title>Breaking the Barrier</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Katz, Jennifer (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">4 April 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">72</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Dawson, Kate (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Dawson, Kate (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Ditzian, Jason</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Steiner, Sid</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This feature-length film chronicles the 26-year-old's struggle to be the best in the world, and right now he's fighting a tough battle. Sid's struggling with life on the road. A cowboy's life isn't easy, and there are times over the past few months when Steiner wasn't sure he could continue. He recently found out he will be a first-time father early next year, a revelation that weighs heavy on his mind. While he contemplates his future in rodeo, Sid is besieged with phone calls from all media types; they're all hoping to record a piece of the "Dennis Rodman of rodeo." Executives at Wrangler hope he'll jump-start their waning youth market. A trailer-maker from Texas promises to build Sid a vehicle to haul horses and his trademark Harley to horse shows. Fans wait in long lines to meet "Sid Rock," an inspiration to a generation just beginning to realize the value of rodeo. Sid feels the double-edged sword of stardom. "Breaking the Barrier" documents the internal struggle of a true cowboy who wants to do right by a sport he loves, but feels a strong dedication to his parents and budding new family. The story has no third person narrator. It will be told in the words of all those we interview to make sure every sentence rings true. The exciting and fascinating world of rodeo provides the perfect backdrop - one that will keep the attention of an audience who likely has never been exposed to the cowboy way.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?082362</url></doc>
