<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="082761">
  <docid>082761</docid>
  <title>Brian Lehrer Live</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Talk-Show</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">5 April 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Walker, Adam (V)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Smith, Alan (XXXII)</producer>
    <producer>Colgan, Jim</producer>
    <producer>McGovern, Nuala</producer>
    <producer>Goldensohn, Marty</producer>
    <producer>Tutschulte, Derek</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lehrer, Brian (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Brian Lehrer, the popular host of WNYC, New York Public Radio's "The Brian Lehrer Show," hosts a live, hour-long weekly television program on CUNY TV. "Just like my WNYC show, we'll be trying to get at the truth about life and politics in New York City, and give regular New Yorkers a voice through live call-ins and e-mail," said Lehrer. "We'll be providing direct access to mayoral hopefuls and other major news-makers, and doing New York television's only `open phones' call-ins. We'll also invite people to send in photos and original videos that say something meaningful about life in New York today. And, as on the radio, we'll find our ways to sneak in some fun!" The program is cablecast in New York City on Wednesdays from 7: 30 p.m. to 8:30 p.m., and is simulcast live and archived on-line at www.cuny.tv. To interact with guests and offer your opinion about topics discussed on the show, call (212) 251-0801 or email brian@cuny.tv. "I listen to Brian Lehrer... Wow, I love that guy. I love the show." - Jon Stewart (in a speech at a New Yorker Magazine forum) "Usually a pretty fair and smart guy" - Bill O'Reilly (on his show) "You are it. You are the man." - Thomas Friedman (on "The Brian Lehrer Show")</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?082761</url></doc>
