<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="084379">
  <docid>084379</docid>
  <title>Brother's Keeper</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Caradonna, Michael</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Caradonna, Michael</producer>
    <producer>Ciarfalio, Carl</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Caradonna, Michael</writer>
    <writer>Davis, Jennifer Elizabeth</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Davis, Jennifer Elizabeth</actor>
      <role>Courtney</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>On the day he is released from prison, Lee Karnes knows his life is about to change. 3 years behind bars doesn't seem like a whole lot, but to anyone who has actually been inside, 3 years can be considered a lifetime. His brother, Anthony arrives at the gate to take him home and this begins the next chapter in his life. Anthony is the owner of a successful business and happy to be in a position to help his brother out. What's family for? Supporting his brother through all he has a head of him, Anthony quickly gives Lee a job and a raise. Lee's life looks to be falling into place. Early one morning, Anthony is awaken by a phone call from Lee. Lee tells Anthony that he needs to get out of town for a little while. Lee unwillingly forces Anthony to join him. While on the run, Anthony finds out Lee's girlfriend, Alix, was found dead after he left her that evening. The cops were looking to talk to him. He was there prime suspect. Lee knows he could never do anything like that to Alix, or could he? Lee has very little memory of the evening in question. Anthony is hit with another bombshell when Courtney informs him that she is pregnant and he should not be running and putting their future in jeopardy. After hearing Lee's story, Anthony is convinced that Lee is innocent. With the help of Anthony's lawyer, Mark, they begin to try to put the pieces together prove their case. Put up against the wall and with no real way out, Lee must face the demons in his present, while still trying to overcome the demons from his past.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?084379</url></doc>
