<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="085813">
  <docid>085813</docid>
  <title>Buffalo Wings</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>McCoy, Sanford</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">24 July 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">18</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>McCoy, Sanford</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>McCoy, Sanford</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Auslander, Adam</actor>
      <role>Peter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bear-McClard, Sebastian</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chauvin, Helene</actor>
      <role>Jana</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chauvin, Hélène (II)</actor>
      <role>Jana</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nusser, Alden</actor>
      <role>Pluto</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The relationships between a silent young woman, her brother and her lover, in an isolated farm house in upstate NY. She had been content holding the house together when her brother returns from military boot camp and the forgotten weight of their past lives together returns and begins to re-enact itself. Her lover from the city is the polar opposite in terms of masculinity from her brother, and not to mention, he is twice her age with a family elsewhere. The two men prove themselves no better than the other, as they contend with each other over her in their own ways, they both leave an emotional weight on Jana which is heightened from her silence. Her only escape both metaphorically and physically is working on a buffalo farm down the road. She relates to the buffalo as they are wild animals who once freely roamed the plains of America and are now being forced to live in small squares en-fenced by electrical wires. What would happen if a buffalo had wings? Would it fly away? Can people recognize an opportunity for their own freedom and break old patterns or is change driven from necessity?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?085813</url></doc>
