<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="086528">
  <docid>086528</docid>
  <title>Bumazhnyy soldat</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Russian</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Russia</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Argentina">13</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Argentina">10 November 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Netherlands">23 January 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="UK">June 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Germany">7 February 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Czech Republic">6 July 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Russia">18 December 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Kazakhstan">4 February 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Italy">1 September 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">118</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>German Ml., Aleksei</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Shumakov, Sergei</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khamatova, Chulpan</actor>
      <role>Nina</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ninidze, Merab</actor>
      <role>Dr. Daniel Pokrovsky</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Kazakhstan, early 1961. Daniel Pokrovsky, a medical officer, currently works for the first Soviet cosmonauts' troop. There Daniel, already married, finds himself in an incredibly complicated and yet tender relationship with a young girl, called Vera. Later Daniel goes back to Moscow where is in charge of the health of the future cosmonauts. He tries not to be just a doctor for the cadets, but also their friend. He can't agree with the fact that these young men could have to sacrifice their lives for the country. His wife Nina feels the same: she doesn't accept him participating in a project that could put human lives at risk, therefore she keeps asking Daniel to leave his job. Daniel decides to leave his wife. Then one of the cadets dies and the medical officer ends up breaking down. This doesn't stop him from leaving for Kazakhstan in order to prepare the launch of the first man into space. Nina follows him to Kazakhstan, where she learns about his involvement with Vera; however she decides not to leave Daniel alone, understanding how ill he is. Giving up attempts to handle the stress, Daniel escapes the day before the launch, but dies on his getaway. Nina takes Vera with her to Moscow, accommodating the girl in her apartment. Time goes by and both women keep living together: none of them will ever get married again, being both still in love with Daniel.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?086528</url></doc>
