<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="087270">
  <docid>087270</docid>
  <title>Burnside</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Beyl, Cameron</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">November 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">120</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Beyl, Cameron</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Yugler, Simon</producer>
    <producer>Beyl, Cameron</producer>
    <producer>Jay, Matt (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Beyl, Cameron</writer>
    <writer>Jay, Matt (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Johnson, Boone</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anderson, Ben (XI)</actor>
      <role>Dusty</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Beyl, Cameron</actor>
      <role>Curtis</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carter, Siobhan</actor>
      <role>Asha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Colgan, Hilary</actor>
      <role>Natalie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Forsyth, Anthony</actor>
      <role>Jack</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jay, Matt (II)</actor>
      <role>Gabe</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Schwartz, Russ</actor>
      <role>Ben</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Three vignettes about life on Portland's infamous avenue. Dusty, a burnt out military reject, can't find a job and, to make matters worse, his girlfriend is pregnant. His luck seems to change when he meets up with an old childhood friend who promises to change all of that, but it very well may cost him his morality. Jack, a troubleshooter and code programmer at a high-tech software firm, is experiencing a reawakening about his job, his girlfriend, and his life. On the outside, his downward social spiral seems to be liberating him from the monotony of the cubicle. However, on the inside, something else is terribly wrong, and it's only a matter of time until it all comes spilling out. Asha, a young high school student, dreams of escaping her restrained family and social life and longs for understanding. Her thoughts manifest themselves in intricate rhyme patterns inspired by her main influence in life, Hiphop music. Her introspective rhymes begin to find a voice through her experiences with the few who support her and those who are out to take advantage.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?087270</url></doc>
