<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="087407">
  <docid>087407</docid>
  <title>Bus Stop</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bell, Christopher Jason</editor>
    <editor>Hatem, Ruba</editor>
    <editor>Li, Zhenyu</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">4 November 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="France">29 April 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">12</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Bell, Christopher Jason</director>
    <director>Hatem, Ruba</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hatem, Ruba</producer>
    <producer>Sartor, Ryan</producer>
    <producer>Sohn, Soopum</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bell, Christopher Jason</writer>
    <writer>Hatem, Ruba</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Tedstone, Maryanne</composer>
    <composer>Tedstone, Michael</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Coy, Charlotte</actor>
      <role>Mona</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Goralnick, Jerry</actor>
      <role>Jerry</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jensen, Joslyn</actor>
      <role>Hannah</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mousa, Suha</actor>
      <role>Tina</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shah, Daud</actor>
      <role>Matt</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Bus Stop is a story of dreams falling apart and relationships disintegrating as selfishness, lack of communication and dishonesty to one self and others begins to master the scene of the troubled marriage of Mona and Matt's. Mona is a singer with a dream and many contradictions. Her indulgence in herself and aspirations has gradually pushed her away from the man she once loved and married. Living the life of a struggling singer with a night bar singing job, her attachment to her marriage is eventually limited to sharing a roof with no feeling of home anywhere in the space. At this point of her life, she gets exposed to a potential source of firing inspiration and an opportunity to bring passion back to her life when she accidentally meets Tina at the bus stop she goes to everyday on her way to work. As the story progresses, the interconnected relationships begin to unfold when the hidden reason behind those accidental meetings becomes clear. Matt is indulging in an affair with Tina every night when his wife is at work. As Tina meets Mona coincidentally every day and night at the bus stop, completely unaware of the connection between her and Matt, something begins to spark between them. What happens when Matt finds out? How do they feel when they all finally meet again at that bus stop as the truth gets revealed to the three of them?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?087407</url></doc>
