<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="087605">
  <docid>087605</docid>
  <title>Buskers Bounty</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Selvage, Patrick</editor>
    <editor>Van Scotter, Philip</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>slapstick</keyword>
    <keyword>silent-comedy</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">61</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Van Scotter, Philip</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Pleviak, Abbey</producer>
    <producer>Van Scotter, Philip</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Van Scotter, Philip</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>McCollough, Bradley</actor>
      <role>the Bounty Hunter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Van Scotter, Philip</actor>
      <role>the Busker</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>'Buskers Bounty' is the story of Apple and her dog Chico. After escaping her abusive boyfriend our heroine and her canine companion hit the trail in search of new life. Armed with only a flute, Apple plays her way into a new town and befriends a street busker and a baroness. The recently widowed Baroness invites Apple and Chico to stay with her at her lovely estate. When Apple returns to town she runs into the Busker who is cross-dressed in an attempt to make more money. She explains that she is in search of 'solid work' and drags the Busker to a diner with a help wanted sign. After being thrown out by the maniacal diner boss, Apple and the Busker change clothes in an alley and Apple secures the job cross-dressed as a little man. Meanwhile the ex-boyfriend hires a bounty hunter to find and kill Apple and Chico; the dastardly villain rides into town on his motorcycle. While a musical jam ensues inside the diner with Apple on flute, the Busker on guitar, and the Diner Boss on mandolin, the Bounty Hunter recognizes Chico from a photograph and kidnaps the poor little fella. Apple is destroyed when she discovers that her dog is missing. She searches desperately for him and stumbles upon the villain's hideout - a wild chase ensues.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?087605</url></doc>
