<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="088638">
  <docid>088638</docid>
  <title>Byala magiya</title>
  <year>1982</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Vepshek, Teodora</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Bulgarian</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Bulgaria</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Bulgaria">22 November 1982</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Hungary">23 February 1984</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">97</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Andonov, Ivan</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Lazarov, Borislav</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Pavlov, Konstantin</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Genkov, Georgi</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Baeva, Kunka</actor>
      <role>Strina Neda</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Getova, Plamena</actor>
      <role>Persa</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gorchev, Anton</actor>
      <role>Stoyadin Gerov</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grigorov, Ivan</actor>
      <role>Stoil</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gudev, Stoyan</actor>
      <role>Dancho</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kaloyanchev, Georgi</actor>
      <role>Bog</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kynev, Velko</actor>
      <role>Andro</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Slabakov, Petar</actor>
      <role>Dyavol</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Todev, Nikola</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The story took place in a village in the mountains, decades ago. There is perhaps the most bizarre place worldwide. Incredible events follow one another. A woman cold-bloodedly kills the village rake (who has as cold-bloodedly raped her) to marry a simpleton from another village. A drunk little boy walks round the village swearing like a trooper; a hen crows rooster-like, a journeyman barber is not able to find a wife and is deceived by the archangel of his dreams in his amorous hopes; a dumb child regain the power of speech; God and the Satan struggle with each other in the imaginations and souls of the people and neither of them gets the upper hand; scores of crippled men and women are cured on the spot; a hen crows in the white fog as if bewailing future misfortunes... The numerous characters in this film live and act artlessly and sincerely in their picturesque and bizarre world. Visible and invisible threads connect them to the village Fair that sweeps them into its exuberant merriment. There is nothing magical in these grotesque and ironic images which is so closely connected with dreams. They reveal the primary and elemental mystery of live.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?088638</url></doc>
