<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="090673">
  <docid>090673</docid>
  <title>Calcutta Hilton</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Sinclair, John (XVI)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>red-light</keyword>
    <keyword>transformation</keyword>
    <keyword>women</keyword>
    <keyword>freedom</keyword>
    <keyword>prostitution</keyword>
    <keyword>sex-trade</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Bengali</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>New Zealand</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="New Zealand">M</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="New Zealand">16 November 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Sinclair, John (XVI)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Sinclair, John (XVI)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Ashton, Evie</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ashton, Evie</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hilton, Annie</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>With more than 6000 women, Sonagacchi is the largest, most infamous sex district in Calcutta, India. Many of these women were stolen from their homes, tricked by strangers or sold into prostitution by friends and family. They have a life they did not choose and no means of escape. Kerry and Annie Hilton live in this notorious red-light district with their family. They have big dreams - dreams of freedom for women trapped in a trade they did not choose. They have established Freeset, a textile manufacturing business that employs women from the area. It provides them with dignity, education and a decent income, but most importantly, a way out of the sex trade. Mena works at Freeset. She was a village girl caught up in the turmoil of Bangladesh's civil war when she ran away in the 1970's. On reaching Calcutta she was tricked into prostitution. Frightened and bewildered by a world she knew nothing of, she was drugged and raped by her first customer. She was just 13 years old. It's 30 years since Mena last saw her mother. Fear and shame have kept them apart, but now she has a job she is proud of. She's decided the time is right to return home for a visit. But can she make it and will her mother be happy to see her? Calcutta Hilton tells the story of Freeset and its life-changing effect on the lives of the women who work there.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?090673</url></doc>
