<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="092585">
  <docid>092585</docid>
  <title>Canbury</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Barrett, Alex (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>nature</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>twenty-something</keyword>
    <keyword>male-female-relationship</keyword>
    <keyword>meditative</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Croatia">9 July 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="UK">8 November 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Germany">3 December 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="France">13 May 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Hungary">15 September 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Italy">29 July 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">12</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Barrett, Alex (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Barrett, Alex (II)</producer>
    <producer>Visser, Andrew</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Barrett, Alex (II)</writer>
    <writer>Coy, Charlotte</writer>
    <writer>Easton, Sari</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Creasey, Jason</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bright, Rachel</actor>
      <role>Rachael</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Coy, Charlotte</actor>
      <role>Ella</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Easton, Sari</actor>
      <role>Katherine</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Groom, James</actor>
      <role>Steveo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McCall, Lachlan</actor>
      <role>Alan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wallace, James (XIII)</actor>
      <role>Panzo</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Canbury is a trilogy of stories concerning the lives of six twentysomethings, set in Canbury Gardens, Kingston-upon-Thames: Part I: Two females sit on a bench. One of them mentions that she recently ran into a pregnant friend of theirs. Their conversation soon turns from their friend to reflections about their own current situations in life: one bemoans the lack of her relationship experience, worrying about the fact she hasn't settled down, while the other firmly believes that they are too young to be worrying about such things. She expresses her belief that they should simply be enjoying and experiencing their lives, but her friend remains unconvinced: to her, relationships are life. Part II: A male takes a seat on a bench, hoping to find a quiet moment during which to eat his lunch. However, before he can start, an attractive female comes and takes a seat next to him. It is clear from their body language that the two characters are attracted to one another, yet neither is bold enough to make a move. After an awkward moment of eye contact the male decides to busy himself in reading a newspaper, hoping to hide his embarrassment. Taking this as a sign that a conversation will never start, the female decides to leave. It is a wasted opportunity for both of them, and the male is left alone and regretful. Part III: Two males sit by the side of the river, comatose through boredom and watching the river pass by before them. They talk about how to spend their time: although one of them is already drinking, he suggests going to a pub. However, his friend, whose neck is in a brace, replies that he can't drink due to the painkillers he is taking, and this reminds him that it is time for him to take his next pill. Seeking some water with which to take the pill, he finds that there is only one drink to hand: his friend's beer. The two friends return to watching the river, but this time they are both drinking.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?092585</url></doc>
