<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="093556">
  <docid>093556</docid>
  <title>Captain</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">26 February 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">13</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Cady, Max (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Fusaro, Lou</producer>
    <producer>Ryan, John (XIV)</producer>
    <producer>Campbell, Caitlin Renee</producer>
    <producer>Stuart, Nicole</producer>
    <producer>Sundmacher, Jack</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Stuart, Nicole</writer>
    <writer>Sundmacher, Jack</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Johnson, Bjorn (I)</actor>
      <role>Carl</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sundmacher, Jack</actor>
      <role>Steve</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Steve, mid thirty's, unpublished author - who had taken a writing class with Carl, an award winning crime novelist. Right away Carl sees the potential in Steve. In writing exercises, he stuns his fellow classmates with his wit and his use of language but Carl wants more out of him. Carl and his wife Trish are planning a trip to Hawaii and ask Steve if he could take care of their dog. Steve says yes without hesitation, thinking it will be a good opportunity to reestablish his relationship with Carl, who three months earlier, told him he must leave class and wouldn't be allowed back until he made a commitment to becoming the best writer he could be. Steve drops by the house to get the details from Trish on what kind of food the dog will get and medications. After his visit, Steve has mixed feelings about agreeing to take care of the dog but decides it's only three days and he needs the money. While at him that evening, he is shocked when Trish arrives. The shock increases when Trish informs Steve that he killed Captain while backing out of the driveway. Steve is stunned and tries to confront Carl and put the pieces together. Could this all be a nasty bit if fiction written by Carl and Trish? Could their story help Steve break through the blocks that had been keeping him stuck?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?093556</url></doc>
