<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="094132">
  <docid>094132</docid>
  <title>Caravan of Light</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Abela, Jean-Marc</editor>
    <editor>Weigel, Melissa</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="United Arab Emirates">7 February 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">16</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Farmanfarmaian, Sahar</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Farmanfarmaian, Sahar</producer>
    <producer>Mahdavi, Amin</producer>
    <producer>Farmanfarmaian, Sahar</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Del Fuego, Shams</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Penman, Joshua</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Farmanfarmaian, Sahar</actor>
      <role>Narration</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Caravan of Light: Initiation is a message, an incantation, a prayer, a word of caution. Humanity has too long used the element of fire for destruction. The Goddess of the Sacred Element of Fire speaks to humanity reminding us of the essential spirit nature of fire - counseling us that if we continue to profane it - if we do not use fire purely for constructive and positive purposes - then fire shall be taken away from the planet, and thus humanity left in total darkness. In effect, the Fire's message is a positive admonition of peace and hope. A choice to use fire to recover what is important about being human, that in ourselves we hold the keys to our own transformation. Sahar Farmanfarmaian captured on film a pilgrimage back to her home country. There, the ancient Zoroastrian traditions and the mystical energy of the desert (whose breathtaking vistas make fleeting appearances in the film) inspired the creation of several fire-rituals. It is from the mesmerizing images of these sacred flames that the Goddess is born. Initiation is an intense musical experience as well.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?094132</url></doc>
