<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="096525">
  <docid>096525</docid>
  <title>Cat's Cradle</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Allan, Gilbert</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Albo, Frank</producer>
    <producer>Presseau, Marc</producer>
    <producer>Torguson, Joanna</producer>
    <producer>Albo, Cara</producer>
    <producer>Dahlseide, Darren</producer>
    <producer>Allan, Gilbert</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Harychan, Natasha</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Albo, Cara</actor>
      <role>Cat Adams</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chante, Keshia</actor>
      <role>Keshia Chanté</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grey, Susan (II)</actor>
      <role>Barie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gummer, Andrew</actor>
      <role>Bryan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kelly, Brad (III)</actor>
      <role>Garrett</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A story taken straight from the headlines. Cats Cradle is about a young pop-star named Cat. Cat is a beautiful, talented pop singer who does it all. She can dance, sing and make it all seem so effortless. However, behind the scenes, she is falling apart at a rapid pace. She manages to juggle the pressures of recording insipid music for pre-teens, marketing teen magazines about "how to get boys to like you", publicity photo shoots, and having her every move documented for her new reality series with her very own camera man joined at the hip. Now, Cat is headlining her first world tour entitled "Abstinence", which will catapult her into international domination and she's finding it harder to breathe. She's getting pressure from every angle, including her overbearing manager, Barrie Chan. Finally after finding her last bit of control being taken away from her, Cat snaps. The only person she can trust is her personal assistant/best friend, Evey, who plots her escape with a borrowed car and a cell phone, which only Evey knows about. Cat sets off for her journey into the unknown, having no idea where she's going, but knowing that she just has to get away. Her road trip is put to a halt when her car breaks down and a good-looking stranger offers to take her into the next town to get her car looked after. The handsome hero is Garrett, a nice, down-to-earth guy who chooses to lead his life without drama but small and quaint. Once her car is taken in, Cat finds out she will be stuck in hicks-ville for some time. Garrett eventually caves in to letting her stay with him and before she knows it, Cat finds herself stranded in a small, unknown town and staying with a hot country guy. But Cats journey is just beginning as she struggles with trying to find herself in a world she is completely unfamiliar in.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?096525</url></doc>
