<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="096681">
  <docid>096681</docid>
  <title>Catch Phrase</title>
  <year>1998</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Game-Show</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Australia">G</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Boughen, Michael</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Burgess, John (III)</actor>
      <role>Himself - Host</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The game begins with one of the contestants playing the Money Chase board, where there are nine dollar amounts available. The amount that is highlighted when the contestant presses their buzzer is the amount that each picture puzzle (or "catch phrase") is worth. The amounts available increase over each of the three rounds. Each round is played with contestants aiming to guess what catch phrase each picture puzzle is referring to, with a correct guess entitling that contestant to reveal a square on the Bonus Catchphrase board, which reveals part of the bonus puzzle. One of the squares contains a mystery prize which is won by the contestant who selects that square. After revealing the square, that contestant guesses the bonus catch phrase this puzzle refers to, with a correct guess winning that contestant extra money. After three rounds, the contestant with the most money becomes the champion, and they play the final prize round, where they have 60 seconds to make a line of 5 squares on a 25 square board by correctly solving the catchphrases revealed behind each letter they select. Two prizes are offered each night, with the more valuable prize won if the winning line includes the centre square - if they can remain champion for 5 nights or more, this prize will be a car.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?096681</url></doc>
