<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="096957">
  <docid>096957</docid>
  <title>Catwoman: The Game</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>VideoGame</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>spin-off</keyword>
    <keyword>based-on-comic</keyword>
    <keyword>based-on-film</keyword>
    <keyword>based-on-comic-book</keyword>
    <keyword>beautiful-woman</keyword>
    <keyword>spin-off-from-film</keyword>
    <keyword>game</keyword>
    <keyword>cat-woman</keyword>
    <keyword>third-person-view</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Brazil">14</certificate>
    <certificate country="UK">12</certificate>
    <certificate country="USA">T</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">6 August 2004</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Germany">12 August 2004</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="France">26 August 2004</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">20 July 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <producers>
    <producer>Gamon, Jeff</producer>
    <producer>Hall, Jace</producer>
    <producer>Leinfellner, Richard</producer>
    <producer>Harris, Simon (V)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Hannigan, James</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Berry, Halle</actor>
      <role>Patience Phillips/Catwoman</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Catwoman is based upon the DC Comics character. The film and game follow the story of Patience Phillips, who is killed after she uncovers a dark secret held by her employers. Brought back to life by a rare Egyptian cat, she becomes Catwoman and sets out to discover the truth about herself and her murderer. Boasting incredible acrobatic skills, the video game Catwoman can leap across roofs, run up walls, pounce on prey, utilize unique "cat senses," and avoid enemy bullets with feline grace. In addition, she can use her whip to swing through the air and utilize the fully interactive environments to trap or knock her foes unconscious. The game will take players through numerous levels set in six different locations from the movie, including the jewelery store, the Hedare Factory, and Hedare's mansion and grounds. Gamers will encounter all the key characters from the movie, including three challenging bosses: Armando, Hedare's head bodyguard; Wesley, the evil and twisted Hedare henchman and Laurel Hedare, the beautiful face behind the cosmetics empire.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?096957</url></doc>
