<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="098974">
  <docid>098974</docid>
  <title>Chaitnaya</title>
  <year>1986</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Ambalam, V.G.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Telugu</language>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">U</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">23 May 1986</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Rao, V. Madhusudan</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Govindam, Purshottam</producer>
    <producer>Shaw, Suraj Kumar</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Nair, Mohan</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Ilayaraja</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Akkineni, Nagarjuna</actor>
      <role>Vikram</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chandramohan (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gautami (I)</actor>
      <role>Padmini H. Prasad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gummadi</actor>
      <role>Commissioner</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Karnad, Girish</actor>
      <role>Major Harishchandra Prasad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Raghuvaran</actor>
      <role>Kalicharan</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Vikram lives a middle-classed lifestyle in India and works as a Garage Mechanic with Roots Car Rally Company. He meets with Padmini, the only daughter of Major Harishchandra Prasad, but their meeting is marred with misunderstandings. One day his Journalist friend, Sudhakar, asks for his assistance, and Vikram tells him to meet him in the garage after hours. On his way to the garage, Vikram almost runs over a gravely wounded Sudhakar, who mumbles something incoherently. Before Vikram could assist his friend, 3 men shoot and kill Sudhakar. Vikram attempts to fight them, but is overpowered, and left unconscious. When he recovers he finds himself in a jail cell, arrested for the murder of Sudhakar. Vikram enlists the assistance of one of his co-workers, and escapes from jail - to attend a car rally in Goa - only to find himself pitted against Sudhakar's killers, who include Cobra and Kalicharan, as well as Padmini, who believes Vikram is a killer, a mysterious woman named Smita, as well as a host of Khaki-clad (Police &amp; Army) and Khadi-clad men (Politicians &amp; businessmen) - who appear to have one mission - terrorize, profit, and kill anyone who dares to stand in their way.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?098974</url></doc>
