<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="099303">
  <docid>099303</docid>
  <title>Champion</title>
  <year>2000</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">A</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">December 2000</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Kuwait">3 January 2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Kumar, Padam</director>
    <director>Memel, Jana Sue</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Anand, Anand Raj</composer>
    <composer>Malik, Anu</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Alter, Tom</actor>
      <role>Doctor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bahadur, Rana Jung</actor>
      <role>Pandey</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deol, Sunny (I)</actor>
      <role>Rajveer Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dev, Rahul</actor>
      <role>Naseer Ahmed</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gokhale, Vikram</actor>
      <role>Police Commissioner</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapila, Padmini</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Mansoor Ali Khan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Koirala, Manisha</actor>
      <role>Sapna Khanna</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Parashar, Deepak</actor>
      <role>Nawab Mansoor Ali Khan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sharma, Abhishek</actor>
      <role>Abbas Khan</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A serious accident took place in Bombay, India, which involves Abbas Khan parents, as a result of which they passed away, leaving all the properties and estate for Abbas Khan to inherit. The police feel that his situation is vulnerable, as they suspect his parents' death was not accidental. They however, arrange for a full-time personal bodyguard in the shape and form of Inspector Rajveer Singh. And Inspector Rajveer agrees to do so. After a series of misadventures, the child takes a liking to Rajveer, and so does the childs' parents secretary, Sapna Khanna. Rajveer comes to know that the assailant behind the killings of Abbas's parents is one Muslim man named Naseer Ahmed, and traces him to a mental hospital where he is an inmate. Naseer has sworn to avenge the humiliation and death of his father and family, at the hands of Abbas's father, by killing each and everyone in the family. Rajveer's brutal efforts to seek information from Naseer gets him behind bars, as the police refuse to believe that a confined inmate is capable of killing. But soon Rajveer is release from prison as he was keeping a low profile while in jail and reach out to find sufficient evidence that will open the law's eye and prove Naseer guilty and as the world's most dangerous underworld don and criminal other than an inmate.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?099303</url></doc>
