<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="099671">
  <docid>099671</docid>
  <title>Changing Blossoms</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Haight, Brad</editor>
    <editor>Marshall, Edward (VIII)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">15 September 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">17</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Cristelle, Terra</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Cristelle, Terra</producer>
    <producer>Haight, Brad</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Cristelle, Terra</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Denali, Mateo</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Busby, Fred</actor>
      <role>Joseph Showe</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Copeland, Christina R.</actor>
      <role>Jeane-anne Luclove</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cristelle, Terra</actor>
      <role>Blossom Luclove</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gross, Lance (II)</actor>
      <role>Tony Gene</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Haight, Brad</actor>
      <role>Washington Riley</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Johnson, Marilyn (III)</actor>
      <role>Miranda Luclove</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McDaniels, Akwe Palesa</actor>
      <role>Teetee</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Changing blossoms is an intimate story involving three women. Miranda and her two daughters Blossom and Jean Ann. A story set up around cultural structure and family traditions, changing blossoms highlights a conflict that can occur in families functioning within a single parent matriarchal structure. Jean Ann luclove, 15 years old and vulnerable is caught in a struggle between her mother and her older sister. A struggle that's been on going and based in a past unresolved issue, Jean Ann despite the conflict still tries to gain Miranda's trust and acceptance. Jean Ann is fascinated by the carefree, indulgent and openly lovingly world of Blossom. while blossom tries to make peace with her past and Miranda and save Jean Ann from the same situation that's causing her on going emotional turmoil. Miranda though seemingly conflicted is forced to make a choice between her daughters and her new lover Joseph who has opened the window to a path that could have love and financial support. Joseph is charming and giving a natural lady's man but with an evident dual personality that causes conflict when he becomes apart of the luclove family. A man of few words his physical presence makes up for his lack of words. Tony Gene is Jean Ann's boyfriend. Slightly older than jean Ann, he's willingly drawn into the Luclove conflict and assumes the role of big brother during Jean Ann's moment of need.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?099671</url></doc>
