<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="100695">
  <docid>100695</docid>
  <title>Chasing God</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Carmichael, Ian (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Arabic</language>
    <language>Hindi</language>
    <language>Italian</language>
    <language>English</language>
    <language>Tibetan</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Australia">24 February 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">53</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Burton, Dylan</director>
    <director>de Vries, Lenny</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>de Vries, Lenny</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Burton, Dylan</writer>
    <writer>Ramsay, Barbara</writer>
    <writer>de Vries, Lenny</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Timothy, Michael</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>French, Dawn</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Narrated by award-winning comedian Dawn French ("The Vicar of Dibley"), this thought provoking film addresses a subject matter rarely tackled: Why do humans believe in a higher power? By interviewing scientists, atheists and religious leaders from diverse faiths, this groundbreaking documentary explores the motivations of humankind to believe in something bigger and more powerful than itself. Travelling the world and asking poignant questions of its subjects, Chasing God is able to look at the relevancy of God in today's harsh world. Today, we see the very existence of humanity being threatened. Human beings are at war with each other, while weapons of devastating destruction exist that can wipe out whole countries. Violence is being mooted as a solution to the need for peace and protection, and many people feel powerless to influence outcomes. New prayer and meditation websites and groups are popping up daily in a desperate attempt for divine intervention. It has always been true that when we human beings are afraid or in pain we reach out for a power greater than our own. Perhaps never before in the history of the world has the sound of God's name been so loudly heard from people of all cultures and religions at the same time. Beliefs about God have divided humanity, yet this documentary seeks to highlight a paradoxical unifying principle that may well lie beyond the divisive interpretations of God. While science cannot prove or disprove the existence of God, ultimately it is either a universal truth or a mass delusion. In the absence of any verifiable proof, what we are then left with are personal experiences. This documentary spotlights the most controversial yet elusive figure in recorded history. No one else has been the subject of such hotly contested debate, disagreement, and wars.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?100695</url></doc>
