<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="100954">
  <docid>100954</docid>
  <title>Chatur Singh Two Star</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Rokade, Nitin</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Mystery</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>number-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Chandhok, Ajay</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Shaikh, Hussain (I)</producer>
    <producer>Aslam, Mohamad (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Ali, Sajid (I)</composer>
    <composer>Ali, Wajid</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dabi, Snehal</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dutt, Sanjay</actor>
      <role>Chatur Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grover, Gulshan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Shakti (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kaushik, Satish</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Mushtaq</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kher, Anupam</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kiran, Shashi (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Menon, Suresh (I)</actor>
      <role>Pappu Panther</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nagar, Sunil</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pradhan, Vishwajeet</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sharma, Murli</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Verma, Arun</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Yadav, Ganesh (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>He knows everything about nothing... and he's on a mission to destroy himself! He is Chatur Singh 2 Star, an infamous member of the Mumbai Police Department who, in his career, has been most successful at botching up cases and making a fool of himself. In spite of being a disgrace to the team, Chatur Singh has just been handed the biggest case in the department's history and of course, this is the perfect chance for him to prove everyone why he is the best officer they have. Chatur Singh takes off on the secret mission to South Africa and he immediately ensures that there is trouble for all, because he is the biggest trouble of all! His antics are hazardous to health and definitely likely to cause serious injury; he is absolutely clueless and yet he keeps stumbling on all the right clues thanks to a little help from the pretty Sonia. His bumbling mannerisms, clumsiness and of course his 'super intelligence' sets off a string of hilarious events which lead to more chaos and confusion than anyone could have ever imagined. The criminals are on the run, with Chatur in close pursuit! Add to this chaotic fray, Pappu Panther, who is Chatur's right-hand or in this case "wrong-hand" man; he adores and worships his master Chatur, which makes him an even bigger idiot than Chatur himself! Sanjay Dutt is at his rib-tickling best with disguises and looks which are absolutely uproarious... but he won't stop at that. So, hold on to your tummies for Chatur Singh's hitting the theatres soon!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?100954</url></doc>
