<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="101639">
  <docid>101639</docid>
  <title>Chemistry Lesson</title>
  <year>1922</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>dancing</keyword>
    <keyword>alcohol-distillery</keyword>
    <keyword>explosion</keyword>
    <keyword>cartoon-dog</keyword>
    <keyword>farmer</keyword>
    <keyword>farmer-alfalfa</keyword>
    <keyword>cartoon-walrus</keyword>
    <keyword>dance</keyword>
    <keyword>visual-pun</keyword>
    <keyword>distillery</keyword>
    <keyword>bloodhound</keyword>
    <keyword>flexing-arm-muscle</keyword>
    <keyword>cartoon-bird</keyword>
    <keyword>dog</keyword>
    <keyword>alcoholic-drink</keyword>
    <keyword>dream</keyword>
    <keyword>underwater</keyword>
    <keyword>it-was-all-a-dream</keyword>
    <keyword>nightmare</keyword>
    <keyword>anthropomorphic-animal</keyword>
    <keyword>cartoon-rooster</keyword>
    <keyword>moonshine</keyword>
    <keyword>flute</keyword>
    <keyword>mermaid</keyword>
    <keyword>rabbit</keyword>
    <keyword>rooster</keyword>
    <keyword>anthropomorphism</keyword>
    <keyword>cartoon-rabbit</keyword>
    <keyword>money-bag-with-dollar-sign</keyword>
    <keyword>walrus</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1922</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">8</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Terry, Paul (I)</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>Farmer Al Falfa brews up some moonshine. He gives some to a rabbit that is exhausted after being chased by bloodhounds. The moonshine proves so powerful that the rabbit races back to the dogs and beats them until they run away terrified. Al Falfa gives some moonshine to a rooster. The bird's feathers explode from its body. Al Falfa drinks the moonshine himself. He's explodes into the air like a cannonball. Lightning crashes around him. He continues hurtling upwards. Suddenly, he has angel wings and desperately tries to grab onto the trumpet-bearing female angel just ahead of him. Finally, without the wings, he lands on the bottom of a planet. He crawls around like a spider. He climbs to the top of the planet and grabs an object that turns out to be an egg. It hatches, and a creature with a chicken-like body, three long, striped necks, and three cat-like heads, emerges and grows enormous as Al Falfa shrinks. Then Al Falfa grows large and the creature shrinks. Al Falfa jumps off the planet and falls toward earth. He crashes through the ice, in between two walruses, and falls into the ocean where he meets a beautiful mermaid who is surrounded by treasure.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?101639</url></doc>
