<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="102757">
  <docid>102757</docid>
  <title>Chicos normales</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Mota Ortiz, Jorge</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
    <language>Arabic</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Greece">22 November 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Czech Republic">27 February 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Spain">23 September 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Egypt">25 November 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Czech Republic">85</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Hernández, Daniel (VI)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Usón, Pablo</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Demestres, Alberto</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Aoulasse, El-Khader</actor>
      <role>El-Khader</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Belefki, Youseff</actor>
      <role>Youseff</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bouchfira, Rabia</actor>
      <role>Rabia</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Saadoun, Mohammed</actor>
      <role>Mohammed</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Ordinary Boys enters into the lives of three young residents of Jaama Mezwak, an impoverished Moroccan neighborhood in the city of Tetouan, home of five of the suicide bombers who blew up the Madrid trains in 2004. Khader is a young man whose family's crushing debts force him to choose between his dream of becoming an actor, or abandoning everything to become an illegal alien in Europe. Rabia is an opinionated, ambitious young woman, with strong religious beliefs, struggling to open a clothing store while waiting the return of her boyfriend. Youssef, a small-time drug dealer coming out of prison, follows any clue he comes upon in search of his brother, disappeared without trace. Life as a criminal. Life as an illegal immigrant or to achieve a working place in the neighborhood . How will these 3 young people build their futures? Ordinary Boys enters into a place that has bred terrorism, but is a fly-on-the-wall film that provides a vision from within of what life is truly like in a poor Muslim community.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?102757</url></doc>
