<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="103567">
  <docid>103567</docid>
  <title>China Lake</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bostick, Roman</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">15 June 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="France">15 May 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">14 September 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="USA">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Bostick, Roman</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bostick, Roman</producer>
    <producer>Ross, Cassie</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bostick, Roman</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Bostick, Roman</composer>
    <composer>Ross, Tony (VII)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Acevedo, Jose (III)</actor>
      <role>Jesus</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bostick, Roman</actor>
      <role>Andrew</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cerhus, Evyh</actor>
      <role>Mary</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Linkman, Wolf</actor>
      <role>Ba'al</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tobin, Randy</actor>
      <role>DJ Aaron</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vasko, Matt</actor>
      <role>Michael</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Walder, Gene (II)</actor>
      <role>Jim Donovan</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A small apartment in Los Angeles, two lovers MICHAEL and ISABEL discuss the crazy day they met. Their recollection of specific events surrounding that day create distance in their otherwise seemingly loving relationship. Michael fixes restaurant computers as his day job but yearns for his passion - to secure a venue to exhibit his art. Visually, Michael's inner sub-conscious begins to be presented with an in-between dreaming and waking state described clinically as 'sleep paralysis' - an actual real-time traumatic experience wherein Michael is plagued by real and/or imagined stimuli in the present, which could be originated from past trauma. The true journey begins when Michael receives a call, from his boss, to fix computers at Jim Donovan's restaurant Graziano's (located near China Lake - a Naval base in the Mojave desert). Michael is familiar with the area as his estranged father (a Naval Officer) had been stationed at China Lake. There he meets Isabel, a mysterious but ordinary girl, working the front desk at the China Lake Country Inn - who triggers the dark side of Michael's psyche and his imagination. Characters begin to appear that propel him to identify with the root of his inspiration. What is real from that fateful day?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?103567</url></doc>
