<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="104305">
  <docid>104305</docid>
  <title>Chojin sentai Jettoman</title>
  <year>1991</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>tokusatsu</keyword>
    <keyword>sentai</keyword>
    <keyword>remake</keyword>
    <keyword>super-sentai</keyword>
    <keyword>super-soldier</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Japanese</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Japan</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Japan">1 November 1991</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">25</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Amemiya, Keita</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Arakawa, Naruhisa</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fujiwara, Hideki</actor>
      <role>Dan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hamada, Haruki</actor>
      <role>Akira</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Haruta, Jun'ichi</actor>
      <role>Ryu Friend</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hirose, Yutaka</actor>
      <role>Emperor Toranza</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ikezawa, Haruna</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kishida, Rika</actor>
      <role>White Swan/Kaori Rokumekan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kusaki, Hideaki</actor>
      <role>Gure/Jet Icarus/Bird Garuda/Great Icarus</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maeda, Kanako</actor>
      <role>Kanta</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maruyama, Maho</actor>
      <role>Rie Aoi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maruyama, Maho</actor>
      <role>Rie Aoi/Maria</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Miki, Mikiko</actor>
      <role>Commander Aya Odagiri</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mizutani, Kei</actor>
      <role>Saki</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Naruse, Tomihisa</actor>
      <role>Yellow Owl/Raita Oishi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Niibori, Kazuo</actor>
      <role>Holy Father</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tachi, Massaki Daisuke</actor>
      <role>Radiege</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tachi, Massaki Daisuke</actor>
      <role>Radiege/Raguen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Takahashi, Kazuo (I)</actor>
      <role>Toran</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tanaka, Kotaro (I)</actor>
      <role>Red Hawk/Ryu Tendo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Umizu, Ryôsuke</actor>
      <role>Rei</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wakamatsu, Toshihide</actor>
      <role>Black Condor/Guy Yuki</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The scientists discover an energy in the environment called Birdnc. They find a way to bio-engineer it and bond it to humans. The Commander of the Sky Forth Ayachokan Odagiri searches for five people to be part of this J-project. She finds Ryu Tendo and his fiancée Rie Aoi and asks them to volunteers. Ryu is half-conscious after receiving the Birdnic when the Vyram (the villain) starts attacking the Earth Ship. However, a force from a torn surface of the Earth Ship catches Rie. Ryu tries to rescue her but she is sucked. Aya knocks down the semi-hysterical Ryu then escape before the Earth ship totally explodes. The Earth Ship throws out the other four Birdnic Waves to the earth, hitting four civilians. Kaori Rokumeikan (a rich young lady), Raita Oishi (a young farmer), Ako Hayasaka (a highschool student) and Gai Yuuki (a lone wolf motor biker). Aya and Ryu try to gather the four to complete the team. They find a tough time in convincing the three (Gai most especially). But there is something with the Birdnic Wave that links him to the team. And this made him realizes to finally join the team. Jet Icarus cannot defeat the empress' baby Sikada kid. Then, a group from Dimensia brings Jet Garuda and together with Jetman force, programs the two robots to merge them and Great Icarus is born. As warriors, they develop their powers and learn their weapons. Still, Birdnic Wave won't take their hearts away. Becoming soldiers doesn't mean they've forgotten how to love. Gai falls in love with Kaori. Her spirit and bravery wakes-up the lone-wolf's cold-heart. And an honest glimpse springs out when Gai finds out that Kaori feels the same for Ryu. Raita, in some way, cares for Kaori. But he knows that he's not the man of her caliber. Ryu, realizing the circumstances keeps his distant. He tells Kaori about Rie. But Kaori won't give up and is still determined to win his heart. Gai, on the other hand, in his feelings. He is ready to protect the woman he loves. And so, Kaori learns to give back the love he's been offering. But Gai broke-up with her after meeting her parents. A new challenge for Ryu has come when he discovers that Maria is his beloved Rie. He can't fight her and in a meantime Ryu is on a state of delusion. But he is able to fight it and lead his teammate. Time has come, when finally they've learned to accept each other. But, Toran grows-up himself and becomes Vyram's new emperor. Radigue won't allow him to kill the Jetman. He and Jetman destroy him. He is rendered in asylum. Radigue makes Maria a vampire. Ryu, though, she has become Vyram (almost a monster) still loves her. Radigue doesn't want Maria to become human again and so he kills her. Grey is killed in one on one challenge with Gai. Radigue becomes giant Raguem, merges himself with Vylock and fight the Jetman. Jetman manages to kill him and ended the Vyram threat. Three years later, the whole team gets back to their normail life. Raita marries his childhood sweetheart. Ako becomes a pop singer. Gai becomes a successful businessman. Ryu and Kaori are marrying each other. Gai is buying flowers for Ryu and Kaori's wedding when a street thug stabs him. He is late for the wedding ceremony . Ryu finds him quite exhausted. They sit together and have a talk. Ryu leaves him as Gai lie down the bench then releases the cigarette he's holding.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?104305</url></doc>
