<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="104623">
  <docid>104623</docid>
  <title>Chot [Aaj Isko, Kal Tereko]</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Dhanashekharan, A.D.</editor>
    <editor>Narvekar, Arun V.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Musical</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>gangster</keyword>
    <keyword>milk</keyword>
    <keyword>politician</keyword>
    <keyword>police-inspector</keyword>
    <keyword>encounter</keyword>
    <keyword>train</keyword>
    <keyword>farm</keyword>
    <keyword>buffalo</keyword>
    <keyword>corrupt-police</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby SR</soundmix>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">A</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">18 June 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Kumar 'Raju', Nabh</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bhardwaj, Ajay</producer>
    <producer>Thakur, Sanjay</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Kumar 'Raju', Nabh</writer>
    <writer>Tiwari, Atul</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Singh, Raju (I)</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>It was 18 years ago that Kishan Yadav came all the way from Bihar to settle down in the Bombay suburb of Jogeshwari, bought some buffalo, opened a tabela (diary farm), ran it successfully, hired loyal employees, and then called his college-educated brother, Kabir Yadav, to come and live with him. Kabir, a computer genius, along with his journalist girlfriend live in a flat, but work tirelessly with Kishan. Then Builder Vora decides to built a multi-storied building nearby, finds that no one wants to buy any flats due to the presence and smell of Kishan's tabela. He attempts to buy off Kishan, to no avail. Then Vora calls in Inspector Lall, who assures him that the tabela and Kishan will both be taken care of. Shortly thereafter, Kabir is abducted, severely beaten, held by Lall, Vora and Prakash Sawant, until such time Kishan surrenders the tabela to them. A subdued Kishan agrees to do so, however, Kabir's girlfriend informs the Extortion Cell of the Bombay Police and as a result Lall is arrested, suspended from work, and lodged in a cell. Kabir recovers and with only one thing his mind - revenge. And that he does carry out against Prakash, and a Police Officer. He is all set to give evidence against Lall, when he himself gets killed. An enraged Kishan now has an option - give up the tabela, head home, and mourn the death of Kabir - or go on a killing spree - thus making himself a target both by the police and Vora's goons.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?104623</url></doc>
