<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="107335">
  <docid>107335</docid>
  <title>Citizen Tanouye</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Yahata, Craig</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>ted-tanouye</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">23 April 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="USA">58</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Horsting, Robert</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Horsting, Robert</producer>
    <producer>Yahata, Craig</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Horsting, Robert</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Taylor, Stephen James</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Adachi, Nicole</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Begovich, Alex</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Choi, Kathy (II)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Froehlig, Tim</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Haghighi, Talayeh</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kim, Billy (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McIlvaine, Heather</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tanouye, Isao</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>CITIZEN TANOUYE is a kinetic "shoot-from-the-hip" style documentary that follows the three-day journey of eight ethnically diverse students as they search for the clues to uncover the lost story of local World War II hero and Medal of Honor recipient Technical Sgt. Ted Tanouye of the highly decorated 442nd Regimental Combat Team. In a nationally covered ceremony on the White House Rose Garden in June of 2000, President Clinton presents twenty Medals of Honor to Japanese American soldiers and their surviving families after fifty-six years of oversight by the US Army. Ted Tanouye was one of those soldiers. Now four years later, the Ted Tanouye Memorial is to be dedicated on the sixtieth anniversary of his heroic action on Hill 140, in Italy. In an effort to understand the man that once walked the halls of their Torrance, California high school over sixty years before, these students piece together Ted's story and that of his family incarcerated at Jerome, AR, from school yearbooks, newspaper articles, Internet sites and insightful conversations with World War II veterans. Stories from Ted's brother Isao "Easy" Tanouye, former classmates and fellow soldiers of Company "K" complete this puzzle and reveal how this all-American boy, of the 442nd RCT, overcame looking like the enemy and was awarded this country's highest military honor. CITIZEN TANOUYE starts as a local quest for the history of a national hero, but quickly develops into a universal story about how a people's struggle for acceptance as Americans and one man's actions sixty years earlier can profoundly affect the lives of today's youth.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?107335</url></doc>
