<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="107435">
  <docid>107435</docid>
  <title>City Jewelz</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Swain, J.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">11 September 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Swain, J.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Leigh, Carrie (III)</producer>
    <producer>Rainge, Parrish</producer>
    <producer>Swain, Barbara A.</producer>
    <producer>Swain, J.</producer>
    <producer>Swain, James E.</producer>
    <producer>Swain, J.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Swain, J.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Cooley, Corwin</composer>
    <composer>Hunter, Donah</composer>
    <composer>Kent, Mel</composer>
    <composer>Planet, Ghetto</composer>
    <composer>Sport (II)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brown, Jennifer (IV)</actor>
      <role>Julia "Jules" Swain</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fields, Amanda (II)</actor>
      <role>Newsreporter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Greene, Chris (III)</actor>
      <role>Jabaal Rainey</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harris, Malcolm</actor>
      <role>G-O</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hoskins, Ben</actor>
      <role>Emergency Medical Tech</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hyman, Noelle</actor>
      <role>Lady</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jordan, Russell (II)</actor>
      <role>Milton Swain</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McGriff, Mega</actor>
      <role>Pop</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Munoz, Ceasar</actor>
      <role>Emergency Medical Tech</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pop (I)</actor>
      <role>Mega McGriff</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Smith, Jaime</actor>
      <role>Nate</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Swain, J.</actor>
      <role>Dirk Swain</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>CITY JEWELZ is a short film that tells the dramatic true story of what happens one tragic night in December when a loving brother and sister are faced with choices that will lead them to crime, confrontation, and death. The story begins when DIRK, an undergraduate student at Hampton University returns home to the Bronx after surviving a near fatal gun shot to his head while away at college. Meanwhile JULES, Dirk's troubled younger sister who still lives at home, is going through her own personal hell as she tries to recover from her boyfriend's recent murder. While Dirk is staying at home he and Jules are living in very cramped quarters and sharing Jules' bedroom. One night tension between them erupts and they get into a heated argument, even coming to blows. Dirk tries to apologize to his sister by offering her a ticket to the City College Celebrity Basketball game hosted by Heavy D and Puff Daddy. Stubborn Jules is having none of it and doesn't accept the apology or the ticket and storms out, not knowing that this will be the last time she sees her brother alive again. The film's powerful ending is a reenactment of the tragic events that took place on December 28, 1991 during the City College Stampede where 9 people were trampled to death as they tried to enter the Celebrity Basketball Game. Actual news footage and interviews from that night are mixed in with the film, giving it the true gritty feel of a docu-drama. This film tells the compelling truth behind one of the most tragic nights in hip-hop.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?107435</url></doc>
