<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="107813">
  <docid>107813</docid>
  <title>Clamp gakuen tanteidan</title>
  <year>1997</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Ito, Yuu</editor>
    <editor>Matsumura, Masahiro</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Mystery</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>anime</keyword>
    <keyword>detective</keyword>
    <keyword>clamp</keyword>
    <keyword>school</keyword>
    <keyword>smart-kids</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Japanese</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Japan</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Japan">3 May 1997</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Nabeshima, Osamu</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Amiya, Masaharu</writer>
    <writer>Arakawa, Naruhisa</writer>
    <writer>Clamp</writer>
    <writer>Kubota, Masashi (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Benedetto, Massimo Di</actor>
      <role>Nokoru Imonoyama</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Minami, Omi</actor>
      <role>Akira Ijuuin</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>CLAMP School: the ultimate educational institution. Catering exclusively to only the best and the brightest of all ages, it is without equal in Japan and the world. But of the ten thousand students, there are three grade-schoolers in particular who stand out. They are Nokoru Imonoyama, President of the Student Council, Akira Ijuuin, Treasurer, and Suou Takamura, Secretary. Put them together, and they are but six feet tall, thirty-three years old, and... the ultimate mystery solving, crime fighting team?! Strange it may sound, but whenever these pint-sized overachievers see a problem a little sleuthing might fix, they spring into action to save the day. On campus or off, they are a force of good no evildoers can rival. But a simple detective service this is not, for Nokoru has a special goal in mind when he picks his cases. With a practical 'sixth sense' for damsels in distress, this twelve year old shameless romantic will stop at nothing to aid a gentle maiden. However, with Nokoru's vast female fan club always after him, it might be the ladies man and not the ladies that needs saving... Filled with adventure, comedy, and touching friendship, this is one story you don't need Sherlock to solve, for these youngsters can give him a run for his Watson.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?107813</url></doc>
