<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="108091">
  <docid>108091</docid>
  <title>Class of '62: From 16 to 60</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Dosaj, Paul</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">15 May 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Gaunt, Marilyn</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Dosaj, Paul</producer>
    <producer>Gaunt, Marilyn</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>This film offers a fascinating insight into the lives of six school friends, who are among the first baby-boomers to turn 60. All born in 1946, these spunky working class Yorkshire-women have lived, loved, laughed and cried their way through the Swinging Sixties to the Naughty Nineties. Marilyn Gaunt started filming them in 1983 at a 21-year Reunion she had organised for the 27 girls of her class. It was the start of a 25 year journey, capturing the lives of classmates Sally - the class "star", Denise - the rebel, Margaret - the boy magnet, Dorothy - the quiet one, Gillian - the early leaver, and Katy - the class clown. In the first film they were pushing 40, and she returned to make a second film in 1995, as they approached their Fifties. Now, as they all turn 60 and can collect their pensions, she catches up with her old friends one last time. Class of '62- From 16 to 60 Since 1995 their lives have taken very different paths. Only two remain in Leeds and three now live abroad. Partners have been lost, new ones found, hopes dashed and hopes fulfilled. Their lives are more captivating than many Soaps. Using archive from two previous films and new footage, the film looks back over the 45 years since they all left school, and forward as these ordinary, yet extraordinary women face the future.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?108091</url></doc>
