<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="108169">
  <docid>108169</docid>
  <title>Classic Dance of Love</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">A</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <directors>
    <director>Subhash, Babbar</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Lahiri, Bappi</composer>
    <composer>Singh, Sukhwinder</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhardwaj, Vikas</actor>
      <role>Suraj J. Malhotra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhatt, Krishna (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chakraborty, Mithun</actor>
      <role>Dr. Ramgopal Acharya</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hingoo, Dinesh</actor>
      <role>Sitara's assistant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kiran, Shashi (I)</actor>
      <role>Sadanand</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mishra, Vivek</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nischol, Navin</actor>
      <role>J.K. Malhotra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Prakash, Gyan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>An orphaned and homeless girl ends up in a dancing school run by Sitaradevi and is named Doli, and is taught all forms of dance. When she matures she meets with London-based Suraj J. Malhotra and both fall in love with each other. Suraj is mesmerized by Doli's beauty and cannot live without her. When his father finds out that his son is wooing a prostitute, he is enraged, and contacts influential Dr. Ramgopal Acharya, to end this relationship so that he can get his son to get married to Damini, the daughter of wealthy Rajvansh. Ramgopal sets about to end this relationship and succeeds, with Suraj returning to London, while Sitaradevi is arrested by the Police for killing a man named Chowdhury, leaving Doli homeless. She seeks shelter in Ramgopal's ashram, where she is allowed entry reluctantly with hopes that she will leave soon. Then the inevitable happens when Ramgopal himself starts getting attracted to Doli's beauty, so much so that he is even willing to give his celibacy, his theory about sex before marriage, as well as prevent anyone from even coming near her!!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?108169</url></doc>
