<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="108472">
  <docid>108472</docid>
  <title>Clear and Present Danger: The Evolution of Modern Terrorism</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Aronowitz, Keith</editor>
  </editors>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">February 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">52</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Bailey, Joel (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>McAbian, Adi J.</producer>
    <producer>McAbian, Tal Dean</producer>
    <producer>Bailey, Joel (I)</producer>
    <producer>Weinstein, Aaron (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bailey, Joel (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Criden, David</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>CLEAR AND PRESENT DANGER - The Evolution of Modern Terrorism, takes an unflinching look at terrorism. From its roots in modern society, through it' historical evolution, to examining the organizational structure of terrorist groups today - Their recruitment, methodology, mission execution and target selection. The program investigates what geopolitical and economic environments enable these groups to flourish and wage traumatizing campaigns of horror placing entire societies under siege, what makes terror so effective and what drives terrorists to make the ultimate sacrifice. Finally, the program investigates the global war against terrorism by revealing the inner workings of intelligence and government agencies, anti-terrorist police forces, and elite military units. It also examines various deterrence mechanisms, border &amp; immigration controls, technological safeguards, monetary controls, but, most importantly, what preventative and humanitarian measures can be undertaken to curtail terrorist groups at their base and heal the wounds that have ripped our world apart. CLEAR AND PRESENT DANGER - The Evolution of Modern Terrorism features commentary and insight provided by Dr. Jonathan White, an expert in Middle-Eastern terrorism, an acclaimed author and an instructor of both the criminal justice and State and Local Anti-Terrorism Training Program with a background in law enforcement.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?108472</url></doc>
