<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="109512">
  <docid>109512</docid>
  <title>Coach</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Mahon, Mick</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Ireland</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Ireland">2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">53</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>McGrath, Liam (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Humphries, Tom (IV)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brown, Hope</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jacobson, Martin (IV)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Major, Larry</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Set against the backdrop of New York's failing public school system, Coach is a journey through the blood, sweat and tears of a High School sporting season. Players battle for a future as coaches act as mentors and guides in their fight to teach their student lessons that will help them in their future lives. Coach Martin Jacobson was a successful college coach before becoming a heroin addict, losing all of his possessions and nearly his life through drugs. Being a High School coach for Jacobson is some sort of redemption. He works with some of New York÷s poorest and most needy immigrant kids. Coach Larry Major has worked in Paul Robeson High School in Brooklyn for the past 10 years. After a crushing defeat in the City Championship final he passes on the school's main coaching position to an ex-student Todd Myles. Myles was en route to a lucrative NBA career when a serious back injury changed his career path last year. Myles has a lot to learn. Coach Major will have to do everything in his power to guide Myles through his first year of coaching.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?109512</url></doc>
