<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="110662">
  <docid>110662</docid>
  <title>Collateral Damage: Bad Medicine in Tennessee</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Rosenfeld, Lauren</editor>
    <editor>Winokur, Julie</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>disability</keyword>
    <keyword>healthcare</keyword>
    <keyword>medicaid</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">January 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">24</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Winokur, Julie</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Rosenfeld, Lauren</producer>
    <producer>Winokur, Julie</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>Addressing one of the most complex and critical issues facing America today - a health care system so badly broken that millions go without coverage and some 18,000 people die each year as a result. It recounts the toll on individuals and entire communities in Tennessee following the single largest Medicaid dis-enrollment in history. In 2005, when Governor Phil Bredesen of Tennessee announced he would reform his state's Medicaid program, people took him at his word. Little did they know that Bredesen's idea of reform meant cutting 190,0000 people off the program almost overnight. The size and speed of the cuts were unprecedented; the suffering they caused was immeasurable. The sickest, neediest people were denied medical care while the nation sat by and watched, and the Governor boasted to other heads of states about his success reigning in the rising cost of health care. The story is told through the eyes and emotions of Tennesseans struggling to get adequate care and those fighting to deliver care with strained resources. This intense, moving film exposes the injustice that occurred in Tennessee and its implications for Medicaid cuts nationwide. In the richest nation in the world, where people die every day because they lack access to health care, the disparities revealed in this film are chilling.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?110662</url></doc>
