<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="110869">
  <docid>110869</docid>
  <title>Colombian Interviews</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Pestes, Ronen</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Silberstein, Haim</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ezra, Tj</producer>
    <producer>Marino, Tori</producer>
    <producer>Michael, Joseph B.</producer>
    <producer>Silberstein, Haim</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Silberstein, Haim</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Camacho, Carlos Humberto</actor>
      <role>Alejandro</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Savage, John (I)</actor>
      <role>James</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In the tradition of Kurosawa's film RASHOMON (a story told in multiple points of view), COLOMBIAN INTERVIEWS is the story of ALEJANDRO, an illegal immigrant. Now sitting in jail, for a crime that unfolds throughout the film, his story of immigration is seen through the eyes of conflicting characters. All he has ever wanted was to live the American dream. Moving to Los Angeles, Alejandro receives a warm welcome from his Colombian community; but quickly learns that to achieve his American dream - assimilation - he must turn his back on his friends, community and disown his very culture. Coming from Bogotá, crime is everything he has always run away from. Life is hard as an immigrant in L.A. and, despite the crime ventures offered him, his pride keeps him out of trouble. Similar to Jake LaMotta in RAGING BULL, he stubbornly insists on doing it solo, moves out of the community, refuses to speak his own language and finally discards the woman who lovingly believes in him. His rigid rules and pride leave him desperately alone and with diminishing options. High and dry in a hopeless situation, he is sucked into the crime and his downfall. This disputed crime is revisited and reconstructed until we discover the truth.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?110869</url></doc>
