<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="111234">
  <docid>111234</docid>
  <title>Columbia World of Sports 8805: Polo</title>
  <year>1947</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Sport</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>polo</keyword>
    <keyword>hollywood</keyword>
    <keyword>one-reeler</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Passed</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">30 January 1947</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">10</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Foster, Harry (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Foster, Harry (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Smith, Cecil (III)</actor>
      <role>Himself - No. 1. Polo Player</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stern, Bill (I)</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A sports short about the game of Polo when the media of the time---radio, newspapers and newsreels---covered it like it was a sport that really mattered to the masses, most of which didn't know it existed. It was close to being the National Sport in most South-American countries, most of the British Empire in which the sun never set that somebody in India or Australia or the Mother Land wasn't scoring a chukker in Polo, and in the United States. Rajahs, sultans, dictators, kings, princes, Hollywood stars and the rich were the ones doing most of the playing, which was seen by very few, and played by even fewer. And the few that played it didn't play it very well, as they and their horses were usually pointed in the direction opposite the direction the ball was traveling. But one who played it as good as it was ever played was a Texan named Cecil Smith, the number-one rated player in the world for many years. He was to Polo what Pele was to soccer, and Tiger Woods is now to golf. They all played the game at a level the other players were't familiar with.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?111234</url></doc>
