<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="111201">
  <docid>111201</docid>
  <title>Columbarium</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Dudkowski, Edmond</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>grief</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">3 September 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">26</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Richard, Linda</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Richard, Linda</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Richard, Linda</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>COLUMBARIUM documents veteran TV news reporter Linda Richard's personal journey back in time to San Francisco of the 1960s, to re-imagine a young love lost there. Lost, and decades later, found. She is reunited with Robert, a boy she loved in high school. When she returns to live in San Francisco, they plan a wedding. Instead she must hold a memorial, an unexpected turn of fate that propels her forward with little warning into the mysteries of a San Francisco "sacred space." She must let go of Robert once again--to place his ashes in the beautiful and extraordinary Columbarium. Linda finds the people who inhabit the Columbarium, both the living and the dead, have stories to tell about what makes our individual lives meaningful. And about how the constancy of caring for one another is key to surviving the loss inherent in every life that risks love. As the Columbarium's caretaker/historian, Emmitt Watson explains, "We are all one. Not two. Not separate. But one." Public buildings can embody our personal histories. If the process of grief is the art of putting one foot in front of the other, the sound of Linda's footsteps on the Columbarium's marble floors is a metaphor for one of life's hardest journeys. Yet we find humor there, an an unexpected grace. As COLUMBARIUM ends, an echo of that bright smile -the smile belonging to the eighteen-year-old we meet in the yearbook photograph at the beginning of the film- flashes across the older woman's face.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?111201</url></doc>
