<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="112504">
  <docid>112504</docid>
  <title>Commit to the Line</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>McKenzie, Christopher (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>interview</keyword>
    <keyword>blood</keyword>
    <keyword>bicycle</keyword>
    <keyword>power</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>women</keyword>
    <keyword>friendship</keyword>
    <keyword>cancer</keyword>
    <keyword>mountain-biking</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">August 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">92</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Dermer, Rachelle A.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Cardaras, Mary</producer>
    <producer>Kaufman, Milissa L.</producer>
    <producer>Dermer, Rachelle A.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Dermer, Rachelle A.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kaufman, Jim (VII)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brown, Elladee</actor>
      <role>Coach</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carmichael, Sally</actor>
      <role>Camp Co-Founder</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dermer, Rachelle A.</actor>
      <role>Director</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grether, Nathalie</actor>
      <role>Coach</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jones, Joan (V)</actor>
      <role>Coach</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"Commit to the line!" is a phrase heard often in mountain biking and is shouted as direction and encouragement by the instructors at the Spokeswomen Mountain Bike Camps. A "line" in mountain biking is the route that the cyclist chooses to take in order to propel their bike down the mountain, across the trail, over obstacles, and carries an implicit warning: if you don't "commit to the line" that you have chosen, a crash will often ensue. Doubt and second thoughts in mountain biking often lead to unpleasant consequences. In order to successfully negotiate difficult terrain on a bike, you must choose a line and remain confident in that choice-the line must be followed through to completion for the best results. This serves as a metaphor for living one's life in a manner that is determined individually and internally, rather than externally by social and cultural pressures. Choosing a path and staying committed to that path, despite difficult obstacles, results in the most satisfying life. The film celebrates women choosing paths that are unexpected, interesting and gratifying, despite cultural and social constructs, which might dictate other choices. Commit to the Line is a celebration of triumph over cancer by the film's director; it is a celebration of women choosing their own course and overcoming fear and obstacles to find that they are vital and powerful in the world.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?112504</url></doc>
