<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="115102">
  <docid>115102</docid>
  <title>Cooking4Luv</title>
  <year>2011</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>digit-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>number-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>intentionally-misspelled-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2011</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Famuyiwa, Rick</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Anderson, Jocelyn (I)</producer>
    <producer>Le, Courtney</producer>
    <producer>Bracy, Tony</producer>
    <producer>Frear, Re'Shaun</producer>
    <producer>McQuarn, Michael</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bracy, Tony</writer>
    <writer>McQuarn, Michael</writer>
    <writer>Winkler, Dawn (I)</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Parker is an attractive, talented chef who runs Alonzo's, a soul food restaurant that serves up gourmet fare. The only problem is, Parker and Alonzo, the restaurant owner, are former lovers who must keep their past where it belongs in order to keep the restaurant running successfully. Alonzo seems to have moved on and found a new love in his life, but Parker is still looking for a new man, which keeps the tension in their kitchen high. At home, Alonzo is having a bit of difficulty integrating his new girlfriend into his life. His kids and his mother seem set on getting him back together with Parker. Meanwhile, with Parker's older sister engaged to be married, the pressure is on to find a new man. Parker's sisters take it upon themselves to set up an online dating profile for her, Cooking4Luv and within days, it seems she has found the man of her dreams. Unfortunately for Parker, things aren't always what they seem, and quickly life gets complicated, both in love and back in the kitchen.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?115102</url></doc>
