<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="115893">
  <docid>115893</docid>
  <title>Corrections</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Hunt, Ashley (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>private</keyword>
    <keyword>prison</keyword>
    <keyword>justice</keyword>
    <keyword>amnesty</keyword>
    <keyword>private-prison</keyword>
    <keyword>correctional-institution</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">25 January 2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">58</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Hunt, Ashley (I)</director>
  </directors>
<plot>Corrections is a story of justice turned to profit, where the war on crime has found new investors: Venture Capital and For-Profit Prisons, the story of the Private Prison. At a time when the US has achieved the highest rate of imprisonment in the world at a cost of $40 billion a year recent legislation like Proposition 36 in California (to give non-violent drug offenders treatment instead of prison) and films like Steve Sodeburg's TRAFFIC indicate a growing dissatisfaction with our war-on-drugs and tough-on-crime strategies. And at a time when our citizens are exposing big tobacco corporations and breaking up Microsoft, there is growing suspicion over corporate corruption as well. Corrections brings these growing concerns together with an innovative documentary in the tradition of filmmakers Emile Di Antonio and Erroll Morris, and such films as Roger and Me. CORRECTIONS weaves together portraits of the leading corporations, interviews with the world's leading experts and the stories of ordinary people, taking audiences behind the walls of one prison where they might not want you to leave.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?115893</url></doc>
