<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="115806">
  <docid>115806</docid>
  <title>Corporate InGREEDients</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>healthy</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film-making</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">28 February 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">76</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Burton, David (XII)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hess, Russell</producer>
    <producer>Wenzel III, J. Thomas</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Burton, David (XII)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ashey, Christopher</actor>
      <role>Consumer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bellino, Jennifer</actor>
      <role>Cardiologist</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carroll, Marlana</actor>
      <role>Health Care</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cullen, Caitlin</actor>
      <role>ER Doctor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dione, Colin</actor>
      <role>Food Industry</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dione, Matt</actor>
      <role>FDA</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dole, Doug (II)</actor>
      <role>Paramedic</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Douglas, Guy</actor>
      <role>Insurance</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hughes, Matt (VII)</actor>
      <role>Cardiac Nurse</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>St. Denis, John (II)</actor>
      <role>EMT</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Williams, Bob (XXVIII)</actor>
      <role>Bob</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In the documentary 'inGREEDients', registered nurse and filmmaker David Burton, discovers an alarming connection between diet and illness while investigating trans fats and hydrogenated oils in America's food supply. Do you know what a partially hydrogenated oil is? What does zero grams of trans fat per serving really mean? Find out in this compelling documentary that takes the audience on a time-line journey through the history of human food consumption from prehistoric times to the present, when heart disease is the number one killer of humans and despite recent changes in food labeling laws, pounds of trans fats are consumed everyday. This documentary features interviews with medical doctors, natural health doctors, scientists and researchers, politicians, journalists, and the lawyer that successfully stood up against two corporate food giants whose products are household names across America. The film also includes a brief look at heart disease, diabetes, and obesity, the three diseases most directly connected with our consumption of trans fats, chemical food additives, and processed food. With cutting edge animations rarely achieved in independent filmmaking, 'inGREEDients' will entertain, inspire, and educate all audiences of all ages.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?115806</url></doc>
