<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="116298">
  <docid>116298</docid>
  <title>Cossack Boys</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Adult</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>teenage-boy</keyword>
    <keyword>friendship-between-boys</keyword>
    <keyword>tradition</keyword>
    <keyword>male-bonding</keyword>
    <keyword>ukraine</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Ukrainian</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Ukraine</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Unrated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">64</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Kostenyuk, Igor</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Eisenlohr, David</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Stephens, Guy Russ</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Loosely translated, Cossack means "free people." Beginning in the 15th century, freedom and the willingness to fight for it, are exactly what this unique Ukrainian clan has become famous for. Throughout their long and colorful history, the Cossacks have been challenged often and hard. First by Turks and Tartars, and later by the shackles of 20th century communist rule. But in the end, these former serfs and slaves have prevailed in their quest for self-rule and independence. Today, the Cossacks fight a new battle, one to preserve their legendary heritage of courage, physical endurance and comradeship. What better way to accomplish this than through the time-honored order of "from father to son." In COSSACK BOYS you'll meet an appealing group of boys, including 13-year-old Senya, eager to master the world-renowned weaponry and horsemanship skills of their ancestors. Dressed in historical native garb, these amazing youngsters and their attentive mentors will sweep you up into a culture few westerners have ever been privileged to observe so intimately. Their gift to you is an enthralling viewing experience you will never forget.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?116298</url></doc>
