<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="116499">
  <docid>116499</docid>
  <title>Couch Potatoes</title>
  <year>1989</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">23 January 1989</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Alaskey, Joe</actor>
      <role>Announcer/Next Door Neighbor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McKrell, Jim</actor>
      <role>Announcer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Summers, Marc</actor>
      <role>Host</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Two teams of three players each stated themselves a sweet name in regards of a television show, past or present (e.g., "The Jeffersons," which spun-off "All In The Family"). In each round, each contestant (on a team) would answer a jump-in question. The contestant who gets the question right will win 25 points, and were given an opportunity to earn more points by answering 3 follow-up question about that very first one being answered. Host Summers would have each member of the team to only answer 1 question, and if the contestant gets it right, the teams still has control, an incorrect answer meant control goes over to their opposing team. Midway throughout the round, a popular TV show would come up on the monitor that a contestant had answered, a celebrity from that same TV series (e.g., Barbara Billingsley, of Leave it To Beaver, Gordon Jump, of WKRP in Cincinnati, Herve Villechaize, of Fantasy Island, Janice Pennington, of The Price is Right, Emmanuel Lewis, of Webster, etc.) would ask a question about what they did (or is doing) on the show alone. After all four rounds of questions, each team was given a chance to catch up by answering more questions that a random amount of money was won (using the randomizer) for each question answered correctly. If a team landed on "Couch-Up," (and if they're behind) must answer this question correctly to tie the teams' score. The team with the most point when the round was over wins $1000 and goes on to the Channel Roulette bonus game, while the other team gets "Cancelled" for not getting enough points onto their score. In the Channel Roulette bonus game, 1 member of each team would pick a VHF channel on TV, from 2-13 (meaning 12 monitors). At that point, the team had to identify what show (e.g., Dallas, Knots Landing, TV 101, F Troop, etc.) was in the picture. Each channel ranged in point values and they were each given 30 seconds to reach 1000 points or more to win $5000, within the time limit given. 3 players on 1 team alternated turns by selecting a channel to describe the television series. If they were right about that series, then the contestant will win whatever points was awarded, if the contestant gets it wrong or pass, and another monitor will be selected with different point values. If a contestant finds "PAY TV," then the team will lose all of their points that they have won up until then, and had to be tried again. If they didn't reach 1000 points, then its $1 for every point they obtained.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?116499</url></doc>
