<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="117277">
  <docid>117277</docid>
  <title>Covert Justice</title>
  <year>1999</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Ingvordsen, J. Christian</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ingvordsen, J. Christian</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zagarino, Frank</actor>
      <role>Frank White</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>As The new millennium approaches, the world has become vastly more dangerous and unstable. With the collapse of the Soviet Union, the superpower conflict has ended and a number of aggressive, rogue nations vie to fill the vacuum left by a splintered USSR. Terrorism, both international and domestic, has grown explosively. The United States recognizes the problem, but lacks the political will to meet it head on with direct military force. The National Security Agency has won the president's approval for a bold alternative. A highly trained covert team drawn from the ranks of the military's SPECOPS (Special Operations) Command and federal law enforcement will be tasked to apprehend those responsible for terrorist attacks and bring them back to the U.S. to face justice. The law enforcement element will be composed of agents from the Federal Bureau of Investigation, which by congressional statute is mandated to apprehend criminals on foreign soil. They will make the actual arrests and build cases that can be brought to trial in America. The SPECOPS contingent of Navy SEALS and aviators will get the team safely into various international hotspots and back out again with their prisoners. The unusual pedigree of the team leads to additional drama as an uneasy alliance is struck between the military and law enforcement elite. Frank White (Frank Zagarino), the team leader, must not only confront the dangers of the missions themselves, but the constant friction between the team members.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?117277</url></doc>
