<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="117886">
  <docid>117886</docid>
  <title>Craving</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Barany, Mitch</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>anorexia</keyword>
    <keyword>birth</keyword>
    <keyword>pregnancy</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">29 September 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">11</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Hirt, Christianne</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Brooker, Delphine</producer>
    <producer>Hirt, Christianne</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Brooker, Delphine</writer>
    <writer>Hirt, Christianne</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Tidsbury, Joshua</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Atkins, Jasmine</actor>
      <role>Young Delphine</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brooker, Delphine</actor>
      <role>Mother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Filipchuk, Eliza Brooker</actor>
      <role>Baby</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khouri, Jon-Paul</actor>
      <role>Sexy French Voice</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Craving is based on the award-winning stage play of the same title about one woman's descent into and recovery from anorexia. Craving the play follows a young woman whose hunger for life leads her out of high school to Europe for a year of adventure. The wonder and excitement of the young woman in Europe contrast with her downward spiral as she struggles with anorexia. At a low of 69 pounds, she realizes that her hunger for life can not co-exist with physical starvation, and she begins her road to recovery. The short film version of Craving adds yet another layer: it is told from the unique perspective of an expectant mother - a recovered anorexic - in her final weeks of pregnancy. Craving is an entirely original perspective on anorexia, contrasting a life-destroying disease with the ultimate act of creation - pregnancy and newborn life. The story juxtaposes three timelines - the present (the pregnancy), the past (the struggle with anorexia), and the future (the baby) - creating a metaphor for the circle of life that is central to the story. Craving's message, that life nourishes life, is at once universal in its theme, and particular to women at risk of anorexia as well as their family and friends.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?117886</url></doc>
