<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="117978">
  <docid>117978</docid>
  <title>Crazy Crosswords</title>
  <year>1994</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Game-Show</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Ciobo, Mark</director>
    <director>Laity, David</director>
    <director>Pyra, Chris</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ciobo, Mark</producer>
    <producer>Laity, David</producer>
    <producer>Pyra, Chris</producer>
    <producer>Wallace, Matt (V)</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Atherton, Jonathan</actor>
      <role>Steel Jensen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grose, Zara</actor>
      <role>Velvet</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pyra, Chris</actor>
      <role>Voiceover</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Saleh, Akmal</actor>
      <role>Bhutros Bhutros Bhutros Galic</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Swindells, Troy</actor>
      <role>Steel Jensen</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A disorganized game show that featured on Community Television Channel BRIZ 31 in Brisbane, Australia between 1994 and 1995. Two teams of two people made up the contestants who would have to buzz in with answers to crossword clues read out by the host, Steel Jensen. If the correct answer was given, the co-host, Velvet, would write the answer on a white board made up to look like a giant crossword puzzle. For each correct answer given, the host would throw a ping-pong ball at the team, who would put this in their basket as a form of scoring. The hosts were actors, thus their real names were not used in the program. The 1995 series saw a change of cast fronted by comedian Jonathan Atherton, which further added to the crazy shenanigans of the program, not to mention the appearance of special guests such as "Eugene", and Bhutros Bhutros Bhutros Galic, played by another comedian, Akmal Saleh. Craziness aside, the contestants did walk away with prizes at the end of the show - packets of nuts for the losers, and a range of theme park and other entry passes for the winners. Originally screening 7pm weeknights in direct competition with Sale of the Century, the show may not have been near as expensive to produce, but is certainly good for a laugh, even when watching repeats over a decade after its premiere.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?117978</url></doc>
