<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="118275">
  <docid>118275</docid>
  <title>Creativity with Bill Moyers</title>
  <year>1982</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Taverna, Kate</editor>
    <editor>Worth, Merle</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>interview</keyword>
    <keyword>artist</keyword>
    <keyword>musician</keyword>
    <keyword>writer</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">22 November 1982</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Worth, Merle</producer>
    <producer>McCarthy, Betsy</producer>
    <producer>Grinker, Charles</producer>
    <producer>Koplin, Mert</producer>
    <producer>Moyers, Bill</producer>
    <producer>Grubin, David</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Blumer, Ronald</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Angelou, Maya</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chicago, Judy</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dienes, Sari</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gordon, Mary (II)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gourley, Ted</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Huston, John (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lasseau, Bernie</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lear, Norman</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Micklus, Sam</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moyers, Bill</actor>
      <role>Himself - Host</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Raphaelson, Samson</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Scheck, Gerald</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Smith, Fred (X)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zukerman, Pinchas</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The series consists of these segments: {1) "Fred Smith, Corporate Creativity (The story of Federal Express)". In the first two years, Federal Express lost $29 million, but F. Smith held fast to his creative and revolutionary idea. Today his company is the most successful business in its field. Smith and his management team describe the original concept of Federal Express. (2) "Garbage -- Another way of seeing". Moyers meets and talks with some of the unusual people whose life work centers on what we throw away: an artist who makes discoveries from trash; worm farmers increasing productivity; and an anthropologist who is uncovering social customs. (3) "Inventors". Creative minds display their many and varied ways of coming up with superior ideas. (4) "John Huston". Huston began his career as a painter and a writer. Later, he came to Hollywood and with the assistance of his father, actor Walter Huston, he began a career directing. (5) "Maya Angelou". Angelou returns to her home town where they make note of the ways that her memories and experience impinge on art. (6) "National Center for Atmospheric Research". In eastern Montana, over 100 scientists and technicians spend each day peering into the sky studying weather and climate and how they affect our lives. (7) "Olympics of the Minds". In New Jersey, educators Ted Gourley and Sam Micklus began an extracurricular school program that has been adopted by more than 1000 schools throughout the country. This program explores ways in which creative thought can be taught and practiced in schools to inspire, enthuse and encourage students to stretch their minds. (8) "Out Art". Moyers suggests that artist confirm the "inner disorder born of chance" as an important stimulus to create new designs, art advertising and even new elements in our society. (9) "Painter/sculptor/welder, Gerald Scheck". Moyers explores the painter's sense of purpose and his unconscious drives and feeling about the meaning of his work. Artist Gerald Scheck sees an "unconscious will" directing his efforts, claiming he doesn't attempt to express it in a painting; it just happens. (10) "Pinchas Zukerman and the St. Paul Chamber Orchestra". Pinchas Zukerman, one of the world's master violinists, takes on a new musical direction by becoming director of the St. Paul Chamber Orchestra. (11) "Portrait of Samson Raphaelson". Raphaelson has written nine plays for the stage and close to twenty for the screen, and most of them were big hits. This program explores his genius, his imagination and his career. (12) "That's no Tomato, that's a Work of Art!". The tomato is one of America's favorite vegetables and the average American consumes 50 pounds of tomatoes or more each year. Thousands of varieties have been developed, but a surprising amount of creative effort is still being poured into producing more profitable and valuable tomatoes. (13) "Women and Creativity". Moyers interviews three women about the choices between a life of creativity and raising a family. Viewers meet artist Judy Chicago, an ardent feminist; Bernie Lasseau, a rural artist; and best#selling novelist Mary Gordon. (14) "The World of Norman Lear, Part 1: The Creative Process". With a string of remarkable successes, such as "All in the Family," "The Jeffersons" and "Maude," writer#producer Norman Lear has shown that millions of TV viewers can enjoy provocative and sensitive entertainment. (15) "The World of Norman Lear, Part 2: The Creative Person". For Norman Lear, the writer's craft depends on an ability to draw on the sights and sounds of life. This program explores Lear's philosophy of writing and creativity. (16) "Young at Art -- New York High School for the Performing Arts". Ambitious young people struggle to become actors, musicians or dancers in addition to passing the required academic courses for their diploma. The program explores the creativity of self#discovery which these high school students exhibit.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?118275</url></doc>
