<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="119113">
  <docid>119113</docid>
  <title>Critical Hours</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Isler, Jim</editor>
    <editor>Isler, Tom</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Reality-TV</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">14 September 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">22</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Isler, Jim</director>
    <director>Kail, Thomas</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Isler, Jim</producer>
    <producer>Isler, Tom</producer>
    <producer>Kail, Thomas</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Isler, Jim</writer>
    <writer>Isler, Tom</writer>
    <writer>Kail, Thomas</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Veneziale, Anthony</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This pilot episode focuses on the world of competitive Lego robotics in New York City. It trails three teams from public schools in the Bronx, Chinatown, and Queens, as they prepare for a competition against 150 of New York's schools. Critical Hours introduces audiences not only to the scientists of tomorrow, but also to the unsung heroes who make it all possible: the teachers. Meet Ms. Vaughan whose patience and enthusiasm are priceless commodities as she launches a robotics program in the Bronx. Meet Mr. Lee, whose steady hand guides his young team to new heights. And meet Mr. Wright, whose intensity and innovative thinking redefine the rules of the game. On tournament day, the atmosphere is electric. The gymnasium is packed with parents, siblings and school cheerleaders. A deejay spins thumping techno music as the schools wage robo-battle. Taking first place is on every student's mind, but even before the first points are recorded, the success of the program is secure, and winner is our collective future.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?119113</url></doc>
