<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="120432">
  <docid>120432</docid>
  <title>Cuando lloran los valientes</title>
  <year>1947</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Martínez, Fernando (III)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>mexican-revolution</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Mexico</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Mexico">8 January 1947</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">105</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Rodríguez, Ismael (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Carmona, Luis (I)</writer>
    <writer>González, Rogelio A.</writer>
    <writer>Manrique, Arturo (I)</writer>
    <writer>Peña, José (I)</writer>
    <writer>Rodríguez, Ismael (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Lavista, Raúl</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arriaga, Jorge (I)</actor>
      <role>Officer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Astol, Paco</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Casado, Eduardo (I)</actor>
      <role>General Manuel Arteche</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Derba, Mimí (I)</actor>
      <role>Cristina's Mother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dondé, Manuel</actor>
      <role>Soldier</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Frausto, Antonio R.</actor>
      <role>Don Isauro</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>González, Rogelio A.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Infante, Pedro</actor>
      <role>Agapito Treviño 'Caballo Blanco'</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Isunza, Agustín</actor>
      <role>Uncle Laureano</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mendoza, Víctor Manuel</actor>
      <role>Colonel José Luis Arteche</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nava, Pepe</actor>
      <role>Largo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Peón, Ramón</actor>
      <role>Executed man</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Plaza Balboa, Rafael</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Quiroz, Salvador</actor>
      <role>General Ampudia</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Roche, Joaquín</actor>
      <role>Pepe, El Pinolillo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Soto La Marina, Armando</actor>
      <role>Cleofas</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vallarino, Ramón</actor>
      <role>Edmundo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ávila, Leopoldo</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The story centers around the brave and valiant Agapito who rescues the orphaned Pinolillo and is set to marry the beautiful Cristina. However his plans are foiled when he is forced to go on the run from the Federales after he lies to protect his horses. Meanwhile, his half-sister Chavela runs away from home spreading the rumor that Agapito seduced her and they have fled together. In fact she goes to see Jose Luis Arteche and seduces him. Arteche however, is in also in love with Cristina, and uses this rumor to woo her away from Agapito. Once Agapito learns of this news, he heads off to find Cristina and Chavela to set the record straight and put his marriage back on track with Cristina. Chavela however throws a spanner in the works, confesses her love for Agapito and convinces him to marry her for the sake of their father. In the meantime, Cristina's brother Edmundo is told to send a message from the Federales to the rebels detailing his supposed treachery, but was tricked by Jose Luis Arteche making the rebels shoot the messenger. He was thankfully rescued at the last minute by Agapito's men who then find the letter regarding Jose Luis Arteche's betrayal. As Agapito patches things up with Cristina, he is captured by Arteche's men. In a reversal of fortunes Jose Luis Arteche is about to let Agapito go free in exchange for keeping quiet about the letter. Just at that very moment Arteche's father, the General walks in, reads the letter about his son's treason, and orders the assassination of both men at dawn the following day. Meanwhile, Chavela's father, Don Isauro, learns of Agapito's imminent execution and the race is on to inform the General that the other man he is going to kill is in fact his son. As Don Isauro rushes in at the last minute to rescue Agapito, Jose Luis Arteche seizes the opportunity to flee. In a twist of fate, Don Isauro rallies his troops to fight the General and unfortunate consequences for Cristina.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?120432</url></doc>
