<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="120425">
  <docid>120425</docid>
  <title>Cuando las mujeres mandan</title>
  <year>1951</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>González, Mario (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Cuba</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Cuba">1951</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>González-Prieto, José M.</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Fernández, José (XII)</writer>
    <writer>Pérez-Blanco, Armando</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Artigas, Aidita</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Benguría, Xonia</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chávez, Marcelo</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dago, Emilita</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Garrido, Alberto</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jar, Fela</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Montalvan, Jorge</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Orefiche, Armando</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Piñero, Federico</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Valdés, Germán</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This musical comedy features one of Cuba's most legendary comedy acts: "Garrido and Piñero" who play the part of two Cuban nationals that somehow are fighting in the Korean war and decide to get away from the conflict. They take over an abandoned plane and fly away landing in an unknown country where women reign and men are condemned to be second class citizens... They are received as enemies and sent to prison but somehow they manage to conquer the favors of the two females who run the country (Xonia Benguria and Olga Uz). However, they are treated by these women like sex toys so they decide to lead an all-male revolution against the establishment. After the success of the uprising, women are put in their places and the dynamic duo replace their girlfriends as the ultimate authorities in this new society. Everyone is happy and join in a conga line that leads to THE END. This incredible trashy film is just an excuse to show well developed women in sexy military outfits. The musical numbers are compelling thanks to Cuban vedettes Aidita Artigas and Sandra plus the remarkable musician Armando Orefiche with his Havana Cuban Boys. It is also interesting to note that the dialog is full of references to "revolution," "counterrevolution," "human rights," , etc., considering that this film was made in Cuba one year before the Batista coup and eight years before the Castro take over.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?120425</url></doc>
