<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="120635">
  <docid>120635</docid>
  <title>Cuban Fire</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <editors>
    <editor>Davis, Ken (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="France">11 May 2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">93</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Ramsay, Brian (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Christie, Edward N.</producer>
    <producer>Crupi, Francesca</producer>
    <producer>Marchello, Frank</producer>
    <producer>Savia, Emile</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>This unique feature film explores the rich history and global influences of the Cuban music through rousing live performances by world-renowned contemporary Cuban artists as well as moving interviews and rare historic footage. Shot entirely in Cuba, captivating visuals and locations, CubanFire quickly and intimately familiarizes its audience with the emotional power and historical prowess of Cuban Music. Cuban Fire Demonstrates the intoxicating energy that has only increased throughout the centuries. CubanFire opens with two brief interviews the explodes with a title song composed by Edesio Alejandro over opening credits with a compliation Cubana visual, introducing our 16 talented artist, including world renowned Juan De Marcos and the Afro Cuban All-Stars, Barbarito Torres, Edesio Alejandro, and Candido Fare. CubanFire explores the styles and varities of Cuban music with performances of rhythms of Guaguanco, Son, Cancion/Bolero, Muscia Campesina, Cha Cha Cha, Pregun, Timba, Nuevo Son, Latin Jazz Cubano, Classica, Changui, Guajiro Son, Acid Son, Merengue, and Son Oriente. CubanFire interwines in this mixture of talented musicians, "real people"; a poet, Eloy Lambia; a painter, Salvador Gonzalez, and a musical dedication to Che Guevara, utilizing original vintage footage. CubanFire represents the culmination of years of research and admiration of the Cuban Musical Artform and presents the Cuban musical reality in a fresh and comprehensive style. CubanFire is a music film project created from the heart.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?120635</url></doc>
