<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="121928">
  <docid>121928</docid>
  <title>Curse of the Bands</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Karim, Shahid (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">21 April 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">33</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Karim, Shahid (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Karim, Shahid (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Karim, Shahid (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Karim, Saleena</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ahmed, Sharjeel</actor>
      <role>Puck</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ansari, Safdar</actor>
      <role>Steve</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ayub, Faraz</actor>
      <role>Ciggy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brown, Adam (XXI)</actor>
      <role>Todd Jackson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Butler, Jack (V)</actor>
      <role>Face</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Karim, Shahid (II)</actor>
      <role>Reece Blu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Savage, John (VII)</actor>
      <role>Tommy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Suleman, Asif</actor>
      <role>Security Guard</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Reece Blu is a good guy but is stuck living in the crime ridden fictional town based in the UK midlands. He works for Steve in a metal fabrication shop. Reece hopes to one day open his very own school of self defence so people can fight back against the local thugs who rule the neighbourhood. Together with his two eccentric student friends Puck and Tommy, Reece embarks on a journey to bring peace to the citizens of the town. That's where things get strange... One evening local thugs the "Mad Lads" Todd Jackson and his partner in crime Cliff "Ciggy" Sampson plan a raid to steal metal Reece works in. They bring along a hired hand known only as 'Face', Todd decides to make a quick buck by raiding the shop - but Reece defends it and the gang get away with only one of two ancient "Chi Bracelets" Steve the owner of the store brought on the internet. According to legend these cursed artifacts were designed to enhance the wearers' personal abilities (at the cost of life energy). By wearing both the wearer is granted invincibility and immortality - but by doing so he incurs the "Curse of The Bands" Only later do Reece and Todd learn the truth behind the "special abilities." When they do, Reece plans to use them as a force of good for the town and Todd will stop at nothing to get the other half back and achieve 'immortality' and rule the neighbourhood.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?121928</url></doc>
