<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="122149">
  <docid>122149</docid>
  <title>Cut-Up: The Films of Grant Munro</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
  </genres>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">9 December 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">110</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Canemaker, John</actor>
      <role>Interviewer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McLaren, Norman</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Munro, Grant</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>To encounter the work of Grant Munro is to discover an artist of inimitable talent and charm. Whether as animator, documentarian, actor, dancer, editor, cinematographer, or general provocateur, his talent, humor, passion, and all-out goofiness have graced the world of cinema for more than fifty years. He is a combination of Joan Miró, Buster Keaton, Chuck Jones, Gene Kelly and Felix the Cat. There is no one like Grant Munro. Munro collaborated with legendary animator Norman McLaren on some of his best-known work. Their amazing pixilated masterpiece Neighbours, a viciously funny Cold War parable on arms escalation, won the best short film Oscar® in 1953. Included on Cut-Up are the animated classics Three Blind Mice, Neighbours, Two Bagatelles, Christmas Cracker, Canon, Toys and The Animal Movie. This compilation also showcases Munro's hilarious work in live-action films including The Ballot-o-Maniac, Ashes of Doom and Boo Hoo. A special treat for animation fans are two films that Munro and McLaren shot but never completed, Six and Seven Eighths and On the Farm. Recently rediscovered and edited by the National Film Board of Canada, they make their world premieres here.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?122149</url></doc>
