<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="122570">
  <docid>122570</docid>
  <title>Czech Tag Team 1</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adult</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>masturbation</keyword>
    <keyword>ejaculation</keyword>
    <keyword>gay-sex</keyword>
    <keyword>anal-sex</keyword>
    <keyword>jock-strap</keyword>
    <keyword>gay</keyword>
    <keyword>sex</keyword>
    <keyword>wrestling</keyword>
    <keyword>homosexual</keyword>
    <keyword>pornography</keyword>
    <keyword>hardcore</keyword>
    <keyword>oral-sex</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">X</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">22 February 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Andrews, Emmett</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hanak, Ales (I)</actor>
      <role>Jarda</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Jirka and Jarda showed up at Can-Am one day, looking to wrestle - who were we to say no? First we put the two chiseled muscle gods up against each other, and then pitted them against some American strength. The result is pure tingling heat as they progress from singles to speedo and jockstrap to full nudity. Besides countless submission holds, the boys obviously know the advantage of fighting dirty with plenty of nipple twists, ball grabs, and crotch squeezes. When Jarda finally submits, he opens his mouth to Jirka's big dick. Jirka is alpha dog and waste no time proving Jarda is the bitch by fucking his friend deep into the pit. Czech mate! With Jirka all cocky from his win, he's first up in the Czech vs. USA battle with Andrews while Jarda recovers. Andrews is a fighter from God Bless - America Ohio, and he's ready to heat up the Cold War. In singlet and under wear ripping action he does our country proud, but ultimately Jirka takes the match grinding Andrews' face into the pit with full nelson. The Stars and Stripes flies at half mast while Andrews takes care of Jirka's flagpole, but just wait for America to strike back in Part 2.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?122570</url></doc>
