<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="125478">
  <docid>125478</docid>
  <title>Dance of the Goblins</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>goblin</keyword>
    <keyword>shape-shifter</keyword>
    <keyword>male-female-relationship</keyword>
    <keyword>magic</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="UK">12A</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">112</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Greenway, Nathan Richard</producer>
    <producer>Channing, Denise</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Hawkins, Jaq</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Bard, Damh Thye</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cherry (XIV)</actor>
      <role>Dani</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Draven, Greg</actor>
      <role>Kahjak</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Goodman, Robert (I)</actor>
      <role>Paul</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Majere, Wendy</actor>
      <role>Oenikemi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sands, Graeme</actor>
      <role>Count Victor</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Many scientists believe that about every 200,000 years, a magnetic pole shift flips the axis of the earth, resulting in sudden and devastating climate change and planet-wide devastation. We are overdue. Five generations after the next 'Turning', the descendants of the few surviving humans carve out a medieval-like existence in the rubble of a ruined city of London. Meanwhile, the goblins live a shamanic, anarchic lifestyle and stay unseen by humans for their own survival. Until one day a human wanders into one of the forgotten underground stations where he is captured and drugged with a mushroom potion that causes memory loss, then expelled. A search party happens to see one of the goblins, and the humans try to dig out the 'demons'. A goblin woman is taken captive but escapes, and it is up to the leader of the humans, Count Anton, to find her and return her to her people. Count Anton's secret friendship with Haghuf, a respected elder among the goblins, as well as his love for their world is compromised as war between humans and goblins becomes unavoidable. It is a war the humans cannot possibly win. Divided loyalties, survival, and growing love for the goblin woman whose world he can never really be a part of challenge Count Anton to find a way to save his own people from their own folly, and from the warrior goblins who have barred his entrance into their world.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?125478</url></doc>
