<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="125524">
  <docid>125524</docid>
  <title>DanceCrazy Presents: Learn to Dance Foxtrot - A Beginners Guide to Dancing the Foxtrot</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>dancing</keyword>
    <keyword>instructional</keyword>
    <keyword>dance</keyword>
    <keyword>fox-trot</keyword>
    <keyword>steps</keyword>
    <keyword>ballroom</keyword>
    <keyword>how-to</keyword>
    <keyword>learn</keyword>
    <keyword>foxtrot</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 January 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Margolin, Evan</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Margolin, Evan</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bryce, Eldon</actor>
      <role>Dance Instructor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hurwitz, Alison</actor>
      <role>Dance Instructor</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Want to embody the essence of Frank Sinatra's fantastic music combined with Fred and Ginger's grace and style? The Foxtrot will make it happen for you! Foxtrot epitomizes elegance, class, and big band sophistication. Popularized at the beginning of the 20th century by vaudeville performers, Fox's Trot was quickly adopted by ballrooms across the nation and transformed into the dance we know as Foxtrot today. Foxtrot not only showcases grace and flair, but also combines it with the swingin' sounds of some of our best loved jazz musicians. It is easy to learn, and extremely popular at a wide variety of events, parties, and weddings. In fact, Foxtrot is one of the most versatile dances you'll ever try! DanceCrazy's Beginning Foxtrot DVD is the perfect way to get started! This comprehensive DVD takes you through each pattern with clear instruction, multiple camera angles, helpful tips, and practice with music. The friendly teachers make learning to Foxtrot easy and great fun. Bring out your inner Fred or Ginger, and learn to Foxtrot with confidence!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?125524</url></doc>
