<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="126323">
  <docid>126323</docid>
  <title>Danji geudaega yeojalaneun iyumaneulo</title>
  <year>1990</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kim, Hyun</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>feminism</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Korean</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>South Korea</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="South Korea">18</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="South Korea">29 September 1990</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Korea">105</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Kim, Yu-jin</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ko, Gyu-seob</producer>
    <producer>Shin, Chul</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Lee, Yun-taek</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Lee, Seung-hie</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lee, Kyeong-yeong</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lee, Yeong-ha</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>An innocent, though anything but naive, woman is in the wrong place at the wrong time. While waiting for her more adventurous friend outside a seedy dance bar, she is approached by two men who ''naturally'' assume that any woman hanging around such a joint is looking for action. Even with their certain alcohol and testosterone overloads, they could not possibly interpret her rejections as merely playing hard to get. But hey, they only gave her what was coming to her, right? I mean, what was she doing hanging around a place like that at that time of night, anyways? This episode proceeds through the mens' idea of foreplay. But, although the woman's experience must certainly have been traumatic, she manages to avoid penetration by maiming her prospective rapists in an almost comical way. You can imagine her disbelief when, after her friends and family discourage her from pressing charges, she is informed that her attacker has the impudence to charge her with assault. Her strength throughout the rest of the movie is admirable, as she remains rational among her incredibly irrational (yet typical) contemporaries.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?126323</url></doc>
