<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="127184">
  <docid>127184</docid>
  <title>Dark Heart</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Frenette, Rob</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Butler, Robert Joseph</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Karns, Aaron</producer>
    <producer>Butler, Robert Joseph</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Butler, Robert Joseph</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anton, John</actor>
      <role>Detective Al Jenkins</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Doom, Jimmy</actor>
      <role>Younger Mr. Saxon</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jhames, Tiren</actor>
      <role>Daniel Saxon</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McKenzie, Fred</actor>
      <role>Mr. Saxon</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Daniel Saxon is an aspiring writer with a life that mirrors the twisted world he habits: vacant. Abandoned. Burnt-out and fragile. Barely making ends meet through a dead-end job at a thankless slaughterhouse, Daniel keeps to himself, struggling to finish both his novel-in-progress and the unwritten story of his life. As Daniel continues to right, Daniel begins to struggle against his dormant inner demons - cryptic memories from his past come to haunt him. Nightmares of an old man, a child, and a deafening heartbeat plague him without remorse, keeping his relationship with Lauren from blossoming... and matters are only complicated when they begin spilling over into reality. Already emotionally vulnerable, Daniel finds his senile, estranged father thrust back into his life without warning, and it soon becomes evident that the old man's past evils hold the key to Daniel's anguish. Soon, Daniel's novel, day job, and love life are thrown to the wayside as he cares for his father, and he is forced down a dark journey of insanity, hatred, writer's block, and murder - and the consequences that ultimately arise.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?127184</url></doc>
