<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="127239">
  <docid>127239</docid>
  <title>Dark Night</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Grant, Daniel (V)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>british</keyword>
    <keyword>cult-favorite</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>cult</keyword>
    <keyword>b-movie</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">19 July 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Grant, Daniel (V)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Grant, Robin (II)</producer>
    <producer>Grant, Robin (III)</producer>
    <producer>Woodcock, George (I)</producer>
    <producer>Grant, Daniel (V)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Grant, Daniel (V)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Bateman, Peter</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fenty, Belinda</actor>
      <role>Felicity</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grant, Daniel (V)</actor>
      <role>Dan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grezo, Chris</actor>
      <role>Will</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maestranzi, Adriana</actor>
      <role>Laura</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maidment, Isabella</actor>
      <role>Tanya</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mcleod, Stephen</actor>
      <role>Johnny</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Noble, Anthony (II)</actor>
      <role>Tony</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stein, Vaughn</actor>
      <role>Tristan</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>An abandoned house and a group of friends. A party. But why has the house been abandoned? What happened there? A clever psychological thriller that unfolds a frightening story through the eyes of each character. The script twists and turns and nothing is as it first seems... Patrick Morgan sits in his room late at night finishing his coursework. Once done he collapses on his bed in exhaustion, relived it's all over. The next day both he and his family are dead. The group are on their way to the long abandoned Morgan family house; once infamous with their unsolved murders, now renowned amongst teenagers for being a great social venue! The party is great fun; drinks, drugs and sex - it's all good...;until something which should never have been unearthed is discovered. Who killed the Morgans? Was it the father? A psychopathic killer? A monstrous beast lurking in the woods? Or is there something else at work which no-one dares think about? Thrills and chills galore in this stylish shlock horror. Shot on a shoestring budget and with echoes of 'The Evil Dead' series and others from the genre, this is a true blood and guts experience! The group of teenagers get more than they bargained for at the abandoned house, pitting their wits against monsters, the undead and each other This is a British B-movie with big bite, definitely not for the faint of heart nor the weak of stomach! Will you survive the dark night?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?127239</url></doc>
