<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="130132">
  <docid>130132</docid>
  <title>Dav Pech</title>
  <year>1989</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">1989</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Sharma, Kawal</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Padmini (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Malik, Anu</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhanupriya</actor>
      <role>Inspector Sunita Verma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chandrashekhar</actor>
      <role>Police Commissioner</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chopra, Prem</actor>
      <role>K.K.</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Christo, Bob</actor>
      <role>Gambler</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dhawan, Sunil</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dubey, C.S.</actor>
      <role>Molester</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hingoo, Dinesh</actor>
      <role>Sikander's victim</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Irani, Manik</actor>
      <role>Sampat</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jeetendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Sikander/Bajrangi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Joshi, Renu</actor>
      <role>Bajrangi's Kaki</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kamaldeep</actor>
      <role>Police Inspector</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Neeta</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Sangeeta</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Shakti (I)</actor>
      <role>Dhurjan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Singh, Gurbachchan</actor>
      <role>Sharda's molester</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Bajrangi and his sister, Sharda, lives in a small village in Central India, and have been orphaned at a very young age. Since Sharda is of marriageable age, Bajrangi arranges for a suitable groom whose dad will approve of this marriage provided he gets a dowry of ten thousand Rupees. Bajrangi does come up with the money and the wedding date is set. While getting some milk for her brother, Sharda gets molested by the dairy farm Manager and his employees, but Bajrangi comes to her rescue. This incident castes aspirations against Sharda, and the price of the dowry is doubled. Unable to pay this amount, and stand the taunts of villagers, the siblings, accompanied by their Kaki, re-locate to Bombay. Upon arrival, they find a small apartment and Bajrangi goes looking for employment. While walking, he is recognized by several people, who call him "Sikander". No one believes him when he refutes this, instead he is abducted by an underworld Don, K.K., and subjected to shock treatment. Thereafter, he is abducted by another gang-leader, Dhurjan, and severely beaten. All the gangsters want is a diary that was purportedly written by Sikander. Bajrangi escapes, only to have the thugs follow and abduct him, as well as Sharda, and it looks it is going to be the end of the road for the siblings at the hands of gangsters - for whom killing is a daily routine.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?130132</url></doc>
