<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="130806">
  <docid>130806</docid>
  <title>Days of the Pentecost</title>
  <year>1995</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <editors>
    <editor>Elbert, Lawrence</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Musical</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>homosexual</keyword>
    <keyword>cross-dressing</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">75</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Elbert, Lawrence</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Gardner, Mario</producer>
    <producer>Winski, Debbie</producer>
    <producer>Crosby, Brandon</producer>
    <producer>Elbert, Lawrence</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Elbert, Lawrence</writer>
    <writer>Gardner, Mario</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arquette, Alexis</actor>
      <role>Mechanic</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gardner, Mario</actor>
      <role>Melena</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kuiland-Nazario, Marcus</actor>
      <role>Carmen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pearson, Andre</actor>
      <role>Mendi Overme</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Days of Pentecost is a feature-length drag action/adventure musical road movie. Inspired by Russ Meyer's 60's exploitation classic Faster, Pussycat! Kill! Kill!, wherein three busty go-go dancers revolt against patriarchal oppression under the hot desert sun. Their leader, Melena D' la Moja, guides the girls with a sharp tongue and a strong arm through the desert in their search for peace, acceptance, and a man. One that won't fuck them over again and again. Melena is joined by Carmen, a feisty Puerto Rican whose search for her Red Bagota lipstick brings about many a slap fight with the other girl, Mendie Overme. After a hostile confrontation with an audience member during one of their dance numbers in West Hollywood, the girls flee the big city, only to have their car break down in a small town. There, they must contend with a closeted homophobic homosexual auto mechanic who sees them as a threat to the delicate web of lies in which he lives. A sinister game of cat and mouse ensues as the girls wait for their fan belt to be delivered to the mechanic. Using their ever helpful gay guide, Melena and company find the nearest gay bar and abduct one of the locals. Lashing out against human stupidity, they oscillate between impromptu musical numbers and torturing their closeted gay hostage. Seduced into a moment of weakness by the mechanic, Mendie allows the hostage to escape. And elaborate chase scene follows as the mechanic and hostage try to escape the grasps of the incensed drag queens.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?130806</url></doc>
