<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="132670">
  <docid>132670</docid>
  <title>De zakbibliothecaris van de Veldstraat</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Volckaert, Didier</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Biography</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>French</language>
    <language>English</language>
    <language>Dutch</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Belgium</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Belgium">2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Belgium">37</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Volckaert, Didier</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Van Dienderen, An</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Volckaert, Didier</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Flirting with fact and fiction, using old school animation techniques and 'State of the Art' digital image processing, Didier Volckaert and An van. Dienderen create a story about an archive in Ghent, named 'Ephemera', its conceiver Ferdinand Vander Haeghen and the Ghent shop street "Veldstraat". This collection belongs to the University of Ghent and consists of very diverse pieces, such as a wing of a bird, bags to contain food, medicines, and fruit, artful leaflets, fragile books and prestigious visit cards. This collection was created by Ferdinand Vander Haeghen (1830-1913+). Fascinating about it was the credo of this genius librarian: "Do not throw away any document." This contrasts sharply with the gigantic quantities of terabytes, which have been made possible by the digital world. In the spirit of this crazy but innovative librarian, the filmmakers dive into this collection to evoke the Veldstraat. They take the viewer on an expedition to People with Stories, and to the history of the street. Baker Bloch, former workers of the shopping hall INNO/GB, several shopkeepers, the director of the Ghent department for Monument Care and the current principal librarian of the University of Ghent, they all present their story on how seemingly unnoticeable daily life in de Veldstraat has drastically changed over the years.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?132670</url></doc>
