<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="132807">
  <docid>132807</docid>
  <title>Dead Canaries</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Pagano, Carl (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">85</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Santoli, Robert</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Santoli, Robert</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Moira, Lissa</writer>
    <writer>Santoli, Robert</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Pagano, Carl (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Archambault, Neville</actor>
      <role>Robert Santoli</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bonsignore, Angelo</actor>
      <role>Johny's Partner</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Caso, Anthony</actor>
      <role>Reporter #2</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Durning, Charles</actor>
      <role>Jimmy Kerrigan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fox, Brandon (I)</actor>
      <role>Nicky DeMartino</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gianino, Gian-Murray</actor>
      <role>Jonny</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gio, Frank</actor>
      <role>Carmine 'The Boss' Luciano</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Higgins, Joel (I)</actor>
      <role>Alan Weis</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lauria, Dan</actor>
      <role>Vito Scaldafieri</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lombard, Michael</actor>
      <role>Mayor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lutkin, Chris</actor>
      <role>Frank</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McGuire, Bryan Michael</actor>
      <role>FBI Agent</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vaz, Marty</actor>
      <role>The Assassin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zayas, Anthony</actor>
      <role>Tommy</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>When small-time mobster, Vito Scaldifieri, is framed for the murder of an undercover Federal Agent, he has two choices - face the death sentence or "sing" to the Feds for their case against mob boss Paulie DeMartino. Though telling all to the government goes against every fiber of his being, he knows it's the only way to save his life and, more importantly, guarantee the safety of his beloved wide Sharon. After a trial in which Paulie is indicted, Vito and Sharon are given new identities and placed into the Witness Portection Program. What they aren't told, however, is that in recent months, several mobsters under government protection have been assassinated in cities and towns all over the country. How they were being found and killed was anyone's guess. Jimmy Kerrigan, a tough, old-school newspaper reporter, begins investigating the Witness Protection Program killings. After winning Sharon's trust he becomes a confidante to both husband and wife throughout Vito's trial, imprisonment and placement into the Program. Jimmy digs deeply into both the underworld and the government in his search for answers. With the help of informants, friends and gangland insiders, he discovers that there's much more gong on than mobsters being rubbed out. In fact, Jimmy uncovers a secret plot that is far more ominous and far reaching. The question is, will Jimmy learn the truth in time to save Vito from being added to the growing list of Dead Canaries?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?132807</url></doc>
