<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="132913">
  <docid>132913</docid>
  <title>Dead Hooker in a Trunk</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Wallis, C.J.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">20 April 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">92</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bateman, Loyd</producer>
    <producer>Charge, Donald</producer>
    <producer>Soska, Agnes</producer>
    <producer>Soska, Marius (II)</producer>
    <producer>Van Graven, Mary Ann</producer>
    <producer>Soska, Jen</producer>
    <producer>Soska, Sylvia</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Wallis, C.J.</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barkes, David</actor>
      <role>Motel Manager</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bateman, Loyd</actor>
      <role>Priest</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bell, Jamie (II)</actor>
      <role>Weirdo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gagne, Rikki</actor>
      <role>Junkie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gallardo, Carlos (I)</actor>
      <role>God</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gulayets, John J.</actor>
      <role>Sketchy Guy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tench, John</actor>
      <role>Cowboy Pimp</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wallis, C.J.</actor>
      <role>Goody Two-Shoes</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Set in beautiful Vancouver, four friends set out on an everyday errand and end up in a fight for their lives when they discover the body of a dead hooker left in their trunk. Lead by a sexy, impulsive Badass, her distant Geek twin sister, their bible thumping, Jesus loving Goody Two Shoes friend, and a chaotic, rock star Junkie pal, the group has to put aside their differences to dispose of the body before they're next. Thrown into their own personal purgatory, they face off against persistent police, a sleazy motel manager, chainsaw wielding triads, and a brutal serial killer. All the while they are followed by a mysterious Cowboy Pimp who wants to claim the corpse for his own. Will they uncover the truth behind the body and be able to stand up to their demons? Buckle up and get ready for the ride of your life filled with gun fights, extreme violence, blood, guts, gore, and goats. Dead Hooker In A Trunk is the unexpected first feature film written, directed, and produced by identical twin sisters, Jen and Sylvia Soska. The two newcomers created an impossible film that is an underground sensation, destined to become a cult classic and will make you fall in love with films again!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?132913</url></doc>
