<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="133551">
  <docid>133551</docid>
  <title>DealFlow</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Busse, Gary</editor>
    <editor>Smith, Kevin (XXV)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Reality-TV</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>business</keyword>
    <keyword>non-fiction</keyword>
    <keyword>travel</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>4-Track Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">26 April 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">22</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Fox, Kevin J.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Cowans, Fred</producer>
    <producer>Weslosky, Tracy</producer>
    <producer>Chan, Dennis (IV)</producer>
    <producer>Malacas, Christine</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bragg, Jennifer</writer>
    <writer>Venne, Kelvin</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Cole, Carson (II)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cowans, Fred</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mason, Peter (I)</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Set against a backdrop of lavish parties, jet setting business leaders and high stakes drama, DealFlow is a fascinating real life look into the world of global business. DealFlowTV follows the principals of a small, highly respected investment bank as they crisscross the globe in search of the next great investment opportunity. Their mission - to find the people, places and passions that shape the future of global business. Each week the DealFlowTV team scours the globe on "fact-finding" missions to determine what regions are hot and which sectors are rising. They shine a light on new business opportunities; new management philosophies; and new ways of investing and making money. These investment dealmakers are smart, opinionated and provocative. One partner follows a logical, quantifiable approach to evaluating businesses and investment opportunities, while the other relies more on gut instinct and her ability to find great talent. Think due diligence meets true brilliance, and though their styles and personalities may sometimes clash, together they are a powerhouse of market intelligence.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?133551</url></doc>
