<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="133606">
  <docid>133606</docid>
  <title>Deaodissea</title>
  <year>2000</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Italian</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Italy">15 November 2000</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Bianco, Anna (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Malfitano, Angela</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mazza, Francesca</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The decision to represent the female characters of the Odissea has revealed a rich seam of suggestion and implication. The women of all ages who partecipated in the choral arrangement of Deaodissea have described a trajectory from a beginning charged with curiosity and expectation: one finds that for many they have gained greater knowledge, skills and critical ability crucial to staging theatrical productions. The watchful gaze of the television camera documented the various stages of this process: the different elements of the play; the expressive enrichments; the building emotional tensions; the partecipation of the expert advisors who joined the production; the contribution of Franca Silvestri, who led the seminar on the "active look"; and the threading togheter of interlinked themes from Angela Malfitano, Francesca Mazza, Anna Redi. In providing a cross-sectional view, the video sails up the tributaries of the production's flowing river: the journey of the theatrical experience; the final shows; and reflections on the work carried out by directors. Beyond its documentary testimony, the video has a stylistic outlook and reveals a precise identity.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?133606</url></doc>
