<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="133734">
  <docid>133734</docid>
  <title>Dear Mr. President</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bennett, Herbert H.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Arabic</language>
    <language>Hebrew</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">March 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Sugarman, Debra</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Cancilla, Dominic</producer>
    <producer>Seale, Victoria (II)</producer>
    <producer>Finley, Summer</producer>
    <producer>Sugarman, Debra</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bennett, Herbert H.</writer>
    <writer>Moss, Devin</writer>
    <writer>Sugarman, Debra</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Rozow, Shie</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Amit (III)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bessan</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Debra (III)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Haneen</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hawad</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In the conflict between Israel and Palestine, both sides share one truth: there are no easy answers. But five teenage girls from the region who met at a peace camp, and a filmmaker who created the camp, feel they can do something to help with this inherited situation...and they are traveling halfway around the world to try. DEAR MR. PRESIDENT is a feature-length documentary film that chronicles the land journey of these teenage girls as they travel in an RV from the West Coast to the East Coast across the USA. Their main goals: to further break down barriers between their enemy cultures and to meet with President George W. Bush. Their intentions: to make deeper personal connections between "enemies," and to serve as ambassadors of their region on their way to hand-deliver a joint statement and an art installation to the President. Over the course of their excursion, the girls stopped in cities, towns and rural communities. They held informal talks and interacted with peers and adults from all walks of life. Along the way, art was created by the girls not only to link them closer together but also to represent their messages left behind, a sign post, a prayer, a hope...for peace and coexistence. As one of the 16-year-old girls says in the film, "It is pretty obvious that violence is not working." The goal of these girls, and of many in their generation, is to find a way for coexistence to work, one relationship at a time. DEAR MR. PRESIDENT is filled with epiphanies, forgiveness, friendship, sorrow and hope.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?133734</url></doc>
