<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="134442">
  <docid>134442</docid>
  <title>Decadere</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Christy, Orion</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">31 October 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Christy, Orion</director>
    <director>Ponton, Michael</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Christy, Orion</producer>
    <producer>Ponton, Michael</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Christy, Orion</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Celico, Dante</actor>
      <role>Zombie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Haigh, Tristan</actor>
      <role>Paul</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hobbs, Steven</actor>
      <role>Steve</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Oliver, Jt</actor>
      <role>Frank</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ponton, Michael</actor>
      <role>Zombie</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The story begins with Paul arriving at an apparent car accident and discovers a dead body in the road, he then approaches the truck, only to be attacked by the driver who is a zombie. Paul flees from the scene and is attacked by more undead, he then runs up the road and is approached by a truck driven by Steve who, after a brief scare, takes Paul to his friend Frank's house where they are to "hold up until dawn." Paul travels into the den where he discovers an old rifle and, after hearing a strange noise, travels upstairs to investigate. In the upstairs bathroom he finds a dead Frank holding a gun, and retreats in shock. Once he reaches the bottom of the stairs he goes into the kitchen to investigate yet another strange noise, once there he is attacked by a zombie, and is rescued by Steve, who uses the den's rifle to incapacitate the kitchen zombie. Steve tells Paul that they must leave because Frank is dead and is attacked by Frank's zombie who suddenly attacks. Paul then runs for the front door, opens it and is immediately attacked by one of the zombies from the road. he then retreats up the stairs and retrieves Frank's dropped pistol, he then cautiously travels back downstairs to confront the undead, but nothing remains, the only evidence of anything remaining is a pool of blood on the ground which he investigates. A strange sound distracts him and he searches for it's origin by traveling into the garage. There, he finds the garage door open, and closes it. He then makes his way back toward the kitchen where he is immediately attacked by the road zombie. He struggles with the zombie and then eliminates it using the handgun. After the zombie's dispatch he, again tries to enter the kitchen, but is attacked by Frank's reanimated corpse, the two struggle, Frank knocks the gun away from Paul, and mounts him. Paul desperately searches for the dropped pistol, finds it, and uses it to dispatch Frank. Paul then rises, covered in blood, and travels to the downstairs bathroom where he is attacked and killed by zombie Steve.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?134442</url></doc>
