<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="134760">
  <docid>134760</docid>
  <title>Deedar</title>
  <year>1951</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Roy, Bimal (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Musical</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">U</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">130</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Bose, Nitin</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bazidpuri, Azm</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Naushad (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Baby Anwari</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Devi, Niharika</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Ashok (I)</actor>
      <role>Dr. Kishore</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Dilip (I)</actor>
      <role>Shamu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Merchant, Jal</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Miraz, Agha</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Murad</actor>
      <role>Daulatram Rai</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Parikshit (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Surendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Yakub</actor>
      <role>Choudhury</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Shamu is a young boy who lives with his widowed mom, and works in the orchard of Daulatram Rai. He is very friendly with Mala Rai, Daulatram's only child, and they often go horse-riding. One day, while riding, Mala and Shamu get thrown down, and Mala is injured. Her enraged &amp; snobbish dad fires Shamu and forbids Mala to ever see him again. Shamu and his mom leave to re-locate elsewhere. On the way, Shamu's mom passes away, leaving a grieving Shamu in the care of young Champa and her uncle. A depressed Shamu runs away, straight into a sand-storm, and loses his vision. Blind and dependent, Shamu is looked after by Champa and her uncle. Years later, the uncle has passed away, but Shamu still lives with Champa and makes a living by singing. Champa adores him, but Shamu is unable to get Mala out of his mind. Dr. Kishore hears him sing, is pleased, and offers to restore his vision free of cost. Before the operation, Shamu gets to meet Kishore's betrothed, who is also pleased to hear his voice. When Shamu regains his sight, his only thought is to find Mala and re-kindle their love. Will fate bring his sweetheart to him, or will Shamu continue his quest for the love of Mala for the rest of his life?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?134760</url></doc>
