<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="135172">
  <docid>135172</docid>
  <title>Deewaanapan</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bernard, Steven (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>DTS</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">16 November 2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Trikha, Ashu</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bhagnani, Vashu</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Shrivastava, Adesh</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Agarwal, Somesh</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bedi, Rakesh</actor>
      <role>Raju (the guide)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carl (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gill, Avtar</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jaykar, Smita</actor>
      <role>Suraj's mom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khanna, Vinod</actor>
      <role>Ranvir Choudhury</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mazhar (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mirza, Diya</actor>
      <role>Kiran Choudhary</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, Om</actor>
      <role>Suraj's dad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rampal, Arjun</actor>
      <role>Suraj Saxena</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sadanand, Kabir</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Samtani, Raju</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Saxena, Sharat</actor>
      <role>Shankar Deshpande</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sethi, Vikas</actor>
      <role>Rocky</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Somi, Anoop</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Suraj Saxena (Arjun Rampal) lives in a remote hill station in India with his dad (Om Puri), mom (Smita Jaykar), and sister, Asha (Amita Nangia). One day he meets with Kiran Choudhary (Diya Mirza), who has come on holiday trip with a group of girls. He offers to show her around and they fall in love with each other. Suraj is unable to see her home by the train as his dad has chest pains and has to be rushed to hospital. But Suraj is unable to get Kiran out of his mind and heart. After his sister get's married, the family decide to relocate to Bombay, where Suraj enlists in College and makes several new friends, as well as becomes a popular football player. He eventually meets Kiran and both renew their romance. Ranvir Choudhary (Vinod Khanna) does not appreciate the attentions of a poor man like Suraj on his daughter, and has Suraj brought up before him and introduced to his many friends, which include prominent lawyers, politicians, high ranking civil and municipal employees, the police commissioner as well as the state chief minister. Suraj is warned of dire consequences if he and his family do not leave town immediately. Suraj does not leave town, and hell descends on his family and himself. His mother is unable to purchase food and is publicly humiliated; his father is followed around by Ranvir's goons, harassed, and robbed, and then faces the ultimate humiliation of being publicly arrested, handcuffed, and imprisoned on charges of conspiring against the country and loses his job; and some of Suraj's friends exile him. With so much pressure, will Suraj relent and leave the city, or will he let his dad rot in prison? Ranvir has sworn to kill Suraj, and if he does so, what will happen to Suraj's mom?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?135172</url></doc>
