<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="135289">
  <docid>135289</docid>
  <title>Defining Edward</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Barry, Emma</editor>
    <editor>Lee, Corey</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">30 September 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">93</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Lee, Corey</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Loewen, Robin</producer>
    <producer>Bristow, Susan</producer>
    <producer>Lee, Corey</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Lee, Corey</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Broom, Russell</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bowie, Sean</actor>
      <role>Accountant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Boyd, Hamish</actor>
      <role>Edward's Father</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Collins, Joely</actor>
      <role>Anna</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Diablo Del Mar, Diego</actor>
      <role>Nick</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McNichol, Joel</actor>
      <role>Edward</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mitchell, Stevie</actor>
      <role>Young Edward</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rumpel, Peter Strand</actor>
      <role>Brian</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Meet Edward Cobb, a depressed, pill popping X-rated cartoonist with no girlfriend, no money and little in life to look forward to. Everything changes when Edward has an allergic reaction, which leads to a mild concussion. Waking confused in the hospital, Edward wanders out into a now unfamiliar world only to collapse again in the middle of nowhere. Returning to consciousness, Edward finds himself attended to by the man who found him, Brian, a doctor. Suffering from amnesia, Edward is offered a helping hand from Brian, who believes he can restore his memory. As pieces of his past slowly return, Edward is introduced to the other residents of the house, Anna, a fragile, introverted artist, and Nick, a foul mouthed, beer and whiskey fueled welder. Divisions appear as the residents of the house take different vastly different approaches to assist Edward in his struggle to regain his identity. And what began as the kindness of strangers, turns into a twisted game of self-preservation, as one man fights to unlock the truth about his own troubled past.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?135289</url></doc>
