<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="135580">
  <docid>135580</docid>
  <title>Del rancho a la capital</title>
  <year>1942</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Mexico</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Mexico">29 May 1942</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>de Anda, Raúl (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>de Anda, Raúl (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Soler, Domingo</writer>
    <writer>de Anda, Raúl (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Bermejo, Felipe</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Argota, Victoria</actor>
      <role>Victoria</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Armendáriz, Pedro</actor>
      <role>Pedro</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cañedo, Roberto</actor>
      <role>Extra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cortés, Margarita</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fábregas, Manuel (I)</actor>
      <role>Julián</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Guízar, Susana</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>López Moctezuma, Carlos</actor>
      <role>Carlos</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Martínez, Paco (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Soler, Domingo</actor>
      <role>Domingo Rodríguez</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Soto La Marina, Armando</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Velázquez, Víctor</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Victoria (Victoria Argota) is the mother of two daughters and one son. They used to be a wealthy family, but now they have financial problems. But that doesn't stop Victoria in his tendency to spoil the kids giving them money, despite the fact that any of them have a work. Nevertheles, Victoria receives a letter from his cousin Domingo (Domingo Soler), who lives in the country with his wife and his son Pedro (Pedro Armendáriz), notifying that they will come to visit them. One of the daughters has to many prejudices about the people from the country. She won't be disposed to stand the presence of her uncle and his family. The other daughter, Angélica, and her brother Julián (Manolo Fábregas), are much more tolerant than their sister. When Domingo arrives with his wife and Pedro, they will suffer the disdain of Victoria's daughter, but also the particular way-of-life of rich people, like the refined manners, the expensive clothes, visiting exclusive clubs. Pedro will be the first in changing dramatically. He'll fall in love with his vain cousin, and after she finds out that her uncle Domingo's also a wealthy man, she'll think a nasty plan: winning the heart of Pedro and engaged with him, in order to keep the money of her relatives, so she could marry with Carlos (Carlos López Moctezuma), his fiancé.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?135580</url></doc>
