<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="135709">
  <docid>135709</docid>
  <title>Deliciosas perversiones polimorfas</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Montes Bradley, Eduardo</editor>
  </editors>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Argentina</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Argentina">72</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Montes Bradley, Eduardo</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kaplan, Sara (I)</producer>
    <producer>Durán, Rodolfo</producer>
    <producer>Montes Bradley, Eduardo</producer>
    <producer>Liendo, Soledad</producer>
    <producer>Montes Bradley, Eduardo</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Laiseca, Alberto</writer>
    <writer>Montes Bradley, Eduardo</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Laiseca, Alberto</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>At times it is impossible to pinpoint what are Laiseca's true memories and what are reinventions of a world which, for better or worse and according to ones convictions, can be real or not. Thus the writer strolls through this documentary with vampires and childhood stories in Camilo Aldao, in the province of Cordoba, Argentina "just a few miles from Saigon". The relationship with his father, the misadventures in the countryside and his early experiences with local girls are constantly being crossed by roaring howitzers, napalm and the sounds of Kalashnikovs in the Vietnamese jungle where twenty thousand of their companions lost their lives. Camilo Aldao, modest example of the humid pampas, was also the birthplace of the first subway in the Americas and other wonders of modernity. Laiseca's imagination knows no boundaries. Somewhere between the virginity and Maria and the plots of Poe, on the margins of the cultural institutions of Argentina, straddling Hawthoe, Spencer and Baudelaire, Laiseca lives a rural nostalgia with a certain degree of perversion and as one of the best-kept secrets among the Argentine iconoclasts.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?135709</url></doc>
