<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="137415">
  <docid>137415</docid>
  <title>Der Bootgott vom Seesportclub. Die 100 ME - Teil1</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Römer, Wolf-Ingo</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>me</keyword>
    <keyword>number-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>sumer</keyword>
    <keyword>brandenburg</keyword>
    <keyword>enki</keyword>
    <keyword>bootgott</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>German</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Germany">81</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Bramkamp, Robert</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Weirich, Susanne</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bramkamp, Robert</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Knoth, Max (I)</composer>
    <composer>Marduk, Max</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Basrawi, Claudia</actor>
      <role>Claudia Basrawi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Meller, Robert (II)</actor>
      <role>Neoist</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mentrup, Mario</actor>
      <role>Neoist</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Scheumann, Steffen</actor>
      <role>Enki</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A Change of Perspectives Interdisciplinary viewpoints, audacious associations, and energizing impulses - daring to look beyond accepted boundaries. At the Lakeside Sports Club, the job-creation program participant is king: He is no less than Enki. According to Sumerian mythology, Enki created humanity, brought culture to civilization, and was the God of Seafarers. Everything would work out fine and lead to enlightenment if only the job-creation program were not ending. Robert Bramkamp's film The Boat God of the Lakeside Sports Club (The 100 Me, Part 1) (Germany, 2005, 81 min, World premiere) magically and playfully combines the Sumerian belief of the 100 Me - the 100 special capabilities which individually can only take effect at specific locations when deployed by a specific person - with the truly unique mini-cosmos of the Lakeside Sports Club. In doing so, he also reveals the connection between the Persian Gulf with the region of the Märkischen Lakes. The theory of cognition, here and now - and an appeal for an extension of Enki's sponsored job-creation program position.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?137415</url></doc>
