<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="141099">
  <docid>141099</docid>
  <title>Derby Dreams: Stories from the 67th All-American Soap Box Derby</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Karpf, Rory</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>digit-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>number-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>racing</keyword>
    <keyword>car</keyword>
    <keyword>nascar</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">4 September 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Karpf, Rory</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Agajanian, Josh</producer>
    <producer>Karpf, Rory</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Karpf, Rory</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kahne, Kasey</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Some say the Soap Box Derby is the single greatest youth organized sport in the world. Children ages 8-17 compete in races all over the globe for a chance to run in the Soap Box Championship held each year in Akron, OH. The event is much more than just kids going down a steep hill in a handmade car. It's a chance for families to bond, kids to discover themselves and for dreams to be realized. For one week these competitors aren't just children, they're champions. Derby Dreams, a documentary premiering September 4th at 8:00 PM on Speed Channel chronicles the stories of seven competitors, while also looking at this unique event. Some of the kids the viewers will meet include: -Andre Langston, Chicago, IL age 13. Andre lives in Garfield Park, an inner city that has the highest per capital murder rate of anywhere in the country. For one week, Andre gets to forget about where he's from and instead dream of what he can become. -Cameron Keistler, Charlotte, NC, age 13. Cameron hails from an affluent neighborhood and at first glance he seems to be just a brash, spoiled kid. But as he develops a friendship with Andre, his softer side emerges. -Mckenzie Shaffer, Cleveland OH, age 10. Mckenzie is always smiling even though she's spent the majority of her life in and out of hospitals due to being born premature. While her stature is small her determination is immeasurable. For Mckenzie and her family, coming to Akron is already a dream come true. The Soap Box Derby is a NASCAR youth initiative. NASCAR notables like Cale Yarborough, Joe Nemechek, Richard Childress and Mike Helton raced Soap Box in their youth. Derby Dreams features appearances by NASCAR drivers Tony Stewart and Jeff Gordon, and former Indy racer Lyn St. James. The program is narrated by Kasey Kahne, one of NASCAR's most popular drivers and a likely candidate for Rookie of the year.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?141099</url></doc>
