<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="142392">
  <docid>142392</docid>
  <title>Destination Earth</title>
  <year>1956</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>american-dream</keyword>
    <keyword>capitalism</keyword>
    <keyword>martian</keyword>
    <keyword>propaganda</keyword>
    <keyword>oil-industry</keyword>
    <keyword>petroleum</keyword>
    <keyword>life-on-mars</keyword>
    <keyword>automobile</keyword>
    <keyword>promotional</keyword>
    <keyword>mars</keyword>
    <keyword>oil</keyword>
    <keyword>ephemeral-film</keyword>
    <keyword>flying-saucer</keyword>
    <keyword>competition</keyword>
    <keyword>oil-drilling</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1956</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">14</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="USA">13</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Urbano, Carl</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Sutherland, John (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Amestoy, Michael</writer>
    <writer>Gordon, George (I)</writer>
    <writer>Scott, Bill (I)</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>The American Petroleum Institute presents "Destination Earth" Color by Technicolor... The cartoon begins by establishing the planet Mars, ruled by a dictator named Ogg. The martians are small green guys with big noses and space helmets. The poor guys are herded by soldiers into a space-age colliseum where Ogg forces them to applaud as they hear his criticisms of problems with martian ground transportation -- no good fuel and too much friction. A single martian is sent to Earth to find a solution. The intrepid Martian crashes his saucer into a farm, sets forth into the city, learns about the glorious benefits of petroleum AND capitalist competition, steals a few library books, and heads back to Mars. He excitedly reveals the truths he's learned to the crowd in the colliseum. The crowd is fueled by the spirit of capitalism and the dictatorship breaks down instantly, to be replaced by the Oil Pioneers, the Oil Explorers, and new management. And we learn that a future with oil and competition is Destination Unlimited. I enjoy John Sutherland's educational cartoons, but this one is really a work of art. The animation is several cuts above his usual good work. Of course a lot of the difference has to do with the presence of Tom Oreb and Vic Haboush as production designers. And whoever animated Ogg (was it Ken O'Brien?) provides lush movement done in a very limited style.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?142392</url></doc>
