<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="143535">
  <docid>143535</docid>
  <title>Devil Dogs</title>
  <year>2010</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <genres>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>jungle</keyword>
    <keyword>rescue-mission</keyword>
    <keyword>columbia</keyword>
    <keyword>mercenary</keyword>
    <keyword>army-general</keyword>
    <keyword>cartel</keyword>
    <keyword>drug-lord</keyword>
    <keyword>animal-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>general</keyword>
    <keyword>ukraine</keyword>
    <keyword>us-marine</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <directors>
    <director>Echavarria, Hector</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Echavarria, Hector</writer>
    <writer>Toledo, Rafael Alfonso</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Angle, Kurt</actor>
      <role>Steve Stagger</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Echavarria, Hector</actor>
      <role>Alejandro de Leon</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Herring, Heath</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mir, Frank</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Silva, Anderson</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>After disagreements on a rescue mission in Ukraine, elite U.S. marines Alejandro de Leon and Steve Stagger are called immediately for another mission. The two put their differences aside and accept the job when they find out what they could prevent if they succeed. They are informed of a serious problem involving Falcao, a very powerful and ruthless drug lord who spreads terror throughout the dense jungles of Colombia. Hard to get to, backed by corrupt politicians and surrounded by soldiers, Falcao is an extremely difficult enemy to bring down. William Carter, a U.S. general in charge of the mission, introduces the men to Chief Gutierrez, a Colombian veteran who will provide support for the marines whose objective is to get as close as possible to the target and eliminate him the old fashioned way. Once the cartel is crippled, the next objective is to assist the Colombian military in neutralizing the rest of the cartel. When Alejandro and Steve land in Colombia, they are lead by Claudia, a beautiful young woman whose parents were killed by the drug lord. As they walk through the dangerous and chaotic jungle, they encounter burned villages, guerrillas and a group of elite mercenaries who have also been hired to eliminate Falcao. Unaware of the mercenaries, the marines unintentionally race to reach their target first and when they do, a intense clash of expert soldiers brings the movie to it's climax.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?143535</url></doc>
