<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="143952">
  <docid>143952</docid>
  <title>Dharma</title>
  <year>1973</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">U</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <directors>
    <director>Chand (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Chand (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Sharma, Om Prakash (I)</composer>
    <composer>Sonik, Master</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ajit (I)</actor>
      <role>Police Inspector Ajit Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arora, Harbans Darshan M.</actor>
      <role>Henchman who offered Chaman Singh a gun</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhalla, Jagdish</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bindu (I)</actor>
      <role>Bindiya</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chand, Master</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chandrashekhar</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Choti, Mohan</actor>
      <role>Car Mechanic</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deo, Ramesh</actor>
      <role>Chaman Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dutt, Uma</actor>
      <role>Police Commissioner</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Faryal (I)</actor>
      <role>Cabaret Dancer #2</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Haksar, Rajan</actor>
      <role>Bhairon Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Helen (I)</actor>
      <role>Cabaret Dancer #1</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jankidas</actor>
      <role>Seth Jamnadas</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Johnny (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kadam, Anjali</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Parvati Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mohit, Master (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moolchand</actor>
      <role>Jeweller Dhanpatram</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Murad</actor>
      <role>Seth</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nischol, Navin</actor>
      <role>Raju</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pran (I)</actor>
      <role>Sevak Singh 'Dharma'</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, Madan (I)</actor>
      <role>Mangal Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Randhir</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sen, Asit (I)</actor>
      <role>Seth Garib Das</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Chandan Singh (Pran) is a dacoit living with in isolation with his followers Bhairav Singh (Rajan Haksar), Mangal Singh (Madan Puri) and his wife Parvati (Anjali Kadam) amongst others. The police, led by Inspector Ajit Singh (Ajit) are fast on the track of Chandan Singh, and soon catch up with him. Chandan Singh is betrayed by his follower Bhairav Singh, who is killed by Chandan Singh, after he attempts molest Parvati. Mangal Singh shields and protects the son of Bhairav, Chaman (Ramesh Deo), and both swear vengeance against Chandan Singh. Meanwhile, while escaping from the police in a boat, Ajit Singh shoots at Chandan Singh and the shot hits Parvati, who falls into the water, and her son, Suraj (Navin Nischal) plunges in after her. Chandan Singh too dives in after them, but is unable to find them. Chandan Singh takes revenge on Ajit Singh's family and abducts his daughter, Radha (Rekha), and Ajit's wife, Asha (also played by Rekha) gets killed accidentally. Years later Chandan Singh emerges as Dharma as well as Nawab Sikander, while Ajit Singh is now the Insepctor General of Police. Nawab Sikander goes to the prostitutions area and there finds Radha, who he recognizes and buys from the Madame, and brings her home, and asks Ajit Singh to be her father, to which he readily agrees as she looks just like his wife, Asha. Rajoo (Navin Nischal is a small time crook who works with Dharma, but has a change of heart when he falls in love with Radha, and swears to be a good person and through the guiding hands of his to-be father-in-law becomes a police inspector, and vows to arrest Chandan Singh. In the meantime, Mangal Singh, Chaman, and Chaman's girlfriend (Bindu) come upon Parvati, who lives in a temple. Chaman decides to impersonate himself as her son Suraj, and after successfully doing this he also manages to fool Dharma into believing that he is indeed their long lost son, vouched for by Mangal Singh. Will Dharma ever be apprehended by the authorities? Will Parvati ever meet her real son? What are the plans of Chaman and Mangal Singh?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?143952</url></doc>
