<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="143929">
  <docid>143929</docid>
  <title>Dhara</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Patil, Anil</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>psychiatry</keyword>
    <keyword>shock-therapy</keyword>
    <keyword>mentally-disabled</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">15 February 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">95</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Mirza, Masud</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Agrawal, Tarang</producer>
    <producer>Sidatar, Iqbal</producer>
    <producer>Jain, Ganesh</producer>
    <producer>Jain, Ratan</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Mirza, Masud</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Mukherjee, Saurabh</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Agarwal, Suman (II)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhatt, Hrishitaa</actor>
      <role>Dhara</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chadda, Protima</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mazumdar, Tina</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pandey, Sudhanshu</actor>
      <role>Dr. Sagar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Punj, Anuj</actor>
      <role>Sahil</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Dr. Sagar is a London-based psychiatrist who works in a hospital. He is strongly opposed to shock therapy as a treatment for mentally ill patients, which is a source of conflict with his colleagues. One day he accidentally saves a girl who is being attacked by a group of men, and takes her home. The girl, Dhara, is behaving extremely childishly, and Sagar quickly finds out that she is mentally disturbed, but not retarded. He decides to keep her out of the hospital, and to take care of her at his own place. As a result of Dr. Sagar's careful treatment and a lot of domestic warmth, Dhara's condition gradually improves. Simultaneously, they slowly fall in love with each other, and Sagar even plans marrying her. When Sagan has to leave for India for a while, he friend Sahil comes to visit him, and decided to stay in his home until he returns. There he stumbles upon Dhara, almost healthy now, and the two fall in love quickly. When Sagar returns from India, he catches them in the act. Sagar, completely broken by this incident, loses his mind himself. Now it is Dhara's turn to take care of Sagar. However, once she succeeds, he loses it herself again.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?143929</url></doc>
