<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="144043">
  <docid>144043</docid>
  <title>Dhokha</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Mundeshwar, Deven</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>betrayal</keyword>
    <keyword>marriage</keyword>
    <keyword>suicide-bomber</keyword>
    <keyword>muslim</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">31 August 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Bhatt, Pooja (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bhatt, Mukesh (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Rafique, Shagufta</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kreem, M.M.</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dabholkar, Bharat</actor>
      <role>Bartender</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grover, Gulshan</actor>
      <role>ATS Chief Raj Mehra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ibrahim, Muzammil</actor>
      <role>ACP Zaid Ahmed Khan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Joshi, Tulip</actor>
      <role>Sarha P. Bux/Sarha Z. Khan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kher, Anupam</actor>
      <role>Saeed Noor Bux</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Vinit</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rana, Ashutosh</actor>
      <role>Police Inspector</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sacchar, Abhay</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shyam, Anupam</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Uday, Bhanu</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Post-September 11, 2001, Zaid Ahmed Khan lives a wealthy lifestyle in Mumbai and resides in an apartment at Shanti Kutir, Juhu Tara Road, Mumbai, and works as an Assistant Commissioner of Police. He is of marriageable age, and his marriage is arranged with Sarha, who is the daughter of Parvez, sister of Dhanish, and grand-daughter of Saeed Noor Bux, who are based in Nasik. The two get married in Udaipur, and subsequently Sarha re-locates to live with Zaid in Mumbai. One day terrorists strike at a club, killing 20 people, &amp; critically injuring several others. The Police are put on alert, and Zaid is summoned to Police Headquarters to identify a body. To his shock the body turns out to be that of Sarha - who was not a victim but was a suicide-bomber. Before he could get over this shock, Zaid is arrested by Anti-Terrorist Squad Chief Raj Mehra and questioned for several days. The media, his friends, including fellow police officers, already believe that he is guilty. Finally, after several days, he is freed, much to the chagrin of opposition parties who believe that Zaid is being freed because of political reasons. While trying to put his life together, Zaid comes across evidence that Sarha may have had an hand in the killings, and thus intrigued he decides to travel to Nasik to find out what really happened, whether his devout Islamic wife was really a terrorist or the victim of a deep-rooted conspiracy.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?144043</url></doc>
