<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="145095">
  <docid>145095</docid>
  <title>Diddy's Kong-Quest</title>
  <year>1995</year>
  <type>VideoGame</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>donkey-kong-junior</keyword>
    <keyword>video-game</keyword>
    <keyword>donkey-kong</keyword>
    <keyword>sequel</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>sonic-the-hedgehog</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">K-A</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Japan">20 November 1995</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">6 December 1995</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <composers>
    <composer>Wise, David (II)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bayliss, Kevin</actor>
      <role>Donkey/Diddy/Dixie/K. Rool</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The Kongs are back! So is that evil King K. Rool. This time the evil king has kidnapped Donkey Kong and holds him for ransom for the banana hoarde. It's up to Diddy Kong to rescue his big buddy, but he needs help, so his girlfriend Dixie Kong comes along to help. Together, Diddy and Dixie must brave pirate ships, oceans, polar ice caps, jungles, an amusement park, a windy jungle, ghosts, and even a zeppelin where Donkey Kong is being held captive. Diddy and Dixie also get help from their animal friends, like returning Rambi the Rhino, Enguarde the Swordfish, Squawks the Parrot [he fights this time], with some new friends like Rattly the hopping Rattlesnake, Clapper the Seal and Squitter the Spider. Of course the Kong family members are here to help: returning is Cranky who offers his advice along with sarcasm, Funky who can transport you to places you've been with his barrel plane, and new members: Wrinkly Kong, Cranky's wife, who can save your game for you, and Swanky who holds game shows that earns you extra lives for every right answer. New villains are ready to fight, including Kaptain K. Rool, you must defeat him, if you are successful, you'll send that evil croc flying to the sharks.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?145095</url></doc>
