<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="147714">
  <docid>147714</docid>
  <title>Die Schwarzwaldklinik - Neue Zeiten</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Grau, Dirk</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>doctor</keyword>
    <keyword>wife</keyword>
    <keyword>beautiful-woman</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>German</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Germany">4 December 2005</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Hungary">17 March 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">95</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Tögel, Hans-Jürgen</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Buchs, Frank</producer>
    <producer>Rademann, Wolfgang</producer>
    <producer>Stocklöv, Christian</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Ewald, Marlies</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Wagener, Hans Günter</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bauer, Eva Maria</actor>
      <role>Ehemalige Oberschwester Hildegard</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dierck, Roswitha</actor>
      <role>Oberschwester Agnes</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ewald, Christian</actor>
      <role>Herr Mensing</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fitz, Michael (I)</actor>
      <role>Herr Bieler</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Habermann, Eva</actor>
      <role>Dr. Sophie Brinkmann</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hehn, Sascha</actor>
      <role>Prof. Udo Brinkmann</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Japp, Stefanie</actor>
      <role>Anna Peters</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jäger, Peer</actor>
      <role>Prof. Hans Köhler</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kreye, Walter</actor>
      <role>Kurt Seeberg</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lippert, Gerhart</actor>
      <role>Herbert Schwarz</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Schroeder, Jochen</actor>
      <role>ehemaliger Pfleger Mischa</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Schwartz, Stephan (I)</actor>
      <role>Walter Haug</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Theuer, Martin</actor>
      <role>Dr. Warstein</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wussow, Alexander</actor>
      <role>Dr. Benjamin Brinkmann</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wussow, Klausjürgen</actor>
      <role>Prof. em. Klaus Brinkmann</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Dr. Benjamin Brinkmann, houseman/intern in the "Schwarzwaldklinik" (Black Forest Clinic/Hospital), experiences by his wife, Dr. Sophie Brinkmann, from the rumor that the clinic/hospital was sold. After he sees, how the personnel is concerned because of the rumor, Benjamin goes to his superior, Prof. Köhler. By him he experiences that the clinic/hospital was actually sold to a private investor, Karl Seeberg, who wants to close the clinic/hospital and make from it a senior home. Benjamin also informs his half brother, in the meantime Prof. Dr. Udo Brinkmann, about the problem. Udo sees the only chance in convincing Karl Seeberg that the hospital is on a long-term basis more profitable. Former auxiliary Michael "Mischa" Burgmann can help with Udo former "Oberschwester" (senior nursing officer/ head nurse) Hildegard Vogt, after she suffered a lumbago. So Mischa may live with Hildegard, while his daughter is in the near in a rehabilitation clinic/hospital, but he must take over the garden work for Hildegard. Sophie Brinkmann gives a contact announcement up for her father, Herbert Schwarz, on which Hildegard gives an answer promptly. As the new owner of the "Schwarzwaldklinik" (Black Forest Clinic/Hospital) hurts heavily with a traffic accident, Benjamin and Udo can save his life. Udo drives Sophie for ridding. On the equestrian farm he becomes acquainted with Amelie Haug, which sits since a riding accident in the wheelchair. Udo will repeatedly visit Amelie. Karl Seeberg awakes from the unconsciousness and he offers Benjamin and Udo from gratitude to convince him up to his reorganization in order not to close the hospital, but only under two conditions: A new administrative manager must be employed and Udo must become leading doctor in the "Schwarzwaldklinik" (Black Forest Clinic/Hospital). Whereupon Udo asks his father, former leading doctor Prof. em. Dr. Klaus Brinkmann, whether he is to accept this position. Prof. Klaus Brinkmann affirms and is proud of his son. Herbert Schwarz helps Udo in the search for a new lodging. The new administrative directress Dr. Anna Peters reduces everywhere the costs of the clinic/hospital, which releases displeasure with the personnel. Sophie makes herself the largest reproaches, after Mrs. Bieler dies at the birth of her daughter and Mr. Bieler refuses seeing his daughter. How will the final decision of Karl Seeberg for the "Schwarzwaldklinik" (Black Forest Clinic/Hospital) fail? Can Udo and Benjamin Brinkmann save the life's work of their common father? Anyhow Amelie will be able to move her legs, Herbert finds Hildegard and with Sophie the situation improves, because Mr. Bieler is now overjoyed of his daughter.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?147714</url></doc>
