<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="149734">
  <docid>149734</docid>
  <title>Die, Zombies... Die!!!</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>LaRocco, Mike</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">28 May 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">105</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>LaRocco, Mike</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hersh, Jonathan</producer>
    <producer>LaRocco, Mike</producer>
    <producer>McCabe, Jon</producer>
    <producer>Schifler, Adam</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>LaRocco, Mike</writer>
    <writer>Schifler, Adam</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Hersh, Jonathan</composer>
    <composer>Khilko, Ivan</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Beverly-Whittemore, Kai</actor>
      <role>Alex Goldenberg</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>LaRocco, Mike</actor>
      <role>Tony Tortarelli</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lepkowski, Andy</actor>
      <role>Ryan O'Grady</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Molaro, Sam</actor>
      <role>Chester Gritz</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Schifler, Adam</actor>
      <role>Mason Von Braxis</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Tony Tortarelli and his good buddy Ryan O'Grady thought they had the perfect job at the Shoreline Hotel, New Mexico's finest winter sports retreat. However, mysterious happenings around the hotel quickly put a damper on their dreams of menial labor and hot ski chicks. As co-workers start disappearing, the hapless duo, along with the nerdy hotel engineer and the smokin' hot hotel accountant, decide to take matters into their own hands and get to the bottom of the funny business. As Tony and friends investigate, it becomes more and more clear that foul play is at work, especially after the arrival of a leather-clad lunatic, Mason von Braxis. Mason, however, insists that something more sinister is afoot... in the form of brain-craving zombies! Miles away from civilization and conveniently without contact with the outside world, the staff doesn't know whom to trust. That is, until a few thousand zombies start knocking at the door. Trapped inside the hotel, the staff must band together with the badass Mason and a genial hotel guest, the 300 pound Polish physicist Wojtec, in order to fight off the casket-monster invasion. The ensuing gorefest, rife with one-liners and decapitations, makes for a zombie-rific conclusion to this campy crowd pleaser.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?149734</url></doc>
