<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="149934">
  <docid>149934</docid>
  <title>Diez</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Martin, Immanuel</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby SR</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">9 September 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">20</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Martin, Immanuel</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Reza, Angela</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Martin, Immanuel</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Allie, Ali</actor>
      <role>Designer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gonzalez, Araceli (I)</actor>
      <role>Little girl</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Soriano, Ben (I)</actor>
      <role>Luis</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>DIEZ follows the story of Luis, a hard working Mexican immigrant in San Francisco's Mission District. When Luis finds a rare and expensive Eames chair for ten dollars at a yard sale, his world intersects with that of the chair. In a neighborhood where people struggle to make a living, Luis must decide what he should do with the chair. DIEZ shows the many different realities that exist the same neighborhood and the contrasting values that accompany them. Diez is a short vignette from a series of stories that make up a feature film about the life of Luis. When Luis was ten years old, a traumatic and life-changing event occurred in his life. That traumatic event would start Luis on a dangerous journey through Mexico that would eventually bring him to the US in a quest to find answers about his past. On his travels, Luis meets many colorful people and has the chance to change their lives. But when Luis finally gets the answers to his past, he must decide whether the journey itself or the answer is more important.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?149934</url></doc>
