<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="150720">
  <docid>150720</docid>
  <title>Dinner with the Bargisavaris</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Saddigh, Negar</editor>
    <editor>Saddigh, Rocsana</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Persian</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 January 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Saddigh, Negar</director>
    <director>Saddigh, Rocsana</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Saddigh, Negar</writer>
    <writer>Saddigh, Rocsana</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Cultures collide when Mark meets Annie's Persian family for one very awkward dinner. Annie's little white lies about her "half-Persian-Mercedes-driving-doctor-suitor" begin to unravel as her family gets a little too close to an unsuspecting Mark. Mark is called on his every fault, his jeans, his gifts, his disdain for the family dog. Annie manages to maintain some order, with the exception of a few off-color comments from her father Abulfazl, but when her outrageously flirtatious cousin Roya comes to dinner, she signals the point of no return. Roya and Annie's over-protective brother Pouya set Mark up for disaster. While Annie tries to mediate the gathering, Mark can't seem to get anything right, from his inappropriate gifts, his forceful personality, and his unusual behavior. When he is offered appetizers he overcompensates for his offensive behavior by overeating and subjecting himself to ridicule. Annie's youngest brother Ali-Reza is the last ingredient in the evening's festivities, and throws his own kabob skewer into the wheel and forces Mark into the most awkward position of the night. Under the judgmental gaze of the Bargisavaris, Mark can do no good. No one is right for the Bargisavaris' pride and joy.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?150720</url></doc>
