<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="152684">
  <docid>152684</docid>
  <title>Dixie Kong's Double Trouble</title>
  <year>1996</year>
  <type>VideoGame</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>donkey-kong-junior</keyword>
    <keyword>video-game</keyword>
    <keyword>donkey-kong</keyword>
    <keyword>sequel</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">K-A</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">22 November 1996</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <producers>
    <producer>Stamper, Tim</producer>
    <producer>Collard, Andrew</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Miyamoto, Shigeru</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Fischer, E. (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bayliss, Kevin</actor>
      <role>Dixie/Kiddy/K. Rool</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Third time's a charm? Not for Donkey and Diddy Kong who have been captured by a huge robot named Kaos. Dixie Kong must go after her friends but she's gonna need help. She visits Funky Kong who's opened up a boat rental shop by the water who sends Dixie's baby cousin Kiddy Kong, who though still young, can be helpful. Funky also says that if Dixie Kong can bring him parts, he can make vehicles out of them, he's even got a special vehicle waiting for Dixie as soon as she can bring him every DK coin in the game. Also along are Kong family members, Swanky who now owns a carnival where Cranky plays, match wits with him at a ball toss game and win points, Wrinkly Kong who stays at home and exercises, plays video games and sleeps. The Brothers Bear are here to help, 12 bears who will give you something that can be useful, some of them might try to cheat you though and some are meaner than others. Together, Dixie and Kiddy must brave levels of pure trickery, dodging lightning, falling rocks, swooping birds and other bad guys, Along the way, Dixie and Kiddy get help from animal friends like Squawks the Parrot, Enguarde the Swordfish, Ellie the Elephant, Psrry the Parallel Bird, Squitter the Spider, Glimmer the Angle Fish, and the Banana Birds and their mother. They must defeat unimaginable bosses, including Kaos and his inventor Baron K. Roolenstein. When you pass them, Donkey and Diddy Kong are freed, who are impressed with the performances of Dixie and Kiddy and think even Cranky would be impressed, but he isn't.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?152684</url></doc>
