<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="153392">
  <docid>153392</docid>
  <title>Dobrovolets</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Smirnova, Margarita</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>drugs</keyword>
    <keyword>volunteer</keyword>
    <keyword>graffiti</keyword>
    <keyword>city-folklore</keyword>
    <keyword>mystical</keyword>
    <keyword>self-search</keyword>
    <keyword>internet</keyword>
    <keyword>non-comformity</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Russian</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Russia</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Russia">2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Russia">95</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Boyakov, Eduard</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Martynov, Vladimir (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dapkunaite, Ingeborga</actor>
      <role>Tir's Mom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Drubich, Tatyana</actor>
      <role>Shtorm's Mom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grudovich, Donatas</actor>
      <role>Grunt</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Iosifov, Ilya</actor>
      <role>Shtorm</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Makarevich, Ivan</actor>
      <role>Tir</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Smolyakov, Andrei (I)</actor>
      <role>Tir's Dad</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Life offers different scenarios to the main character of the film, who answers more readily to the name of Tir than to his real name. He could become a drug-courier and earn good money, he could work in the office writing occasional reports on his colleagues who use the Internet for their own purposes. He could try to make his parents' dream come true, go into university and become one of his many peers for whom a career is the top priority. Tir chooses another way. He enters a strange game where real life is the playing ground. He guesses the riddles and tries to find the author of this game, the anonymous and enigmatic Python - a graffiti artist who makes true masterpieces of his kind. Everything linked to Python is mystics-ridden, permeated with city folklore, reaching out beyond the laws of reality. Finding Python, becoming like Python, taking hold of his magical opportunities for artistic self-realization - this preoccupies Tir more than anything else. City magicians, strange signs, mysterious Internet labyrinths, love that Tir meets in search of his dreams, the death of a friend, all this is intertwined in symbols that are just about to become readable.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?153392</url></doc>
