<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="153460">
  <docid>153460</docid>
  <title>DocStock</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Ficara, Rich</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Reality-TV</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">3 March 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Sagan, Sasha</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Toba, Jage</producer>
    <producer>Sagan, Sasha</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Carroll, Rebecca (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Abrams, Abiola</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carroll, Rebecca (I)</actor>
      <role>Host</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fleischer, Rachel</actor>
      <role>Herself (2007)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Furjanic, Cheryl</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nussbaum, Gabriel</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Poras, Marlo</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Raftery, Bill</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Plum TV takes the side of the independent filmmaker and profiles work that is truly independent, and still in progress. With channels in Aspen, Vail, Martha's Vineyard, the Hamptons and Nantucket, Plum has an audience that can change the life of a filmmaker and change the destiny of a film. DocStock features the very best documentaries-in-progress, along with smart, funny, and pointed interviews with the filmmakers who make them. It is hosted by Rebecca Carroll, a critically acclaimed author, interviewer, and editor-at-large of The Independent Film &amp; Video Monthly magazine. Says Plum CEO Tom Scott, "By profiling these great films and filmmakers, we can be a platform for them and their movies, getting them exposure that is typically unavailable to these types of projects." The life of a film can be changed by the tastemakers that watch our channels: the writers and editors, brokers and reps, lawyers, distributors, filmmakers, directors and producers who love movies and can spot talent when they see it.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?153460</url></doc>
