<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="154238">
  <docid>154238</docid>
  <title>Doing Therapy</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Giacobello, Joe</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>cult-favorite</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>anxiety</keyword>
    <keyword>male-female-relationship</keyword>
    <keyword>love</keyword>
    <keyword>panic</keyword>
    <keyword>melodrama</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">10 March 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">98</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Giacobello, Joe</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Giacobello, Joe</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Giacobello, Joe</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dietz, David</actor>
      <role>Crazed Stalker</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fisher, Minda</actor>
      <role>Reporter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Giacobello, Joe</actor>
      <role>Joe Giacobello</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Interval, Tom</actor>
      <role>Dr. Thomas Warner</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kernion, Jackson</actor>
      <role>Bob Thorton</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Quinn, Patrick Kernan</actor>
      <role>Mike/Boom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sestric, Chris</actor>
      <role>Camera Guy</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"Doing Therapy" is a lighthearted romantic comedy set in modern-day Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. Humorous, silly, and even suspenseful at times, it is a heartwarming tale with the sincerity and simplicity of a black-and-white 1950s melodrama. In the middle of a highly successful film career, Diane Rischard, a famous Hollywood actress, suddenly develops a problem while onstage. She is stricken with frightful, paralyzing panic attacks that begin to affect her job and her personal life. In an effort to help her, her family seeks out the best anxiety specialist in the country -- an offbeat psychologist (Joe Giacobello) working out of a clinic in Pittsburgh. To avoid the media attention, Diane goes to Pittsburgh, and the unlikely couple is stuck together for an entire month in extensive 24-hour-a-day therapy. As they work together to figure out her problem, Diane reveals that she has been harboring a secret -- a man has been stalking her. The psychotic predator soon surfaces, once again posing a threat to her physical and mental well being. Through therapy, both patient and doctor learn a great deal about themselves and each other. Struggling with his own "ghosts" from the past, Joe fights his feelings for Diane. Eventually, Diane puts her new skills to the test as she shoots a major scene for an upcoming movie. In an action-packed climax, the stalker appears on the set and attempts to kill her. In the end, both Joe and Diane must face their greatest fears, head-on, in a struggle for life, love, and sanity. Can they come to terms with their issues without driving each other completely insane?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?154238</url></doc>
