<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="156279">
  <docid>156279</docid>
  <title>Doolittle Raiders</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Mattson, Todd Kennedy</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">15 October 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Mattson, Todd Kennedy</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Mattson, Todd Kennedy</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Holt, John (VIII)</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>"Doolittle Raiders" is an animated documentary, portrayed through the viewpoint of the opposition to Bush from within Bush country, both inside and outside the system. The feature has been animated using a rotoscoping process, going through live action frame by frame, and using that as the basis for animation. The animation style is loosely based on the oil and watercolor looks of realistic American painters such as Edward Hopper, Andrew Wyeth, Winslow Homer, and John Singer-Sargent - whose paintings can, at a distance, be mistaken for a photograph. Starting and ending in Crawford, Texas, "Doolittle Raiders" follows Texan Deaniacs up to Iowa for the primaries, Texan protestors to NYC for the 2004 RNC protests, Demfest 2005 in Austin, and finally Cindy Sheehan's roadside protest in Crawford. Various political figures show up from time to time, although the focus of the film is more about the common man and woman involved in politics, and more specifically, a comparison/contrast of the approaches of Democratic party activists and war protestors. Where do their methods and ideologies overlap, and where do they diverge?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?156279</url></doc>
