<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="157074">
  <docid>157074</docid>
  <title>Dost</title>
  <year>1989</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">4 August 1989</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Muralimohana Rao, K.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Suryanarayana, A.</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Burman, Rahul Dev</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Amala</actor>
      <role>Pooja</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anand, Vikas</actor>
      <role>Raja's boss</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Asrani</actor>
      <role>Sukhiya/Sukha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chakraborty, Mithun</actor>
      <role>Raja</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Christo, Bob</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gaud, Jack</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ghanshyam</actor>
      <role>Bhola (Brijmohan's servant)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Annu</actor>
      <role>Forest Officer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Amjad (I)</actor>
      <role>Sher Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Kader (I)</actor>
      <role>Budhi (Sher's nephew)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khote, Shubha</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Sher Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Kiran (I)</actor>
      <role>Nagendra S. Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Sujit (I)</actor>
      <role>Brijmohan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Manmauji</actor>
      <role>Poojary</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mishra, Bandini</actor>
      <role>Gilli</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Saxena, Sharat</actor>
      <role>Mongola</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tahil, Dalip</actor>
      <role>Anthony</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>After the shooting death of Forest Officer Anthony, the authorities assign orphaned Raja to his post, which he accepts. Upon arrival, he finds out that there are some corrupt officials working, and he quickly dismisses them. He than, with the help of local tribals and their leader, Mongola, exerts control over the region, preventing poaching, illegal cutting of trees, event rescues an elephant from the jaws of a crocodile. He meets with wealthy Pooja, and both fall in love with each other. Pooja's dad, Brijmohan, wants her to marry Nagendra, the son of Sher Singh, but Pooja refuses to do so, and as a result marries Raja without her father's blessings. As a result of poaching and confining Pooja, Nagendra and Sher are arrested and imprisoned for six years. Six years later, they are released and find out that Pooja is still married to Raja and they now have a son. Nagendra and Sher conceive a scheme to break-up their marriage, get Pooja and her son out of the way, and then kill Raja. Before they could take any steps in this direction, the elephant that was rescued by Raja, goes berserk, destroys property, attacks Pooja, Raja and their son, grievously injuring him, and has to be subdued. As a result of this attack, Pooja decides to leave Raja and goes back to live with her dad. Now Raja must decide what is to be done about the elephant; protect himself against Nagendra and Sher Singh; as well as attempt a reconciliation with his wife and son. The question remains, does he have enough time to do this?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?157074</url></doc>
