<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="158981">
  <docid>158981</docid>
  <title>DragonMan: The Adventures of Luke Starr</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <genres>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>based-on-novel</keyword>
    <keyword>animal-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <producers>
    <producer>Domina, Mario</producer>
    <producer>Domina, Mario</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Lazaris, Ted</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Teenager Luke Starr appears to be living a rather dull uneventful life in Milwaukee, Wisconsin. That is until a mysterious dark force catapults Luke into a series of wondrous adventures. Luke Starr, respected, feared and hated by many as the one born to greatness is suddenly propelled with great swiftness into a nightmare, forced to come face to face with destiny. DragonMan is an unforgettable fantasy adventure, filled with wizardry and mystery that carries you away on the wings of magic to bewitching lands, where fairies dwell, wizards rule and witches still cast their evil spells. The story unfolds with the mood of impending danger set early on, as a well liked young teenage hero, Luke Starr, enters a mysterious realm of Earth known as the mythical world of Spellville, by way of an eerie portal in search of his kidnapped friends. For despite his humble Midwest origins, Luke is no ordinary teenager. Imbued with super powers following a ritualistic exchange of blood with a clever dragon, Luke soon discovers the awesome legacy of his birthright, a dark side of great strength, brutal fury and must learn to accept the fact that he is known in this other world as the Chosen One. Still, unquestionably human, he must come to grips with what he has now become, the most violent force in nature; a dragon hybrid, known as DragonMan. And ready or not, he is thrust into a nightmarish life and death battle to try and save Planet Earth from alien beings hell-bent on destruction. At the same time grappling with his own fears and doubts while always in an inner conflict with himself trying to keep the violent nature of the dragon in check, making it a tough road to travel for this Christian teenage boy of strong religious and morals beliefs. In a pace that never flags, Luke and an ancient dragon must now join together in an epic struggle that is all neatly stitched together by an intriguing cast of characters, both good and evil and not-exactly-as-they-seem, wherein unsolved murders, a mysterious psychic and an ominous stranger keep the action rolling until the climactic conclusion.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?158981</url></doc>
