<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="160458">
  <docid>160458</docid>
  <title>Drona</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Salgonkar, Shyam K.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>fight</keyword>
    <keyword>prague</keyword>
    <keyword>sandstorm</keyword>
    <keyword>horse</keyword>
    <keyword>save-the-world</keyword>
    <keyword>good-versus-evil</keyword>
    <keyword>snorricam</keyword>
    <keyword>hero</keyword>
    <keyword>train</keyword>
    <keyword>sword</keyword>
    <keyword>beautiful-woman</keyword>
    <keyword>castle</keyword>
    <keyword>villain</keyword>
    <keyword>female-bodyguard</keyword>
    <keyword>bodyguard</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>one-word-title</keyword>
    <keyword>magic</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Ireland">12A</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Netherlands">2 October 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="India">2 October 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="UK">2 October 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Behl, Goldie</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kidwai, Iqbal</producer>
    <producer>Humlova, Daniela</producer>
    <producer>Oberoi, Namrata</producer>
    <producer>Behl, Shrishti</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Behl, Goldie</writer>
    <writer>Sarkar, Jaydeep</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Ghanekar, Dhruv</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bachchan, Abhishek</actor>
      <role>Drona</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bachchan, Jaya</actor>
      <role>Queen Jayati</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chopra, Priyanka</actor>
      <role>Sonia</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fischerová, Tatána</actor>
      <role>Sister Anne</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Menon, Kay Kay</actor>
      <role>Riz Raizada</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stevens, Conan</actor>
      <role>Asura - Demon</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Far away in a distant town, there was once a young man named Aditya, Brought up by a foster family, Adita was unaware of his real identity and the destiny that awaited him. Ever since he was a child, a recurring nightmare haunted him. And when he woke up in fright, there was no one he could ever hold on to except for a magical BlueCross petal that came wafting in the wind, never failing to make him smile through his tears. Somewhere far from here, an evil sorcerer, Riz Raizada, a descendant of the asuras (legendary demons) had become dangerously impatient, in his thirst for the precious secret. The secret, which was the missing link, in this grand plan of taking over the universe. To get to the secret, he'd have to defeat the Drona. And herein, lay his problem. He didn't know who or where the Drona was! One sudden day Aditya and Riz came face to face and Riz immediately recognized him as the Drona. Aditya's destiny had caught up with him and his life was about to take him on a journey he had never imagined. Aditya couldn't comprehend why Riz's men were hunting him down. Just when he was about to be captured, a cult that believed that The Drona was their Messiah came to his rescue. Sonia, the leader of the cult, revealed Aditya's real identify to him. Baffled, Aditya found it all too hard to believe. Having no time to lose, Sonia decided to take Aditya back to his place of birth, the ancient kingdom of Pratapgarh where his mother, Queen Jayanti Devi would have all the answers to his questions. But before he could embrace his mother, Riz and his army of the darkest powers caught up with him. Aditya would now have to rise to the occasion and embrace his destiny. For the sake of mankind he would have to become the legendary warrior he was born to be. Drona. Thus began Drona's journey through myths and legends. Along with Sonia, he would fight the evil spells of the absolutely lethal Riz Raizada. By battling odds, he would discover skills that he never knew he had. But would his fears catch up with him? Would the nightmares from his childhood come in the way of his epic journey? As good and evil clash in this contemporary fantasy fable, a breathtaking adventure beckons you into a world of mythic heroes and malicious magicians, of enchanted lands and life altering choices, of cunning curses and absolute innocence. The magnificent world of Drona!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?160458</url></doc>
