<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="162375">
  <docid>162375</docid>
  <title>Durgaa Maa</title>
  <year>1986</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Reddy, K.S. Rami</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bhagyam, Smt P.</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Jain, Ravindra</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Banerjee, Beena</actor>
      <role>Annapurna</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khote, Shubha</actor>
      <role>Shanta</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kiran, Raj</actor>
      <role>Non-believer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Pradeep</actor>
      <role>Superintendent of Police</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Malhotra, Madhu</actor>
      <role>Kaushalya K. Mahajan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Murad, Raza</actor>
      <role>Harihar Swami</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Paintal</actor>
      <role>Karodimal 'Lalaji' Mahajan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sachin (I)</actor>
      <role>Shankar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shivpuri, Om</actor>
      <role>Somnath</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The Superintendent of Police of a town in India finds an abandoned female baby on the footsteps of Devi Maa Durga's Mandir, takes her home, much to chagrin of his wife, Shanta, adopts her and names her Parvati, who grows up to be a staunch devotee of Devi Maa Durga but is subjected to emotional and physical abuse by Shanta. When her foster father finds out that she is attracted to a poor newspaper delivery boy and the Mandir's flute-player, Shankar, he arranges their marriage, and even lets them live in a shanty hut that he owns in the same town. Parvati must, however, attend to the daily chores which include cooking, cleaning, and washing dirty dishes in Shanta's house. The couple soon become parents of a daughter and name her Durga. The town's money-lender Karodimal Mahajan, in his quest for more wealth, solicits the services of Harihar Swami, who asks him to perform the sacrifice of a young 7 year old healthy girl who is free of all physical and mental ailments. Watch what happens when Karodimal selects Durga for this sacrifice.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?162375</url></doc>
