<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="162437">
  <docid>162437</docid>
  <title>Dushman Duniya Ka</title>
  <year>1996</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Heera, S.</editor>
  </editors>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">20 September 1996</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Mehmood (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ali, Masoom</producer>
    <producer>Babubhai</producer>
    <producer>Mishra, Ashok (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Quaisi, Aziz</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Malik, Anu</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ali, Manzoor</actor>
      <role>Lucky</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Das, Chetana</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jalal, Farida</actor>
      <role>Manager of women's shelter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jankidas</actor>
      <role>Jankidas</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jeetendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Mahesh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Salman (I)</actor>
      <role>Special appearance</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Shahrukh</actor>
      <role>Badru (Rickshaw driver)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Ashok (I)</actor>
      <role>Doctor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Laila (I)</actor>
      <role>Lata</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lever, Johnny</actor>
      <role>Head-master/College Lecturer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lilliput</actor>
      <role>Professor Liliput</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Manmauji</actor>
      <role>Shop-keeper</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mehmood (I)</actor>
      <role>Baba, drug pedlar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Murad, Raza</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nasir (III)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Raj, Jagdish</actor>
      <role>Police Inspector</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sharma, Abhishek</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Mahesh is a honest and diligent young man, who has no knowledge of his background as he was raised in an orphanage. One day he meets Reshma, who is also an orphan, and both fall in love and get married. They live a harmonious life, and soon are proud parents of a healthy young boy who they name Lucky. Lucky grows up to be as honest and diligent as his dad, and his future appears to be very bright. Lucky has a childhood sweetheart in Lata, and both plan to marry soon with the blessings of their respective parents. Then Mahesh's world is turned upside down when he finds drugs in Lucky's pocket. He speaks to Lucky about this, and Lucky promises to give up drugs forever, and does live up to his promise. While driving home one day, Mahesh witnesses a drug peddler selling drugs to a group of youths, which also included Lucky. He notifies the police, and they arrest the youths, but the peddler manages to escape. All the other youth tested positive for drugs, except for Lucky. When he returns home, his parents refuse to believe him, this angers him and he and his father come close to fisticuffs. Mahesh asks Lucky to leave, and he does so. Even Lata will have nothing to do with him. Lucky regresses to drugs and his friends, until he runs out of money. Now he must either steal or even consider killing someone for money, - and the only ones he could think of taking money from are his parents. What will be Lucky's fate?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?162437</url></doc>
