<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="163809">
  <docid>163809</docid>
  <title>E nu lie zhuan</title>
  <year>1999</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>shoplifting</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Mandarin</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Taiwan</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Taiwan">PG-12</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Taiwan">14 August 1999</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">115</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Chan, Ying-Yu</director>
    <director>Lin, Jing-Jie</director>
    <director>Wen, Yao-ting</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Chiu, Shun-Ching</producer>
    <producer>Wang, Shih-Fang</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Chan, Ying-Yu</writer>
    <writer>Lin, Jing-Jie</writer>
    <writer>Wen, Yao-ting</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chang, Ken (II)</actor>
      <role>Cop (segment "My Own Personal Gun")</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chang, Shih</actor>
      <role>Man (segment "Queen of the Bench")</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chia, Alyssa</actor>
      <role>Xiao Ping (segment "A Dog from Hong Kong")</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chung, Wallace (I)</actor>
      <role>Ah-Liang (segment "A Dog from Hong Kong")</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fan, Rui-Jun</actor>
      <role>Li Li (segment "Queen of the Bench")</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Huang, Pei-Wen</actor>
      <role>Xiao Lu (segment "A Dog from Hong Kong")</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lin, Ruby</actor>
      <role>Girl (segment "Queen of the Bench")</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This is a collection of three films by emerging Taiwanese directors all revolving around the theme of strong, young women involved in mayhem of some sort. In all of them the theme of alienation within the crowded streets of Taiwan runs strong. "Queen of the Bench" (Yao-Ting Wen dir.) Li Li is an extra who longs for her big break as an actress. In the meantime she spends much of her time shoplifting and trying to find creative ways to break into the big time. After pestering a director and ambushing him in the parking lot to get a part, she gets the call and shows up ready to be a star. Will this really be her chance or is she being exploited? "My Own Personal Gun" (Jing-Jie Lin dir.) Ah-Tsai is wasting her life with drugs, hanging out with losers and small time crooks. One day she passes out in front of a young cop who falls for her in a big way. He makes excuses to run into her and she doctors his drink. He wakes up to find she has stolen his gun and she leads him on a wild goos chase to retrieve it. While he runs all over the city looking for it, the gun is still in her possession. Will she use it to spiral even further down into oblivion? "A Dog from Hong Kong" (Ying-Yu Chan dir.) A recent Immigrant from HK brings along his pet doggy who promptly becomes lost. He is heart-broken and sets up fliers everywhere to find him. In the mean time, two women find the little pup and take him in. When one of the girls meets the owner and sees his fliers, she decides to play a trick on him. She and her friend dye the dog a different color and ask him to take care of it for awhile. What will happen if he discovers the trick?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?163809</url></doc>
