<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="164193">
  <docid>164193</docid>
  <title>Eager Beavers</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Murphy, Curtis</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">17 May 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Harris, Mary (X)</director>
    <director>Murphy, Curtis</director>
    <director>Tomarchio, Bridgetta</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Harris, Mary (X)</producer>
    <producer>Murphy, Curtis</producer>
    <producer>Tomarchio, Bridgetta</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Harris, Mary (X)</writer>
    <writer>Murphy, Curtis</writer>
    <writer>Tomarchio, Bridgetta</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Archontis, Aris</actor>
      <role>House Owner</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bragg Lumsden, Melissa</actor>
      <role>Drea</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chick, Erin</actor>
      <role>Crew Girl</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Duncan, Cameron (V)</actor>
      <role>Randi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harris, Mary (X)</actor>
      <role>Katy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Keane, Sean (III)</actor>
      <role>Crew Guy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Klecha, Nikki</actor>
      <role>Brooke</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Murphy, Curtis</actor>
      <role>Curtis</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Reetz, Michael</actor>
      <role>Jeff</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rundle, Kieran</actor>
      <role>Guy in Park</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Supeck, Steve</actor>
      <role>Dog Owner</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wahlquist, Brian</actor>
      <role>Joey</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Hollywood pseudo-celebrity Bridgetta, (the beauty, and established actress and model in Hollywood), and her long time, sensible friend Katy, (the brains), decided to start a business together in Hollywood, pimping out good looking folks to do household chores for a high price. So instead of people hiring a normal cleaning service to do household chores, clients can call upon Eager Beavers to have a hot girl/guy to do all sorts of odds and ends jobs. Clients can pay a bit extra to even have their hot chore person wear a bikini or a fetish outfit! Bridgetta's motto is 'Hollywood is a vary vain place to live so why not profit from it?!' Most of the clients are celebrity clientele. In fact, each episode will feature at least 1 celebrity client. Celebrities will play themselves, but everyone else is fictional. But who doesn't want their own reality show these days?! Bridgetta thinks it's a great idea to hire a crew to film a reality series around the set up and progress of their business. That way they can get some publicity for their company out of it as well. Katy just had NO idea what she was getting herself into while going into business with Bridgetta. The girls run into a lot of trouble trying to overcome the challenges, both expected and unexpected, coupled with their inexperience and downright stupidity.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?164193</url></doc>
