<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="164263">
  <docid>164263</docid>
  <title>Earl's Canoe: A Traditional Ojibwe Craft</title>
  <year>2000</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>waterway</keyword>
    <keyword>ojibwa-indian</keyword>
    <keyword>equipment</keyword>
    <keyword>environmental-issues</keyword>
    <keyword>tool</keyword>
    <keyword>native-american</keyword>
    <keyword>ritual</keyword>
    <keyword>craft</keyword>
    <keyword>spiritual</keyword>
    <keyword>canoe-building</keyword>
    <keyword>wisconsin</keyword>
    <keyword>transportation</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>usa</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">27</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Vennum, Thomas</director>
    <director>Weber, Charles (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Vennum, Thomas</producer>
    <producer>Weber, Charles (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nyholm, Earl</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>With the participation of other members of the Ojibwe Nation In this documentary we meet Earl Nyholm, a member of the Ojibwe Nation, as he walks through the woods on Madeleine Island, Wisconsin. He's looking for just the right birch tree to select for the bark which will be used in the making of a traditional Ojibwe canoe. He talks about the respect that the Ojibwe People have for nature and for the spirit of the particular tree used in the making of a canoe following the traditions that had been handed down through the generations. We are told that this spot is a good one for building this canoe as Madeline Island was a sacred place and a center for the Ojibwe Nation in earlier times. We watch the entire process from peeling the bark from the tree to shaping the form of the canoe with heavy rocks and then the elegant stitching together of the canoe's parts. Earl tells us that artists have always depicted birch bark canoes with the distinctive white pattern of the bark on the outside. This is a myth, as they are actually made with the white, outer bark of the tree, on the inside of the canoe. While the task is arduous the work proceeds step by step with the help of other members of the Ojibwe Nation. The excellent camerawork allows us to see in great detail the ingenious process. While it is not as easy as going down to the local sporting goods shop and picking up an aluminum model, there is the sense of satisfaction knowing that the materials and the process are integrated with the natural environment and provide a spiritual link to the past. This program is suitable for all ages and will be very useful for anyone interested in canoe making, in the preserving of a Native American craft, in teaching Native American Studies, and anthropology.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?164263</url></doc>
