<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="165705">
  <docid>165705</docid>
  <title>Edmund</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Christopher, Erahm</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">8 October 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">18</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Christopher, Erahm</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Annab, Dana</producer>
    <producer>Pohl, John C.</producer>
    <producer>Christopher, Erahm</producer>
    <producer>Stiban, Sam</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Christopher, Erahm</writer>
    <writer>Romanski, Daniel</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Fung, Darren</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Browne, Dominique</actor>
      <role>Kate Clark</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chakron, Valerie</actor>
      <role>Renee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Corbeil, Jesse</actor>
      <role>Jack</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dansky, Martin</actor>
      <role>Mr. Gromes</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fagan, Doreen</actor>
      <role>Debra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kartus-Solomon, Evy</actor>
      <role>Ms. Slovac</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Paterson, Mike (II)</actor>
      <role>Ben</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Romanski, Daniel</actor>
      <role>Edmund</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zimmerman, Shawn (I)</actor>
      <role>Josh</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Edmund is a socially challenged inventory clerk struggling to interpret the world around him. He lives alone in an oddly organized apartment and is consumed by drink coasters, television programs, and logic puzzles. Despite his disorders, he has managed, with the help of his brother, to maintain a job, relationship, and routine that provides normality in his life. However, this comfortable existence changes completely when a late night reality show inspires him to propose to his current girlfriend. Motivated by his belief that marriage will further normalize his life, he leaves work early to craft an engagement surprise in her apartment that she will never forget. While Edmund is passing the time at his favorite tavern, his younger brother arrives to borrow money and coherence him to replace an absent player at a weekly poker game. Edmund agrees to attend under strict conditions that will not break his daily routine. At the game, Edmund's emotions flair when he discovers one of the players has been sleeping with his girlfriend. After a short scuffle he leaves the game running and begins an emotional journey that creates confusion and chaos in his seemingly ordered life.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?165705</url></doc>
