<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="165856">
  <docid>165856</docid>
  <title>Edward</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>History</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>adult-film</keyword>
    <keyword>anime</keyword>
    <keyword>human-rights</keyword>
    <keyword>children</keyword>
    <keyword>surrealism</keyword>
    <keyword>student-film</keyword>
    <keyword>alternative</keyword>
    <keyword>experimental</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hungarian</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Hungary</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Hungary">19 June 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Hungary">8</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="default">9</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Bogdán, Zoltán</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bogdán, Zoltán</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kárpáti, Tibor (II)</actor>
      <role>All characters</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Edward arrives in Wales. The Earl of Montgomery entertains the King. Edward is not enjoying the feast, because his vanity is not flattered enough. He demands that his greatness be celebrated in a toast, but none of the guests dare to answer the King's request. So, the King demands that a local bard sing a song about his greatness. The first bard is an old man who starts to sing about Edward's cruel atrocities. Edward is angered and sends the bard to the burning stake. The next bard is a young one. He continues the way of the old bard, so he is sent to the stake as well. The third bard is a strong and huge one who comes without calling. He breaks everything and scatters everyone, but the superior number of soldiers overcome him. Then Edward orders to burn every bard who doesn't want to yield. After this action Edward runs back to his home in London but he can't enjoy himself. The sense of guilt drives him mad because five hundred bards went to the flames singing but none of them yielded.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?165856</url></doc>
