<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="166305">
  <docid>166305</docid>
  <title>Eggbaby</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Wessel, Brian (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>first-kiss</keyword>
    <keyword>teenage-girl</keyword>
    <keyword>asian-american</keyword>
    <keyword>teen-angst</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">14 June 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">22</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Truong, Nadine</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hamamoto, Andi</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>No, Christine</writer>
    <writer>Truong, Nadine</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Montes, Zeltia</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Axford, Ashley</actor>
      <role>Catholic School Student</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Balmores, Cristina</actor>
      <role>Allison</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Banham, Camille</actor>
      <role>Catholic School Student</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barer, Libe</actor>
      <role>Liz</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Berthiaume, Monique</actor>
      <role>Catholic School Student</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dugan, Katie</actor>
      <role>Catholic School Student</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ellis, Emily</actor>
      <role>Catholic School Student</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fudim, Danielle</actor>
      <role>Catholic School Student</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Graul, Alyssa</actor>
      <role>Catholic School Student</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hamamoto, Tori</actor>
      <role>Catholic School Student</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hoashi, Keisuke</actor>
      <role>Mr. Chin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kowal, Tim</actor>
      <role>Grocery Store Patron</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McGuire, Michael (XII)</actor>
      <role>Grocery Store Patron</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Miller, Jennifer (XXV)</actor>
      <role>Catholic School Student</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Newkerk, Jonathan</actor>
      <role>Grocery Store Cashier</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ryhne, Oh</actor>
      <role>Grocery Store Patron</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Allison, an innocent 15 year old Asian American Catholic school girl, who is assigned to care for her own little EGGBABY, is trying to understand the world around her. The EGGBABY class assignment on responsibility coincides with her very first romance with an old boy. After her mother refuses to let her take an egg from home for her EGGBABY project, Allison steals one from her local supermarket. It's is there where she meets the handsome older grocery store clerk named Matt. Matt gives Allison her first kiss and a new and exciting relationship forms. Armed with conflicting messages, from her friend Liz, her parents, clashing cultural messages, and her own beliefs; Allison experiments with the clerk. She becomes overwhelmed with the responsibility of caring for her EGGBABY and her budding romance with Matt, especially after her mother, Mrs. Chin, lambastes for talking about sex. Things become even more complicated when Matt expresses that he wants to take things to the next level. Allison, naive and innocent, is not ready. Things are further complicated when she accidentally walks in on her parents having sex. This upsets Allison and as a result, she hastily runs to Matt and angrily demands that he have sex with her. Matt, realizing that Allison is blinded by anger and frustration, rebuffs her pleas and demands. Allison is humiliated and tells Matt to leave her alone. Mrs. Chin catches Allison sneaking back into the house at 2am. Allison confesses to Mrs. Chin that she was with Matt. When Mrs. Chin starts to lecture Allison about boys, Allison lies and blurts out that she had sex with Matt. Mrs. Chin, reeling and hurt by her daughter's 'confession' retreats to her bedroom. Allison follows her, all the while pleading for her mother to talk to her. In a fit of rage, Allison smashes the EGGBABY against the door. In that moment, Allison must come to terms with love, loss, responsibility, and growing up.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?166305</url></doc>
