<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="169367">
  <docid>169367</docid>
  <title>El bosque de la luz</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>San Martín, Puy</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>bosnian-war</keyword>
    <keyword>teenager</keyword>
    <keyword>racism</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Austria">20 June 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">28</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Alastruey, Karlos</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Lasa, Koldo</producer>
    <producer>González, Miguel Ángel (VII)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Alastruey, Karlos</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Evoghli, Arsham</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Alastruey, Aintzane</actor>
      <role>Anna</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Baigorri, Javier</actor>
      <role>Drunk man</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Berruezo, Itziar</actor>
      <role>Lidia</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Castillo, Hektor</actor>
      <role>Branko</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lahuerta, Santiago</actor>
      <role>Skinhead</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A drunken man in a bar is insulting immigrants, disabled and ethnic minorities (a story non connected with the other one, and that will end with a beating received by the drunken man from a group of skins). In parallel, three Bosnian Muslim brothers (a teenager girl and two children) run out of their village, just destroyed, and where their parents have been killed by Serbian paramilitaries. The children are terrified and walk about through the forest till they meet a Serbian paramilitary who just left his group, because he cannot stand anymore with the killings and massacres. The children try to escape from the Serbian, but one of them steps on a mine and dies in front of his sisters. From that moment on, the paramilitary takes care of them, and together they start a journey towards the seashore trying to escape the war. In their way they meet a Serbian junior youth, which has lost his parents too. In a first moment he shows a big refuse to the Bosnian Muslim girls. Paradoxically, thanks to the Serbian paramilitary, the Serbian boy will learn to respect them as human beings. During their journey, the Bosnian teenager discovers that the paramilitary belongs to the group that destroyed her village and killed her parents. One night, some noises are heard and the paramilitary goes to see, but he is killed. The next day the group follows its way, now without any adult. Hungry and tired they arrive to a solitary house where a woman offers them food, and where the transformation made in the children during the journey will be made manifest.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?169367</url></doc>
