<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="170602">
  <docid>170602</docid>
  <title>El encuentro de un hombre solo</title>
  <year>1974</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bustos, José W.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Mexico</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Mexico">24 October 1974</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">100</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Olhovich, Sergio</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Badin, Anuar</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Olhovich, Sergio</writer>
    <writer>Peña, Rodolfo F.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Carrión, Gustavo César</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Aspíllaga, Patricia</actor>
      <role>Susana</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bracho, Diana</actor>
      <role>Renata Castillo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gimeno, Luis (I)</actor>
      <role>Giacomo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Joscowicks, Alfredo</actor>
      <role>intelectual</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Luke, Jorge</actor>
      <role>Alberto Romero</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>López Rojas, Eduardo</actor>
      <role>maestro</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Obregón, Alfonso</actor>
      <role>young Alberto</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Obregón, Claudio</actor>
      <role>Guido Leone</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puebla, Rodrigo</actor>
      <role>Gabriel Martínez Escapita</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ramos, Ricardo (I)</actor>
      <role>young Gabriel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Retes, Gabriel</actor>
      <role>Ricardo Arriola</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Alberto Romero is a writer and journalist. He's trying to write a novel, inspiring himself in his own childhood in a small town. Alberto remembers a traumatic event, when his best friend Gabriel burns out after he saves a baby girl from a fire. Fortunaly, Gabriel survives but he's very injured and has to wear a bandage all over his head and hands. But Gabriel becomes a hero in the town. Days later, Alberto has to move to Mexico City, and never sees again Gabriel. As an adult, Alberto works for a paper and develops a literary career writing tales. He has a friend, Guido who's very gifted for writing and criticizes Alberto's texts, believing that he still has to give his best in writing literature. One day, Alberto decides to visit Obregon, his native town, in order to find some inspiration for his novel. Guido gives him some advices, like talk with common people and learn about his real life. But Alberto will find his old friend Gabriel, living a miserable life because of his deformed face and dealing with the scorn and the gibes from the villagers. The baby saved by Gabriel is now a pretty girl, Renata and Gabriel is in love with her. Alberto will try to catch up with Gabriel, now a carpenter. But Gabriel's blaming Alberto about his deformity, because that day Gabriel was the brave one and Alberto simply felt fear. Renata doesn't know that Gabriel saved her when she was a baby. But Alberto has a problem with alcohol, and during a drunkenness moment he will ask for Gabriel to do something terrible with Renata, so he can gets the end for his novel.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?170602</url></doc>
