<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="174980">
  <docid>174980</docid>
  <title>Electric Revolution: Gage Brewer</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bayerl, Brian</editor>
    <editor>Moormann, Mark</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>electric-guitar</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">10 April 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">12</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Moormann, Mark</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bayerl, Brian</producer>
    <producer>Moormann, Mark</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brewer, Loti</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>'Electric Revolution' documents Gage Brewer's world premiere performance of the electric guitar in Wichita, Kansas in 1932. Like so much else having to do with the obscure origins of the electric guitar, the name of Gage Brewer had slipped into the foggy past. Brewer never recorded a record or published a hit song, but he did acquire two pre-production electrics from his guitar maker friend George Beauchamp in Los Angeles, and brought them back to Wichita for a series of highly publicized Halloween concerts, the first public performances using an electric guitar. Gage Brewer died in obscurity in Wichita in 1985, unknown and unappreciated. The producers traveled to Kansas to shoot an exhibit honoring Brewer's career and highlighting the origins of the electric guitar. Loti Brewer, Gage's son, was interviewed at his father's grave site, and across the street at Gage's former Shadowland club. Included in the short film is the song "Just You Sweet You," the earliest known Gage Brewer composition. Using Brewer's prototype 1932 Ro-Pat-In Spanish-style electric guitar and a vintage Rickenbacher 'frying pan' electric steel guitar, the song was brought to life by musicians and recording engineers inside the Shadowland club in Wichita, Kansas.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?174980</url></doc>
