<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="176238">
  <docid>176238</docid>
  <title>Embargo</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Huppé, Paul</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>French</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">5 April 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">23</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Forgues, Jocelyn</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Charbonneau, Robert</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Forgues, Jocelyn</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Aymar, Marcel</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Blundell, Nicole (II)</actor>
      <role>Julianne Ladouceur</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>D'Ambrosio, Anthony</actor>
      <role>Antoine</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hammond, Tori</actor>
      <role>Nikki</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mancini, Michael (VI)</actor>
      <role>Marc Ladouceur</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Thibodeau, Guy</actor>
      <role>Roméo Ladouceur</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Marc Ladouceur (Michael Mancini) has taken over the family cattle ranch from his father (Guy Thibodeau), but as the summer draws to a close, things are getting rough for Canadian ranchers. Onerous decisions by the Food Inspection Agency, a US embargo on Canadian beef - everything is playing against them. The ranchers mobilize, but the Ladouceur farm is sinking deeper into debt and the situation is taking its toll on Marc and Julianne's (Nicole Blundell) marriage. Is there any way out? Embargo raconte l'histoire touchante de Marc Ladouceur (Michael Mancini) propriétaire d'une ferme bovine dans l'Est ontarien. Les choses ne vont pas très bien pour les éleveurs de bovins au Canada : décisions de l'Agence canadienne d'inspection des aliments, embargo des États-Unis sur le boeuf canadien, tout joue en leur défaveur. Les agriculteurs se mobilisent, mais pendant ce temps, à la ferme Ladouceur, les dettes s'accumulent et Marc voit son mariage avec Julianne (Nicole Blundell) battre de l'aile. Une solution est-elle envisageable?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?176238</url></doc>
