<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="183259">
  <docid>183259</docid>
  <title>Eugene</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Mandarin</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Singapore</country>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">PG-13</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">6</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <writers>
    <writer>Jayaram, Nikhil</writer>
    <writer>Kuhnz, Anthony</writer>
    <writer>Wu, Min Xiu</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kuhnz, Anthony</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Soo, Eugene</actor>
      <role>Eugene</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Eugene is a monologue loosely based on a number of stories that may or may not be true, collected from a single interview. The events recount Eugene's experiences of gang and army life that coincide with the development of his personal philosophy. The film will be shot part interview style but consists of mostly non-diegetic inserts that match the tone of Eugene's monologue. In the first act, he recounts three main events of his past gang life: 1.) Reasonless fights with rival gangs, inserts of his favorite weapon: a motorcycle helmet, "Because you don't look suspicious with them." 2.) The importance of tattoos as identification, inserts of Eugene's tattoos and a montage of close-ups of a clean physique and 3.) An awkward moment with a blood-covered friend, inserts of gang members running through a mall intercut with Eugene lighting a cigarette. Eugene recalls a moment of his army life in the second act. He tells us the story of a kid jumping off the tenth floor of his apartment. Insert Eugene flicking a cigarette off the edge. He also briefly recalls the funeral, "I didn't know what to feel;He had everything. It was all such a waste, you know?" We see how this event changed Eugene's outlook in the third act as he looks back at his life and expresses his new personal philosophy: We should learn from others' mistakes and live life with a bit of grace. He briefly explains the Buddhist philosophy of karma and how "You are responsible for yourself."</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?183259</url></doc>
