<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="184632">
  <docid>184632</docid>
  <title>Everywhere But Here</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Snider, Paul (III)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>shipwreck</keyword>
    <keyword>nature</keyword>
    <keyword>children</keyword>
    <keyword>lost</keyword>
    <keyword>love</keyword>
    <keyword>marooned</keyword>
    <keyword>island</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">4 October 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">80</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Snider, Paul (III)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Raines, David (III)</producer>
    <producer>Snider, Paul (III)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Snider, Paul (III)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Snider, Paul (III)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Snider, Michael (II)</actor>
      <role>Ryan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Snider, Paul (III)</actor>
      <role>Jeff</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Jeff is an entrepreneur with an unrelenting drive to succeed. His dream is to revolutionize the cell phone industry with his new invention called 'Everywhere', a mobile phone that presumably works everywhere in the world. His ambitions take over his life, as his neglected girlfriend Gail would attest to. She wants to get married and raise a family, but commitment to a long-term relationship, and particularly commitment to children, is not something Jeff is looking for. Jeff's biggest goal right now is to find an investor to fund his cell phone project. And he did. However while celebrating his success, through an unfortunate boating accident, Jeff becomes marooned on an island with two young children. Ironically, Jeff's cell phone does not work on the island. With neither Jeff nor the children understanding each other, this adventure/comedy reveals the most unexpected changes life can throw at you as the three castaways search for food, confront their fears and uncover a side of life that was not known to previously exist. It is Jeff's story of survival, not only surviving the hardships of living off the land without the help of technology, but also learning to survive the two children. After three days on the island, and with no chance of rescue in site and a serious injury to one of the children, Jeff has to make a choice - continued self absorption to save himself, or self sacrifice to save the children.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?184632</url></doc>
