<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="184848">
  <docid>184848</docid>
  <title>Evo</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Hockenhull, Oliver</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>History</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>evolution</keyword>
    <keyword>canadian</keyword>
    <keyword>film-essay</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">11 October 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">75</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Hockenhull, Oliver</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Hockenhull, Oliver</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>E V O is a visually daring documentary look at evolutionary theory that comes off like a university course in paleobiology as taught by Marshall McLuhan." Monday Magazine Festival Screenings: - The International Documentary Film Festival of Amsterdam - 2002 - European Media Arts Festival, Germany -2003 - The Hot Docs ! International Documentary Festival - 2003 - The Vancouver International Film Festival - 2002 - The National Gallery of Art, Washington, D.C. - 2003 E V O is a feature digital essay on questions of Evolution and Consciousness and features eminent Evolutionist/Oxford Professor/Author Dr. Richard Dawkins. "A playful, fiercely intelligent exploration of the history and future of evolutionary theory and its impact on human society...Packed with striking concepts and intricately composed imagery, E V O, hums with energy and insight." Vancouver International Film Festival - Elan Mastai E V O - a philosophical, whimsical, radical investigation. Including imagery created with hacked C.G. software, inflections of artificial life algorithms and fractal generators. E V O - a study and reflection on the history and future of evolutionary theory, its meaning to humans, with a focus on the question of contingency as argued by Naturalist Stephen J. Gould in his best seller "Wonderful Life: The Burgess Shale and the Nature of History".</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?184848</url></doc>
