<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="185094">
  <docid>185094</docid>
  <title>Excitable Speech: All About Cinderella</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Woo, Ling-ling</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>story-telling</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Mandarin</language>
    <language>Cantonese</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Hong Kong</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Hong Kong">61</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Lai, Linda Chiu-han</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Woo, Ling-ling</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>The myth of Cinderella undergoes a series of generative twist to illumine the inventive power of speech. 11 children and 3 educated women engaged in a game of improvisation via their talking-head camera presence. Tale-telling to some children is the realization of creative instincts, to others the performance of self, or it's simply a tedious pedagogic vessel. My research-creation completes with adult women transforming the usage of Cinderella-objects into agents of their own stories, however fragmentary or elliptical. The event of tale-telling woke up the child in them; children language was appropriated to perform unarticulated subjectivities. Gender is a complex system, most revealing in language-in-action. The coda is a grand finale celebrating the magical power of objects and their own unlimited lives. Story-telling is the most primitive form of play. Harmless it may look, it is also the most sophisticated embodiment of ideological workings. The same story of Cinderella hides and enacts a child's family background, moral formation, the effects of socialization, her aspirations, projection of a good life and so on.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?185094</url></doc>
