<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="188005">
  <docid>188005</docid>
  <title>Fake</title>
  <year>2010</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>artist</keyword>
    <keyword>fake</keyword>
    <keyword>forgery</keyword>
    <keyword>art-collector</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Friedle, Greg</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bull, Lauren</producer>
    <producer>Friedle, Gary</producer>
    <producer>Bruni, Graziano</producer>
    <producer>Del Vecchio, Ken</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Friedle, Greg</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Baker, Blanche</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Needham</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ballard, Matt (I)</actor>
      <role>Burglar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Clohessy, Robert</actor>
      <role>Patrick White</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cohen, Allegra</actor>
      <role>News Anchor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Collins, Keith (I)</actor>
      <role>Darren</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Flint, Jill</actor>
      <role>Kelly Monaghan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Garo, Armen</actor>
      <role>Bartender</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mann, Gabriel (I)</actor>
      <role>Daniel Jakor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Noble, James (I)</actor>
      <role>Mssr. Rousseau</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Raio, Nick</actor>
      <role>Officer Broadus</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stevens, Fisher</actor>
      <role>Tom Kozinski</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Thornton, David (I)</actor>
      <role>Tay Murphy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Youse, David</actor>
      <role>Langford Downing</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Daniel Jakor is one of the most prolific and successful artists the world has never heard of. Struggling to sell his own art, he soon finds his true genius lies not in the creation of his own work but in the forgery of the great masters that have come before him- artists like Picasso, Monet, Degas and Renoir. And with the help of a Tay Murphy, corrupt gallery owner in Boston, Daniel soon learns the intricacies of the art world as he becomes a true master himself. But Tay's life is spiraling out of control and his personal demons have brought him to the edge where he hangs on by a thread. Indebted to the mob for more than he can possibly pay back, Tay gets Daniel roped into working for Seamus White, the head of the Irish "family" in New England and an avid art collector. As Seamus's schemes become bolder and bolder, not only pushing the boundaries of Daniel's ability but the limits of forgery itself, there is only one person who can track him down and bring him home...his ex-fiancée who, as an authenticator with the famed auction house, Sotheby's, discovers his fakes and the depths of trouble he's really in. Can she find him before the FBI does? Or will his double-crossing the mob bring his world crashing down around him? And, more importantly, in the end, if no one knows- if they'll never know- is it really Fake?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?188005</url></doc>
