<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="188116">
  <docid>188116</docid>
  <title>Falene</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Cristiani, Gabriella</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Italian</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">September 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">65</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Maldonado, Andres Arce</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Azim, Raffaella</producer>
    <producer>Costantino, Giovanni</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Longo, Andrej</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Onnis, Toto</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sassanelli, Paolo</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Two old friends, in their forties, meet at night in the street. They have a small talk about life, they actually talk about nothing and their chatting shows the emptiness of a desired, dreamed, imagined existence that has never been really lived. This night is not like the others. They have to meet somebody and after this meeting they could be able to change life, to make their dream come true: to leave the ordinary world around them, a world they have never had the strength to escape from and in which they have always been involved. Two indolent men who move in the limbo of life, trying to vaguely grasp the meaning of it and becoming in the end the metaphor of a blind and desperate mankind. But theirs is an absurd, childish and unrealistic robbery. Their dreamed escape from the world is deceptive: their meeting with life is actually a meeting with death and failure's lucid folly is waiting for them, the end of all their dreams and the tragic and late awareness of a useless and wasted life.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?188116</url></doc>
