<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="188813">
  <docid>188813</docid>
  <title>Family Inc.</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Ting, Emily</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Mandarin</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Hong Kong</country>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">3 March 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">75</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Jen, Helen (I)</director>
    <director>Jen, Helen (II)</director>
    <director>Ting, Emily</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Epstein, Udy</producer>
    <producer>Ting, Emily</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cohen, Joshua (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cohen, Paola</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kane, Randy (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lam, Linda (I)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lee, Jennifer (XXV)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ting, Charles</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ting, David</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>When filmmaker Emily Ting was asked by her father to return to Asia and take over the family business, she didn't exactly know how to say 'no.' Promising herself she would try it out for just one year, she traded in her friends, her filmmaking pursuits, and her love of New York for a grueling new life as CEO in training in one of Hong Kong's most notorious toy companies. Two years later, she's still there - with no end in sight. From picking up the slack left behind by a runaway brother to steering a sinking company on the brink of bankruptcy to competing against a 26 year old step mom for the future reign, Emily finds herself getting more and more stuck in a life she didn't choose for herself. But her biggest challenge yet is in trying to reconnect with an absentee father whose passion for his business has outshone his relationship with his family. In an attempt to come to terms with her new life, Emily turns the camera on herself and her family and the result is an incredibly honest and at times bittersweet family portrait that begs the question - what can one end up sacrificing in the name of supporting his family?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?188813</url></doc>
