<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="189131">
  <docid>189131</docid>
  <title>Fanfaren der Ehe</title>
  <year>1953</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Seng, Lilian</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>man-pretending-to-be-woman</keyword>
    <keyword>poverty</keyword>
    <keyword>cruise-ship</keyword>
    <keyword>musician</keyword>
    <keyword>stowaway</keyword>
    <keyword>man-disguised-as-woman</keyword>
    <keyword>baby</keyword>
    <keyword>nurse</keyword>
    <keyword>sequel</keyword>
    <keyword>social-services</keyword>
    <keyword>husband-wife-relationship</keyword>
    <keyword>steamer-trunk</keyword>
    <keyword>band</keyword>
    <keyword>white-lie</keyword>
    <keyword>man-in-drag</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>German</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>West Germany</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="West Germany">12</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="West Germany">3 September 1953</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="West Germany">88</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Grimm, Hans</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Braun, Harald</producer>
    <producer>Richter, Georg (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Lützkendorf, Felix</writer>
    <writer>Witt, Herbert</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Grothe, Franz</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Benkhoff, Fita</actor>
      <role>Daisy van Roy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Borsche, Dieter</actor>
      <role>Hans Mertens</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carstens, Lina</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Yell</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Egger, Inge</actor>
      <role>Gaby Mertens</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grimm, Oliver</actor>
      <role>Kind</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gubo, Olly</actor>
      <role>Gaby Mertens</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Haagen, Margarete</actor>
      <role>Schwester Rosmarie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Henckels, Paul</actor>
      <role>Kapitän</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hübner, Bruno</actor>
      <role>Arzt</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Karlstadt, Liesl</actor>
      <role>Rebecca</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kirchner, Doris</actor>
      <role>Pat</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Schönböck, Karl</actor>
      <role>Dobler</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Thomalla, Georg</actor>
      <role>Peter Schmidt</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vogel, Rudolf (I)</actor>
      <role>Wurm</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>von Meyerinck, Hubert</actor>
      <role>Hornisse</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Musicians Hans and Peter have married the two girls they met in the band in the earlier film, Fanfaren der Liebe (1951). They are still penniless, when their wives discover that unmarried female musicians are wanted on a luxury cruise ship, they tell a white lie and go. The two husbands have to stay behind and look after the small babies, and when a children's nurse comes round from the Social Services office to see that everything is all right, she is horrified at the way the men are looking after two babies. To avoid getting reported to the children's court, the men say that their wives will be back shortly. The nurse accepts this, and says she'll be back in half an hour. The two men find the women's clothes they wore in the earlier film (when they played in an all-women band) and when the nurse returns, they pretend to be their own wives; amazingly she accepts this, but marches them off to the children's clinic for some overdue post-natal tests. At the clinic it suddenly becomes clear that the tests inlcude the health of the "mothers", and on being shown where to undress, the two men panic and run for it, grabbing the nearest babies as they do so ... and taking someone else's baby in the process. The two men decide the only thing to do is to join their wives on the ship, but when they explain that to the boarding officer, he says that he knows all the musicians are single, and he won't let them on board. Overhearing that a VIP guest, Mrs Yell, and her lady companion are about to arrive, and spotting her steamer trunks nearby, the two borrow some of their clothes and bluff their way on board. Their wives have been enjoying the attention that "single" women get on a cruise ship, and there is some friction now, especially as the men have to stay undercover, as they are in effect stowaways. Eventually, at a later stop, the real Mrs Yell and her real companion catch up with the ship, and they come face to face with their doubles ...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?189131</url></doc>
