<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="190335">
  <docid>190335</docid>
  <title>Fast Lane Summer</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Herbert, Judith</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Sport</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>top-fuel</keyword>
    <keyword>car-racing</keyword>
    <keyword>sports-car</keyword>
    <keyword>drag-racing</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">5 May 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">77</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Bleich, Eli F.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bleich, Aaron</producer>
    <producer>Bleich, Eli F.</producer>
    <producer>Pearce, Kathleen</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Civelli, Mike</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumre Jr., Jerry</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Fast Lane Summer is high speed, high drama. It is the inside picture of what life is like for a Top Fuel Nostalgia racing team. Weeks of preparation for six seconds of speed... ending with the burst of a parachute to slow you back down... or a burst of flame from an exploded engine. Fast Lane Summer is an inside picture of what life is like for the owner... and for the people he depends on... his crew chief and his mechanics, his friends and family, his sponsors, and of course his driver. It chronicles the constant tuning, testing, and traveling... the good times and the bad times... and the desperate times as well. The times when things are running smoothly and everyone is riding high... and the times when nothing seems to work at all... and you don't know who to blame. Fast Lane Summer is an exciting subject for fans familiar with racing because it brings you right inside the team... and inside a racing series as well. Fast Lane Summer is equally exciting for the layman... because it is an amazing story, filled with interesting characters, interesting cars, and an interesting lifestyle.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?190335</url></doc>
