<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="190331">
  <docid>190331</docid>
  <title>Fast Lane</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Usher, Jane (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby SR</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Australia">28 July 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Australia">15</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Scicluna, Grant</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Scicluna, Grant</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Hughes, Mark (IX)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>McClements, Catherine</actor>
      <role>Louise</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Schumann, Ben</actor>
      <role>Ash</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Thomas, Rhys (V)</actor>
      <role>Jared</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>14-year-old Ash returns home late, clammy and pale. His mother knows something has happened, but Ash cannot bring himself to tell her. He receives an sms from his best friend Jared, asking "You reckon you killed him?" Ash and Jared are used to taking risks - racing full pelt on their bikes; sneaking into old, abandoned buildings; or going to parties where girls get so drunk their inhibitions slide. If he stops to think too much about consequences, Ash usually gets teased by Jared. Recklessly, Ash takes up Jared's dare to throw bricks off the freeway overpass, and it smashes into a car below. The consequences hit Ash head-on, and he runs, not staying to check if their reckless action proved fatal... Sensing something is very wrong, his mum demands to know what he has done. After he tells her, she is disgusted that Ash never thinks responsibly when he is with Jared. Naturally, Jared is unfazed by the incident, and just looks forward to their next game. Having seen the fractures in his friendship with Jared, however, Ash knows he must farewell his reckless youth.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?190331</url></doc>
