<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="190549">
  <docid>190549</docid>
  <title>Fatal Consequences</title>
  <year>2010</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bouknight, Jonathan</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Mystery</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">R</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">15 January 2010</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Wilson, Lito</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Wilson, Lito</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Wilson, Lito</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Battle, Gregory</actor>
      <role>Maxillian Russell</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bell, Lela</actor>
      <role>Kimberly Williams</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Douglas, Keith (II)</actor>
      <role>Ryan Anderson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wright, Orlando</actor>
      <role>Victor Dupree</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Young, William Allen</actor>
      <role>Thomas Shaw</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A riveting thriller in the tradition of Agatha Christie, Fatal Consequences, spins a web of deception, lies and murder. In the conservatory of "Blood Mansion", the island dwelling of Maximillian Russell, an aging horror star, a group of actors have gathered together for a read through of a new script written by an up and coming playwright. When the last of his guest arrives, the host instructs the gatekeeper to unleash the guard dogs and with a moat full of piranha Maximillian is confident he has his guests trapped like rats. It seems that someone has been sending him newspaper clippings about the suicide thirty years ago of Marilyn Graham, an actress he had an affair with, and he intends to find out who is responsible. Before he can put his plan into action, Tiffany Scott, one of his quests is found with her throat cut. Shortly after Maximillian himself dies, poisoned by one of his own chocolates. Marooned in the house with thick fog swirling outside, the other guests which includes: Thomas Shaw - Maximillian's agent, Eleanor Reed - Maximillian's personal assistant, Dominique Chambers - a seasoned actress, Victor Dupree -star of stage, screen and an occasional casting couch, Ryan Anderson - playwright, Judy Davis - designer, Vera Hill - housekeeper &amp; Kimberly Williams - an ingénue, realize that the murderer must have some connection with the deceased Marilyn Graham. As the action progresses the finger of suspicion points at each of them until the truth is revealed.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?190549</url></doc>
