<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="191384">
  <docid>191384</docid>
  <title>Fear of Attraction</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Ruwanpathirana, Rasika</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">27 April 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">72</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Ruwanpathirana, Rasika</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Gonzalez, Nancy (II)</producer>
    <producer>Prabhakaran, Sibu</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Manzo, Manuel</writer>
    <writer>Ruwanpathirana, Rasika</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Johnson, Tyrone (II)</actor>
      <role>Dave</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kamhi, Ana Inez</actor>
      <role>Carmen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Montenegro, Liliana</actor>
      <role>Marina</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sato, Garret</actor>
      <role>Monk</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Torres, Jeff</actor>
      <role>Marcos</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Z., Mario</actor>
      <role>Priest</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Marcos, who grew up in the streets of Los Angeles, has never had values in life. Kiki is a free spirited girl, who is lost in the present and refuses to believe in reality, and lives in the deep dreams of her own. Dave, Kiki's neighbor, thinks and acts as her guardian angel. Dave's world is Kiki's life. Until the day came when she needed him the most and he wasn't able to protect her. All he was able to do was watch her die. Carmen is a caring girl who has waited for her brother Marcos to come home, he was lost to the streets years ago. When Marcos finds a missing person bulletin of himself, he uses Carmen to hide; after all he has nothing to lose and no guilty conscious. Until one night, it is interrupted by Kiki's playback memories. Dave accused for the murder of Kiki, is interrogated by Detective Molina. When the truth comes out, Detective Molina finds out that the man she has been sleeping with (Marcos) has been living with another woman (Kiki), and Dave is the only witness to her murder. Molina is on the run and on a mission. To hunt who might be the father of her unborn child and the only clue guiding her is Dave's bazaar scrap book.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?191384</url></doc>
