<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="195018">
  <docid>195018</docid>
  <title>Finding Electra</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Krug, Jordan</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">75</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Pickle, Chris</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Barbeck, Jason</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Pickle, Chris</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Blasternaut</composer>
    <composer>Raffoul, Jody</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barbeck, Jason</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pickle, Chris</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sly, Sam</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Cooper has trouble making good choices. Unemployed, uneducated and with a taste for cheap beer, it's no surprise that he lives in a soon to be condemned industrial building. Enter Rita; a vixen, a stripper (stage name Electra) and worst of all a liar. Rita is the last women any sane man would want to fall in love with. Of course Cooper can't help himself. Two weeks after their first encounter, Cooper and Rita are sharing his rundown seedy apartment. After Cooper discovers that Rita has been cheating on him (repeatedly), he forces his brother Jake, (a perpetual trouble maker), to help him catch her in the act. Using a video camera to document the action, the brothers come up against a hurdle neither was expecting: Rita's temper Because he "invaded her privacy", Rita ends her relationship with Cooper. Cooper is crushed, and Jake is amused. Despite the reality of Rita being a gallivanting floozy, Cooper can't get over the fact that he is hopelessly in love with her. He believes that without her he's a loser, and now having pushed her away with his perverse curiosity, he'll have to pull out all the stops to win her back. Using the camera to document the aftermath, Jake continues to participate in, and berate Cooper for, his constant struggle to reunite with Rita. Repeatedly attempting to help Cooper, Jake inadvertently gets him into much deeper trouble, compounding his brother's frustration. Soon the camera itself becomes a problem, as Cooper is forced to deal with the consequences of his brother's actions, and with the nature of their own relationship. "Finding Electra" is a documentary-style film that follows Cooper on his seemingly helpless journey to win back the love of his life, (or maybe discover that those he loves most support him the least). Between loansharks, prostitutes, and duct tape, Cooper realizes that the choices you make can have very unpredictable outcomes.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?195018</url></doc>
