<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="195276">
  <docid>195276</docid>
  <title>Finkle's Odyssey</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Scott, Johanna</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby SR</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Portugal">26 February 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">9 June 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">17</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Clay, Barney</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Neate-James, Claire</producer>
    <producer>Wakeman, Richard</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Clay, Barney</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Greswell, John</composer>
    <composer>Taylor, Chris (XXX)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Marks, Gareth</actor>
      <role>Swallows</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wilkinson, Matt (I)</actor>
      <role>Finkle</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This is the story of Finkle, an unfortunate young writer whose inspiration has dried up. His concentration is constantly diverted to a small hole that has recently appeared in his ceiling that secretes an unsettling slime. Finkle is called upon by a mysterious salesman named Swallows who produces a suitcase containing test tubes that he claims are each filled with ideas. Finkle uncorks one of the tubes and releases the 'idea'. Within seconds of the 'trial treatment' Finkle agrees to purchase the entire case! On closer inspection it seems the 'Idea' is actually a living microscopic mite. Once again he sits down to write. This time he releases the cork and sits back awaiting 'inspiration'. While waiting he falls asleep and the mite escapes. In attempting to re-capture the elusive idea, the rest of the test tubes break and all the ideas escape into the mysterious orifice. Not one idea is saved. Finkle investigates and gets sucked up into the organic innards of this unknown entity. He pushes himself through the passageway that resembles a vast, overgrown intestine. His progress however, is soon thwarted by a dormant body blocking his path that appears to be another version of himself. Finkle begins the excruciating task of pushing himself along with everything else through the hole which we soon discover leads back into his bedsit. It seems however, that as soon as the clutter reaches the opening, it is secreted out into his room as an unknown pulpy, slop. Eventually Finkle reaches the opening and finds himself back in his bedsit. As he plummets back down into his room, he in turn falls into the now enormous mountain of pulp that has gathered onto his desk. He delves into the pulp and discovers that actually it is none other than a mountain of freshly digested words. On his sleeve he discovers the word 'story'. Finkle sets out to cover his entire room with the words before finally sitting back down to write</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?195276</url></doc>
