<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="195649">
  <docid>195649</docid>
  <title>Firefighter F.D.18</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>VideoGame</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Mystery</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>burned-to-death</keyword>
    <keyword>haunted-past</keyword>
    <keyword>survivor-rescuing</keyword>
    <keyword>blood</keyword>
    <keyword>number-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>arson</keyword>
    <keyword>kidnapping</keyword>
    <keyword>arsonist</keyword>
    <keyword>backdraft</keyword>
    <keyword>firefighting</keyword>
    <keyword>political-corruption</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Japan</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Japan">15</certificate>
    <certificate country="Australia">G</certificate>
    <certificate country="USA">T</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Japan">26 February 2004</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="UK">23 April 2004</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Germany">23 April 2004</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="France">23 April 2004</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Italy">23 April 2004</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">9 March 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Minami, Tatsuma</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ishizuka, Michihiro</producer>
    <producer>Minami, Tatsuma</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Tachikawa, Megumi</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Falt, Dennis</actor>
      <role>Paul Murphy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Glover, Charles (I)</actor>
      <role>Richard Grace</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kelso, Eric</actor>
      <role>Dean McGregor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Naishtut, Michael</actor>
      <role>Craig Andrews</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Storms, Christian (I)</actor>
      <role>Jason Hunt</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wells, Chris (I)</actor>
      <role>Harris Blackwell</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>When the fire broke out in the Tunnel of interstate 42, the firefighters along with Dean McGregor came to bring the situation under control by putting out the fires and rescuing all trapped survivors. When they found one of the survivors Senator Harris Blackwell, they rescued him. Just when Dean and the firefighters' situation in the Tunnel was taken care of, another fire broke out in the Laboratory building. Dean, who is extremely disturbed and haunted by his tragic past must come along with the other firefighters to rescue the survivors and put out the fire in the Laboratory building. Just upon reaching the area where another survivor Paul Murphy was, the bridge he was standing on both had the path destroyed, leaving him stranded and at the same time, Dean was able to put out the fire in the bridge area. However, Dean tries to rescue Paul Murphy, but Paul Murphy was badly burnt and the bridge collapse taking Paul Murphy's corpse with him into the pit. Disturbed and full of guilt, Dean McGregor was prompted by Craig Andrews to leave the Lab. Later, in the Cruiser, the firefighters gather in a formal party room to be congratulated on putting the fire out of the Tunnel and the Lab. Later, Dean McGregor stands outside of the deck with so many things on his mind. Emilie Arvin, the news reporter who Dean rejected the live interview during the fire in the tunnel, wanted to find out why Dean is so upset and disturbed. While Dean explains many tragic pasts including the time he lost his sister during the fire several years ago, Dean was forced to fight the fire again as it broke out this time on the Cruiser. Dean suspects that there was an arsonist who was linked to Paul Murphy was behind the worst arson committing. Will Dean be able to stop the arsonist from committing such atrocious crime?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?195649</url></doc>
