<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="195601">
  <docid>195601</docid>
  <title>FireHouse TV</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bloom, Michael A.</editor>
    <editor>Facente, Blake</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">23 September 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">23</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="USA">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Bloom, Michael A.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bloom, Michael A.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bloom, Michael A.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>JennaMusic</composer>
    <composer>Leigh, Jenna (II)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sutter, Ryan</actor>
      <role>Host</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Firehouse TV is the first reality show of its kind; a compelling behind the scenes look at the lives of firefighters. Most of us see firefighters on the 11 o'clock news, usually faceless behind heavy protective gear and helmets. They are the quiet heroes, and their lives are often fascinating and inspirational. Ryan Sutter, probably the country's most recognizable firefighter due to his winning the hit reality TV show "The Bachlorette", and also for his spokesperson work with the Firefighter's National Trust hosts each episode. Ryan is one of those amazing people who is movie-star good looking, is smart (he's an architecture major), is an accomplished painter and writer, and even did a stint in the NFL. But ask Ryan who he is, he'll quickly say, "I am a fireman". The bond of firefighters is not easily broken. You never stop being a firefighter. Firehouse TV is more than just an Emergency-Call program. Unlike "Cops", where cameras only document the gritty detail of anonymous cops making arrests, this is a show that allows a peek behind the respirators and fire protective clothing, so that we can celebrate the lives of these real American heroes. This is what they do before, after, and during the emergencies to which they respond. They are some of the most honest, decent, and heroic people to be found anywhere. A typical firefighter doesn't hesitate to rescue people from a burning building. It's not just their job; it's their calling. Firehouse TV travels the country and spends a complete 24-hour shift in different firehouses as emergencies occur. Instead of titillation and seeing people plied with liquor and encouraged to take their clothes off, we see sober men and women suiting up to face danger and risk their lives. Firehouse TV showcases people who are pillars of their community. Each week we learn what makes them tick.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?195601</url></doc>
