<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="195922">
  <docid>195922</docid>
  <title>First Generation</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Thibault, Genevieve</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">July 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">85</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Maisuria, Ishwar L.</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Maisuria, Ishwar L.</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gill, Akesh</actor>
      <role>Asha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Haroon (I)</actor>
      <role>Ajay</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"First Generation" is about an immigrant South Asian family in transition. The story unfolds through the actions of individual members of the Ratanji family. Asha and Ajay are in their early twenties and the cultural differences between them and their parents are reaching a peak. The secret love affair between Asha and Kevin becomes increasingly tense when pressure is exerted on Asha by her mother who wants to marry her off in the traditional manner. The father, on the other hand is more concerned about Asha's education. He has lost all hope in his son Ajay, who has a history of getting in trouble within the family and with the outside world. The father has invested all his trust in Asha until she reveals her secret affair, which leaves him feeling extremely betrayed. He is unable to control his rage. His violence and the constant persuasion by Kevin leaves Asha with no choice but to go her own separate way. Ajay is lost and confused in his enclosed world showing all signs of isolation. A final tragic situation has a humbling effect on the family, which ironically brings them all together...briefly</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?195922</url></doc>
