<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="196294">
  <docid>196294</docid>
  <title>Fishbowl</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Hendrickson, Brian (III)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">September 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">7</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Neely, Kimber</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Allison, Hayley (I)</producer>
    <producer>Allison, Hayley (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Neely, Kimber</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anderson, Christopher (X)</actor>
      <role>John Willows</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Heikkila, James</actor>
      <role>Colin</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Colin is a recent college graduate who is trying to figure out what to do with the rest of his life. He is under pressure to make the choices that will determine whether he takes the most logical path of health benefits, good credit, and marriage or takes a chance and looks beyond. He grew up thinking that he had the world in the palm of his hand and he expects life to answer to his sense of immediacy. When it doesn't he is left passively swimming by. He feels like he has no options and is trapped swimming circles in his fish bowl, with no purpose or direction. The story follows his struggle with staying in this small, yet safe bowl or to escape! A wonderful twist of fate opens his mind to the possibility of an ocean beyond his bowl. He meets Selene, the quirky office rebel, who makes up crazy stories about her coworkers and sneaks away in the middle of the day. Selene takes Colin to her 'secret place,' an isolated beach where a road has eroded away into the waves. Colin realizes that he has to leave the office and everything else in his life to escape his fishbowl and he offers to take Selene with him. Surprisingly Selene can't bring herself to go. She is trapped in a fishbowl she can't even see.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?196294</url></doc>
