<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="196762">
  <docid>196762</docid>
  <title>Fixation</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Mystery</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>underground-film</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>women</keyword>
    <keyword>student-film</keyword>
    <keyword>alternative</keyword>
    <keyword>neo-noir</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">13</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <composers>
    <composer>Hanes, Simon (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cortopassi, Colin</actor>
      <role>Marshal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Elizabeth, Astrid</actor>
      <role>Isabelle</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Matteson, Alex</actor>
      <role>Drew</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mattison, Alex</actor>
      <role>Ian</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Isabelle is a teenager, an artist and student who takes advantage of the public transit system. One night, after seating herself in her favorite spot, she finds an envelope addressed to her. Upon inspection, she finds it is filled with photographic negatives. She phones her boyfriend and changes the evening plans from date to detective work. They meet at the darkroom and develop the photos, eventually coming to realize that they were the unwitting subjects of the photographer. The boyfriend, aware of Isabelle's curious nature, pleads against her investigation wile he is on vacation, citing the obvious danger. Over gelato, she agrees to postpone her inquisition, and they part. On the ride home however, she finds something she missed, a strip of paper with the time 5:30 pm scribbled on it. This compels her to disregard her promise and follow the clues inside the envelope. The next day, she follows the photographs to a rusty shed in the middle of a bushy public park. She opens the door to find a man, who notices her and bolts up. Isabelle runs, but is struck with a hammer by her pursuer. She wakes much later inside the shed, to find the man tending to her. Dazed and confused by the blow on the head, she begins to ask questions. The young man, obliged to answer, introduces himself as her bus-mate, vying for recognition. As the amnesia wears off, she must find a way out, past an unstable person with an unhealthy fixation.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?196762</url></doc>
