<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="197085">
  <docid>197085</docid>
  <title>Flash Bomba</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Filipino</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Philippines</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Philippines">7 February 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Santos, Dondon</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Guinoo, Roxanne</actor>
      <role>Marissa</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Inventor, Nanette</actor>
      <role>Nanny Claude</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Locsin, Rio</actor>
      <role>Rhodora</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lucero, Sid (II)</actor>
      <role>Gorio</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Magdayao, Shaina</actor>
      <role>Flash Bomba/Roldan Legazpi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Magundayao, Elijah</actor>
      <role>young Gorio</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Marquez, Julius 'Empoy'</actor>
      <role>Tikboy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Montes, Jacob</actor>
      <role>young Roldan Legazpi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Paule, Allan</actor>
      <role>Lucas</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pimentel, Lito</actor>
      <role>Enrico Legazpi</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Roldan Legazpi lived a comfortable life with his wealthy parents until a tragic encounter with a tikbalang left him unable to walk but he uses his hands to walk. Roldan Legazpi is being paralyzed due to his encounter of a wicked "tikbalang" (half-human, half-horse creature), he managed to remain sturdy by strengthening his upper body to an incredible level of athletic ability and did ever through martial arts with thorough physical training when he learns to walk with his hands. Flash Bomba challenged the Tikbalang to a battle with his physical limitations thru Martial Arts. Tikbalang granted Roldan Legazpi his superpower of the Tikbalang's magic hair to allow Rolden transforms into his super-powered version - a being with large hands &amp; feet, as well as superhuman power by using his new abilities, he became a superhero called Flash Bomba. Flash Bomba has superhuman strength, the ability to walk up on the walls, to generate "thunderclaps" using his large hands or block almost anything with same. In spite of his enlarged extremities. Roldan returns to the woods to find the mystical powers that the tikbalangs possess success his mission. Roldan assumes a new superhero alter-ego known as Flash Bomba to use his gifts to protect the helpless and fight crimes while enjoying fame on the side.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?197085</url></doc>
