<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="197664">
  <docid>197664</docid>
  <title>Flight from Death: The Quest for Immortality</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Shen, Patrick (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Australia">M</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Shen, Patrick (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Heeney, Andrew</producer>
    <producer>Bennick, Greg</producer>
    <producer>Shen, Patrick (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bennick, Greg</writer>
    <writer>Shen, Patrick (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Byrd, Sean (I)</composer>
    <composer>Sauppe, Eric</composer>
    <composer>Shepard, Elijah James</composer>
    <composer>Watts, Adam (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Byrne, Gabriel</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sprecace, Perrin</actor>
      <role>Original Narration</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Narrated by Gabriel Byrne (Usual Suspects, Vanity Fair, Miller's Crossing), this seven-time Best Documentary award-winning film (Silver Lake Film Festival, Beverly Hills Film Festival) is the most comprehensive and mind-blowing investigation of humankind's relationship with death ever captured on film. Hailed by many viewers as a "life-transformational film," Flight from Death uncovers death anxiety as a possible root cause of many of our behaviors on a psychological, spiritual, and cultural level. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; Following the work of the late cultural anthropologist, Ernest Becker, and his Pulitzer Prize-winning book Denial of Death, this documentary explores the ongoing research of a group of social psychologists that may forever change the way we look at ourselves and the world. Over the last twenty-five years, this team of researchers has conducted over 300 laboratory studies, which substantiate Becker's claim that death anxiety is a primary motivator of human behavior, specifically aggression and violence. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; Flight from Death features an all-star cast of scholars, authors, philosophers, and researchers including Sam Keen, Robert Jay Lifton, Irvin Yalom, and Sheldon Solomon culminating in a film that is "not only thought-provoking but also entertaining and put together with a lot of class" (Eric Campos, Film Threat). Three years in the making and beautifully photographed in eight different countries, Flight from Death is "a stimulating, ultimately life-affirming film, filled with big ideas and revelatory footage" (Jeff Shannon, Seattle Times).</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?197664</url></doc>
