<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="198464">
  <docid>198464</docid>
  <title>Fly</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Ashby, Jason Andrew</editor>
    <editor>Purcell, Brian (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>belief</keyword>
    <keyword>magic</keyword>
    <keyword>time-travel</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby SR</soundmix>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 January 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">25</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Ashby, Jason Andrew</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Benhard, R.G.</producer>
    <producer>Hardin, Terry</producer>
    <producer>Harding, Christina</producer>
    <producer>Benhard, R.G.</producer>
    <producer>Hardin, Terry</producer>
    <producer>Harding, Christina</producer>
    <producer>Purcell, Brian (II)</producer>
    <producer>Benhard, R.G.</producer>
    <producer>Ashby, Jason Andrew</producer>
    <producer>Purcell, Brian (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Ashby, Jason Andrew</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Colburn, Samantha</actor>
      <role>Rylee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hickey, John James</actor>
      <role>Murray</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jameson, Rane</actor>
      <role>Lucas</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Schmid, Tom</actor>
      <role>Dr. Nordac</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Not bound by conventional mentality, Lucas and Grace have discovered their own colorful world of magnificent possibilities. This is in stark contrast to their closed-minded psychiatrist, Dr. Nordac. Though in her past, Grace has suffered an abusive relationship with her father, she remains child like, clinging to hope and acceptance of what may still be good in her world. Lucas is a Zen-like individual, who speaks softly, and often, in parables. Little is known of his days before he was a wandering street magician, only that he held tightly to the belief that his magic was real. Dr. Nordac presents himself with great stoicism, yet under the surface he is concealing a troublesome secret of his own. He becomes increasingly concerned with the influence that Lucas's "magic" has on Grace and the other patients. Cautioning the young magician only deepens their divergence, as even the doctor's hold on reality begins to slip, and he soon discovers, that truth lies not in what we see, but in that which we believe. The film opens with a quote from Emily Dickinson, which conjures an interesting perspective of the world's take on madness. The ending is a magical finale that employs fantasy to examine one man's dark reality.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?198464</url></doc>
