<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="199571">
  <docid>199571</docid>
  <title>For All the Tea in England</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Stratogiannakis, Napoleon</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>tea</keyword>
    <keyword>passion</keyword>
    <keyword>england</keyword>
    <keyword>obsession</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">1 July 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">14</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Mcleod, Kerry (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Califano, Anton</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Jeffery, Graham</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>The average person in Britain drinks 1,000 cups of tea per year, and it's the second most popular beverage in the world (after water). In so many ways, the image of tea as something quintessentially British is synonymous with a sepia-toned image of our nation - whether tea cosies in a working class home or a group of ladies sipping tea from fine china. Yet with nearly every nation on the planet now represented in this country, how true does that image remain? 'For All the Tea in England' is a tea break-sized glimpse into the many and varied ways that Britain's favourite brew is enjoyed today - and it's not always a simple case of tea bag and milk. There's Xun, a self-confessed tea addict with a cupboard full of Chinese tea; Grazyna, a tea hoarder and a convert to the traditional English cuppa; Alex, a convert to tea itself who takes it so seriously he's now dedicated his life to the enjoyment of it; Zita, Nina and Mary who argue that there are as many tea traditions in India as there are houses; and Steven and his wife Anna from Tanzania, who reveal some startling similarities with the ladies from India.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?199571</url></doc>
