<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="201146">
  <docid>201146</docid>
  <title>Fortune's Sweet Kiss</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">November 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Nearing, Daniel</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Lausane, Lutia</producer>
    <producer>Nearing, Daniel</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Nearing, Daniel</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>D'Orsay, Brooke</actor>
      <role>Cassandra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hiro, Lorne</actor>
      <role>Cy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pulchinski, Travis</actor>
      <role>Young Vince</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sklar, Stuart</actor>
      <role>Lieut. Mark Southern</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Walden, Monty</actor>
      <role>Vince</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Vincent Wolfe is a homicide detective with the Toronto police. Lately he's been unable to close his cases. He keeps seeing homicides where his partner sees suicides. To Vince, the crime scenes seem staged to make it look like a victim has taken his own life. But Vince is a troubled man. The recent death of his father is forcing him to confront memories of his abusive childhood and the long-suppressed memory of the accidental death of his older brother. It's clear to Vince's partner and his lieutenant that Vince is becoming unstable, and when he starts to believe that obvious homicide scenes are linked to the perpetrator who staged the suicides, the department assigns him involuntarily to Dr. Denude, the in-house psychiatrist. Cassandra Wells is a woman in her twenties who is similarly haunted by memories of her father's abuse and his ultimate suicide. Sandy can't escape the thought that she is to blame and struggles as a consequence in her attempts at intimate relationships. When a man she has invited to her apartment becomes the next victim in the strange pattern of homicides, she is traumatized again. And worse, she is the only living witness. In gaining Sandy's trust, Vince reveals his background to her, and the two of them discover that not only do they share a traumatic history of paternal abuse, they share it with a third party -- the "suicide killer." And all of their lives are at stake when the killer decides that Sandy has betrayed him. FORTUNE'S SWEET KISS is a relentlessly paced psychological thriller -- at turns comic, sensitive, sensual, and tragic -- that explores and ultimately conquers the dark memories that rule the lives of childhood victims of physical abuse.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?201146</url></doc>
