<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="201693">
  <docid>201693</docid>
  <title>Fourth Time Around</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Sycamore, Maximilian</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>music</keyword>
    <keyword>family-tragedy</keyword>
    <keyword>obsession</keyword>
    <keyword>friendship</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">15</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Sternberg, Eddie</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Connell, Marcia</producer>
    <producer>Codjoe, Florence</producer>
    <producer>Sternberg, Eddie</producer>
    <producer>Sycamore, Maximilian</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Sternberg, Eddie</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Berger, Alex (IX)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Berger, Howard</actor>
      <role>Rob's Father/Rob's Boss</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Falck, Tom</actor>
      <role>Rob</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fisher, Harriet</actor>
      <role>Amber</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grant, Micaela</actor>
      <role>Girl in Cafe 3</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Popper, Joseph</actor>
      <role>Man in Cafe</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>After guilt brought his life crashing down around him Rob was able to build one of strict routine to protect him from the world. But as past events catch up with him Rob finds solace in surprising ways. Rob's world is ruled by a routine that itself has been shaped by a personal tragedy. But when Rob's compulsive nature strips him of his girlfriend and job, his only links to reality he is brought to the brink of madness. Drinking to numb the pain of his life, Rob fails to notice that hope may be closer than he realizes. Amber has lived with Rob for almost four years but they've barely spoken, and never socialized. So when he hits rock bottom she has no idea what to do. If she's going to help him then she must find out what's wrong but this means opening doors to parts of his life that Rob wants to keep hidden. When Amber discovers Rob's passion for music she believes she has simply found a way to keep him calm. But after an outburst Amber realizes she may have just hit upon a clue to the tragic events that rule Rob's life, revealing to her the reason why the name Amanda is written on his wall.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?201693</url></doc>
