<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="204425">
  <docid>204425</docid>
  <title>Friend or Foe</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Ray, Brian (I)</editor>
    <editor>Reilly, Ryan (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Game-Show</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">17 October 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>DiPirro, Richard Brian</director>
    <director>Kreisberg, Brad (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Abraham, Ken (I)</writer>
    <writer>Spotto, Brad</writer>
    <writer>Stone, Bob (II)</writer>
    <writer>Zohn, Sheryl</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Hall, Larry (V)</composer>
    <composer>Mabe, Tom</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bolick, Lisa Marie</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fagg, Robert</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fisher, Kimberly</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kessler, Cliff</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Montgomery, Lisa Kennedy</actor>
      <role>Herself - Host</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Parisi, Michael E.</actor>
      <role>Himself - Contestant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pounder, Dave</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pounder, Dave</actor>
      <role>Himself - Contestant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Swerdzewski, Zach</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Walberg, Mark L.</actor>
      <role>Host</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"Friend or Foe" was a game show combining knowledge and trust -- the catch being contestants (previously unknown to each other and paired at the beginning of the show) had to decide whether their partner would fairly divide the pot. Six contestants (three choosers and three "potential partners") are paired off and head to their own isolation booth. After spotting the teams $200, host Kennedy reads a series of multiple-choice questions, each worth $500. Both team members had to agree on an answer; after reviewing the guesses, Kennedy revealed the correct answer and announced the winnings. After four questions, the team with the least amount of money (or, in case of a tie, who took the longest time answering) are eliminated from the game ... but not until they head to the Trust Box to divide their winnings. That's where the fun (and oftentimes, shenanigans) begins. Each team member made a brief statement to their partner on why he/she should vote "Friend" and split the money. The contestants then made their decision, via hidden buttons on their side of the Trust Box. If both voted "Friend," they evenly split the money; if they each voted "Foe," they forfeited the whole thing. But if one voted "Friend" and the other went "Foe," the "Foe" kept everything and their "friend" disappointed, to put it mildly. A second round of four questions was played with the remaining teams, with questions worth $1,000 and the lowest-scoring team to that point eliminated after a visit to the Trust Box. The last remaining team advanced to the speed round, where they teamed to answer up to 10 questions (at $500 apiece) within 60 seconds. Three wrong answers stopped the game, but if they answered all 10 questions correctly, their pot is doubled. Then it's one last visit to the Trust Box, where they decide if they want to keep it all, hog it for themselves or blow the whole thing.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?204425</url></doc>
