<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="207329">
  <docid>207329</docid>
  <title>Fusion: Kanye West, Gnarls Barkley, Lupe Fiasco</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="China">23 February 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="China">120</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Clark, Adam Christian</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>McKeon, Daniel</producer>
    <producer>McKeon, David</producer>
    <producer>Wang, Carrie</producer>
    <producer>Jackson, Kyle Dean</producer>
    <producer>Pao, Alan</producer>
    <producer>Swegal, Christian</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barkley, Gnarls</actor>
      <role>Themselves</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cee-Lo</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chan, Jackie (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gillis, Gregg</actor>
      <role>Girl Talk</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mouse, Danger</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>West, Kanye</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Hunan TV, made history by airing a concert with some of the most popular Taiwanese, Hong Kong, Chinese and US musical artists together on one stage. On February 13th and 14th artists including Jackie Chan, Kanye West, Gnarls Barkley, A-Mei, Lupe Fiasco, Tan WeiWei and Ly Yu Chun from the Chinese show Supergirls came together and captivated thousands of adoring fans during their live performances at the Aladdin Theatre in Las Vegas for Fusion 2007. On Sunday night February 25th in China, Fusion 2007 became a landmark achievement in media sharing by bringing a musical lineup that truly bridges social gaps to over 200 million households throughout mainland China. This was the first of six broadcasts. It is the first time for Hunan Satellite TV to promote an overseas Chinese New Year concert in North America. It was also the first time for the stars Tan WeiWei and Ly Yu Chun from the hit Chinese show, Supergirls, to visit USA and perform at Fusion 2007. "This historic show aired successfully on Hunan TV on February 25th in China to millions of viewers," said the Vice President of Hunan TV, Mr. Liu Hui Dong.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?207329</url></doc>
