<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="207985">
  <docid>207985</docid>
  <title>G Spots?</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bitton, Yael</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>DTS</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 April 2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">13</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Fine, Daniel Scott</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Molinari-Rosaly, Jose Gilberto</producer>
    <producer>Fine, Daniel Scott</producer>
    <producer>Stockton, Carla</producer>
    <producer>Applebaum, Eve</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Fine, Daniel Scott</writer>
    <writer>Stockton, Carla</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>B' Racz, Istvan</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chaban, Michael</actor>
      <role>The Knight</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>David, Keith (I)</actor>
      <role>The King</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Duncan, Sandy</actor>
      <role>The Queen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Izzo, Markanthony</actor>
      <role>The Caveman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lute, Denise</actor>
      <role>The Hag</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Marks, Annika</actor>
      <role>The Maiden</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This deconstruction of Chaucer's fairy tale follows the whimsical, sad dilemma of an errant Knight who errs just one too many times and is caught with his pants down by the omniscient eye of the all-powerful court that rules the universe. Having deflowered a virgin and thus having committed the gravest of the gravest of crimes known to his society, the Knight is sentenced to beheading. Enamored of the Knight's pretty face, the Queen takes pity of the helpless, hapless man and offers to commute his sentence on one condition: that he find a satisfactory answer to the question, "What does a woman really want?" The Knight, who has no clue - how could he? - sets off on a quest to find the solution to the riddle. He speaks with a diverse population in the present, past and future, and he finds himself confounded by the array of answers he elicits from his respondents. Always at his heels is an intolerably ugly old Hag, forever tormenting him with a persevering phrase uttered in an unintelligible language. The Hag possesses the answer to the question; but is unlikely to listen because, as everyone knows, beauty is truth. Isn't it?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?207985</url></doc>
