<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="209999">
  <docid>209999</docid>
  <title>Gaon Hamara Shaher Tumhara</title>
  <year>1972</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Kumar, Naresh (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kumar, Naresh (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kudalkar, Laxmikant Shantaram</composer>
    <composer>Sharma, Pyarelal Ramprasad</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Aarti</actor>
      <role>Bindu C. Pandey</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhagwan, Master</actor>
      <role>Film Director</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kamaldeep</actor>
      <role>Ram C. Pandey</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kanhaiyalal (I)</actor>
      <role>Advocate Chandershekhar Pandey</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khanna, Padma</actor>
      <role>Cabaret Dancer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Rajendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Brij "Birju" Bhushan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Sujit (I)</actor>
      <role>Shyam C. Pandey</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Satyadeep</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shamsher (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sunder (I)</actor>
      <role>Sunder (Paanwala)</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Chandershekhar Pandey and his wife, Lajwanti, come to visit Brij Bhushan and his widowed mother in their village. They assure Brij's mom that in exchange of their land, they will get Brij a small shop in Bombay, and in this way they get the land transferred in their name. Ten years later, Brij's mom passes away and re-locates to Bhuleshwar, Bombay, where Chandershekhar lives with his wife, two unmarried sons, Ram and Shyam, and an unmarried daughter, Bindu. Brij is treated as a mere servant, not paid, but abused and beaten everyday, needless to say Chandershekhar is not going to fulfill his promise of getting him a shop. His only companion on which he shoulder he can cry is the Pandey's maidservant, Parvati alias Paro. Then things turn better for Brij when he finds himself the lucky owner of a Rs.2,50,000 lottery ticket. This suddenly changes everyone's attitude toward him, he is pampered, fed, driven around town, and even given new clothes. But when the Pandeys find out that the ticket he is holding is not the winning number, Brij is once again beaten, and asked to leave. The question remains, with nowhere to return to, where will poor Brij go?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?209999</url></doc>
