<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="210081">
  <docid>210081</docid>
  <title>Garam Coat</title>
  <year>1955</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Mukherjee, Hrishikesh</editor>
  </editors>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">129</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Kumar, Amar (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bedi, Rajinder Singh</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bedi, Rajinder Singh</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhardwaj, Brahm</actor>
      <role>Jewelery shop owner</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chand (IV)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jayant (I)</actor>
      <role>Sher Khan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Rashid (I)</actor>
      <role>Munnilal 'Munni'</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sahni, Balraj</actor>
      <role>Girdharilal 'Girdhari'</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sharma, Baij</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Girdharilal lives a poor lifestyle in Delhi along with his wife, Geeta, and two daughters and a son. He works as a Money Order Clerk in the Post Office, earns Rs.110/- per Mensem, and wears a torn coat that his wife is tired of stitching. One day at work, he makes an error in a money order but does manage to fix it, collects his pay and returns home, refusing to drink alcohol with his co-workers, Sher Khan and Munnilal. He then sets out to buy some snacks and toys for his children and loses a 100 Rupee note. Unable to recollect where he lost it, he decides to kill himself but when he misses the train he returns home and confides in his wife. She assures him that she will manage somehow. He manages to borrow money, even finds a part-time job, to pay off his bills, but is unable to pay his electricity bill. One night he returns home and finds the pantry full. His mind distracted with doubts about his wife's character, he starts making mistakes at both his places of employment, and returns home to find his door locked, his wife missing, and his children playing outside. When he questions them about the whereabouts of their mother, they refuse to tell him. Shortly thereafter Sher Khan and Munnilal, concerned about their co-worker, find him near the railway tracks heading straight into an on-coming train. Sher manages to rescue him, and this is when he will tell them the devastating news that Geeta has taken to prostitution and he has killed her. Watch what impact this has on his employment, his children, and his friends.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?210081</url></doc>
