<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="211432">
  <docid>211432</docid>
  <title>Gehra Daag</title>
  <year>1963</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Ralhan, O.P.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ralhan, O.P.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Chatterjee, Dhruva</writer>
    <writer>Rizvi, Ehsan</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Ravi (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bihari (I)</actor>
      <role>Bihari - Jail inmate</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kiran, Usha</actor>
      <role>Usha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Krishna, Manmohan</actor>
      <role>Jailor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Rajendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Shanker</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mohan, Ram (I)</actor>
      <role>Ram</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, Madan (I)</actor>
      <role>Ramesh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Raja, Bupet</actor>
      <role>Tinku</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shahid, Moppet</actor>
      <role>Chimpu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sunder (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Shanker lives a poor lifestyle along with his elder sister, Usha, and a younger sister, Asha, in a town called Baksar. Both he and Usha attend the same college. One day a student, Ram, attempts to molest Usha, Shanker intervenes, arguments lead to fisticuffs, and Ram ends up getting killed. Shanker is arrested, tried in Court, and sentenced to 14 years in jail. While there he gets the news that Usha has married Ramesh, and has given birth to two sons, Tinku and Chimpu. Due to his good behavior, he gets discharged after 10 years, returns home and on the way there rescues an elderly woman, who had fallen from the boat, meets her daughter, Shobha, and both fall in love. Upon arrival at home, he is given a warm welcome by everyone, and this is when Shanker finds out that Usha has told everyone that he was employed in Africa for 10 years. Ramesh picks an eligible young man for Asha to get married to but on the day of the marriage, the Prosecuting Attorney recognizes Shanker, the wedding gets canceled, an infuriated Ramesh will not have anything to do with Shanker, who attempts to kill himself, and is rescued by Shobha, who takes him home to her mother, who takes note of their romance and plans their marriage little knowing that all their lives will soon be shattered after Shanker makes a life-altering discovery in Shobha's house.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?211432</url></doc>
