<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="211788">
  <docid>211788</docid>
  <title>Gemini - The Twin Stars</title>
  <year>1988</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>drugs</keyword>
    <keyword>escape</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Switzerland</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Netherlands">AL</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Germany">110</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Sandoz, Jacques</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Sandoz, Jacques</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Billeter, Jean-Bernard</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Holton, Nigel</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Azzolina, Michael</actor>
      <role>Airport barman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carey, Roland</actor>
      <role>Hotel manager</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Clément, Aurore</actor>
      <role>Maria-Helena Buffington</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Edwards, Jango</actor>
      <role>Mike</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Folger, Mark</actor>
      <role>Reuben</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Furrer, Adrian</actor>
      <role>Peter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Giannatos, Mihalis</actor>
      <role>1st. Policeman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harrison, Richard (II)</actor>
      <role>Senator Buffington</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hugener, Lorenz</actor>
      <role>Emil Fassler</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jones, Wynston A.</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Keeper, Carole</actor>
      <role>Boutique owner</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kolovos, Vassilis</actor>
      <role>Chief of police</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Krasnobajew, Sasha</actor>
      <role>Balz</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moynahan, Dennis (I)</actor>
      <role>Dennis</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nock, Thomas</actor>
      <role>Thomas Fassler</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Patrick, Gene</actor>
      <role>Matthew McLaren</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Petrella, John (III)</actor>
      <role>Sonny</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sofianos, Apostolos</actor>
      <role>2nd. policeman</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>GEMINI, THE TWIN STARS is the story of a star-crossed friendship which springs up when a young man's flight from danger crosses another man's quest for adventure. Traveling from New York to Geneva, from Swiss mountain peaks to remote Greek islands, Matthew McLaren is a carefree New York college student in the midst of finals. His world changes dramatically when he is wrongly implicated in the drug dealings of a friend, who is shot down by undercover agents. Frightened and desperate, Matthew buys a one-way ticket to Switzerland and escapes, unwittingly becoming the object of an international manhunt. Enroute to Geneva, Matthew meets Maria-Helena Buffington, the aristocratic, dissatisfied wife of a U.S. Senator. Maria-Helena introduces Matthew to the fast life of the international set, and the two begin a passionate affair. Matthew's past catches up with him, however, in the form of two policemen hot on his trail. After a frantic chase through a glittering nightclub, Matthew escapes again. this time to the sequestered Appenzell region in the foothills of the Alps. There, Matthew is befriended by Thomas Fassler, a young Swiss man who lives with his farm family. For Thomas, Matthew is the embodiment of the worldly adventurer, an American «cowboy» on holiday. For Matthew, Thomas' innocence, enthusiasm and love of nature are a refreshing change. The pair set off to find adventure, first in St. Moritz where they join Maria-Helena, and later in the never-ending party life of the Greek island of Mykonos. With the police closing in, we realize that Matthew and Thomas share a destiny that is fatefully charged with mystery and jeopardy. Offering a new twist to the classic love triangle, GEMINI, THE TWIN STARS is an international coming of age story.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?211788</url></doc>
