<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="212035">
  <docid>212035</docid>
  <title>Generation RX</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Gilchrist, Charles L.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>education</keyword>
    <keyword>attention-deficit-disorder</keyword>
    <keyword>ritalin</keyword>
    <keyword>children</keyword>
    <keyword>prozac</keyword>
    <keyword>suicide</keyword>
    <keyword>school</keyword>
    <keyword>adhd</keyword>
    <keyword>health</keyword>
    <keyword>psychiatric</keyword>
    <keyword>mental-health</keyword>
    <keyword>fda</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">11 November 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">81</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Miller, Kevin P.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Gilchrist, Charles L.</producer>
    <producer>Miller, Kevin P.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Miller, Kevin P.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Aylsworth, Richard C.</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Suchet, David</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>For decades, scores of doctors, government officials, journalists, and others have extolled the benefits of psychiatric medicines for children. GENERATION RX presents "the rest of the story" and unveils how this era of unprecedented change in Western culture really occurred - and what price has been paid by our society. International award-winning filmmaker Kevin P. Miller (Let Truth Be The Bias, The Promised Land) "delivers a jaw-dropping emotional ride," and "weaves a terrifying tale of criminal conspiracy, the mass abandonment of medical ethics, and the routine betrayal of an entire generation." By employing the expertise of internationally respected professionals from the fields of medicine, ethics, journalism, and academia, GENERATION RX investigates collusion between drug companies and their regulatory watchdogs at the FDA and focuses on the powerful stories of real families who followed the advice of their doctors - and faced devastating consequences for doing so. GENERATION RX is a film about families who confronted horror and found nowhere to turn for help - and how scores of children have been caught in the vortex of mind-bending drugs at the earliest stages of their growth and development. This powerful documentary also questions whether we have forced millions of children onto pharmaceutical drugs for commercial rather than scientific reasons. Ultimately, Generation RX may help parents decide whether the perceived benefits of these medications outweigh the serious risks to children.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?212035</url></doc>
