<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="212394">
  <docid>212394</docid>
  <title>Gentle Lovers</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Wright, Kendrick</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">21</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Caputi, Gino</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Jackson, Guy J.</producer>
    <producer>Pais-Caputi, Nayantara</producer>
    <producer>Caputi, Gino</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Caputi, Gino</writer>
    <writer>Jackson, Guy J.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Tremante, Michael</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fernandes, Reena</actor>
      <role>Consuela</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jackson, Guy J.</actor>
      <role>Clark Hanover</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kangas-Kent, Rana</actor>
      <role>Heather Mozes</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maikish, Christopher</actor>
      <role>Will Markesby</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Merrimen, Dr. Raphael</actor>
      <role>Sheldon Lebowitz</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Winston, Stan</actor>
      <role>Mr. Fern</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A screwball romantic comedy in the vein of You Can't Take It With You, Gentle Lovers tests the love bonds of a well-groomed milksop and his ever-so-slightly more adventurous paramour in an epic spat of jealousy, betrayal, and hypersensitivity. Pity poor Will Markesby. In reading his literary club newsletter, he discovers a veiled reference to what may or may not be a passionate romance between himself and the lovely Emily Lofton. to correct this mistake, Will writes a fatal note to Mr. Fern, the newsletter's editor. Not quite getting the gist of Will's grievance Mr. Fern complicates matters by writing to Emily to offer his apologies. But Emily has also misunderstood the passions between Will and herself and so fires off an angry letter to Will for having misled her. Will, blinded by anger, responds in kind, and soon missives are shuttling back and forth in a spectacular war of words. Eventually, the devastation uncovers two gut-wrenching problems in the affair of Will and Emily: Emily feels that Will perhaps isn't enough of a sensualist, and Will feels that Emily may sometimes be giving their mutual friend, Clark Hanover, too much attention. Only Consuela, the loyal maid, holds the solution, in a secret letter, the last letter to be revealed, a letter Consuela keeps tucked in the breast pocket of her uniform, close to her heart. What will the secret of the secret letter possibly be, and will it forever alter the destiny of Will and Emily...?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?212394</url></doc>
