<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="213847">
  <docid>213847</docid>
  <title>Gevald</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Hayat, Tali</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Musical</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Arabic</language>
    <language>Hebrew</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Israel</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Germany">6 February 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Israel">16</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Braun, Netalie</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Braun, Netalie</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Braun, Netalie</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Alexander, Elisha</actor>
      <role>Skinny Shuki</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Liberman, Adili</actor>
      <role>Naama</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Meltzer, Noga</actor>
      <role>Tal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Naveh, Gil</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The gay community in Jerusalem is a Jewish-Palestinian community struggling for the basic right to exist. As the life of gays, lesbians and transgenders in Tel-aviv becomes more open and free, the community in Jerusalem faces many obstacles and threats and constantly lives in fear. Various religious groups oppose the mere presence of gay people in the holy city and argue that homosexuality is an illness that should be eradicated. Before each pride parade the there are huge and violent protests held by religious organizations to prevent the parade from taking place. The city is covered with anti-gay propaganda posters claiming that homosexuality is a sin and encouraging the public to act against the gay community in whatever means they see fit. In the 2005 Jerusalem pride parade, three people where stabbed by an Ultra-Orthodox religious Jew who charged at the marchers with a knife. To prevent such things from happening the following year, the parade was canceled and replaced with a small event in a confined area. Gevald tells an almost impossible love story between two women at the eve of the 2006 pride event in Jerusalem. The two were a couple till one of them, a religious woman, could not deal with it and left to be married to a man. A few months later she suddenly shows up to warn her beloved from something dangerous she knows is about to happen at the pride event the following day. Will she be able to save her life? The plot takes places the night before the pride event in the "Shushan", the only gay bar in Jerusalem (which was since closed). This is the only place were gay, lesbian, transgender, bisexual and intersex people can come together and be who they are.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?213847</url></doc>
