<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="213978">
  <docid>213978</docid>
  <title>Ghar Grihasti</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Santosh (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Tillekar, Mahesh</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kukreja, Amit</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Tillekar, Mahesh</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Bhadkamkar, Kamlesh</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Alter, Tom</actor>
      <role>Drug smuggler</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arya, Sulabha</actor>
      <role>Basanti V. Deshmukh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Berde, Laxmikant</actor>
      <role>Lachke</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hingoo, Dinesh</actor>
      <role>Vijayalaxmi's dad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jairam (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jayapradha</actor>
      <role>Temple dancer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khote, Shubha</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khote, Viju</actor>
      <role>Tarka's husband</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Akshay (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maruti, Guddi</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Sharma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mohan, Mac</actor>
      <role>Mangesh's friend</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Parvez, Yunus</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Young, attractive, and compassionate Janki Deshmukh lives in a small flat with her elderly mom, Basanti; her disabled father who is awaiting a Court decision for compensation for losing his left arm; brother Mangesh who is busy looking for a job; younger sister, Sharuvir alias Sharu; and a physically handicapped brother, Banthu. She works as a Receptionist, with an employer, Jagdish, who secretly adores her. Her dad does win the case, but Mangesh gets the money so that he can bribe someone to get a good job. However, he ends up marrying a wealthy young woman named Shakala, and subsequently moving out of the flat. Shocked at this, her dad has a heart attack and passes away. Then a few days later, the family wakes up to find that Sharu has disappeared, possibly eloped with one Narendra, who she has been meeting secretly. To make matters worse, Basanti's health get worse, she gets diagnosed with serious kidney problems, which can only be corrected through expensive surgery. With no one, save her handicapped brother, Janki must now come up with the money required for the surgery - or end up losing her mom as well.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?213978</url></doc>
