<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="214396">
  <docid>214396</docid>
  <title>Ghosts of Elitch Theatre</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Johnson, Tim (XXVIII)</editor>
    <editor>Liban, David</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>theatre</keyword>
    <keyword>ghost</keyword>
    <keyword>elitch</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">TV-G</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">17 March 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">27</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Liban, David</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hadzi, Anna</producer>
    <producer>Liban, David</producer>
    <producer>Maes, Katherine</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Liban, David</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Eldridge, Robert (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bonner, Bryan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Causey, Kevin</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Giem, Gary</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hickenlooper, John</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hull, Betty</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The Elitch Theater was built in Denver in 1891 with the notion that it would bring to its stage some of the worlds most popular stars. People like Grace Kelly, Sarah Bernhardt, Edward G. Robinson, and Robert Redford, just to name a few. The building has fell into disrepair and there was a danger of it either collapsing or burning down. Fortunately, it was put on the national registry of Historic Places and listed as a Landmark with both the state of Colorado and the city of Denver. And now it is being renovated. This documentary is both an historical documentary about the theatre and a ghost story. Many people believe the Ghost of Mary Elitch has kept the theater from falling. It history is fascinating and sheds light on the early days of Denver. The filmmakers brought in a group of Paranormal Researchers to determine if indeed the theatre was haunted. The theme of the film is really Its about the passion for the place, and the power of the place. This theatre is not just a big thing to Denver, but to the nation. It is the oldest standing summer stock theater in the country. Also it explores Mary Elitch's history. She is a fascinating person and the only woman in her time running an amusement park. She is celebrated by feminists for doing this at a time when it was nearly impossible for a woman to have this sort of success.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?214396</url></doc>
