<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="214456">
  <docid>214456</docid>
  <title>Ghulami</title>
  <year>1985</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="UK">15</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">199</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Dutta, J.P.</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Dutta, O.P.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kudalkar, Laxmikant Shantaram</composer>
    <composer>Sharma, Pyarelal Ramprasad</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bachchan, Amitabh</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chakraborty, Mithun</actor>
      <role>Jabhar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dharmendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Ranjit Singh Choudhary</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gill, Avtar</actor>
      <role>Shamu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Haksar, Rajan</actor>
      <role>Makhan Singh Choudhary</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Bharat</actor>
      <role>Thakur Shakti Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Huma</actor>
      <role>Persian Singer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Mazhar (II)</actor>
      <role>Thakur Jaswant Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kharbanda, Kulbhushan</actor>
      <role>Havaldar Gopi Dada</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Latkar, Sulochana</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Makhan Singh Choudhary</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mohan, Ram (I)</actor>
      <role>Masterji</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Murad, Raza</actor>
      <role>Fatehpur's Thanedar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shah, Naseeruddin</actor>
      <role>SP Sultan Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shivpuri, Om</actor>
      <role>Bade Thakur</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Srivastav, Anjan</actor>
      <role>Bade Thakur's Munim</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Near India and Pakistan's border-town of Fatehpur, lives Ranjit Singh Choudhary who has been labeled as a rebel by his schoolmaster and his dad, Makhan's employer, Bade Thakur, as he could not stand the injustice that was meted to farmers like his dad, and his ancestors who had become economic slaves to the upper-caste Thakurs, who loaned them some money, mortgaged their land, made them toil in the fields, took away their crops, molested their women, and when they passed away, forced their children to take on the debt. Ranjit decides to leave for good, but does return on the very day of his dad's passing. He is asked to assume the loan left unpaid by his dad, when he refuses to do so, he is treated as a bandit, leading him to confront the corrupt Police Force. When Bade Thakur's daughter, Sumitra, who was Ranjit's childhood sweetheart, marries DSP Sultan Singh, a buffalo is slaughtered and left to rot in the community well, poisoning the water, resulting in several deaths, including that of the local schoolmaster. Bandit Surajbhan Singh robs the wedding party, earns the wrath of Sultan, is hunted down, and brutally killed, resulting in Sultan's promotion as SP. Now the stage is all set for Sultan to capture Ranjit, which he does, but Ranjit manages to escape, joins forces with Havaldar-turned-renegade, Gopi Dada, and an army officer, Jabhar, to confront the Thakurs, and attempt to rid the records that bind the farmers to loans that were taken centuries ago. Sultan has undertaken to stop Ranjit, Gopi, and Jabhar, at all and any costs - and with the might of the law and the Thakurs behind him - it does look like Ranjit and his men may not have any chance at survival - leaving the evil to flourish on forever.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?214456</url></doc>
