<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="214884">
  <docid>214884</docid>
  <title>Gigs, Loose Wires</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">4 July 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">23</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Maisuria, Ishwar L.</producer>
    <producer>Ali, Mehdi</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>"Zack is a stand-up comic. His sister Zoe is a lounge singer. Their agent, George is a novice. Welcome to the 'gigs' nobody wants to talk about: birthday parties, old folks' homes, dingy bars, and country fairs, even prisons..." George the agent works out of an office which doubles as a storage room in the back of his papa's barbershop. Slick talking and well intentioned, George has a cell phone and isn't afraid to use it. But when he somehow stumbles on a last-minute replacement gig for singer Zoe at an exclusive club, her comedian brother Byron is furious. Who wouldn't be, having just come from a nightmare gig at a rest home? When things threaten to go wrong during Zoe's performance, will Byron step up to help his sister? And does this dream gig mean that George is finally on to something? Don't count on it. As the series progresses, George's gigs become the stuff of legend, and Byron and Zoe's showbiz careers waver precariously between fame and dejection as their sibling rivalry reaches the kinds of heights that only two spotlight-craving, temperamental, fame-hungry stage hogs can achieve. They never give up. Helping and hindering is a revolving cast of fellow performers, amateur and professional, some handling the pressure and others losing it in ways that only stage performers can. Meanwhile, Zoe's roommate Miki, an artist, always armed with a digital camera, is there to capture the excitement. And businessman, Mr. Vijay Kumar, a Fijian immigrant of Indian descent and owner of the Irish bar/restaurant where Byron and Zoe work to pay their bills, sees himself as George's next client, regaling the agent with heavily-accented celebrity impressions every chance he gets. Combining fast-paced dialogue with stand-up comedy and musical performances, the pilot episode 'Loose Wires' of the sitcom "Gigs" follows the exploits of a core group of endearing characters while entertaining the viewer with the talents of a real-life comedian and a gifted singer.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?214884</url></doc>
