<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="218033">
  <docid>218033</docid>
  <title>God's Baboons</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bartolic, Alan</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>baboon</keyword>
    <keyword>god</keyword>
    <keyword>monkey</keyword>
    <keyword>animal-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">17 January 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">105</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Sutton, Jonathan (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bartolic, Alan</producer>
    <producer>Beharry, Peter</producer>
    <producer>Sutton, Jonathan (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Sutton, Jonathan (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Hertzman, Amos</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kanagawa, Hiro</actor>
      <role>Clive</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pastko, Earl</actor>
      <role>Michael</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sutton, Jonathan (II)</actor>
      <role>Alex</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This darkly comic DV feature charts a young artist's tightrope walk between creativity and madness. Twenty-five-year-old Alex has been using his growing accomplishments as an actor to hide from his true dream of writing - he yearns to work alone, but fears the associated isolation and responsibility. His doubts are amplified by the fact that his late father - from whom Alex inherited both talent and a genetic disposition towards mental instability - ended his literary career by taking his own life. Encouraged by the mentorship of Michael, a subversive priest, Alex is determined to force a confrontation with his fear. He quits the lead role in a career-launching production of Hamlet, cutting off any financial security in order to push himself into his writing. In doing so, he inadvertently exchanges the portrayal of a character's madness for the reality of his own. Hamlet's drama proceeds to unfold, complete with murder plots, Oedipal promptings, a father's ghost, an irresponsible mother, an imposing stepfather, an alienated girlfriend, and an increasingly inescapable descent into delusion and mayhem - only outside of the imaginary world of the theatre, it is Alex's life that provides the setting...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?218033</url></doc>
