<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="218086">
  <docid>218086</docid>
  <title>God's Little Monster</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Antepli, Julie Gulnihal</editor>
    <editor>D'Lerma, Alex</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>dream</keyword>
    <keyword>religious-faith</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">28 October 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">20</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>D'Lerma, Alex</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Emanuel, Russ</producer>
    <producer>Adair-Rios, Mark</producer>
    <producer>Arzola, Maria</producer>
    <producer>Lozano, Vince</producer>
    <producer>Kitchens, David</producer>
    <producer>Zarai, Ben</producer>
    <producer>D'Lerma, Alex</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>D'Lerma, Alex</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Westin, Philip</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Adair-Rios, Mark</actor>
      <role>Monty</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Alexander, Mason (I)</actor>
      <role>Linda's Mom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>D'Lerma, Alex</actor>
      <role>Father Antonio</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>DeCola, Dena</actor>
      <role>Linda Church</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Griffin, James D. (II)</actor>
      <role>Composer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lozano, Vince</actor>
      <role>Raymond Church</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Matson, April</actor>
      <role>Goth</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Naten, Danny</actor>
      <role>Brody</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>God's Little Monster (GLM) is a disturbing, surreal, fable about convicted killer Raymond Church (Vince Lozano) who challenges his daughter Linda's (Dena DeCola) religious faith in an attempt to possess her mind and soul. Linda Church is a God fearing young woman haunted by a re-occurring violent nightmare / childhood memory and feels like she's losing her mind. The nightmare nags Linda for answers to questions she's been ignoring all her life concerning her abandonment by her parents during childhood. Only one man can give Linda the answers she needs. But the man with the answers is a convicted killer and he's also Linda's estranged father, Raymond Church, aka God's Little Monster. Linda gains a meeting with her father, Raymond, but 'daddy' never gives away anything for free. Haunted by her nightmare, Linda searches for answers about her missing mother, herself, and her father...God's Little Monster. GLM cleverly jumps back and forth between reality and Linda's nightmare dream-scape as composer Dr. Philip Westin provides an eerie, classical, music score. Actors Vince Lozano ('Pirates of the Caribbean') and Dena DeCola ('Elizabethtown')are emotional risk takers and deliver riveting performances that are sure to gain critical attention and numerous awards. Writer / Director Alex D'Lerma ('Alvarez &amp; Cruz') provides a unique, dark and thought provoking script. He is an actor's director and his skill at drawing out emotionally risky and honest performances from his actors is reminiscent of John Cassavetes.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?218086</url></doc>
