<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="218699">
  <docid>218699</docid>
  <title>Gojiri</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Marathi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barve, Sunil</actor>
      <role>Shrikarerao Sahasrabuddhe</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chavan, Abhijeet</actor>
      <role>Nanu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nalawade, Arun</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Widower Tatya lives a middle-class lifestyle in a small village off of the Konkon Coastline in Maharashtra, India, along with his daughters, Gojiri and mentally challenged Suha. On Suha's birthday, while picking mangoes, Gojiri falls down the tree, hurts her head, passes out, and is hospitalized. Tatya is told that she has damaged her temporal lobe beyond repair, as a result the contact between her short and long term memory has been lost, so she can only remember what occurred the day before, and will virtually re-live her life as 'groundhog' days. Since then Gojiri has been celebrating Suha's birthday every single day. Then Shikarerao comes to this village all the way from Nasikh city. He meets with and falls in love with Gojiri and would like to marry her. He finds Gojiri receptive and even proposes to her through Nanu, his real estate agent, who is attempting to sell Shikarerao's 'haunted' property. Nanu tells him the truth about Gojiri, but he is smitten and is unable to let go. Watch what happens when Shikarerao persists in wooing Gojiri, is beaten by angry youth, and then reprimanded by the village elders/Panchayat for insulting and molesting Gojiri, and the impact this will have on him, Tatya and Gojiri herself.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?218699</url></doc>
