<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="218669">
  <docid>218669</docid>
  <title>GoingGreen: Every Home an Eco-Home</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Morgan, Diannah</editor>
    <editor>Walls, Tom (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>nature</keyword>
    <keyword>tomato-juice</keyword>
    <keyword>eco-living</keyword>
    <keyword>green</keyword>
    <keyword>environment</keyword>
    <keyword>earth-friendly</keyword>
    <keyword>ecology</keyword>
    <keyword>global-warming</keyword>
    <keyword>conservation</keyword>
    <keyword>alternative-energy</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">15 June 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">24</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Vogelsang, Judith</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Proteau, Mary</producer>
    <producer>Vogelsang, Judith</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Proteau, Mary</writer>
    <writer>Vogelsang, Judith</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>DeMartino, Mike</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shalhoub, Tony</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Mixing humor with everyday, affordable examples at home, GOINGGREEN tours the original Eco-Home with a group of middle-school kids who discover first-hand some simple, inexpensive ways to become more earth-friendly. Guided by eco-pioneer Julia Russell, Founding Director of the non-profit, Eco-Home Network, the children learn how to conserve water through drip irrigation, soaker hoses, graywater systems and drought-tolerant, California Friendly landscaping. They discover why and how to compost, what household hazardous waste may be lurking in their own homes, and how to use the sun's energy to light, heat and power their homes with sun pipes, solar hot water heaters and solar panels. The kids experience the delight of making their own organic tomato juice with tomatoes they picked right off the vine in Eco-Home's backyard garden. They learn, hands-on, how to compost, and have fun watching the progress of several serious-looking bugs that Julia describes as a crucial part of the 'composting team.' The kids ask questions and then come up with some of the answers! GOINGGREEN shows us how we can live earth-friendly lives on a limited budget, even in the middle of a city.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?218669</url></doc>
