<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="218863">
  <docid>218863</docid>
  <title>Gold Fishing</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>goldfish</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">28 June 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">04</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="USA">5</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Rice, Christopher (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Rice, Christopher (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Christiansen, Katie</writer>
    <writer>Nieman, Kevin</writer>
    <writer>Rice, Christopher (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Christiansen, Katie</actor>
      <role>Gold Fish</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sutphen, Matt</actor>
      <role>Robber</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>After an identity thief is declined from using a credit card at the gas station, a man enters and asks for all of the money. The man breaks the clerk's nose with a bag of ice and kidnaps the girl in a quick escape. That morning, the ID thief wakes up with a painful split in her head and notices her hands are bound by rope. She takes the opportunity to make a run for it but the kidnapper is right behind her. He catches up with her, pulls her to the ground, and drags her back to the car where he makes her drive. After a heated fight, he finally announces he's going to kill her and makes her pull over. She dives out of the moving car as it rolls toward a fence. She digs in her bag, pulls out a small handgun, and fires at the car. She walks up to the car and notices that the robber is gone. Later that day, the ID thief confronts the FBI concerning the robber and what happened. The interviewer tells her that the video tape from the gas station only recorded her and that there was no other man there except the clerk. They accuse her of robbing the gas station, driving through the country, and binding her own hands in rope. She tells them they're out of their minds and asks if they really think she's that crazy. At that moment, the robber appears in the corner of the room with a devilish smile as he looks at her.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?218863</url></doc>
