<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="218822">
  <docid>218822</docid>
  <title>Gold</title>
  <year>1997</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Cranstoun, Tony</editor>
  </editors>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">1 December 1997</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">50</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <writers>
    <writer>Mellor, Kay</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ashbourne, Jayne</actor>
      <role>Lisa Johnson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Boardman, Lee</actor>
      <role>Kevvo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Callard, Rebecca</actor>
      <role>Tula</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chadwick, Justin</actor>
      <role>Rabbit</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dibley, Janet</actor>
      <role>Paula Graham</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Durkin, Barbara</actor>
      <role>Katie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Edwards, Danny (I)</actor>
      <role>Sherrie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Headey, Lena</actor>
      <role>Colette</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hole, Joanna</actor>
      <role>Amanda</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>James, Geraldine</actor>
      <role>Rose Garrity</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kotz, Adam</actor>
      <role>Vinnie Marshall</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Meredith, Ifan</actor>
      <role>Charlie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Salmon, Colin</actor>
      <role>Raymond Wallace</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The third part to the trilogy, 'Gold' is the last chapter into the lives of two ex-prostitutes, and their battles to break their ties with the red light area. Split into three different stories, we see the return of Carol Johnson and Rose Garrity, as they try to help the women on the Lane, and stop themselves with being roped into the world of prostitution. 'She's Back' tells the story of Paula Graham, a 37 year old prostitute who has come back to the Lane, from being trapped in a failed marriage, only to find her business falling, when all her clients are murdered. Believing her to be the prime suspect, Carol and Rose must help Paula battle the journey of the Police, while trying also to break her ties with the lane as well. Stars Janet Dibley as Paula Graham. 'A Walk On The Wild Side' shows Rose becoming involved with trans-sexual prostitute, Sherrie, who has been moved to a 'toleration zone', where prostitutes can be kept clean and healthy. As she battles to save Sherrie from prison, Carol is having trouble with finances, when she finds herself face-to-face with Curly's nephew, Vinnie, who demands all money from Curly's will, to be transferred to his bank account. Stars Danny Edwards as Sherrie and Adam Kotz as Vinnie Marshall. 'Tainted Love' sees the prostitutes happily working in the 'torelation zone', while the 'Hustler's Arms' becomes bombarded with pimps from Leeds, who look set to take over the working streets. The leader of the pack, Raymond, becomes obsessed with Sherrie, and soon discovers her hidden secret. Meanwhile, Carol and Rose have a visit from Carol's half-sister, Lisa, who falls into the arms of risky pimp, Charlie, who is set to threaten Carol's chicken factory and her daughter. Stars Colin Salmon as Raymond, Jayne Ashbourne as Lisa and Ifran Meredith as Charlie. We also see the return of Colette, Rose's long-lost daughter who becomes increasingly worried about the relationship between herself and Rose, as she becomes deeply involved in prostitution and drugs.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?218822</url></doc>
