<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="219508">
  <docid>219508</docid>
  <title>Gone to the Dogs</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>West, Cliff (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="UK">12</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">30 January 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Barnard, Philip</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Barnard, Philip</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Bastin, Alec</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Booth, Anthony (I)</actor>
      <role>Jack</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bryan, Dora</actor>
      <role>Rose</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Gone to the Dogs is a surreal comedy about a stagnant relationship and the trials of old age. The central character is Jack, a lecherous chain-smoking old man whose life reaches a dead end when he retires with his wife Rose to a grubby British seaside town. Sexually frustrated and unable to accept the passing of youth, Jack vies for the attention of the young women in his new seaside abode. At the funfair he attempts to impress them with his strength on a striker machine. Mid-swing he suffers a fatal heart attack and tumbles into the big beyond. But this isn't the end for Jack. After his cremation he returns to Earth as a disorientated stray dog. It's not long before he's back with his wife Rose who has no idea that this hairy waif is a reincarnation of her dead husband. So begins Jack's bizarre journey of self-discovery as he struggles with his new existence and finally learns what marriage is all about. Bawdy humour is mixed with an eerie atmosphere to create a unique story that is both funny and unsettling.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?219508</url></doc>
