<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="219633">
  <docid>219633</docid>
  <title>Gonzo Music Diaries, NYC</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Ambrosini, Giacomo</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>music-festival</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Argentina">22 March 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Netherlands">23 November 2006</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="France">24 May 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Switzerland">April 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">82</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Szuper, Roy</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Szuper, Roy</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Szuper, Roy</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Beal, Dana</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bessman, Jim</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Delsener, Ron</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Franklin, Joe (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fuchs, Dana</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Holmstrom, John</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Joe, Concert</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kristal, Hilly</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Peel, David (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shakerleg</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Szuper, Roy</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Yoel, Drew</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Gonzo Music Diaries, NYC is a time capsule of the music and politics that shaped New York City in 2004. Director/Producer Roy Szuper, brother-in-law and music fanatic Concert Joe, and punk rocker Tony Petrozza, set out to create the 1st Annual Williamsburg Music Festival as a statement of protest against the incoming Republican National Convention. Joe acts as our guide through the New York music scene while Szuper borrows money, seeks advice, and secures talent for the festival. Along the way we meet legendary activist/musician, David Peel, who entertains us with his history of political irreverence. We also interview another New York legend in Hilly Kristal, founder of CGGB's, who touches on topics such as the corporatization of music and the impending closing of CB's. After tremendous financial maneuvering and miles of red tape created by the city bureaucracy in their pre-RNC paranoia, the festival takes place as scheduled, 9 days before the RNC. Despite all the hard work and expectations, torrential rains put a damper on the festival. Despite the rains, 8 bands performed including David Peel, Tony Petrozza and his band SQNS, Dana Fuchs, the city's most intense subway performer Shakerleg, and headliner Vernon Reid and friends. Despite the financial disaster for producer Roy Szuper, the spirit of the festival carries us through to the RNC. Once there, we experience the largest protest in the history of any political convention in history and the premiere activist concert of RNC week featuring Tom Morello and Michael Franti and Spearhead. The film also features appearances Agnostic Front lead guitarist and Hardcore Tattoo Founder Vinnie Stigma, Dana Beal, leader of the Yippies, legendary TV/radio host Joe Franklin, Jake Hill, Publisher of Spin Magazine, the festival's main sponsor, and Punk Magazine founder John Holmstrom. .</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?219633</url></doc>
