<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="221751">
  <docid>221751</docid>
  <title>Grandma Dorothy's House</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kastelowitz, Noah</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">26 March 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Kastelowitz, Noah</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kastelowitz, Noah</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>Grandma Dorothy is ninety years old. Dorothy is also a compulsive hoarder. She throws nothing away, including her garbage. After many years of not allowing anyone into her home, a visit by the local fire department triggers a series of events including Dorothy's eviction and a threatened condemnation of the property. Packed floor to ceiling with a lifetime of accumulation, the structure is collapsing on itself. While Dorothy sits on the front porch and considers the situation, a demolition crew empties the contents of the house into eleven bus-sized dumpsters, removing over 15,000 cubic feet of refuse and possessions. Dorothy's perception of her belongings and their sentimental value is starkly contrasted with the sheer quantity, filthy condition, and hazards of living with what she has assembled. From Dorothy's point of view, the cleanup of her home is unfair, unnecessary, and a violation of her rights. Hoarding, the pathological and secretive compulsion to stockpile "stuff," is estimated to affect about ten percent of the elderly population. Carried to extremes, it poses significant health and safety risks for the hoarder, as well a difficult management problem for family members, neighbors, and landlords. Scientific and clinical research has only recently begun regarding the causes and treatment of this poorly understood condition. This short documentary reveals what is typically hidden from the community and unrecognized by individuals afflicted by the compulsion to hoard.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?221751</url></doc>
