<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="221971">
  <docid>221971</docid>
  <title>Grass Roots</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>based-on-comic-strip</keyword>
    <keyword>smoking-marijuana</keyword>
    <keyword>drug</keyword>
    <keyword>based-on-comic</keyword>
    <keyword>stoner</keyword>
    <keyword>drugs</keyword>
    <keyword>hit</keyword>
    <keyword>endo</keyword>
    <keyword>marijuana</keyword>
    <keyword>cannabis</keyword>
    <keyword>pot</keyword>
    <keyword>dope</keyword>
    <keyword>joint</keyword>
    <keyword>marijuana-joint</keyword>
    <keyword>drug-humor</keyword>
    <keyword>cannabis-use</keyword>
    <keyword>weed</keyword>
    <keyword>reefer</keyword>
    <keyword>pot-smoking</keyword>
    <keyword>adult-animation</keyword>
    <keyword>stoned</keyword>
    <keyword>ganja</keyword>
    <keyword>smoke</keyword>
    <keyword>420</keyword>
    <keyword>underground</keyword>
    <keyword>cult-comedy</keyword>
    <keyword>slacker</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2012</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Borthwick, Dave</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Higham, Bruce</producer>
    <producer>Lascelles, David (I)</producer>
    <producer>Leighton, Andy</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Davies, Paul B.</writer>
    <writer>Shelton, Gilbert</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>For once, The Freak Brothers find themselves with plenty of cash and some righteous weed. But this is no ordinary marijuana: it's been genetically modified as part of a sinister government plot to take over the dope market. When Norbert the Narc - secret agent and rock-jawed defender of decency - accidentally hands the prototype weed to the Freak Brothers, and they discover its bizarre side effects, the feds are hot on their trail and the Boys have to leave town, fast. Now's the time to fulfil their long-cherished dream of retiring to grow marijuana in the country. So, they acquire a remote plot of land and enthusiastically embrace Mother Nature - but Mother Nature fights back. And the three obliging 'chicks' who join their 'commune' soon give the Brothers a painful lesson in the realities of modern gender politics. Meanwhile, the local town turns out to be run by a crazed fundamentalist religious sect who practice weird baptism rituals. And what goes on in the Secret Sinister Government Research Institute up in the hills? Surely, the Brothers can't have chosen to hide out right next to the very place where the government is testing the genetically modified 'product'...can they? This rip-roaring yarn is related by Fat Freddy's Cat, whose long-suffering tolerance of human idiocy makes him a perfect narrator. However, his admirable sang froid is ruffled when he falls in love with a local mountain lion. And, as the story reaches a nail-biting, bong-clutching climax, only his selfless heroism can save the Freak Brothers from the most dangerous enemies of all - themselves.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?221971</url></doc>
