<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="222843">
  <docid>222843</docid>
  <title>Gregory Peck: His Own Man</title>
  <year>1988</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>French</language>
    <language>Spanish</language>
    <language>Portuguese</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">28 May 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Feldman, Gene (I)</director>
    <director>Winter, Suzette</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Janson, Stephen</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Feldman, Gene (I)</writer>
    <writer>Winter, Suzette</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bacall, Lauren</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fonda, Jane</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hepburn, Audrey</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lemmon, Jack (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Minnelli, Liza</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Quinn, Anthony (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>HIS OWN MAN One of Hollywood's most enduring and popular stars draws on his memories to tell the amusing and touching story of how it was when the studios ruled supreme, and how a shy and inarticulate boy from a broken family could rise to super stardom to become one of the most handsome, attractive and respected of movie leading men. His early career proved his talent; his later years showed that with the talent came a wise and humane individual. Unfashionably modest in these days of hard-hitting self-aggrandizement, Peck takes us with him on this long and fascinating journey from early theater roles, through his first film parts up to today. This entertainment special uses clips from Peck's most important movies including The Yearling, To Kill a Mockingbird, Spellbound, Moby Dick, Roman Holiday, Duel in the Sun, The Guns of Navarone, MacArthur, Captain Hornblower, The Boys From Brazil - and interviews with Jane Fonda, Audrey Hepburn, Liza Minnelli, Anthony Quinn, Jack Lemmon, Lauren Bacall, directors Robert Mulligan and J. Lee Thompson, and Peck's son Stephen.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?222843</url></doc>
