<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="223032">
  <docid>223032</docid>
  <title>Gridiron Goliaths</title>
  <year>1953</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">3 February 1953</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">9</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Reek, Edmund</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Reek, Edmund</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Allen, Mel (I)</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Mel Allen narrates highlights of the 19th annual game between the College All-Stars and the defending NFL champion, with recap segments of previous games. The is was an affair where the National Football League champions squared off before the season against a team of graduating college players from the prior college football season. The college players actually won several games during the years this event was staged, mostly because professional football players of the period had real jobs during the off-season---pro football was not a year-around pursuit for the players and they needed other jobs as the game didn't pay that well during the early years---so, this game was just part of training camp and was usually a sloppy affair on the part of the professional team. Later, when pro football grew in popularity and the pro teams were more stable, the game became a mismatch and died for lack of competition on the part of the college All Stars. Plus, most of the All Stars had been drafted by various pro teams---the game was played before they reported to the training camp of the team, that had drafted them, and it soon became evident that it was in the best interest of the defending NFL champion to inflict as much damage as possible on the All-Stars, as the majority of them would soon be reporting to the training camps of other NFL teams.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?223032</url></doc>
