<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="224430">
  <docid>224430</docid>
  <title>Guides and Gurus</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Reality-TV</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">1 June 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Romeike, Christopher J.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Lerech, David</producer>
    <producer>Benmergui, Ralph</producer>
    <producer>Novak, Allan</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Novak, Allan</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Teachers, preachers, healers and hypnotists Guides and Gurus is a 13 part documentary series that profiles some of North America's most fascinating spiritual leaders. Guides and Gurus explores the beliefs and daily practices of spiritual healers and leaders all over North America, from Lorraine Bennington, a hypnotherapist who performs past-life regressions, to self-proclaimed "spiritual midwife" Enocha Ranjita Ryan. We encounter soul painters, shamans and spiritual emissaries, Kabbalists, Wiccans and many more. Guides and Gurus is a companion to the VisionTV series 5 Seekers, hosted by Ralph Benmergui. The program was shot in locations across North America, including Sedona, Arizona, a major centre for alternative spirituality and Cortes Island, B.C. "Many Canadians have become interested in exploring spiritual traditions and practices that lie outside the realm of conventional religion. Meeting the fascinating individuals profiled in Guides and Gurus will help viewers to appreciate just how spiritually diverse our society really is and may give them food for thought as they ponder their own spiritual paths." - Ralph Benmergui, host and executive producer.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?224430</url></doc>
