<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="224877">
  <docid>224877</docid>
  <title>Gunaah</title>
  <year>1993</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Bhatt, Mahesh (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Roshan, Rajesh</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deol, Sunny (I)</actor>
      <role>Ravi Sohni</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Desai, Anang</actor>
      <role>Rai</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gill, Avtar</actor>
      <role>Rama's assistant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapadia, Dimple</actor>
      <role>Kavita Sharma/Kavita Singh/Kavita A. Khanna</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Mushtaq</actor>
      <role>Hotel Manager</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khurana, Akash</actor>
      <role>Mahender Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mehta, Sujata</actor>
      <role>Rita Pinto</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Murad, Raza</actor>
      <role>Rama Patil</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, Rajesh</actor>
      <role>Sujit Singh Tanha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Saigal, Sumeet</actor>
      <role>Dr. Ashok Khanna</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Singh, Manohar (I)</actor>
      <role>Dr. Joe D'Costa</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Off the coast of Goa, India, some fishermen find a body of a battered young man, and they take him to the nearest medical facility run by Dr. Joe D'Costa. After the doctor's treatment, the young man recovers, but is unable to remember anything. For five long years he lives amongst the fishermen and ponders his past life and fate, then suddenly he meets someone who remembers him, and subsequently gets his memory back. He now remembers that he is Ravi Sohni, a Journalist, who was assigned the task of exposing a politician by the name of Mahinder Singh. He does so, resulting in the death of Mahender, but it is only after his death that he finds out that Mahender was not a corrupt politician and that he was being set-up to bring him down. Now Ravi must use all his resources to try and set right the wrong done by him - a wrong that may have devastated the life of the young woman that he loved - none other than the daughter of Mahender - Kavita. When he finds Kavita, he realizes that nothing is the same anymore, not only does Kavita hate him, but she is also married to a young man named Dr. Ashok Khanna - who has been arrested, charged with murder and may face the death penalty. Watch how Ravi goes around to re-open a trail that has been cold for five years, and to find the person(s) responsible for his current plight.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?224877</url></doc>
