<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="224985">
  <docid>224985</docid>
  <title>Gunlok</title>
  <year>2000</year>
  <type>VideoGame</type>
  <genres>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>fictional-war</keyword>
    <keyword>video-game</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Kingsley, Jason (IV)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Best, Emerson</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Cookson, Edward</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Boulter, John (IV)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cocklin, Nadia</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jennings, Adam (I)</actor>
      <role>Gunlok, Hark, Elint</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jones, Tim (IX)</actor>
      <role>Frend</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Martin, Gary (I)</actor>
      <role>Maskelyn</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>At the end of the 21st Century machines ran the world and mankind enjoyed an age of leisure, our every whim catered for by sophisticated robots. Finally mankind relinquished control of the machines. It took the machines scant days to discover that their power was now absolute. The world was plunged into darkness. Unrestrained, the machines waged war against themselves and mankind. Humanity desperately gathered its forces, but humans had lost the initiative. In a last ditch attempt to turn the tide of the war a crash program was instigated to create a break-through weapons technology - a combination of power armour and a radical new energy technology which tapped into a resonance at the Earth's core - Earth Power. An Advanced Special Forces Group had just started testing the battle armour prototypes when the machines resolved their differences and turned all their attention to mankind. The Earth's surface was bombarded with neutron bombs from ageing orbital weapon platforms. There were few survivors. Humankind had lost the war. Some years after the bombardment mankind was almost extinct. The machines had consolidated into Corporations, driven by imperatives programmed into them by the business empires of the early 21st century. The Corporations ruled the Earth while a few isolated pockets of human resistance fought on. This is Gunlok's world. A ravaged planet populated by hostile machines. You play Gunlok, a lone member of the Advanced Special Forces Group. The machines have won, but humans continue to strive against them. After a period of training and contemplation you are now in absolute control of your battle armour and Earth Powers. You decide now is the time to strike back. Now is the time to take the fight to The Corporation.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?224985</url></doc>
