<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="225493">
  <docid>225493</docid>
  <title>Guy in a Field</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Stanley, Jonathan (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Australia">3 June 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Australia">15</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Stanley, Jonathan (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Edmonds, Miranda</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Stanley, Jonathan (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bolton, Georgia</actor>
      <role>Wife</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gorman, Reg</actor>
      <role>Father</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lyndon, Simon</actor>
      <role>Guy</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Guy wakes in a field. As his eyes blink open he's faced with the odd sight of a dog looking back at him. Intrigued by this, GUY even asks the dog its name. It's this question that begins to unhinge GUY. He loses his calm. Where he is? Why is he in a field? The dog flees crashing through the brush; as sounds of reality begin to build behind Guy. As he ominously turns to face the noise, a drop of blood trickles down his cheek. Guy is facing a nightmare. A road divides the endless fields. Two mangled cars face each other. The body of a 60 year old FATHER, an 8 year old DAUGHTER and an unconscious WIFE lie before him. Compounding this nightmare is GUY'S memory, or lack of it. He doesn't remember a thing, not even his name. All he knows is that he is injured, he must have been thrown from one of these cars. We are left with a kind of psychological whodunit. As Guy proceeds to piece together his identity amongst the carnage. Trapped in an open landscape by his amnesia, GUY wants to grieve, but doesn't know who for. He wants his memory back, but also fears the truth.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?225493</url></doc>
