<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="226933">
  <docid>226933</docid>
  <title>Hadersfild</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Glusac, Marko</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>based-on-play</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Serbo-Croatian</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Serbia</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Serbia">5 July 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Greece">22 November 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Germany">9 November 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Hungary">6 May 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Bosnia and Herzegovina">24 August 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">95</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Zivkovic, Ivan (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Djuricko, Ljiljana</producer>
    <producer>Glogovac, Nebojsa</producer>
    <producer>Susljik, Goran</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Kraljacic, Dejan</writer>
    <writer>Sajtinac, Ugljesa</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Decermic, Irina</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cetkovic, Vojin</actor>
      <role>Dule</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Glogovac, Nebojsa</actor>
      <role>Ivan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kecojevic, Damjan</actor>
      <role>Igor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lukic, Suzana</actor>
      <role>Milica</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Manojlovic, Miki</actor>
      <role>Pesnik</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Susljik, Goran</actor>
      <role>Rasa</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tatic, Josif</actor>
      <role>Otac</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tomic, Milan (I)</actor>
      <role>Radnik na otpadu</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Story is set in a small town in Serbia. Rasha is thirty, lives with his alcoholic father and trying, and failing, to make ends meet by giving literature lessons to teenage girls and hosting a program on the local radio, presenting new books and interviewing authors. Ivan, a promising judoist in his teenage years, has since had a history of neurosis, psychotic episodes, hospitalization, being heavily medicated, involvement in various occult groups and practices, prior to having been baptized in the Orthodox Church. Milla is very attractive, energetic, resourceful and very straightforward: it immediately becomes clear that, apart from having a student/teacher relationship, she and Rasha are lovers. Doole is a wannabe yuppie: he works for the local representative of major confectionery brands and is doing his best to act the part of a successful businessman who is well aware of global business trends - as he sees them. The monotony of their lives is interrupted by arrival of Igor, who has lived in Huddersfield since the beginning of the nineties, and this is the first time he's come to visit since. They all get together in the evening, and what begins as a cheerful high school reunion party of close friends with a lot of catching up to do, turns into an emotional roller coaster of reminiscing, dark humor, bitterness, uncontrollable laughter, anger, grim soul searching. Through the very personal accounts of their own lives and lives of their high school friends, we get to reveal the ominous mark the final decade of the twentieth century has left on them and their entire generation, and find the answer to the question: do they have the strength to move on?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?226933</url></doc>
