<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="227186">
  <docid>227186</docid>
  <title>Hailey Makes the Boy Bride</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>sissy</keyword>
    <keyword>sex</keyword>
    <keyword>bondage</keyword>
    <keyword>erotica</keyword>
    <keyword>femdom</keyword>
    <keyword>spanking</keyword>
    <keyword>cross-dressing</keyword>
    <keyword>dominatrix</keyword>
    <keyword>domination</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 August 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">119</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Arguilo</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Floyd, Michele</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Arguilo</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Blackwell, Benzo</actor>
      <role>Benny</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lanewood, Louisa</actor>
      <role>Luiza</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Benny, the rich kid from the right side of the tracks, is marrying the sexy, seductive Louisa in two days. His strict upbringing forbids him to be together before he has taken his vows. This sends the frustrated Louisa to find solace in the arms of her roommate, best friend, and secret lover Hailey Young. Hailey is in love with Louisa and desperately wants her to call off the wedding. Unfortunately, Louisa wants more from life than being with Hailey. She plans to go ahead with the story book wedding she has been dreaming about her whole life. Hailey is hired to entertain at Benny's bachelor party. While performing, the masked Hailey Young gets Benny to tell her his deepest, darkest sexual fantasies. Now she has him exactly where she wants him; groveling at her feet. She dresses Benny up in his wife's wedding night lingerie and leaves him on the bed awaiting his fiancé. When Louisa realizes that the person she is about to marry is barely even a man she makes the best of the situation. The story book wedding goes on as planned but Benny is the boy bride who is forced to spend the rest of his life as an all-around sissy.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?227186</url></doc>
