<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="227126">
  <docid>227126</docid>
  <title>Hai xun jian bing</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Chen, Hsiao-tong</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>hazing</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Mandarin</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Taiwan</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Taiwan">6 November 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Taiwan">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Lin, Tom (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Yeh, Ju Fen</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Lin, Tom (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Chen, Singing</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chea, Chang</actor>
      <role>Rookie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cheng, Yu-Chieh</actor>
      <role>Private First Class</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Huang, Chien-wei (II)</actor>
      <role>Private</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Juan, Pinky</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>On the night of March 18th, 2000, the presidential election, as usual, three coastguards are on patrol by the seaside of Yi-Lan. Private First Class, just out of lock-up, is equipped with a walkie-talkie. The Private (second in command) has a military 65-K2 rifle and the Private recruit (rookie) has two clips of ammunition. From the walkie-talkie comes the news that the captain is heading back to base and is done with that nights post checks. Seeing that it's still a long, boring night ahead, The Private starts looking for excuses hazing the rookie. At first, Private First Class doesn't seem to mind too much. Until the trick, "The moon chase" is pulled on the rookie does Private First Class start feeling sympathy towards the rookie. As the hazing turns more ugly, Private First Class urges The Private to stop his immoral actions. The two argue and Private First Class slowly comes to the realization that he too, was once picking on rookies; and he is actually responsible for this unstoppable cycle of pain. When did he become someone he loathes? What can he now do to change it? As the long night comes close to an end, the mysterious seaside woman nicknamed "28" shows up. The Private forces the rookie to have sex with "28" as a rite of passage all soldiers on this coast have gone through. Private First Class steps forward to stop this horrendous act, yet his choice of action may be just as ridiculous and absurd...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?227126</url></doc>
