<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="227347">
  <docid>227347</docid>
  <title>Hajji Washington</title>
  <year>1982</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Persian</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Iran</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Iran">100</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Hatami, Ali</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Diano, Mario</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Entezami, Ezzatolah</actor>
      <role>Hajji Hossein-Gholi Noori</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harrison, Richard (II)</actor>
      <role>President Andrew Johnson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mohammadi, Esmail</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The final version of this film which has not been screened yet, is the story of Hajji Hossein-Gholi Noori, Iran's first ambassador to the United States who went to Washington during the reign of Nasir al-Din Shah Qajar and thus became known as "Hajji Washington." During his one-year stay there, because of the Embassy's slack business and subsequent lack of resources, he is compelled at first to get rid of his servants and then gets personally involved in the case of a Native American who seeks political asylum in the Embassy. The central government recalls him because of his lack of success in carrying out his diplomatic functions while the American Government expels him for giving political asylum to a Native American. Humiliated and dejected, Hajji Washington returns home. Entezami's remarkably strong portrayal of an Iranian Qajar statesman with all the typical characteristics of the period is combined with the particular traits of the personality of Hajji Hossein-Gholi Noori as seen by Ali Hatami and Ezzatollah Entezami.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?227347</url></doc>
