<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="228287">
  <docid>228287</docid>
  <title>Hammer &amp; Tickle</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Cornell, Jules</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>History</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>communism</keyword>
    <keyword>totalitarian-government</keyword>
    <keyword>humor</keyword>
    <keyword>joke</keyword>
    <keyword>fight-for-freedom</keyword>
    <keyword>poland</keyword>
    <keyword>totalitarianism</keyword>
    <keyword>russia</keyword>
    <keyword>berlin-wall</keyword>
    <keyword>eastern-europe</keyword>
    <keyword>east-germany</keyword>
    <keyword>romania</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>France</country>
    <country>Germany</country>
    <country>Canada</country>
    <country>UK</country>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Germany">8 January 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="France">8 January 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">30 April 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">89</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Lewis, Ben (VII)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Pagan, John (I)</producer>
    <producer>Halvorssen, Thor</producer>
    <producer>Lewis, Ben (VII)</producer>
    <producer>O'Doherty, Fiona (II)</producer>
    <producer>Chiari, Luca</producer>
    <producer>Camdessus, Christine</producer>
    <producer>Mallen, Leah</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Lewis, Ben (VII)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Williams, Ken (II)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gorbachev, Mikhail</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Havel, Václav</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jaruzelski, Wojciech</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Medvedev, Roy</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Reagan, Ronald (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Schabowski, Günter</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sodann, Peter</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Walesa, Lech</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>George Orwell wrote that in a repressive political system every joke is a "tiny revolution." Jokes were an essential part of the communist experience because the monopoly of state power meant that any act of non-conformity, down to a simple turn of phrase, could be construed as a form of dissent. By the same token, a joke about any facet of life became a joke about communism. Hammer &amp; Tickle recounts a humorous history of the Soviet Union and its satellite states through the jokes that flourished under the oppressive regimes in Russia and Eastern Europe. Jokes, the film contends, were a language of truth under Communism; a language that allowed people to navigate the disconnect between propaganda and reality and provided a means of resisting the system despite the absence of free speech. Using animated sequences, manipulated archival footage, and sketches to resurrect the jokes, the film offers an ironic take on the history of Communism while simultaneously investigating the social and political impact of jokes under Soviet rule. Interviews with Solidarity leader and former Polish president Lech Walesa, hard-line Polish leader General Jaroszelski, German actor Peter Sodann, German satirist and author Ernst Roehl, East German newspaper editor and Politburo member Guenter Schabowski, and academics Christie Davies and Roy Medvedev address the role that jokes played in challenging and weakening the Communist system from the inside even as joke-tellers faced censure or time in the Gulag for voicing their humor. Light and irreverent in its tone, Hammer &amp; Tickle is really about the ultimate seriousness of joking and the use of the power of laughter to overcome hardship. This history of humor under the Soviet regime offers a direct, incontrovertible way to understand what it was like living in a Communist society, and is also proof that the human spirit can never be broken.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?228287</url></doc>
