<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="229055">
  <docid>229055</docid>
  <title>Hannah Wolfe</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Jung, Jan</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Danish</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Denmark</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Denmark">95</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Jung, Jan</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Jung, Jan</producer>
    <producer>Ravn, Jens (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Jung, Jan</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Højfeldt, Solbjørg</actor>
      <role>Elisabeth Dahlerup</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jensen, Henning (I)</actor>
      <role>Edvard Voldsted</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kaysø, Dick</actor>
      <role>Frank Carlsen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lykkegaard, Henrik</actor>
      <role>Søren Flindt</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>'Hannah Wolfe' struggles to make ends meet. To overcome her unemployment and single motherhood tribulations she takes on odd jobs as private investigator for a local bureau owned by the lazy ex-cop Frank Carlsen. Although she initially detests her next job for the wealthy owner of a posh health spa clinic, she quickly warms to the problems with sabotages against the place and death threats against the husband - a classy plastic surgeon. Although the culprit is easily caught the motives seem clouded. The evasive answers bring her nowhere closer to the truth. When then suddenly the hubby is murdered the chase is on to solve the case before the police. With her prior knowledge from the sabotage case Hannah Wolfe gets a head start. But what she is only told much later is the existence of the mature plastic surgeon's love affair with a much younger model from his vast group of cliental. Matters are complicated by an accidental love interest with the junior police investigator on the case. Creating a split between the much hated police superior and the much younger and less experienced assistant Hannah Wolfe manages to bring herself on the wrong side of the law. By misleading the police and defending the wrong people she ends up getting caught in her own web -- or is it really her own? Nothing is what it looks like and Hannah needs to understand the real motive before she can escape the trap and catch the real killer.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?229055</url></doc>
