<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="229230">
  <docid>229230</docid>
  <title>Hansel &amp; Gretel Rocks in 3D!</title>
  <year>2010</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Musical</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>digit-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>punctuation-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>number-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>3d-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>rock-musical</keyword>
    <keyword>fairy-tale</keyword>
    <keyword>based-on-fairy-tale</keyword>
    <keyword>hansel-and-gretel</keyword>
    <keyword>ampersand-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>exclamation-point-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </countries>
  <producers>
    <producer>Wenders, Wim</producer>
    <producer>Mehlitz, Marco</producer>
    <producer>Sesay, Kira Madallo</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Sesay, Kira Madallo</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Pijnaker, Emiel</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Germany (The Holy Roman Empire) 1635. The Thirty Years War has ravaged the region. Consequently, a dreadful famine is spreading throughout the land. A hardworking woodcutter, his twin teenage children Hansel and Gretel and their stepmother, live in a small cottage in the woods. Although times are extremely harsh, their father does not lose hope. He tries his best to fill his children's cup with love. However, a danger other than food scarcity lurks within their home. Their cold-hearted stepmother sees Hansel &amp; Gretel as unnecessary "dead weight." She believes in order to save herself she must get rid of the children. Without their father's knowledge, she abandons the children in the deepest, darkest part of the Enchanted Forest. When their father discovers the stepmother's treachery, he urgently sets forth into the woods to find them. Hansel and Gretel are truly lost. However, they are not alone. The Enchanted Forest is home to the legendary creatures of German mythology. The siblings are thrown into a fast paced magical adventure.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?229230</url></doc>
