<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="229835">
  <docid>229835</docid>
  <title>Har Har Mahadev</title>
  <year>1974</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Chandrakant (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Chandrakant (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Shah, Anandji Veerji</composer>
    <composer>Shah, Kalyanji Veerji</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhagwan, Master</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhattacharya, Abhi</actor>
      <role>Bhagwan Vishnu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Devi, Sarita</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Devi, Sumitra</actor>
      <role>Sati</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gadkar, Jayshree</actor>
      <role>Devi Parvati</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gopal, V.</actor>
      <role>Nandu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Irani, Aruna</actor>
      <role>Mohini</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khanna, Padma</actor>
      <role>Rati</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Krishna, Gopi</actor>
      <role>Kamdev</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Modak, Shahu</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Polson</actor>
      <role>Nandikesh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Radheshyam (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Raj, Jagdish</actor>
      <role>Tarkasur</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Raje, Babu</actor>
      <role>Narad Muni</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Randhawa</actor>
      <role>Lankeshwar Ravan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Satyajeet</actor>
      <role>Shri Ganesh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sen, Asit (I)</actor>
      <role>Shivji's devotee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Singh, Dara (I)</actor>
      <role>Bhagwan Shiv</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Mahadev Shivji intervenes to stop the warring Bhagwans Shri Brahma and Indra, a feud which started with their respective spouses. Since Shivji is unmarried, both convince him to get married to Devi Maa Sati, which he does. When Satiji's dad, Raja Daksh neglects to invite Shivji to a Yagna, Shivji gets offended resulting in Satiji committing herself to the Holy Fire, leaving Shivji to go into a deep meditation atop the Kailash Parvat. When a demon named Tarkasur starts to terrorize the Devas, and the only way he can be stopped is by a son sired by Shivji, the Devas convince Shivji to get married to Devi Maa Parvati, which he does, and a five-headed son, Kartikeye, is born, who soon slays Tarkasur. Wishing someone to look after her interest Parvatiji creates a son names him Ganesh, to stand guard at her doorstep. Ganeshji even refuses to let Shivji in, and is able to stand up against Brahmaji and Indraji themselves, until finally he is beheaded by Shivji. An enraged Parvatiji asks her husband to bring Ganeshji back to life, which he does albeit with the head of an elephant. Eventually Ganeshji gets married to Narad Muni's sisters, Riddhi and Siddhi, while Kartikeye remains single. Another demon, Mahisasur, terrorizes the Devas and is slain by Parvatiji. Shivji is pleased with Lankeshwar Ravan's devotion (by beheading himself nine times) makes him the most powerful human of all as well restores all ten of his heads. Shivji and Parvatiji face more challenges when Ravan decides to lift Kailash Parvat to prove that he is indeed the strongest human, and the enraged son of Mahisasur, Gajasur, incites Bhagwan Shri Hanuman to battle Ganeshji.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?229835</url></doc>
