<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="229975">
  <docid>229975</docid>
  <title>Hard Choices: Fast Trackers</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Australia">2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Australia">26</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Mayfield, Nathan</producer>
    <producer>Rieckermann, Ralph</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>Short Track ice racing wasn't big news until Stephen Bradbury won Australia's first ever Winter Olympic Gold medal in 2002. Like Bradbury, Alex McEwan, Stephen Lee, Mark McNee and David Reid all dream of winning Gold, but to make the team they will have to draw on their mental toughness as well as their athletic ability. With the new season about to begin a new Australian team will be chosen. Each of the four skaters will have to decide how much he is willing to endure to make the team. Practicing a winter sport in sunny Brisbane brings its own challenges. Limited rink availability means 5am training sessions most days of the week. With little funding or support the skaters struggle to make ends meet, often sacrificing training for work and vise-versa. The skaters are best of friends off the track but they will have to be ruthless with one another as they compete to secure a place in the team. Alex finds himself battling to hold his number one spot against his rival Mark but first Mark must overcome a serious knee injury. Stephen Lee's frustration increases when his great form at the 2002 Olympics continues to elude him. Work demands and self-confidence flout David's efforts as he struggles to keep up with training. Beside them through their struggles, is coach Ann Zhang. With limited resources and support Ann is determined to keep her athletes on track. Her hopes are pinned on their success, but she must also oversee grueling 'time trials'; the measure by which her athletes success or failure will be determined. But it's not all bleak. A spectacular sport to watch, there are small victories along the way as each skater's resolve is tested, in his quest to make the World Championship team.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?229975</url></doc>
