<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="229977">
  <docid>229977</docid>
  <title>Hard Choices: Unchain My Heart</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Australia">2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Australia">26</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Mullins, Anthony (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Mayfield, Nathan</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Mullins, Anthony (II)</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Htoo Htoo is a Burmese freedom fighter who, after being imprisoned and tortured for three years in a military jail, has escaped to Australia and started a new life. He has been granted citizenship and started a family with his partner Xang who is from Thailand. For the first time he can have a life of peace and freedom. Despite this, Htoo Htoo is still not free. His heart and mind are still troubled by Burma's continued oppression. So much so that he will risk everything to help his people to freedom. Htoo Htoo wants to raise awareness in Australia about Burma's plight. To attract media attention he plans to publicly chain himself in heavy leg irons for a month, just as he was chained for seven long months in prison. He hopes it will encourage the Australian government to impose economic sanctions against the dictatorship. But there's a problem. Htoo Htoo's radical campaign, if it is successful, may see his family in Burma jailed as subversives. Not only that but his new family in Australia are struggling to understand his one-man campaign to free Burma. With the strain of nursing their new-born son Xang wonders why Htoo Htoo isn't more focussed on his family duties here. The problem seems to be is that he is struggling to live in two worlds; one free, the other in chains. This is a story about the personal sacrifices one man is prepared to make to continue his country's struggle for freedom.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?229977</url></doc>
