<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="231899">
  <docid>231899</docid>
  <title>Have You Seen Clem</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>homelessness</keyword>
    <keyword>consumerism</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="France">16 May 2005</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">26 January 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Lyttle, Erich</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>TeJumson, Anthony Hong</producer>
    <producer>Wilkins, Dan</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bruno, Danny</actor>
      <role>Bruno</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jamieson, Kris</actor>
      <role>Jaymo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lozito, Tony</actor>
      <role>Tony</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Weredail, Clem</actor>
      <role>Clem</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Despite living in one of the most affluent countries in the world, millions of people in the United States live in poverty, and hundreds of thousands are homeless. Jaymo, an aspiring filmmaker, suddenly finds himself homeless and living out of his car. Desperate to find his way out, he begins shooting a documentary about the overlooked homeless people in this sharply divided society. When he meets a mysterious bum named Clem, Jaymo realizes that every homeless person has a cart full of secrets and a unique story of personal collapse to tell. Together they embark on a classic American road trip to different cities to meet and understand more about the forgotten homeless people that struggle to live on and find contentment on the streets of America. Their eye-opening journey through the supposedly glamorous United States culminates in Nashville, where Clem seeks his ultimate revenge against the unscrupulous banker that caused his fall from grace. The soundtrack is a riveting mix of original songs performed entirely by the street musicians that the filmmakers meet as they traveled across America.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?231899</url></doc>
