<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="232130">
  <docid>232130</docid>
  <title>Hawkeye's Night Stories</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Hawkeye (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>black-and-white</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Unrated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">3 August 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">80</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Hawkeye (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Fiddleman, Laurie</producer>
    <producer>Hawkeye (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Hawkeye (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Hawkeye (II)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fiddleman, Gerry</actor>
      <role>Various</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fiddleman, Laurie</actor>
      <role>Various</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hawkeye (II)</actor>
      <role>Various</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The five short films included in this collection are... "THE SHINEY" - This is a "Bonus" episode! Originally filmed in late 2004, early 2005! It was originally planned to be the first episode of the "Night Stories" series. It was held back in favor of releasing "Some Thing" as the first episode. After review and a bit of re-editing we have decided to release this as a bonus episode in the series! It contains some fantastic videography from HAWKEYE! Thrilling winter imagery! A juxtaposition of exterior footage creating a genuine claustrophobic mood! A "must have" episode for all the collectors out there! "SOME THING" - Stan Richards is an independent filmmaker... Who moved to the country with his lovely wife Chrissy. He thought the peace &amp; quiet would do him good... At first the peace &amp; quiet was a little TOO peaceful &amp; quiet... Then SOME THING came knocking! Would all of his years of movie watching and screenplay writing help him with his uninvited guest? You'll See!... "THE VISITOR" - Just how well do you know who you think you know?! This episode starts off with a rather explosive beginning! Signaling the start of a cat &amp; mouse game that keeps both the characters AND the viewers guessing right up to the end with an exciting twist! Who is the cat? And who is the mouse? You'll definitely have fun all the way through! Be prepared for a surprise! "LIFE ON A STRING" - Billy Childress has just begun a journey through what some may call a mid-life crisis. Laid up with a sprained knee from his usual touch football game with his buddies, he begins to wallow in a bit of self-pity... His moans and groans both frustrate his loving wife Tammy, as well as worry her. While shopping at a remarkable estate sale she is offered something that on the surface seems like a simple gift for her husband, something to lift his bruised spirits... Billy discovers something a bit more about this simple gift! Something that may just change his whole outlook on life! Something that may change your's as well! "CREATIVE WRITING" - Martin Wordsworth is a writer... A struggling writer who is facing the age-old problem of "writer's block". At the suggestion of his wife, he decides to apply a new method to his writing... In the form of a very special little item. A curious little item that even surprises Martin with what it can do! After a while Martin hits on an idea that could and would change his life forever! In ways he could never imagine! As the old saying goes... "Be Careful What You Put In Writing!"</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?232130</url></doc>
