<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="233394">
  <docid>233394</docid>
  <title>Heartlines</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Meyburgh, Catherine</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Sotho</language>
    <language>Zulu</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>South Africa</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="South Africa">November 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">95</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Gibson, Angus</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Gavshon, Harriet</producer>
    <producer>Jammy, David</producer>
    <producer>Pretorius, Mariki</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Gibson, Angus</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Miller, Philip (IV)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kgoroge, S'Thandiwe</actor>
      <role>Thando</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mabaso, Mduduzi</actor>
      <role>Manyisa</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Molepo, Mpho</actor>
      <role>Pastor Jacob</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ngema, Mbongeni</actor>
      <role>Bra Stone</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tshabalala, Thabo</actor>
      <role>Sibusiso</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>After serving a jail sentence for theft, Manyisa, a young man with a cruel past and an uncertain future, is released. He is offered a new chance at life by a well-meaning pastor, Jacob Musi. Manyisa, firm in the belief that no-one ever gives without expecting something in return, is suspicious of Jacob's generosity. Life has taught Manyisa not to trust anyone... Despite his best efforts, Manyisa is seduced by the friendship offered by Jacob's young son, S'bu. But his attempt at a new life is threatened by the reappearance of two old acquaintances, who have traced him to the pastor's house. They bring him the message that his old guardian, Bra Stone, a crime-lord in the township of Alexandra, demands that he returns to him. Meanwhile, Jacob must grapple with the revelation that Bra Stone was responsible for the death of his younger brother, Elias, a few years previously. The burden of this knowledge is deepened by his growing suspicion that Manyisa was involved in the murder. Jacob and Manyisa must learn that the journey to redemption is not without pain.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?233394</url></doc>
