<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="234646">
  <docid>234646</docid>
  <title>Helen Lundeberg: American Painter</title>
  <year>1988</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">15 June 1988</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">56</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Amodeo, John</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Tobey, Moss</producer>
    <producer>Boles, Tom</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lundeberg</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>From her childhood and early education in Pasadena to enrollment in the Stickney Memorial School of Art in 1930, this documentary follows Helen Lundeberg through her co-founding (with Lorser Feitelson) of Post-Surrealism in 1934, her experiences in running an art gallery on Hollywood Boulevard, her work with the Federal Arts Project (mural and print divisions) from 1936 to 1942, her return to the easel in the 1940s (after the war and her 'war work') and her development through her work of the 1950s to the 1980s. As the narrative focuses upon the artist, another narrative is taking place. The history of the period becomes alive through her involvement in the programs and the people. When working on a mural of the Fullerton, California Civic Center she relates: "I was the only one of my crew, including about four or five men, who had a driver's license so I was elected to drive the truck to the mural site...until some busy-body said WHAT IS A WOMAN DOING DRIVING THAT TRUCK! So that was the end of my career as a truck driver!" "After the Federal Arts Project murals, I wanted to do works that I could hold in my hands... that only I would touch." During the decade of the 1940s, with the closing of the WPA/FAP, Lundeberg executed a group of small 'mood entity' paintings that are 'jewels'. The camera carries the viewer from Lundeberg's studio of 1987 back to 1912 family snapshots in Pasadena, to Hollywood Boulevard of the 1930s, through to the 1970s. Throughout this story, Helen Lundeberg's paintings reveal the creative powers and the aesthetic of her evolution as one of America's foremost artists. Lundeberg discusses her techniques, her philosophies, her themes, her fears and her goals. The viewer emphasizes, shares and learns. This project documents the work of a great artist and, simultaneously, documents a period in American art history as directly experienced by a participant. Helen Lundeberg died in Los Angeles, California on April 19, 1999.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?234646</url></doc>
