<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="236918">
  <docid>236918</docid>
  <title>Heretics</title>
  <year>2010</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>History</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>one-word-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">12 March 2010</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Taulère, Patrick</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>François, Anne</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Calvetti, Michel</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>1243, the South of France. After more than twenty years as a Knight Templar in the Holy Land, Ronan returns to Europe in search of redemption. Drained by the atrocities committed in the name of God, he now longs to a meditative and non violent life. Yet, when he saves two enigmatic children from the claws of the King's soldiers, he finds himself embroiled in a new religious war, the first of its kind between Christians, the Crusade against the Cathars. Hunted down by the merciless Crusader Guy of Lévis, Ronan decides to lead the children to Montsegur, the last Cathar stronghold still defying the authority of the Roman Pope and the French King. In this eagle's nest in the heart of the Pyrenees mountains, he discovers the strange heretics. First uneasy around these dark mystics, keepers of ancient secrets, he is rapidly seduced by their open mindedness and peaceful asceticism. His inner confusion deepens further when a proud and pure Cathar woman, Isabel, enters his life. Despite their religious obligations, a shy and ill-fated bond is forged between them as war looms above the land. When the Crusaders attack the castle, for what will be one of the longest siege in history, Ronan strives to protect the children and help the Cathars in their resistance against persecution. He embarks in a journey where treason, love, ferocious ambushes and deadly conspiracies will test his resolve and vows of non violence. He will unveil clues about the real identity of the two children and the mysterious Cathar Treasure that seems to obsess the Papacy. A unforgiving trip that might be the only way to heal his recurrent nightmares and give a new meaning to his life. A tale of honor and love told through the eyes of Isabel, a symbol of hope in a world crushed by religious intolerance.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?236918</url></doc>
