<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="237481">
  <docid>237481</docid>
  <title>Herz ohne Krone</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Hutter, Michou</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>German</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Germany">26 May 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Germany">95</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Patzak, Peter (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Paunescu, Vlad</producer>
    <producer>Pucker, Walter</producer>
    <producer>Esche, Matthias</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Piazza, Barbara</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Banzaru, Radu</actor>
      <role>Journalist</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Berg, Birte</actor>
      <role>Melanie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bloéb, Gregor</actor>
      <role>Phillip</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Breuer, Jacques</actor>
      <role>Adam</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brigliadori, Eleonora</actor>
      <role>Linda Marco</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>De Torrebruna, Riccardo</actor>
      <role>Mr. Sinclair</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Giegerich, Karin</actor>
      <role>Emile</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Iacob, Cristian (I)</actor>
      <role>Kameramann</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moraru, Petre</actor>
      <role>Minister #1</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nero, Franco</actor>
      <role>Bear's Trainer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nitu, Gelu</actor>
      <role>Minister #2</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Petrof, Boris</actor>
      <role>Museumsleiter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Popa, Razvan</actor>
      <role>Moderator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Popescu, Valentin</actor>
      <role>Minister #3</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tappert, Horst</actor>
      <role>Rudolph der Listige</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Trandafir, Claudiu</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This comedy is set in the tiny and fictitious state of Sachenia, located close to the Alps. The sleepy and provincial region has magnificent landscape and beautiful old buildings, and is one of Central Europe's best kept secrets. The hero of this cheerful and ironical story is Rudolph VIII, the last regent of the tiny state, who was forced to abdicate several years beforehand. He still proudly wears his royal title even though his kingdom has become increasingly tinier over the years, and is now little more than a city state. Rudolph lives in exile. Rather than choosing some faraway place to live, he decided to reside just beyond the borders of his country. On sunny days, from the hills in his grounds and on rainy days from his tower window through a telescope, he can see the little state's busy market place, and also his former castle. Sometimes catches glimpses of his arch enemy: a journalist named Linda Marco, the woman who, wrote him out of power. She had accused him in the press of being out of touch, a 70 year old man stands for the past, not the future, and this had impressed the populace so much that Rudolph was forced to leave his country and go into exile, something he has never forgiven Linda Marco for. Rudolph has a loyal secretary: Adam Severin, a doctor of history, who looks after Rudolph's correspondence and also administers the ex king's substantial art collections. But without King Rudolph in power, a scandal suddenly threatens to erupt in Sachenia. The people are furious when they realize that several if not all of their ministers are embroiled in a massive corruption scam, a plan to turn the tiny state into a gambling centre in the style of Las Vegas, and also into a tax haven. As television's face and voice of Sachenia, the journalist Linda Marco is on the scene instantly. Rudolph is unaware of all the fuss in Sachenia because he makes a point of never reading or watching any news that is even remotely related to the place. It gradually becomes clear that almost all the MPs in the Sachenian parliament have become embroiled in the scandal, which is assuming ever larger dimensions. Even the spirited Linda Marco is affected by the scandalous goings on, albeit indirectly: her boyfriend Philipp is one of the corrupt organizers of the scam. When she realizes he has been tricking her and has simply used her for his own ends, she is so shocked that she walks out on him. A short while later Rudolph's manservant announces an unexpected visitor: Linda Marco. Rudolph is quite astonished, but even though he is curious to know what has driven Linda Marco to come and see him, he decides not to see her. Linda Marco doesn't give up that easily, however. Using a ladder, she climbs up resolutely onto the balcony of Rudolph's room and makes it quite clear to the stunned ex regent that he must not, on any account, return to power. She begs him to see reason, he represents the past and not the present, and must not allow himself to be swayed. Rudolph asks Adam to send her away, but shortly afterwards he suddenly gets a visit from a Sachenian deputation: a vote has been taken in the tiny state and four fifths of the population want him back as their king! Rudolph is of course delighted. What can he do but accept? He doesn't realize that he is letting himself in for a great more than he bargained for. Linda is very annoyed at the people's decision. She refers to it as a forward into the past attitude. But she is powerless to do anything but wait until Rudolph makes his first mistakes. She loves her country deeply too, just like Rudolph, but wants to save it from misrule at all costs. One day Rudolph suddenly has an idea: he decides to enlist Linda as a helper of his cause rather than treat her as an enemy. She is utterly surprised at his offer of a deal. But her love of Sachenia wins out over her dislike of the old king, and she agrees to help him. They decide to battle the forces of corruption together. Meanwhile, the conspirators are gathering in Chicago. Melanie von Auerfeld, an ex mistress of Rudolph, who married an American gangster, is working together with a mafia gang and several of the corrupt Sachenian ministers to turn Sachenia into one enormous Las Vegas style gambling and amusement centre. Philipp, Linda Marco's ex boyfriend, is also part of her team. Melanie is very upset, and her Sachenian visitors are very embarrassed, to hear that the monarchy is being restored. Melanie von Auerfeld now realizes there is only one way out. She and her son Harry set off for Sachenia immediately. At first it is unclear what her real objective is, but when it transpires that she was Rudolph's former mistress and is eager to get her Harry to succeed Rudolph to the throne of Sachenia, the situation becomes very dangerous for the old king. An unexpected and unwelcome visitor, Melanie settles into Rudolph's castle and from then on does all she can to bring about his downfall so that she can capitalize on it. Several adventures ensue, during which the king and Linda Marco grow increasingly fond of each other and, together with Adam, do their best to defeat Melanie and her evil plans.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?237481</url></doc>
