<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="238649">
  <docid>238649</docid>
  <title>Hiding and Seeking: Faith and Tolerance After the Holocaust</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Greenstein, Zelda</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>religion</keyword>
    <keyword>holocaust</keyword>
    <keyword>jewish</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Yiddish</language>
    <language>Polish</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Unrated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Poland">25 April 2004</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">30 August 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Daum, Menachem</director>
    <director>Rudavsky, Oren</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Haas, Ari</producer>
    <producer>Semp, Rochel</producer>
    <producer>Shubowitz, Devorah</producer>
    <producer>Nix, Melissa Kathleen</producer>
    <producer>Dornbaum, Martin</producer>
    <producer>Daum, Menachem</producer>
    <producer>Rudavsky, Oren</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Daum, Menachem</writer>
    <writer>Rudavsky, Oren</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Zorn, John</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Daum, Akiva</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Daum, Menachem</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Daum, Rifka</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Daum, Tzvi Dovid</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Menachem Daum, the son of holocaust survivors, and a New York Orthodox Jew worries that both of his sons, full time yeshiva students who live with their families in Israel, are becoming seduced to intolerance by their religious studies. "All religions today are in danger of being hijacked by extremists." To open their perspectives just a little he sets off with his wife, Rifka, and both sons, Tzvi Dovid and Akiva, to visit the Polish towns where his parents grew up and to try to find the Catholic farmers who hid his father-in-law from the Germans. Enduring the bemused tolerance of his sons, Menachem persists until they find Honorata Matuszezyk Mucha who as a young woman brought food nightly to Rifka's father and his two brothers for 28 months until the end of World War II. The Daum sons perspectives widen a bit to allow for good Gentiles, but they also encounter some resentment from the Poles who heard no word from the three brothers after they left their hiding place, not even a postcard with a thank you. A lot of issues are surfaced but left unresolved in this well crafted documentary.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?238649</url></doc>
