<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="239125">
  <docid>239125</docid>
  <title>High, Fast and Wonderful</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Galvin, Maryanne</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>circus-performer</keyword>
    <keyword>migrant-worker</keyword>
    <keyword>racecar-driver</keyword>
    <keyword>spirituality</keyword>
    <keyword>lapsed-catholic</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">10 August 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">43</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Galvin, Maryanne</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Mulligan, Joe (I)</producer>
    <producer>Galvin, Maryanne</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Galvin, Maryanne</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Herbert, Tom (III)</composer>
    <composer>Lay, Jon</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Charlotte, Hobelman Sister</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hobelman, Charlotte</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Phil, DeRea fr.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Is it really possible to distance oneself from the physical realities of death and still expect to enjoy the physical wonders of life? Filmmaker Maryanne Galvin found herself in the vortex of life's downside: two cancer surgeries in 6 months; laid off one job and facing uncertainty about future employment; another 40 something birthday and the sense of time moving swiftly; and the sudden death of dear friend. In a very vulnerable emotional state, Galvin contemplated joining the circus but quickly realized she had no marketable skill to offer that venue. Instead, she focused her energy on an unsuspecting Catholic priest, Fr. Gerry Hogan, The National Circus Chaplain, and decided he'd make a fine subject for her next film. This turned out to be an emotional watershed. Galvin, a "lapsed Catholic" then sought solace in her faith-but in the most unlikely places: amongst Circus clowns, champion race car drivers and civil war refugees on Nantucket Island. Under the protective wing of her omnipotent narrator, an animated dove, Galvin embarks on a whirlwind sojourn in search of meaning, connection and a renewal of faith. So many people (not just Catholics) are experiencing crisis of faith due to the tremendous advancements in technology over the past century-which have primarily occurred within a spiritual vacuum. As a culture, Westerners have developed a large and dangerous "sink hole" having evolved so much faster technically than spiritually. The film explores how certain individuals in some very unusual places rekindle their faith and fend off both the fear of falling deeper into a void of egoism and material idolatry and the slow spiritual death awaiting most of humanity. Approached from a Western Judeo-Christian angle but minus religious overtone, "High, Fast and Wonderful" explores the personal, cultural and spiritual ramifications of seeking comfort in the face of life's tragedies-within the dysfunctional family of the Catholic Church. There are no miracles, sermons, or evangelical revelations--it's just pure Galvin relating her discourses about life's twists and turns. Taking us inside the lives of four highly unique clergy and their flocks, the film explores the many issues these extraordinary individuals face in their respective communities. The official "tour guide" through this vast hinterland of spirituality is Sister Charlotte Hobelman, a diminutive Sister of Notre Dame stationed at the Office for the Pastoral Care of Migrants and Refugees with the US Catholic Conference of Bishops in Washington D.C. Sr. Charlotte coordinates the mission aptly titled, "People on the Move", creating a "world where immigrants, refugees, migrants and people on the move are treated with dignity, respect, welcome and belonging." Under her aegis are: Fr. Gerry Hogan, The National Circus Chaplain, Fr. Phil DeRea, CART Ministries and Fr. Richard Wilson, Pastoral Care for Immigrants on Nantucket Island. Each sustain the Catholic Church's long tradition of promoting and defending the human rights and dignity of people on the move, advocating social remedies to their problems and fostering opportunities for their spiritual growth. In depth interviews with individuals in their flocks-Grandma, the "Jewish Disciple" at the Big Apple Circus recounts the ambiguous role of spirituality among itinerant circus performers, giving a nod to pluralism and Fr. Gerry's role in breaking down stereotypes. Ringling's daredevil clown, Bello Knock recognizes his father's passing as a deeply spiritual moment shared with the circus community largely due to Fr. Gerry's unique "ministry of presence." Fr. Phil's ministry exposes the wonder and precariousness of tending to spiritual needs of Champion CART Race car drivers, including driver Dario Franchetti's revelation about his scariest moment (it had nothing to do with high speeds but everything to do with wife Ashley Judd). The complexities of tending to recent immigrants, migrants and refugees in post 9-11 America compels Fr. Richard Wilson to reach out to a marginalized Hispanic community on Nantucket Island, MA. From the travails of the homeless El Salvadoran man who finds refuge in an abandoned car on Main Street until a local family "adopts" him to the thriving community with old world values merged seamlessly with new world technology and lifestyle. High, Fast and Wonderful offers a multi layered saga- an interior as well as surface odyssey via a compilation of intimate yet extemporaneous interviews, rare archival footage, photo montage, and footage shot at death defying heights and speeds and unique animation. The original musical score by Berklee graduate, Jon Lay, highlights the punchy narration by Boston Magazine writer and WTKK-FM host, Annie Copps.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?239125</url></doc>
