<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="239955">
  <docid>239955</docid>
  <title>Hip Hop Street Credentials</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Garton, Gabriel</editor>
    <editor>Torres, Anthony (IV)</editor>
    <editor>Vasquetelle, Israel</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>musician</keyword>
    <keyword>singing</keyword>
    <keyword>hip-hop</keyword>
    <keyword>singer</keyword>
    <keyword>song</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">18 May 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">53</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Samuel, Tony</director>
    <director>Vasquetelle, Israel</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Jenkins, Thomas</producer>
    <producer>Vasquetelle, Israel</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Iz-Real</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Aesop Rock</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Iz-Real</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Keith, Kool</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kirkland, Pee Wee</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kurt, Kutmasta</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Paperview</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pen, Poison</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sir-fa, Silva</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Technique, Immortal</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Williams, Saul</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Street Credentials is a pass to an up-front and personal perspective into the underground Hip Hop scene directly from some of the most unique and diverse personalities in the industry today. From Hip Hop's most outrageous icon, Kool Keith; to the multifaceted and introspective recording artist, spoken word poet, and movie actor, Saul Williams (SLAM, K-PAX); to underground superstar Aesop Rock, they're here. Street Credentials pulls no punches while delivering hard insight into the industry, culture and the careers of some of the most interesting people within the genre. Enter the world of Harlem's Immortal Technique, Hip Hop's most dangerous Emcee. Get insight into the history of New York City's Mixtape game with veteran DJ Silva Sir-Fa. Check out the inside track on running an independent record label from KutMasta Kurt (producer of remixes for Linkin Park and The Beastie Boys). O.G., street basketball legend, and former MTV reality host, Pee Wee Kirkland breaks down his take on the state of the rap industry. While on the streets of Brooklyn, freestyle champ Poison Pen reveals the life of a battle emcee. This is a look at Hip Hop from a purist, independent and entrepreneurial angle. This DVD release continues the decade-long Insomniac tradition of revealing the true and many times unheard ideologies about success, obstacles, and life within the Hip Hop music industry directly from personalities that have all earned their Hip Hop Street Credentials.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?239955</url></doc>
