<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="240497">
  <docid>240497</docid>
  <title>His Highness the Wheel</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Tabakovic, Mirsad</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Serbo-Croatian</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Bosnia and Herzegovina</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Bosnia-Herzegovina">7 August 2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">24</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Panjeta, Lejla</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Panjeta, Lejla</producer>
    <producer>Sahinovic, Almir</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Panjeta, Lejla</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>In Sarajevo, in 2000 Mr. Mato Radman invented the Boomerang Wheel and its rotation in the experiment refuted Einstein's and Newton's laws on which the whole modern physics is based. Mato deals with the problem of wheels from his early childhood. In his working opus he has hundreds of handmade wheels for different applications and several awards for his inventions on the world level. While making experiments to find the wheel flexibility and trying to improve the wheel structure, which has not been changed from antique period up today, Mato reached the elastic wheel. By its improvement the Boomerang Wheel was made, which refutes the formula E=mc2 and F=ma. This means that for the moment of rotation the mass is not any more primary, which also means that energy does not depend on mass, as Einstein and Newton say. This invention changes scientific postulates, modern physics and improves the civilization offering its boundless application of energetic potential. Mato did not realize his invention by pure chance. Behind the Boomerang Wheel years of continuous and hard work stand and they were not interrupted even during the war in BiH nor in the post war period in which Mato has not material conditions for work, except his bedroom where his ideas are born, the living room where he makes the sketches of wheels and where he makes his inventions. Nevertheless, Mato's persistence and brilliancy overcome cruel life conditions and rise high to the world level and even above it. The Boomerang Wheel is not technical civilization invention but the child of Nature and dedication of human spirit in making a Cosmos a better place to live. Mato's invention, His Highness the Wheel, comes to us from another world.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?240497</url></doc>
