<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="241523">
  <docid>241523</docid>
  <title>History of Advertising: General (1930-1950)</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Reid, Scott (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>History</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>calendar</keyword>
    <keyword>advertisement</keyword>
    <keyword>batteries</keyword>
    <keyword>automobile</keyword>
    <keyword>black-&amp;-white-to-color</keyword>
    <keyword>coffee</keyword>
    <keyword>color</keyword>
    <keyword>jam</keyword>
    <keyword>technology</keyword>
    <keyword>general</keyword>
    <keyword>usa</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">11 November 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">117</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Reid, Scott (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Calendar, Bart</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Chauhan, Manish</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Nobody likes to admit it - but we all love advertising. Yet in this modern age so much advertising effort is put into television and the Internet. Back before the days of high technology advertisers had to be much more creative when looking for ways to make their message stand out! The two disk set History of Advertising - General 1930-1940 shows you the myriad of creative ways advertising agencies used to sell their products including: Sky writing- Billboard advertisements- Short films- Electric signs. Imagine being an advertising executive at the heart of the Great Depression - the worst economic cycle in American history. Most people did not have any spare cash. It was virtually impossible to get people to spend money! Yet, unless admen wanted to find themselves on the unemployment line they had to find a way. A complete track by track list of the interesting topics on the disk includes: Nonesuch Coffee- Behind the Bright Lights- Sky Billboards- Time Savers for House Makers- Film Mystery, A (Dreft Screen Ad)- For Good Living (Brown Derby Beer Promo)- True Experience of Officer Harold Sewell, The- To Market, To Market (Part I)- To Market, To Market (Part II)- Curtis-Wright Shorts (7 Subjects)- An Old Chinese Proverb: One Picture Is Worth Ten Thousand Words. The DVDs work on any zone DVD player. The disks come with a 30 day money back guarantee and ship in traditional Amaray style DVD cases. The footage on the disks has been expertly restored and preserved in the digital format.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?241523</url></doc>
