<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="242163">
  <docid>242163</docid>
  <title>Ho Jaata Hai Pyaar</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Khan, Basit</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Agarwal, Rajesh (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Singh, Uttam</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Agnihotri, Rati</actor>
      <role>Asha B. Roy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Aleeza</actor>
      <role>Suman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Banerjee, Beena</actor>
      <role>Kamla</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dhawan, Anil (I)</actor>
      <role>K.K.</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ghai, Gaurav</actor>
      <role>Rajesh 'Raj' R. Kapoor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jeetendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Ravi Kapoor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Razak</actor>
      <role>Rajesh's assistant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Kiran (I)</actor>
      <role>Balwant Roy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Singh, Ambakshay</actor>
      <role>Ajay</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Businessman and widower, Ravi Kapoor, lives a very wealthy lifestyle in India along with his school-going son, Rajesh. When the business expands, both father and son re-locate abroad, leaving behind Rajesh's childhood sweetheart, Anjali Roy, virtually heartbroken. Ravi lets his employee, K.K., who lives a wealthy lifestyle also with his wife, Kamla, and daughter, Suman, handle the business in India. Years later, Rajesh has matured, and both he and his dad come to India for a visit. Rajesh's attempts to locate Anjali are in vain, and his dad and K.K., unknowingly arrange his marriage with Suman. Eventually both Suman and Rajesh fall in love with each other, leaving Suman's admirer, Ajay, devastated. Then Anjali re-enters Rajesh's life and the two re-kindle their friendship and also plan to get married with the blessings of their respective families. Then all of a sudden Anjali refuses to meet with Rajesh nor return his phone calls. Neither Rajesh nor Anjali know that if even they were fated to meet, their wedding cannot for reason(s) only known to Anjali's mom, Asha.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?242163</url></doc>
