<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="243198">
  <docid>243198</docid>
  <title>Hollywood Desperado: Rebel or Royalty</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>screaming-with-excitement</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">118</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Monroy, Jaime</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Aldridge, Kristen</producer>
    <producer>Monroy, Jaime</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Monroy, Jaime</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Aldridge, Kristen</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barrilla, Barnaby</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bernstein, Jay (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Checkor, Norman</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dark, Johnny</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Federman, Wayne</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gibbs, Marla</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grant, John (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Guerrero, Daniel (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Horvitz, Louis J.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hutcherson, Jarvee</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lowe, Skip E.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Macari, Sonya</actor>
      <role>As Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Marcucci, Robert</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Marcucci, Robert P.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Marrero, Ace</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Muscat, Mike</actor>
      <role>Himself / Announcer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nelson, Keith S.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Reyes, Luis (XIII)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rich, Allan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shore, Sammy</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Smith, Frazer</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tuna, Charlie</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Velasco, Jerry</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Velasco, Jerry G.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wayne, Jeff (IV)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Hollywood Desperado: Rebel or Royalty is an inspirational true story of Jaime Monroy, who, like most of us, has a dream. Struggling to fit in, he becomes determined to stand out! As a street smart fearless kid from the barrio of East Los Angeles, he uses his head and heart to seek fame and fortune in the bright lights of Hollywood. This Latino boy next door makes his own breaks at age 16 by day, handing out tickets to television show tapings in front of Hollywood's Grauman's Chinese Theatre. By early evening, parking cars for legendary comedians at the Friar's Club in Beverly Hills, and late at night, answering phones and separating the mail for Hollywood Screen Legend Mae West. Still under age, he paints in a mustache as a disguise to emcee at the Playboy Club, while Playboy bunnies protect the young teen comedian from drunk hecklers. Jaime Monroy cultivates a style to do ordinary things in an extraordinary way. He knows what he wants and goes for it with an all or nothing conviction and relentless energy, taking the audience as a passenger on a roller-coaster ride of risks, excitement, and disappointments. He becomes a west-coast Olympic prospect in the decathlon, then, because of the Iran hostage crisis, President Jimmy Carter boycotts the 1980 summer Olympics. While touring as a top opening act comedian, Jaime thinks he's been discovered as a sitcom star and is signed by Hollywood power players, but to his surprise, he is marketed as America's next teen idol. "But I'm a comedian, not a singer", yells Jaime Monroy, as he's pushed out on stage in front of hundreds of screaming girls. During a Hollywood Writer's Strike, struggling to make money, he gets and idea! Using his foresight and showmanship, he screen prints on t-shirts out of his garage and becomes a million dollar marketing man and patented inventor, then comes face to face with the 1992 L.A. riots as it burns millions to the ground. Having lost it all - money, a shot at stardom, feeling like giving up, Hollywood Desperado: Rebel or Royalty features Jaime Monroy's phoenix-like power to re-create himself from ashes. Making all audiences laugh and Latinos proud, Jaime Monroy has had his share of misfortunes and career success. Filled with laughter, tears, struggle, but most of all faith, this insightful, revealing, heart-warming, funny and inspiring documentary - part stand-up comedy, part self-help - traces the journey of this multi-talented young man. Jaime Monroy has an unshakable shining spirit of optimism and hope, keeping this persevering underdog on target to get the job done and succeed.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?243198</url></doc>
