<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="244095">
  <docid>244095</docid>
  <title>Home of Strangers</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Saville, Geoff</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>gangster</keyword>
    <keyword>cross-cultural</keyword>
    <keyword>asian</keyword>
    <keyword>family-relationships</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Australia">19 August 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Nguyen, Doan (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Seamons, Owen</producer>
    <producer>Nguyen, Doan (II)</producer>
    <producer>Seamons, Owen</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Nguyen, Doan (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Korr, Lance</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ada, Steve</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Huynh, Jimmy</actor>
      <role>Benjamin</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A story of three individuals whose unique paths cross unexpectedly, and who are lead on a journey to resolve their own personal conflicts and learn about the importance of relationship. Ben is a young Vietnamese Californian gangster. He escapes the unfullfillable demands and violence of a criminal life and flees to Brisbane. In this quiet town, Ben is offered a friendship, a lover and a family. Ben soon realises that he cannot outrun his past as the Dean, the gang's leader comes to reclaim his most prized asset. The young and innocent Vietnamese girl Lien is placed out of her comfort zone as she travels to Australia to attend university and make her family proud. But her experiences are far from what she anticipated, and she must keep the reality of her situation from her parents. Chavonne has just left one of her many relationships. She dreams of one day finding genuine love. She shoulders the weight of responsibility at home, looking after her younger sister and alcoholic father after the death of her mother. Audiences will be captivated as the lives of these three people become entangled, up until its dramatic conclusion.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?244095</url></doc>
