<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="245853">
  <docid>245853</docid>
  <title>Horse</title>
  <year>2010</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>ex-marine</keyword>
    <keyword>drug</keyword>
    <keyword>undercover-agent</keyword>
    <keyword>drug-cartel</keyword>
    <keyword>taliban</keyword>
    <keyword>drug-lord</keyword>
    <keyword>soldier</keyword>
    <keyword>fbi-agent</keyword>
    <keyword>animal-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>heroin</keyword>
    <keyword>american-soldier</keyword>
    <keyword>immigrant</keyword>
    <keyword>one-word-title</keyword>
    <keyword>albuquerque-new-mexico</keyword>
    <keyword>sergeant</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Malkin, Laurence</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Duncan, Tai</producer>
    <producer>Korenberg, Rosanne</producer>
    <producer>Malkin, Laurence</producer>
    <producer>Schiff, Paul</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Malkin, Laurence</writer>
    <writer>Thumann, Chad</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barraza, Adriana</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Guzmán, Luis (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Luna, Diego (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Martinez, Benito (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Sergeant Thompson takes his life in his hands when he disobeys a direct order to save four innocent Afghani children from an imminent air strike, designed to destroy an opium field. As the deadly poison rains from the sky, Thompson grabs the children, bundling them into a nearby cave where he comes face to face with a platoon of hardcore Taliban soldiers. Having saved the lives of their children, the stony faced men are honor bound to let him go, handing him a brick of heroin resin as his 'reward'. Thompson is sent home. Albuquerque, New Mexico: in desperate need of cash, Thompson has to decide what to do with his new found stash of drugs. Does he hand it in to his heartless superiors, or try to get it into the hands of a drug lord known to one of his fallen comrades, who goes by the name 'The Cook'? Calvin is after the same man. In the guise of a heroin addict, he's actually an undercover FBI agent and ex-US Marine, who's determined to catch the leader of the most violent and deadly cartel he's ever come across, if it's the last thing he does. Across town, a young immigrant from El Salvador is working as a short order chef in a low rent Mexican restaurant. Carlos is a quiet, unassuming man, who lives at home with his domineering mother, and who puts his heart and soul in to the preparation of his beloved cuisine that's when he's not taking murderous and bloody revenge on his enemies in his secret life as the deeply troubled, lethal drug baron known as 'THE COOK'. Very soon, Thompson and Calvin cross paths, and a tense partnership develops as they plot to hunt down 'The Cook'. In a world where no one is quite who they claim to be and nothing can be taken at face value, no one is ever too far away from a bullet or a blade.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?245853</url></doc>
