<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="247451">
  <docid>247451</docid>
  <title>House Party at Carson Manor</title>
  <year>1915</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">5 December 1915</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Foster, J. Morris</actor>
      <role>Pritchard Moore</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jewett, Ethel</actor>
      <role>Cousin Blondine Elliott</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jones, Morgan (I)</actor>
      <role>Detective Oliver</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>SYNOPSIS, Reel Life, November 27, 1915: "Pritchard Moore gives a house party at his estate, Carson Manor. On the second day, a gardener employed on the grounds is found dead. Detective Oliver is summoned. He substantiates Moore's suspicion that his hired man has been murdered. The detective in disguise mingles with the guests. His attention is drawn to Blondine Elliott, Pritchard's cousin. She identifies him immediately as an officer, taking pains to let Oliver know it. Several days later, a tennis match is arranged by Miss Elliott, between their host, Pauline Coombs, his fiancée, Oliver and herself. The detective sees Miss Elliott deliberately deflect a ball which falls into a bush filled with brambles. Pritchard springs forward to recover the ball, but a warning cry from Oliver brings him to a standstill. 'Who would have benefited by your death?' demands the detective. Moore hesitates, then replies: 'My cousin, Miss Elliott.' 'That bush,' says Oliver, 'is covered with a deadly acid. One scratch from the poisoned brambles would have been fatal.' Aides of Oliver's now bring forward a Hindu prisoner at sight of whom Blondine Elliott turns ghastly pale. 'My assistants and I have witnessed your secret meetings with this man,' continues the detective, coolly. 'I have lost!' cries the woman. 'Life is a gamble, and I am willing to pay the penalty.' She presses to her mouth a strange ring upon her forefinger, and sinks back unconscious."</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?247451</url></doc>
