<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="247583">
  <docid>247583</docid>
  <title>House of Jazmin</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>de la O, Ernesto</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Reality-TV</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>front-row</keyword>
    <keyword>fashion-week</keyword>
    <keyword>designer</keyword>
    <keyword>runway</keyword>
    <keyword>fashion</keyword>
    <keyword>red-carpet</keyword>
    <keyword>working-women</keyword>
    <keyword>clothing</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">22 September 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Harding, C.B.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Costa, Susan</producer>
    <producer>Fox, Marcus (III)</producer>
    <producer>Fox, Marcus J.</producer>
    <producer>Hamm, Peter (II)</producer>
    <producer>Taylor, Jonathan (IV)</producer>
    <producer>Vetri, Adam</producer>
    <producer>Debiec, Christopher A.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Costa, Susan</writer>
    <writer>Vetri, Adam</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Costa, Joey</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Costa, Joey</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Costa, Susan</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Costa, Susan</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Licari, Nonna</actor>
      <role>Herself - Grandma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Licari, Nonna</actor>
      <role>Herself - Grandma</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>On the surface, Jazmin Whitley is just your average American twenty year old. She lives in a modest suburban home outside LA with her Mom and brother. She also spends a lot of time with her Sicilian grandparents who live in the house next door. Scratch a little deeper however, and what you have is a young lady on the verge of adulthood who happens to be a talented fashion designer determined to become one of the best in the world. House of Jazmin follows the day-to-day adventures of this young fashion ingénue as she tries to adjust to the stresses of running her own clothing line label and the high fashion dramas of catwalk shows and all of this begins straight out of high school. Her girly demeanor and innocent outlook belie the fact that Jazmin already has 6 collections under her belt. She takes her business very seriously but running your own label at the tender age of 20 can be difficult when you are the same age as your models and your buyers are much older than you. There is little chance that Jazmin will get lost in the glitz and glamour of the fashion business any time soon, because both of her feet are kept firmly planted on the ground by her close knit family. Ultimately this series is about what happens when you mix a young girl following her dreams with the very adult demands of the fashion business. All while she still tries to remain true to herself.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?247583</url></doc>
