<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="249752">
  <docid>249752</docid>
  <title>Hulchul</title>
  <year>1951</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bankar, Vitthal</editor>
  </editors>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">U</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <directors>
    <director>Ojha, S.K.</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Jaipuri, Hasrat</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Sajjad (I)</composer>
    <composer>Shafi, Mohammad (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Baby Anwari</actor>
      <role>Asha as a child</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Balraj (II)</actor>
      <role>Junior</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cuckoo</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Faizi (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jeevan (I)</actor>
      <role>Paul</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kabir, N. (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Dilip (I)</actor>
      <role>Kishore</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sahni, Balraj</actor>
      <role>The jailer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Singh, K.N.</actor>
      <role>Asha's brother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Yakub</actor>
      <role>Gurudev</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>On the day of his wedding, the life of a jailer is saved by an inmate during a prison break. Back in his cell the prisoner, Kishore, recounts his life story. He spent his childhood amidst the family of a wealthy thakur (landowner) and was treated like a son. But when the thakur died his jealous son relegated Kishore to the status of a servant. Kishore's romance with Asha, the young thakur's sister, earns him a beating. Rather than besmirch the family's honour by eloping, he agrees to leave on condition that he may return when he has become worthy of Asha's hand. He finds a job as a carnival daredevil, diving in flames from a high platform into a tank of fire. However, the carnival's lady owner wants thrills of a different kind and she isn't one to be trifled with -she killed and stuffed her cat to stop it running away..... When Kishore makes it clear that his heart lies elsewhere, Madame is not amused. She arranges for Kishore to be murdered. But the plan goes awry and Kishore ends up being wrongly convicted of her murder and thus finds himself in jail. Both the jailer and his fellow inmates sympathise with him. The jailer wants him to meet his new bride whilst his fellows work on a plan to get him released. One of these is a good idea, the other is not.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?249752</url></doc>
