<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="249849">
  <docid>249849</docid>
  <title>Hum Jo Keh Na Paaye</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bhatia, Deepa</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>marriage</keyword>
    <keyword>pregnancy</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">10 June 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">153</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Thackeray, Smita</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Singh, Uttam</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Joshi, Tarla</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Karnik, Gauri</actor>
      <role>Divya</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khare, Sonali</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kher, Anupam</actor>
      <role>Neeraj Mehta</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nayyar, Ankur</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sanyal, Abhishek</actor>
      <role>Abhishek N. Mehta</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Abhishek Mehta lives with his businessman father, Neeraj, and grandmother. His father would like him to lend a hand in their failing business, especially after the terror attacks of September 11, 2001 in the United States. Abhishek has a crush on a fellow student by the name of Divya for about two years but he has been unable to tell her. He gets his chance when both of them go for an outing, both meet, and fall in love with each other. He confides in his grandma, who in turn tells Neeraj, who goes to meet with Divya's parents - not to make marriage plans - but to strongly oppose them, as he would like Abhishek to stand on his feet before getting married. Abhishek and Divya reluctantly agree and go their separate ways for a couple of years. Six months later, Divya comes to know that Abhishek is having an affair with her friend, Sakshi; that she is pregnant and wants to abort the child, and having failed to do so, kills herself. Divya and Neeraj are appalled at Abhishek's behavior, and Divya swears she will never have anything to do with him. What Divya and Neeraj do not know is that Abhishek is forced to maintain his silence - for a reason that may bring devastation to the Mehta family.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?249849</url></doc>
