<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="249851">
  <docid>249851</docid>
  <title>Hum Kaun Hai?</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Maitra, Raviranjan</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Mystery</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>mansion</keyword>
    <keyword>children</keyword>
    <keyword>remake</keyword>
    <keyword>suspense</keyword>
    <keyword>army</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">A</certificate>
    <certificate country="UK">12A</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">3 September 2004</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Kuwait">29 September 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Shankar, Ravi Sharma</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Juneja, Soni</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Rekhi, Talat</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Chowdhury, Sanjoy</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Aman, Master</actor>
      <role>David Williams</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bachchan, Amitabh</actor>
      <role>Major Frank John Williams/Frank James Williams</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chatterjee, Moushumi</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Martha Pinto</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chopra, Prem</actor>
      <role>Anita's husband</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dharmendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Virendra 'Viru' (Guest Appearance)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gokhale, Vikram</actor>
      <role>Virendra's boss</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapadia, Dimple</actor>
      <role>Sandra Williams</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kashyap, Shitla</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lahiri, Abhijit</actor>
      <role>Edgar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rahman, Fazal</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vicky, Master</actor>
      <role>Vicky</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>After the mysterious disappearance of her maid, butler, and gardener, Mrs. Sandra Williams, the wife of Major Frank, who lives in a palatial house with two children, Sara and David, writes a letter to the local employment agency to get replacements. Martha Pinto, in the company of Edgar and Maria, a dumb woman, apply for these vacancies. Sandra hires them, explains that her children's eyes may be damaged by sunlight, the curtains are to be drawn at all times, as she gets migraines by any loud noise everyone must remain quiet, there is no electricity and all work must be done during the daytime, and the entire house is candle-lit. The staff get busy with their work, and it is then Sarah tells her mom that she has noticed other people in the house that are visible to her only, and she draws the picture of a male, a female (his wife), their son, Vicky, and an elder woman with magical powers. Sandra disbelieves her, but when she starts feeling someone's presence in her house, as well as hearing noises, she decides to investigate. She finds out that the letter she had to the employment agency is still lying in the mailbox. She must now find out how Martha, Edgar and Maria came to know of the vacancies, and of the presence of a album with dead people's photos. Watch as events beyond her control unfold, leading her, Sara and David face to face with the other unseen people in this household.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?249851</url></doc>
