<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="250387">
  <docid>250387</docid>
  <title>Hunted</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Charif, Moe</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">PG-13</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">5 May 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">20min,57sec</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Charif, Moe</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Charif, Ahmad</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Chun, Greg</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Courtney (VI)</actor>
      <role>Larry</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fuentes, Jessica (I)</actor>
      <role>Emily</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Haidar, Ahmad</actor>
      <role>Ali</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Krys, Leonard</actor>
      <role>Mr. Johnson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Peterson, Courtney</actor>
      <role>Larry</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Peterson, David (X)</actor>
      <role>David</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sanchez, Clark</actor>
      <role>Confederate Clyde</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Trapani, John</actor>
      <role>John</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Emily wakes up to find herself in the middle of nowhere. Chased by a group of complete lunatics; and for reasons beyond her comprehension, instincts kick in as she tries to make sense of the mess she has stumbled into whilst surviving at the same time. Hunted is a movie revolving around such people, who would stop at nothing in order to entertain themselves, even if it involves kidnapping innocent human beings, and toying with them for the sole purpose of amusement. They are kids in a garden, with a magnifying glass to play with. The concept of 'right' and 'wrong' simply does not exist in such people's minds, leaving them to act upon instinct. On the other hand, you have on the receiving end, an innocent person who goes about her life normally, wanting nothing but to be able to make ends meet, and better herself for the future, when she is snatched from her reality, and placed in this bizarre twisted game which she knows nothing about. She too has to rely on her instincts, since there is no society, and no one to watch over her, it is the law of the jungle, the survival of the fittest.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?250387</url></doc>
