<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="251190">
  <docid>251190</docid>
  <title>Hybrid</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>exploding-building</keyword>
    <keyword>wolf-pack</keyword>
    <keyword>rescue-from-fire</keyword>
    <keyword>dog-group</keyword>
    <keyword>bison</keyword>
    <keyword>sense-of-hearing</keyword>
    <keyword>flashback-sequence</keyword>
    <keyword>animal-behavior</keyword>
    <keyword>eye-transplant</keyword>
    <keyword>one-word-title</keyword>
    <keyword>running-through-fields</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Australia">M</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Greece">7 March 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Greece">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Lanskaya, Yelena</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Olsen, Arne (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Frewer, Terry</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bateman, Justine</actor>
      <role>Andrea</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hughes, Aaron (II)</actor>
      <role>Wilcox</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Korey, Tinsel</actor>
      <role>Lydia</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McLaren, Brandon Jay</actor>
      <role>Ashmore</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Monteith, Cory</actor>
      <role>Aaron Scates</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Norsworthy, Robert</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sorensen, Brett</actor>
      <role>Deaver</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tanner, Gordon (I)</actor>
      <role>Phelps</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tootoosis, Gordon</actor>
      <role>Grandpa</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Woytowich, Will</actor>
      <role>Mobley</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>It's an experiment in human behavior. It's an exploration of the most natural of animal impulses. It's something new under the moon. And it bites. When security dispatcher Aaron Scates is blinded in an explosion, he's put in the care of Dr. Andrea Hewlitt, famous in her field for spearheading extraordinary-though controversial-medical breakthroughs. Her newest is cross-species organ transplants, and Aaron is her first human subject. When a severely wounded wolf is brought to Dr. Hewlitt's office by museum curator Lydia Armstrong, Dr. Hewlitt leaps on the opportunity and successfully transplants the wolf's eyes to Aaron-despite Lydia's objections. Aaron, however, is thrilled. Not only can he see again, he can see in the dark. He also has an unusually acute sense of hearing, and tears into a raw steak like never before. Unfortunately, he also tends growl, and to target people as prey. Lydia knows why. Knowing Aaron is in danger-to himself and to others -Lydia confesses that she too is a cross-breed but has learned to channel her feral instincts into a source of strength, not violence, with the help of her shaman friend, Claude Robertson. After Lydia and Aaron explore their other animal instincts in the privacy of Lydia's lair, she takes him to Claude's for a rite-of-passage to integrate the young man's spirit with that of a wolf. But Dr. Hewitt's colleagues, who have seen Aaron's wilder side, are determined to hunt the beast down and destroy him. What they don't know is that Aaron has more on his side than a shaman and an empathetic girlfriend. He's made some new friends at the zoo. They travel in packs. And they don't need a full moon to commune. Like Wolfen, The Howling, and An American Werewolf in London before it, Hybrid delivers a snarlingly sharp twist on the werewolf genre for an all new generation of animal lovers.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?251190</url></doc>
