<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="251977">
  <docid>251977</docid>
  <title>I Am Not a Chair</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">25 June 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">28 December 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Krishnamsetty, Kumar</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Zimmerman, Justin (I)</producer>
    <producer>Krishnamsetty, Kumar</producer>
    <producer>Sadhanala, Murali</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Krishnamsetty, Kumar</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hawkins, Shuhe</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kenney, Kim</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>I AM NOT A CHAIR is the story of a relatively high functioning quadriplegic who sets out on a job hunt, applying for teaching jobs in the area of his personal passion and expertise: painting, and dance. His applications are met with rejection, first, by a rigid bureaucrat and next, by a friendly but patronizing job recruiter. Turned down for both jobs - based, obviously, on his disability - he returns to his studio/apartment, turns on a rousing Bollywood song, and, all alone in the place, proceeds to demonstrate his rare and stunning gift - for both painting, and dance. But is it a dream? A fantasy? A memory (from before the accident that paralyzed him)? Is it his spirit we see? His ghost? Is it, in fact, real? The ambiguity of this sequence is heightened when he leaves with his friend, and a Realtor enters the apartment with a prospective buyer. What happens next suggests that reality may be more complicated and slippery than we imagine, and the viewer is left to decide what has taken place here, and what it means.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?251977</url></doc>
