<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="252734">
  <docid>252734</docid>
  <title>I Love Lucy Christmas Show</title>
  <year>1956</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>immaturity</keyword>
    <keyword>slapstick</keyword>
    <keyword>flashback-sequence</keyword>
    <keyword>kids-and-family</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>christmas</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">G</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">24 December 1956</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">26</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Kern, James V.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Arnaz, Desi</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Hatch, Wilbur</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arnaz, Desi</actor>
      <role>Ricky Ricardo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ball, Lucille</actor>
      <role>Lucy Ricardo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Frawley, William</actor>
      <role>Fred Mertz</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grant, A. Cameron</actor>
      <role>Santa Claus</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Keith, Richard (I)</actor>
      <role>Little Ricky Ricardo</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>It's that time of year again. Christmas! Ricky and Lucy tell Little Ricky all about Santa claus, each in their own unique way. Then Little Ricky is sent to bed and then Fred and Ethel come with the Christmas tree. Lucy has Fred saw off several branches while the gang recall the time Lucy announced to Ricky she was "expectant" with Little Ricky. They also recall the time Lucy forced herself to be in Ricky's barbershop quartet. Back to the present, Fred has overtrimmed the tree and is sent out to buy another one. He soon returns with another tree and is overjoyed, because due to the time of day, he got the tree at half price. The gang then recalls the night Lucy announced the baby was ready to come and everybody frantically races off to the hospital--forgetting Lucy. Well, Christmas morning soon arrives and Ricky, Lucy, Ethel and Fred are each dressed as Santa Claus. Suddenly, in comes a 5th Santa. It was Fred! It turns out the 4th Santa was in fact THE Santa Claus. He disappears as the Ricardos and Mertzes stare in disbelief. Which soon turns to belief.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?252734</url></doc>
