<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="253460">
  <docid>253460</docid>
  <title>I Would Rather</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kupelian, Ken</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">18 April 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">5</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Nelson, Shawn (VII)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Decher, Teresa</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Decher, Teresa</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Witkam, Herman</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Blake, Madison</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Calkins, Robert</actor>
      <role>Erik</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Decher, Teresa</actor>
      <role>Sammy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gordon, Lealon</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ratliff, Aaron Thomas</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A group of friends start playing the game 'would you rather', and when Vivian is asked whether she would save herself or save her friend, Vivian and Sammy both know that Vivian would have rather saved herself than her friend. Sammy leaves the group and goes to the bathroom downstairs where she is assaulted. As Vivian still ponders the question, she receives a text message from Sammy saying 'help'. Vivian expresses her concern to the group, and the rest of the group is startled by Vivian's mention of Sammy. The group has to remind Vivian that Sammy has been dead for a long time. In disbelief, Vivian tries to show them Sammy's text message, but after looking to her phone, the text message has vanished... and so has all of Sammy's stuff. Vivian, unconvinced and unwilling to believe Sammy is truly dead, goes into the bathroom where she finds Sammy in critical condition in the hands of the assailant. After a moment of hesitation, Vivian chooses to save her friend and is injured in the process. However, since Vivian attempts to save friend, rather than herself, Vivian's bravery is rewarded, and both Vivian and Sammy are brought back to life.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?253460</url></doc>
