<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="254270">
  <docid>254270</docid>
  <title>I neraida kai to palikari</title>
  <year>1969</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Syropoulos, Vasilis</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Greek</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Greece</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">102</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Dimopoulos, Dinos</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Mihailidis, Lakis</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Mamangakis, Nikos</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Argyris, Giannis</actor>
      <role>Vrontakis</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Charalabidis, Yorgos</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Garbi, Joly</actor>
      <role>Fourtounakis' Sister</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grammenos, Thanos</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kalogirou, Spyros</actor>
      <role>Skandalakis</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Konstadara, Mitsi</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Koumarianou, Eirini</actor>
      <role>Manousos' Mother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Marouda, Nitsa</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pahis, Stratos</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Papagiannopoulos, Dionysis</actor>
      <role>Fourtounakis</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Papamichael, Dimitris</actor>
      <role>Manousos</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pashalidis, Nikos (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Peryalis, Notis</actor>
      <role>Priest</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Savaidis, Kostas</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stypas, Hristos</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Taxiarhis, Foivos</actor>
      <role>Mayor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tsoukas, Nikos</actor>
      <role>Police Officer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tzanetakos, Alekos</actor>
      <role>Manousos' Friend</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This is a story of two families, on the island of Crete, whose everlasting rivalry has split the inhabitants in two groups. In Chania, Crete the townspeople either defend the Fourtounakis or the Vrontakis families, and for what cause? It started ages ago and they don't even remember why they hate each other. Captain Fourtounakis' daughter, Katerinio (Aliki Vougiouklaki) is her clan's cherished offspring. Women envy her outgoing spirit and strength, men lust over her beauty and the Vrontakis clan despises her defensive nature. Her father has arranged a marriage with a wealthy but very unattractive Cretan, Skantalakis. To Katerinio's surprise, her dreams of a gentle and handsome husband were shattered. Captain Vrontakis wouldn't settle for anything less than a wife with an enormous dowry for his son Manouso (Dimitri Papamichael) who has been living in Athens since he was a child, only because of his father's fear that he will grow up and fall in love with his rival's spiteful daughter, Katerinio. So, he arranges a marriage between Manouso and Lenio whose dowry exceeds her appearance. When Manouso returns to the island after so many years he comes across a huge celebration and decides to join the party. When Manouso and Katerinio spot each other their eyes lock and it's love at first sight. Merely minutes later he is informed that she is Fourtounakis' daughter and that he had just crashed her engagement party. Manouso is determined to make Katerinio his, even if it means not telling her whose son he really is, since Katerinio is keeping the hatred more alive than anyone.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?254270</url></doc>
