<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="255620">
  <docid>255620</docid>
  <title>Ice Bear</title>
  <year>2010</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Parker, Oliver (IV)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>animal-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Parker, Oliver (IV)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hare, Mary</producer>
    <producer>Sherborne, Toby</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>In May 2009, to prepare for his exhibition on the Arctic, renowned animal sculptor, Mark Coreth set off across the Baffin Island sea-ice in search of polar bears. Local guides took him and filmmaker, Oliver Parker, across a breath-taking environment of frozen sea. Here they encountered an array of Arctic birdlife and Inuit hunters on the trail of seal and polar bears. They also discovered a land of ancient blue icebergs, crumpled ice ridges and desert terrain. In his search for the elusive polar bear, Mark soon found himself merging with the bear's ice-locked kingdom; a kingdom showing the premature signs of Arctic spring. After bitter snowstorms and days of white-outs, Mark finally found his bears. The more Mark immersed himself in this landscape, the more he felt his mission must be to capture its essence in a very public sculpture. He realized that he must craft a life-sized polar bear made from this landscape; from ice, with a skeleton, which would be revealed as this iconic animal melts. Now back in England, Mark is preparing to start work on his skeleton. He wants to have this cast in bronze, but acknowledges that this will cost a small fortune; money that he needs to raise if he is to make his vision a reality. He has just been granted permission to exhibit his 'Ice Bear' outside the National Gallery on London's Trafalgar Square. For ten days Londoners and visitors from around the world will have the opportunity to touch the melting bear and the skeleton as it emerges. Are the authorities aware that this is the same time as the UN Climate Conference in Copenhagen? Mark will find out at the September site meeting, when he faces both Westminster Council and the police to discuss his fast-approaching event. Mark realises that if he is to make an environmental statement on Trafalgar Square, his work must be grounded in fact. Alongside his friend, naturalist Nick Baker, he will travel to Churchill, Canada. Scientists here are studying the world's largest gathering of polar bears, as every November they wait for Hudson Bay to freeze over. Mark and Nick will talk with climate and bear experts, like Professor Ian Stirling, to get a vivid picture of the problems the Arctic ecosystem now faces. On average, ice break-up takes place here three weeks earlier than it did thirty years ago when Ian first came to study these bears. Scientists estimate that this floating ice is 40% thinner than it was 40 years ago. The 2009 Catlin Arctic Survey found the Arctic sea-ice to be on average only 1.8 metres thick. Mark believes his work must embody this science. He has decided to place the data he will gather in Churchill within the frozen base of his London sculpture. On Trafalgar Square, Mark will finally create his Ice Bear vision from a ten tonne block of white ice. He has high hopes for this event. Success in London could open the door to bears in other world cities. As the days pass, the touch of countless hands will reduce this magnificent bear to a pool of water and a skeleton. What will be the reaction of the half million or so who will encounter it? Art, at its very best, can touch our emotions and can change us. Will this deeply symbolic work empower its audience to make environmental changes to their lives? Ice Bear will capture the essence of the issue human society now faces. This is neither political, nor economic; but fundamental.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?255620</url></doc>
