<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="256031">
  <docid>256031</docid>
  <title>Ich wollte einfach nur dieses Foto haben</title>
  <year>1993</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kutschker, Thomas</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>War</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>media</keyword>
    <keyword>experimental-film</keyword>
    <keyword>yugoslavia</keyword>
    <keyword>photography</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>German</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Germany">14</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Kutschker, Thomas</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kutschker, Thomas</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Kutschker, Thomas</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>The photographer Olaf Wyludda was wounded in Croatia in 1992 while waiting for bombs to kill a woman and a child running across the street. Overwhelmed by his failure he describes the war and this potential picture so intensely that at the end the spectator has this photograph in his mind. "I just wanted to make this certain image, that's why I had to risk it." The wrong lense causes that this image cannot be made from a safe distance. He has to get closer, has to wait although the bombs were getting closer and closer. Intrigued by the scene of two people who are running across the street paniced to death. He remains professional. After the explosion, after the "light went out", after he was injured, he remembers. He rememberes the arrival in Croatia, his cameras, waiting for the images on the front. The first death hwo is brought in from the fights. Searching for the right angle for taking pictures. The wagon that hit a mine. Pictures of the wrack. The most important thing for the fighters: food. He looses a Leica camera. His leica is refound. Again and again the scene with the old woman and the little child running across the street, trying to escape. An image of war, without weapons, without tanks - impressive,cruel. 1/1000 of a second of cruelty. Being obsessive to take this image on one side, which made him forget everything and the impressions that leave the war events on the other this non existing image is created in the mind of the spectators.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?256031</url></doc>
