<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="256300">
  <docid>256300</docid>
  <title>Identity Burglars</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Conliffe, Iain</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">5 October 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Gilbert, Jason F.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Gilbert, Jason F.</producer>
    <producer>Keener, Christopher (I)</producer>
    <producer>Remich, Adam</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Keener, Christopher (I)</writer>
    <writer>Remich, Adam</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Weston, Rob (II)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Charles, Chasen</actor>
      <role>Michievious boy at board</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Darigo, Sal</actor>
      <role>School Teacher</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Keener, Christopher (I)</actor>
      <role>Koman Panyachev</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McGinn-Lacmuth, Kate</actor>
      <role>Dr. Helen Winthorp</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Remich, Adam</actor>
      <role>Sizliski Fortunov</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>If you want to see a film about a family of vulnerable, yet touching, Irish immigrants, and the trials they face in the whirl-wind of New York, or if you are seeking out a movie about orphan Cheetahs that are Buddhist, and play soccer, or a movie so bold, so excruciatingly sexy, and so distractingly beautiful that it will move you in ways you never thought possible, then this film is the apotheosis of your gluttonous desire. The colorful, and starving Lehigh Valley Stevenson, author of horror novellas, turns to writing love letters for passers-bye, and becomes a muse for the citizens of Philadelphia. The Detector, a schizophrenic, and sweet man of vast nuance, sentimentality and corduroy apparel, arms himself with only a defective metal detector, as he embarks on an odyssey, and searches for something that lies at the heart of it all. Wily Russians run amok on an American submarine, and a second-string amateur hockey player fulfills his community service hours in front of a live audience of children, and through his simple nature, teaches us that drunks are people too. A mighty, yet aged Zeus readies the gorgeous Bacchus to play God with the lives of mankind. And the sad and lonely tale of the sweet Audrey, a wandering spirit, who looks for meaning in a marriage that has somehow become vacuous, stale, and potentially dangerous. These are but half the threads that are masterfully woven together by the brilliant and handsome filmmakers, into the rich and expensive tapestry that is Identity Burglars. A comedy that makes the first strides in Nu-form, the completely ad-libbed Identity Burglars ushers in a new precedence for filmmaking. Join the gigantic cast as their stories explore life, and exalt just how funny it can be.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?256300</url></doc>
