<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="256426">
  <docid>256426</docid>
  <title>Idol: Pag-asa ng bayan</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>student</keyword>
    <keyword>teenage-boy</keyword>
    <keyword>delinquent</keyword>
    <keyword>scholar</keyword>
    <keyword>best-friend</keyword>
    <keyword>honor</keyword>
    <keyword>friendship</keyword>
    <keyword>idealist</keyword>
    <keyword>morality</keyword>
    <keyword>cheating</keyword>
    <keyword>computer</keyword>
    <keyword>coming-of-age</keyword>
    <keyword>honesty</keyword>
    <keyword>high-school</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Tagalog</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Philippines</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Philippines">PG-13</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Philippines">1 August 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Philippines">77</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Buendia, Cesar Evangelista</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Buendia, Cesar Evangelista</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>De Mesa, Michael (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jose, Cedric</actor>
      <role>Eleazar Zabarte/Elly</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jose, Jacklyn</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Idol reveals a serious story about honesty, honor and integrity. Eleazar Zabarte or Elly (Cedric Jose) is a working student . He is a scholar and is now a candidate to become the class valedictorian. His father works at a government institution but is quite idealistic and incorruptible, which explains why his family still remains so poor. Charismatic Elly works part-time as a student assistant and he has indirect access to confidential school papers. He has earned the trust of the school staff, and because of this, it would not be difficult for him to get hold of this year's final exams-the one which his best buddy Simon and their other friends need to pass in order to graduate. Friendship and "utang na loob" win over the values that Elly's father has instilled in him. The young boy decides to sneak into the secretary's office, open the computer file and print a copy of the exam. As the story ends, the principles of each of the characters are put to the test. The word integrity acquires a new meaning and our values as Filipinos are revealed in this indie film.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?256426</url></doc>
