<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="256666">
  <docid>256666</docid>
  <title>If This Day Never Happened</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Giorgobiani, Khatuna</editor>
    <editor>Shengelaya, Mirian</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Georgian</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Georgia</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Georgia">17 September 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Giorgobiani, Khatuna</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Giorgobiani, Besarion</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Giorgobiani, Besarion</writer>
    <writer>Khandolishvili, Eka</writer>
    <writer>Sharvadze, Salome</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Akhobadze, Eka</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gurji, Anna</actor>
      <role>Anna</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khutsishvili, Nodar</actor>
      <role>Father</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kinkladze, Mariam</actor>
      <role>Mary</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tavadze, Niko</actor>
      <role>Nick</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>War brings a lot of misfortune for people, it is not important is it a big, global war or a little one, still war is war. But what happens when the war is over and torture of people still goes on? Has a human being invented the wars to justify their cruelties or shift the blame on someone else? - No! I was born with kindness and love in the world and you can not make me frightened. Perhaps, at the end of the movie, 13 years old Anna answers the invitation of life with these words by her strange dancing. Mary is broken in an early age by life, war, mother's death, a blind father, a little sister and a strange environment. How can she keep herself and her relatives? She knows only thieving and selling her body. Anna, Mary's younger sister earns money by singing in the street. Father plays the hooter and she sings. Ann is strong on the contrary and despite a little age she is everybody's hope and patron: an old father, elder sister, old person left in the hospital and even a leg broken doll, being left in dustbin. Sisters and their blind father live in Tbilisi district, in a destroyed room of some department. During the Abkhazian war they escaped from Sokhumi and the government of that time let them live there temporarily, and now the owner of the building threatens them to dismiss from this "pigsty" (as Mary calls her house). Anna is a strong fulcrum, life depends on whom, when Mary is arrested for taking drugs and the policemen dismiss the beggars from the streets, Anna escapes them and begins to dance around. Almost all the world looks at her attractive dancing being surprised.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?256666</url></doc>
