<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="260163">
  <docid>260163</docid>
  <title>Iltrentasette</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Gavioli, Diego</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Biography</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Italian</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Italy">25 July 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Italy">55</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Greco, Roberto (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ronconi, Silvia</producer>
    <producer>De Donatis, Luca</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Greco, Roberto (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Belli, Andrea (I)</composer>
    <composer>Dennis, Chris (I)</composer>
    <composer>Galeazzi, Lucilla</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Degli Esposti, Piera</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Four men are sitting at a table playing cards. A fifth man is watching, sitting next to them. As the game is livening up, one of them starts the so called "memory carousel". Twenty five years have passed since the bomb explosion at Bologna railway station. The men talk the local dialect and keep playing. They recall the memory of Piera Degli Esposti: she's talking about her station, her emotions, her expectations... So the trip begins, through the memories of sixty men and women. A trip that begins on that morning, around six, when the town is waking up, in the torpor of a hot Italian Saturday, the first Saturday of August. And then the bomb. Human lives are broken, destroyed, changed.... saved. We relive those moments, through the narration of the ones who were involuntary protagonists in a solidarity machine set in motion in Bologna on that day: in front of the railway station, in the hospitals, in the long queues where people are waiting to donate blood, in the special support offices set up by the Town Council, on the buses that are carrying corpses to the legal medicine centers. Just as in a Greek choir, the protagonists of that day are reciting their stories and offering their memories, animating the spirit that was leading them through that day.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?260163</url></doc>
