<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="260629">
  <docid>260629</docid>
  <title>ImagiNation</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Romagnoli, Lisa</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">5 March 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">57</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Romagnoli, Lisa</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cassidy, Kayleigh</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chabot, Josh</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chretien, Colette</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Costa, Josh</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rahill, Max</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>'We are thinkers. We are travelers. Our world is a place of endless possibilities. We are explorers. We are creativity. Together we can solve any challenge. Our destination is our imagination. We are a team!' Destination Imagination is a non-profit organization for kids, from kindergarten though high school. The program is designed to foster teamwork, creative problem solving, and innovation. It's the world's largest creativity and problem solving organization, with over 250,000 participants from all 50 states as well as 56 countries. Teams match wits and abilities in regional, state, and global creativity tournaments. Up to seven kids to a team work together to create their unique solution to a specially written Team Challenge: their solution is presented in the form of an 8-minute skit. The St. Joseph Regional Junior High School Alumni Team is up to the task. This team of 14 and 15-year-olds work for months to create the ultimate 8-minute skit; to be performed at one of the five Regional Competitions in their state. They brain-storm, they write, they build, they sew, they paper-mache, they rehearse...and, finally, they perform.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?260629</url></doc>
