<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="260676">
  <docid>260676</docid>
  <title>Imagine Afrika</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Fahey-Goldsmith, Bridgette</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Reality-TV</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>africa</keyword>
    <keyword>african-youth</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>French</language>
    <language>Portuguese</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>South Africa</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="South Africa">18 September 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">24</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Bekolo, Jean-Pierre</director>
    <director>Dube, Mickey Madoda</director>
    <director>Kalimunda, Jacqueline</director>
    <director>Matabane, Khalo</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Dube, Mickey Madoda</producer>
    <producer>Kaplan, Ken (II)</producer>
    <producer>Carew, Carolyn</producer>
    <producer>Carew, Carolyn</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>The first authentic African reality show sets up pan-African challenge for continent's young achievers and promotes the vision of an HIV-free generation. Imagine Afrika pits 12 outstanding young African achievers against one another to come up with solutions to some of the continent's most pressing problems. Chosen through a continent-wide call for nominations resulting in more than 10,000 applications, the contestants have been chosen to represent the diversity of Africa and for their exceptional personal achievements and talents. Over 13 weeks the 12 contestants in three teams will compete on location in South Africa, Ghana, Rwanda, Mozambique and Uganda in working with local communities to initiate efforts to address local problems. With the primary goal of demonstrating the power of personal initiative, self esteem and leadership in charting a future vision for a better future for Africa, the contestants will specifically focus on factors driving the HIV/AIDS epidemic as the most debilitating of the endemic diseases affecting Africa. Witness the drama as 12 strong personalities from different cultures and backgrounds battle to find common ground and to work with local communities across five countries to help initiate efforts to tackle basic problems like housing, water supply, nutrition and HIV/AIDS prevention, treatment and care. The teams will demonstrate the talents and leadership of Africa's next generation of leaders and promote the vision of an HIV-free generation by challenging all Africans as individuals and as part of families, communities and nations to think how they can contribute to that goal. Each week audiences across 31 African countries will vote for their favorite teams and a special panel will score the teams efforts. All the scoring will be tallied and the teams will come together for a thrilling finale.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?260676</url></doc>
