<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="263221">
  <docid>263221</docid>
  <title>In the Land of Smiles</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>McClain, Virgilia</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>thailand</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Thai</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">65</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>McClain, Virgilia</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>McClain, Virgilia</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Siriruttanapan, Boonrut</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Set in Thailand after the coup d'etat of September 2006, "In the Land of Smilies" explores the paradox between Thailand's seductive and modern surface and the country's socially depressed and unscrupulous inner core. In Pattaya, the lives of people within the scattered slums are followed as well as the UK charity, Kate's Project, that aids them. Together, the three members of Kate's Project have worked to provide over 100 children with tuition and supplies to attend school as well as rehouse families that are in the direst need. Many families of which are without birth certificates and identification making it nearly impossible to obtain an education, job or any governmental assistance. To most, they are invisible people when met on the street and illegitimate citizens without any assurances of life except hardship. Poverty and the unstable condition of life that is generally lent in their situation, is the vehicle for many that become targets of infamous and exploitative trades of crime. The second story, set in Bangkok, follows the life of Thai political journalist, Pravit Rojunaphruk ensuing the coup and the developments leading up to the December 2007 general election. Thailand's politically volatile atmosphere paints the backdrop to the limitations and censorship of journalism in opposition to one of few objective writers in a time of rumblings for new democratic and social order. "In the Land of Smiles" is a unchartered journey into the heart of an old world culture in search for its identity and political future.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?263221</url></doc>
