<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="263334">
  <docid>263334</docid>
  <title>In the Name of Love: A Texas Tragedy</title>
  <year>1995</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">12 September 1995</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">96</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>D'Elia, Bill</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hoffman, Gary (I)</producer>
    <producer>McLain, Chuck</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Hill, Danielle (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Alban, Alissa</actor>
      <role>Victoria Jennings</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Babatunde, Akin</actor>
      <role>Herschel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bartlett, Bonnie</actor>
      <role>Aunt Alice</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bowman, Margaret</actor>
      <role>Landlady</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Boyce, Rodger</actor>
      <role>Motel Manager</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bush, Rebeccah</actor>
      <role>Pamela Jo Peyton</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Crenna, Richard</actor>
      <role>Lucas Constable, Sr.</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Davis, Travis (I)</actor>
      <role>Terry Buffet</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Davis, Vince (I)</actor>
      <role>Photographer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Denney, David (I)</actor>
      <role>Cheeter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Duffey, Todd</actor>
      <role>Davey Coombs</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grote, Vernon</actor>
      <role>Good Ole Boy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Guthrie, Bill (III)</actor>
      <role>Mr. Jennings</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Güney, Kamal</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hayden, Michael (I)</actor>
      <role>Luke Constable</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hunter, Neith</actor>
      <role>Elaine Phelps</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Leighton, Laura</actor>
      <role>Laurette Wilder</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Marich, Marietta</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Jennings</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Osborn, Norbert</actor>
      <role>Valet</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Prichard, Marshall</actor>
      <role>Paramedic</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sifuentes, Everett</actor>
      <role>Servant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Terry, Todd (I)</actor>
      <role>Billy Farber</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Waters, Mark (I)</actor>
      <role>Dwayne</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Watson, Woody</actor>
      <role>Deputy Waters</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This is a story of two lovers, Luke and Laurette. Luke is the grandson of a rich Texas family who raised him after the death of his parents. Laurette is daughter of a blue-collar worker. They have different worlds, different lifestyles... What if they meet? After a car accident with his fiancée, Luke can no longer walk without the assistance of orthopedic canes. Because of his disability, his fiancée leaves him. While at a barbecue at his best friend's home, Luke then meets Laurette. They fall in love and marry despite pressure from Luke's grandparents. But, what happens? Laurette pressures Luke to leave his family or obtain a piece of land, an early inheritance from his grandfather, so that they can live a life separate from his grandparents. Luke's grandfather refuses and Laurette leaves him. Laurette is forced to file for a divorce, but find they are unable to stay apart. They continue to see each other secretly, until Loretta runs out of the money she received from the divorce settlement provided by Luke's grandfather. They turn to Luke's house to live, and Luke's grandfather gives an ultimatum to his grandson: leave Laurette and stay or stay with Laurette and leave with nothing. They leave together, hoping to build a new life, but Luke is unable to get a job and becomes increasingly depressed. Laurette tells Luke that she can no longer stand by and watch him destroy himself and goes out for a night on the town alone. Upon her return, Luke threatens to shoot Laurette, she tells him to go ahead and kill her; Luke pulls the trigger, killing Laurette. Luke somehow manages to get Laurette's body out of the house and to a remote location on his family's property. After placing Laurette's body on top of gathered branches and twigs, he lights it all on fire and watches Laurette's body burn. He momentarily considers killing himself, but is unable to do so and apologizes to Laurette for not being strong enough to do so. Later that night, Luke, sitting in his pickup, is surrounded by law enforcement and arrested for murder.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?263334</url></doc>
