<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="263467">
  <docid>263467</docid>
  <title>In the Shadow of the Cobra</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Holmes, Christopher (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">109</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Nicolaou, Ted</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>C.H., Ramoji Rao</producer>
    <producer>Jackson, David A.</producer>
    <producer>DeMartini, Frank</producer>
    <producer>Johnston, Marisa (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Schwartz, Ira</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Folk, Robert</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Acheson, James (II)</actor>
      <role>Jake Whitcomb</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grover, Gulshan</actor>
      <role>Kabir</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hauer, Rutger</actor>
      <role>Gallo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Joelson, Greg</actor>
      <role>Michael</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Johnson Jr., Mel</actor>
      <role>Russell</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>O'Hagan, Michael</actor>
      <role>Hyde-White</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In the vein of Raiders of the Lost Ark, this action-packed thriller takes us on a roller-coaster ride from the bone-chilling cold of Moscow to the mystical beauty of India. An ancient tablet found by famous British Archaeologist Professor Hyde-White is believed to be a road map to the legendary Lost Temple of Faramundi and its hidden treasures. But before he is able to set out on his expedition, the Professor, along with the tablet, are taken hostage by a group of mercenaries, led by the vicious Philipe Gallo. When the Professor is found missing, one of his students, Jake Whitcomb, finds the Professor's journal, inside of which is a copy of the map. Jake decides to take action. Knowing that the legend of the Temple describes ancient mystical music as the key to unlock its secrets, Jake enlists the help of Samantha "Sam" Kincaid, an expert musicologist. The two are catapulted into the chase of their lives in the pursuit of the kidnapped Professor and the Lost Temple. Nothing is easy for this pair. As Jake and Sam bicker throughout their trek across India, they find Kabir, a museum curator who possesses an artifact, which he claims can produce the musical tone required to open the door to the Temple. Throughout their journey they survive gun battles, vicious hand-to-hand fighting, vision-blurring car chases, and a heart-stopping train wreck hundreds of feet above a rocky gorge. Tired, bruised, and out of breath, they finally free the Professor and arrive at the Temple of Faramundi only minutes before Gallo and his men. Inside the breathtaking structure, they discover wondrous artifacts of an advanced but long dead civilization. Amid a towering forest of shimmering crystals, they begin to explore this ancient marvel. When the mercenaries catch up, Sam, Jake, and the rest of their entourage find themselves in the clutches of the bloodthirsty Gallo.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?263467</url></doc>
