<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="263456">
  <docid>263456</docid>
  <title>In the Shadow of Feeling</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Law, Bryan (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>psychopath</keyword>
    <keyword>shadow</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">17 November 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">44</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Law, Bryan (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Law, Bryan (II)</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>This film takes a look at the factors that turn children into adult psychopaths. The film follows the story of a 17 year old boy named, "Johnathan" who was labeled as a psychopath at age 14, while on trial for first degree murder. It examines factors such as parenting, genetics, and society in determining the psychological state of any child as they develop into adults. Psychopaths (now referred to as Anti-Social Personality Disorder) are described essentially as individuals with no ability to empathize or show true emotions. They can recreate the exact pantomime of emotions, but the actually feelings rarely come to pass. They are, by definition, without conscience. Roughly 2% of the total population is estimated to be completely psychopathic, while about 15% would be considered "Partial Psychopaths", or incomplete manifestations of the illness. These people are commonly depicted by the media as the very few serial killers and high profile criminals that we seem to focus on; however, they also do extremely well in business and politics. Johnathan was able to explain his story and his childhood, in order to give us a better idea of his life. We examine his home life and his relationship with his family to better understand why he was labeled as a psychopath. If society wishes to better themselves and to create functioning, and constructive members of society, we must first understand how to relate to each other. The solution requires generations of people to form better bonds with family and friends in the earliest years of life. Long term plans do not tend to be favoured by most; however they are often the most silent and acquiescent way to change people.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?263456</url></doc>
