<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="263775">
  <docid>263775</docid>
  <title>Inaugural Hobgood Challenge</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Arsenault, Otto</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>surfing</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">23 April 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">46</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Barranco, Paul C.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Barranco, Paul C.</producer>
    <producer>Marckx, Michael</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Atkinson, Dion</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barranco, Paul C.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Beru</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Geiselman, Eric</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hobgood, CJ</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hobgood, Damien</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Marzo, Clay</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Payne, Dusty</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Widiartha, Garut</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wright, Owen</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Inaugural Hobgood Challenge presented by PacSun scores perfect pits. CJ and Damien host the first ever ASP sanctioned Pro Junior Specialty event in Micronesia, bringing 6 of the world's best surfers under 20 to the surfing world's latest discovery. For CJ and Damien Hobgood, the first week of February was nothing but work. Hosting 6 of the world's best Junior surfers, at the first ever ASP sanctioned Pro Junior Specialty event, is work after all. Following a three-year development of their Camp Hobgood, CJ and Damo took 2006 off, and re-thought the project. The result of the break was the Inaugural Hobgood Challenge. The invited surfers, chosen by CJ and Damien personally, represent a global cross section of what they feel are the next generation of the world's best surfers and will compete in a progressive format competition for the inaugural championship. Included on the list were Dusty Payne (Hi), Clay Marzo (Hi), Eric Geiselman (USA), Dion Atkinson (Aus), Owen Wright (Aus) and Garut Widiarta (Idn). Following a week of small swell, the crew final hit pay dirt at the 11th hour, with a clean 4-6' swell. The night before the event was to run, cards were drawn to establish the heat draw. Ironically, each heat was a showdown of Goofy vs. Regular foot. In the end, following 3 rounds of heats, goofy footer Owen Wright took the championship, at the Inaugural Hobgood Challenge presented by PacSun.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?263775</url></doc>
