<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="264196">
  <docid>264196</docid>
  <title>Independent America: The Two-Lane Search for Mom &amp; Pop</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Hosein, Hanson</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>road-trip</keyword>
    <keyword>big-box-stores</keyword>
    <keyword>starbucks</keyword>
    <keyword>wal-mart</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">7 November 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">81</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Hosein, Hanson</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hosein, Hanson</producer>
    <producer>Hughes, Heather (VI)</producer>
    <producer>Powers, Tom (II)</producer>
    <producer>Powers, Tom (IX)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Hosein, Hanson</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hughes, Heather (IV)</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Independent America: The Two Lane Search for Mom &amp; Pop follows Hanson Hosein (Emmy and Overseas Press Club winner, former NBC journalist) and his wife, Heather Hughes (NBC News) as they hit the road and travel 13 thousand miles through 32 states in search of Independent America. They do it all while abiding by two simple rules of the road: 1) No Interstates: They can only travel on secondary highways and country roads 2) They can only do business with Mom &amp; Pop. No McDonalds, No Best Westerns. No Wal-Marts. The documentary feature uncovers the growing discontent with big box, corporate America. The filmmakers capture pockets of resistance across the country, which adds up to a nationwide opposition: Starbucks is vandalized in Colorado. Supporters of an anti-big box law in Arizona are compared to Nazis. A rebellious Texan city forces Borders Books into retreat. Patriotic residents of America's "Fourth of July" capital in Nebraska start to turn on their new super center. And an entire town in Wyoming goes into business for itself after it's abandoned by its chain department store. And what does the world's largest retailer have to say about it all? The filmmakers stop in Bentonville, Arkansas - home to Wal-Mart - to find out. Independent America: The Two Lane Search for Mom &amp; Pop is a film that encourages people to think hard about where they spend their money. And it offers a rare, and comprehensive view of a country at loggerheads with the free market economy it has mastered.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?264196</url></doc>
