<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="264553">
  <docid>264553</docid>
  <title>Indoor Fireworks</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Rijkelijkhuizen, Bert</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>elevator</keyword>
    <keyword>lift</keyword>
    <keyword>factory</keyword>
    <keyword>digital</keyword>
    <keyword>fireworks</keyword>
    <keyword>crack</keyword>
    <keyword>london-england</keyword>
    <keyword>viper</keyword>
    <keyword>jaguar</keyword>
    <keyword>safe</keyword>
    <keyword>amsterdam-netherlands</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Netherlands">26 September 2003</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">9 November 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">12</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Buitendach, Rudolf</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Higginson, David</producer>
    <producer>Hooijer, Wiendelt</producer>
    <producer>van Helden, Hans</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Hughes, David (XIII)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Badalamenti, Angelo</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Burrows, Spencer</actor>
      <role>Malfie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wadham, Anthony</actor>
      <role>Vince</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wadham, Tony</actor>
      <role>Vince</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>It is the afternoon before Britain's traditional firework night and Cockney low-lifes Vince and Malfie are poised over the blueprints for a Fireworks factory. This is it, their one shot at getting stinking rich. Their plan is real simple - although Vince still has a hard time getting it through Malfie's thick skull. With firework night looming, it's obvious that everyone's been buying fireworks like crazy, right? And therefore the factory must have its coffers stuffed full of money , right? Wrong! The first part of the plan goes easily enough - but after cutting the alarm cables and sneaking inside, the lads discover that the riches seems to have been locked into the sturdiest of combination safes this side of Fort Knox. There's only one solution: lug it back to the car and transport it to the nearest blow-torch. Ah, but the safe proves way too heavy for a flight of stairs and all seems lost until Malfie spots the big old industrial lift and presses the button. It slowly creaks up to the first and then the doors slide open and a warm welcoming light beckons them in. With much effort and cursing they get the safe into the old lift, press the button and down they go - well halfway down anyway! The lift gets stuck halfway between the two floors with the dodgy electrical wiring flicking the lights on and off, and there they are bound to stay as it appears that they have exceeded the maximum weight by at least one big sturdy old safe. In this close confinement tempers begin to fray as Vince and Malfie get to grips with their predicament - and come to blows with each other. But nothing gives - their only salvation appears to be the 'emergency bell' on the control panel. They stare at the cause of their misery - the big old safe, no doubt stuffed with money. With time to kill they decide to try all the possible combinations on the safe. Stuffed with money they can at least try and share a bit of their riches to bribe an emergency electrician or guard into silence and their freedom. Even this plan seems to be pitted against our desperados, however, and as the lift door finally swings open after hours of mind-numbing number-crunching the only thing inside appears to be a tiny slip of paper with the safe's combination code written on it. Our heroes are down but not quite beaten yet, as they bankroll their pockets for all the spare cash they can muster. Finally as dawn breaks outside they press the emergency button and wait. But fate has one final punch-line in store... ...who knew that when they cut the alarm cables they also severed their only link to the outside world? Or that firework factories close down the day before firework night? Ah well, if they can just survive the next nine months...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?264553</url></doc>
