<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="265648">
  <docid>265648</docid>
  <title>Insaaf: The Justice</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">5 March 2004</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="UK">5 March 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Srivastava, Shrey</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Fasih, Mohammed</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Balani, Anant</writer>
    <writer>Mokashi, Chinton</writer>
    <writer>Subhash, Sudhindra</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Nikhil (I)</composer>
    <composer>Vinay (III)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bachchan, Amitabh</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Henna (II)</actor>
      <role>Reena, Journalist</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Joshi, Mohan</actor>
      <role>CBI Officer Pradhan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kunika</actor>
      <role>Minister Rameshwari Verma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Morea, Dino</actor>
      <role>IPS Officer Abhimanyu Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sapru, Tej</actor>
      <role>Inspector Brij Bhushan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shankara, Dayal</actor>
      <role>Narendra "Bunty" Verma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Suri, Sanjay</actor>
      <role>IAS Officer Vishwanath Prasad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vardhan, Varun</actor>
      <role>Yogi, Social worker</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vyas, Shri Vallabh</actor>
      <role>Chief Minister Chandramohan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Yadav, Rajpal</actor>
      <role>Kailu</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Vishwanath Prasad is an Indian Administrative Service officer and lives in Bombay with his wife, Kunti, and a daughter, Sanaa. One night when he returns home, his wife tells him that she has been sexually assaulted and names the culprit as one Bunty. Vishwanath is angered at this outrage and speaks to a senior police officer, who initially offers all help to prosecute Bunty. But when the senior police officer finds out that Bunty is really Narendra Verma, the daughter of Home Minster Rameshwari, he backs off and tells Vishwanath he cannot do anything. Vishwanath then goes to the nearest police station to lodge a F.I.R. (First Information Report), however, Police Inspector Brij Bhushan refuses to write it. When the Governor refuses to meet with him, he telephones the State Chief Minister Chandramohan, who invites him to his house the very next day. The next at the Chief Minister's residence, he finds Rameshwari and Bunty also present there. Chandramohan asks Bunty to apologize, but Vishwanath is not satisfied as he wants Bunty to be criminally prosecuted. Then Bunty's goons take over and start terrorizing Vishwanath and his family. Frustrated, Vishwanath kills himself. His suicide case is turned over to the Central Bureau of Investigation and assigned to Officers Pradhan and Abhimanyu Singh. Shortly thereafter, Bunty and Rameshwari are arrested, charged and the matter is brought to court. The court dismisses the case and Bunty &amp; his mom are set free. Subsequently, Abhimanyu's girlfriend, Reena, gets more evidence, the case is re-opened and a warrant issued for Bunty's &amp; his mom's arrest. It is here that the young and naive Abhimanyu will find how hard it is for justice to prevail especially when the suspect is the son of an influential Home Minister, and that politics does rule above everything else.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?265648</url></doc>
