<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="265722">
  <docid>265722</docid>
  <title>Insatiable</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kirby, Jessie (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>lesbian</keyword>
    <keyword>suspected-paedophile</keyword>
    <keyword>food-crisis</keyword>
    <keyword>cannibalism</keyword>
    <keyword>urinating</keyword>
    <keyword>one-word-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Ireland</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Ireland">2 August 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Australia">18 April 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Switzerland">6 November 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Ireland">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Kirby, Jessie (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>McDonnell, John (I)</producer>
    <producer>O'Riordan, Eva</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Coughlan, Sean</writer>
    <writer>Kirby, Jessie (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Keegan, Brian</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cronin, John (II)</actor>
      <role>John</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Donnelly, Laura (III)</actor>
      <role>Rachel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kearney, Damien</actor>
      <role>Sgt Kenny</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kenny, Jon (I)</actor>
      <role>Mr Harvey</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sheehan, Michael (X)</actor>
      <role>Bobby</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Set in the not so distant future, the economy has crashed and food is rapidly running out. Meat sources are gone due to BSE and a new strain of Chronic Wasting Disease. Bird flu has killed off most of the fowl. The fish in the sea are full of radiation. All over the world vegetable crops are failing. In a small village in Ireland Mr. Harvey a supermarket owner believes he alone can stave off the locals hunger. ELLIE is a 24 year old with no direction in life. Her Mother has been mentally ill for years and Ellie is her sole carer. Ellie works for Harvey in order to keep food on the table. When Harvey suddenly starts selling meat again Ellie has her suspicions that it is not stored pig meat as he claims. RACHEL is Harvey's niece, her family having already perished in the crisis she now depends on Harvey to keep her alive. Her loyalties are torn when she grows close to Ellie. Ellie uncovers that the recently deceased from the village are the main ingredients of the new meat and lets the community know, only to discover that all those purchasing the meat knew all along that it was human. When the meat runs out Harvey and his cohort Sergeant Kenny turn to murder to keep the supermarket fully stocked. Ellie and Rachel fight to stop Harvey continuing his macabre crusade.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?265722</url></doc>
