<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="266006">
  <docid>266006</docid>
  <title>Inside Iraq: The Untold Stories</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Goodwin-Grayzel, Lindsey</editor>
    <editor>Pfrommer, Wolfie</editor>
    <editor>Ray, Rick (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>iraq</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">PG-13</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">31 December 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">84</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Shiley, Mike</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ostrow, Page</producer>
    <producer>Ray, Rick (II)</producer>
    <producer>Okonek, Sharon</producer>
    <producer>Ray, Rick (II)</producer>
    <producer>Shiley, Mike</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Shiley, Mike</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Schroyer, Thomas</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shiley, Mike</actor>
      <role>Mike Shiley</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In March 2003, Mike Shiley was doing what most ordinary Americans were doing-sitting on the sofa, watching the nightly news coverage of Gulf War II and wondering what was really going on in Iraq. Shiley, an avid world traveler, was personally driven to travel to Iraq and produce a documentary film about what was happening behind the scenes. Although Shiley is not a journalist, he convinced local television affiliate KATU in Portland, OR, to grant him permission to cover the Oregon National Guard in Iraq. Shiley still needed press credentials, so he went to his local Kinko's print shop where he ingeniously made a homemade press pass. He then cashed in airline miles and with a single contact name written on a crumpled piece of paper, crossed into Iraq-setting off on a journey that would change his life forever. Armed only with a camera and a local guide, Shiley traveled throughout the country of Iraq for two months, filming unique stories the national media ignores, showing the reality of life in Iraq beyond the media and military spin. Rather than trying to push a political point of view, Shiley let his camera roll, catching a multitude of real-life moments that tell it like it is.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?266006</url></doc>
