<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="266745">
  <docid>266745</docid>
  <title>Interceptor</title>
  <year>1989</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">19 July 1989</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Croft, Annabel</actor>
      <role>Host</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Malric-Smith, Michael</actor>
      <role>Mikie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>O'Kane, Sean (II)</actor>
      <role>The Interceptor</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A successor to 'Treasure Hunt', this game show puts a whole new twist on the old game of hide and seek. Two contestants are each given a locked backpack - one containing £1000, the other merely weighted. No one knows for sure which contains which. The contestants are ferried to remote parts within an area of the English countryside. Within a 45 minute time limit, and guided by the host at a nearby base camp, they must move across the area, gain the key to the other contestant's backpack, meet up, and exchange keys. Trying to stop them is The Interceptor, who will spend most of the game trying to 'zap' the contestants' backpacks with a device that will jam the lock, making it impossible to open. Both the Interceptor and the contestants are allowed to use any mode of transport available - with the Interceptor's preference being his menacing black helicopter, piloted by his long-suffering servant Mikie. The contestants may have to perform a challenge to get their key, but if they succeed in getting it, meeting up, and manage to avoid getting the money-containing pack zapped by the Interceptor, they will win the game.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?266745</url></doc>
