<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="267993">
  <docid>267993</docid>
  <title>Invisible</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Alexandrova, Boryana</editor>
    <editor>Bojanov, Konstantin</editor>
    <editor>Georgieva, Stela</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>street-culture</keyword>
    <keyword>drugs</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>eastern-europe</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Bulgarian</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
    <soundmix>Matrix Surround</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Bulgaria</country>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Unrated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">15 June 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Bojanov, Konstantin</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>McGeehan, J.J.</composer>
    <composer>Tomihisa, Masami</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bunovski, Alexsandar</actor>
      <role>Sasho</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pavlov, Stanislav</actor>
      <role>Stani</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Petrov, Kamen</actor>
      <role>Kamen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Proshev, Rumen</actor>
      <role>Remi</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>After the crumbling of the Soviet empire, heroin flooded the streets of many cities behind the former Iron Curtain. It offered an alternative lifestyle largely unknown until then. In the late 1990s heroin addiction in Eastern Europe had reached epidemic proportions. Invisible takes place in Sofia, Bulgaria and follows a group of six young people on a three year journey through the highs and lows, dreams and tribulations of life with heroin addiction. The story bypasses the social problems and dynamics associated with addiction and focuses on the existential views and philosophy of the participants; it becomes a platform for their ideas and concepts of the world surrounding them. The participants represent a group of "social outcasts", who remain largely invisible in society. They are members of a generation eager to discover and explore the new "commodities". Invisible is unprecedented in the intimacy with which it portrays its subjects. It presents perspectives influenced by euphoria as well as the sobering reality that follows, without passing judgments, without trivializing, denigrating, or exploiting it.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?267993</url></doc>
