<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="268795">
  <docid>268795</docid>
  <title>Is Anybody There?</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kappaz, Philip</editor>
    <editor>Luna, Israel</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Mystery</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>punctuation-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>ghost</keyword>
    <keyword>question-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>secret</keyword>
    <keyword>ouija-board</keyword>
    <keyword>friend</keyword>
    <keyword>spirit</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Luna, Israel</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Luna, Israel</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kappaz, Philip</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Adam, Vikas</actor>
      <role>Zak</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Castro, Al</actor>
      <role>Renzo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cook, Katrina</actor>
      <role>Shopper</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ko, Emily</actor>
      <role>Karen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Magee, Jason (I)</actor>
      <role>Sam</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Martinez, Miranda</actor>
      <role>Miranda</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stapleton, David (II)</actor>
      <role>Joseph Wheeler</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zak, Bob (II)</actor>
      <role>Customer in Store</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Four friends get together one evening to play with a ouija board. Each player is instructed to follow three simple rules: Rule #1:.... Never ask a spirit how he or she died. Rule #2:.... Never ask a spirit how you are going to die. Rule #3: (&amp; most important):......Never stop playing without saying goodbye. While playing the ouija board they encounter three spirits: Maddy, a 6 year old girl, Brenda, a teacher of 35 and Joseph, a man in his 40's, who begin revealing personal secrets about each of the players. The spirits also reveal dark secrets from their own past leading the players to solve the mystery that led them to their demise. As suspicions and conflicts build, the friends are pitted against each other as they become more intrigued with the spirits in the board and the strange way in which they all seem connected. Is it real or is it all just a game? Are the spirits really communicating through the board or is it the subconscious thoughts of the players guiding the pointer? How did these spirits die? Will they break a rule and ask? What would happen if a rule is broken? Is there some strange connection between the friends and the spirts? What would happen if they forget to say goodbye? It's just a game...isn't it?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?268795</url></doc>
