<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="269818">
  <docid>269818</docid>
  <title>It Can Be Done</title>
  <year>1999</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Green, Liz (III)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">22</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>East, Jon (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Jankey, Les</producer>
    <producer>Wilkins, Trey</producer>
    <producer>Brill, Jeanette</producer>
    <producer>Roncoroni, Ginny</producer>
    <producer>Panton, Alex (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>East, Jon (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Sekacz, Ilona</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cameron-Blakey, Nadia</actor>
      <role>Claire Sterling</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Charleson, Brendan</actor>
      <role>Vince Cudlow</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grimes, Frank</actor>
      <role>Wilhelm Reich</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Heenehan, Mark</actor>
      <role>Henry Stone</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Losey, Joshua</actor>
      <role>Silt</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wilkins, Trey</actor>
      <role>John Armstrong</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"It Can Be Done" is set deep in the backwoods of Maine, USA, during 1956 and - in a fictional interpretation of true events - tells the story of a fateful day in the life of Dr Wilhelm Reich, maverick psycho-analyst, bio-physicist and sexual revolutionary. Amidst a climate of McCarthyite paranoia and 50s fear of sexuality, a team of federal agents swoop on Dr Reich's headquarters. Intent on closing down the operations of a lone madman they instead discover a busy research laboratory and encounter the spirited Dr Claire Sterling. She fights a losing battle to stop the agents destroying the laboratory. Meanwhile, Reich struggles to save a cancer patient - John Armstrong - with his controversial "orgone accumulator" and radical body psycho-therapy. As the agents start incinerating Reich's books and axing his equipment, Reich emerges to witness the devastation which he had fled Nazi Germany to avoid. Armstrong, now revealed as the local sheriff, tries in vain to stop the men from Washington. Reich however turns to his fantastic invention - the cloudbuster - to take the upper hand.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?269818</url></doc>
