<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="270124">
  <docid>270124</docid>
  <title>It's Academic</title>
  <year>1961</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Game-Show</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>non-fiction</keyword>
    <keyword>quiz-show</keyword>
    <keyword>high-school</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1961</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Altman, Sophie</producer>
    <producer>Altman, Susan</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>James, Art</actor>
      <role>Host, New York Version (1969-1971)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McGarry, Mac</actor>
      <role>Host</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A weekly quiz game featuring three teams of high school students from their respective schools. Each team had three members, one of whom was captain. Each game consisted of four rounds. In the first three rounds, teams answered questions one team at a time. A packet of ten question would be chosen from twenty packets by a captain of one of the other two teams, and play would proceed. In the first round, teams would be awarded ten points for a correct answer with no penalty for an incorrect answer. A team could pass if it couldn't come up with an answer, in which case one of the other two teams could try to answer at the end of the round. In the second round, teams would still be awarded ten points for a correct answer, but would be penalized ten points for an incorrect answer and five points if they passed on a question. In the third round, teams had the option of doubling point values. If they accepted (and almost always did), they would be awarded 20 points for a correct answer, penalized 20 points for an incorrect answer and ten points for a passed question. There was a two-minute time limit for each team. If a team answered all ten questions correctly, a 50-point bonus was awarded. The final round was known as the grab bag, a three-minute free-for-all in which anyone from any team could respond. A correct answer was worth 20 points, with a 20-point penalty for a wrong answer.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?270124</url></doc>
