<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="270111">
  <docid>270111</docid>
  <title>It'll Have Blinking Eyes and a Moving Mouth</title>
  <year>1993</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Booth, Gary C.</editor>
    <editor>Jordon, Edward</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">3 November 1993</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">88</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Bergh, Jeb</director>
    <director>Jordon, Edward</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bergh, Jeb</producer>
    <producer>Booth, Gary C.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Jordon, Edward</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Flatmo, Micki</composer>
    <composer>Kraus, Dean</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Maybe it'll have wings that go up and down and rotor blades that spin 'round on the top. It might look like a U.F.O., an armadillo or a lobster. It could even be a nine foot tall high heeled shoe! But...First and foremost, it's a kinetic sculpture - a fantastical work of art and people-powered vehicle designed to travel over all-terrain courses. Over twenty-five years ago, California artist Hobart Brown founded the first-ever kinetic sculpture race. From its modest beginnings as a whimsical parade of Dr. Seuss contraptions, the race has grown to become the Triathlon of the Art World - a 38-mile test of creativity, ingenuity and the outer limits of the human spirit. "IT'LL HAVE BLINKING EYES AND A MOVING MOUTH" is a tribute to Hobart Brown and other veteran racers who have not only sculpted magical vehicles, but also magical lives! Part character study and part road rally, the film is a kinetic slice of life about love, art, machines and the artists who pedal them. Alternately funny and poignant, this charming documentary will have you dreaming of your own machine and maybe..."It'll Have Blinking Eyes and a Moving Mouth!"</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?270111</url></doc>
