<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="272323">
  <docid>272323</docid>
  <title>Jackpot</title>
  <year>1974</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Game-Show</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>non-fiction</keyword>
    <keyword>partially-lost-tv-series</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1975</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Gargiulo, Mike (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Vickers, Michael</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Edwards, Geoff (I)</actor>
      <role>Host (1974-1975)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gaynes, Edmund</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Howell, Wayne</actor>
      <role>Sub-Announcer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pardo, Don</actor>
      <role>Announcer (1974-1975)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pardo, Don</actor>
      <role>Himself - Announcer</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"Jackpot" featured 16 contestants attempting to solve riddles and become the "King of the Hill" and share in a potential top prize of $50,000. The 16 players played for the entire week, and it was a common thing for numerous contestants to win big jackpots. At the start of the week, one of the contestants was selected at random to be the "king of the hill". This player stood at a podium facing the other 15 players who represented the numbers 1-15 which each had a dollar value and a riddle. Before the game begins, host Geoff Edwards goes to the big board and reveals what the "Super Jackpot" is worth. The "Super Jackpot" is determined by two numbers: One which is a random value between 10 and 1000, and the second is what the number is multiplied by, which was between 1 &amp; 50. The highest "Super Jackpot" was won on a January 1975 show, and was worth $38,750. The "Super Jackpot" card appeared at least once every 10 shows, but could appear even more frequently than that. During the game, the king of the hill selects a number. That player stands up, says how much their riddle is worth, and reads the riddle. If the king of the hill gets the riddle right, they stay where they are. If they are wrong, they switch places with the riddle reader, and are out for the rest of that game. The jackpot value went up with every riddle read. One player in the game had the "Jackpot" riddle, and the King of the Hill could answer the riddle then or elect to wait and put more money in the jackpot. The way the "Super Jackpot" was won could happen either by the "Super Jackpot" card popping up, or if the jackpot value matched the last three digits of the Super Jackpot total. In the case above, the Super Jackpot could be won if the value hit $750. Also in the game could be double and triple bonus cards which could add more to the jackpot total. The show was on the air for 21 in 1974 &amp; 1975, and was hosted by Geoff Edwards on NBC. The show returned to TV in 1985 on the USA Network with host Mike Darrow, and was taped in Canada. This version gave contestants a chance to win a car as well as cash. Geoff Edwards returned to host a syndicated version of the show in 1989, but when the production company went bankrupt, the show was cancelled in March 1990. Only two episodes of the 1974-75 version exist today, including the $38,750 win. Every episode of the 1985 &amp; 1989 versions still exist, and both have been seen on Game Show Network at various times in the last few years.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?272323</url></doc>
