<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="272780">
  <docid>272780</docid>
  <title>Jai Ganesh Deva</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Shankar, K.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ahuja, Sanjesh</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Viswanathan, M.S.</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ganesh, Delhi</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ganesh, Jai</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ravi, Nizhalgal</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ravi, Radha</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Sage Kondilivar narrates the story of Bhagwan Shri Ganesh to his devotees as well as demonstrates the powers of Ganeshji when he sends his wife, Aasri, to Devlok to seek wealth equivalent to the weight of a mere grass branch which results in Devrajya Indra himself appearing along with Yamraj, Agnidev, Vayudev, Kuber and other Devs in his humble ashram. He also narrates the story of a naive young lad, Nandi, who with Ganeshji's blessings became a scholar; a barren woman, Surekha, who is rescued by Ganeshji in the form of an elephant and is able to conceive; Ganeshji's appearance at the banks of river Kaveri, his meeting with Lankeshwar Vibhishan (brother of Demon-king Lord Ravan) and the Staphana of Vishnu Mandir; Bhagwan Shri Shivji, who is the father of Ganeshji, bestows on Ganeshji the titles of Gyan Siddhi (all knowing); Vinayak (bravery); Vigneshwar (to rid of suffering), and Gajanan (to carry out Shivji's tasks) as well as Ganeshji's tryst with arch enemy Gajmuksura, which leads to a confrontation between Ganeshji and his mother, Devi Maa Parvati, who has sworn to protect her devotee, Premada's husband, none other than Gajmukasur, and the reason why a mouse is associated with Lord Ganeshji.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?272780</url></doc>
