<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="273382">
  <docid>273382</docid>
  <title>James Pond 3: Operation Starfish</title>
  <year>1993</year>
  <type>VideoGame</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1993</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <producers>
    <producer>Easterbrook, Rupert</producer>
    <producer>Shrapnell, Kevin</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Sorrell, Chris</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Joseph, Richard (I)</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>A super spy's work is never done, and that's certainly true in James Pond's case. After being defeated by James Pond at the North Pole, Doctor Maybe heads for the moon with the intention on mining it's vast cheese supply. Taking out an ad in the Vermin Today newspaper he enlists thousands of rats to help him ship the high grade Stilton back to earth, cornering the markets and funding his criminal empire. Luckily F.I.5.H. have sent James Pond after him and he's about to have one crazy adventure across the various, eccentric landscape of our swiss-cheese moon. As James Pond, you must travel to Earth's only natural satellite and foil Maybe's plans before it's too late. With help from Special Agent Finnius Frog whose jumping ability can come in handy you'll have to make your way through more than 100 levels of interstellar action. And don't forget to use the special FI5H gadgets you've got at your disposal: suction boots, fruit gun, x-ray glasses, and a rocket pack. If you're able to survive against Dr. Maybe's 40 different types of enemies, then you'll come face-to-face with the evil mastermind in a showdown that will decide the fate of the world!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?273382</url></doc>
