<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="273571">
  <docid>273571</docid>
  <title>Janam Janam Ke Phere: Alias Sati Anapurna</title>
  <year>1957</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Karkhanis, Kamlakar</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">U</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <directors>
    <director>Desai, Manmohan</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Desai, Subhash</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Desai, Manmohan</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Tripathi, S.N.</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Amar (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Champaklala</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Desai, Manher</actor>
      <role>Raghu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumari, Kanta (I)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumari, Krishna (I)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mahipal</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pande</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tripathi, S.N.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vyas, B.M.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vyas, Satish</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Kamla and Mahapatra live a wealthy lifestyle in a small village in India. They are bereft of any children, they pray to Bhagwan Shree Indra and are blessed with a male child, Raghu. The Astrologer preparing his Janam Kundali (astrological chart) tells them that Raghu will grow up to be an atheist. Alarmed, Mahapatra ensures that Raghu is brought up in a strict Hindu religious background. But Raghu is won over by the four temptations Lobh, Madh, Kaam, and Krodh and becomes an atheist and continues to be one even when he is fully matured. Anapurna, his childhood sweetheart attempts to get him to be a believer, and even marries him for this purpose, albeit in vain. Then one day Raghu walks away from her life, leaving her uncle, Gangadhar, to arrange her wedding with wealthy Kishan, but she refuses. Gangadhar then approaches the Maharaja, who initially decides to oppose Gangadhar's plans, but starts to lust after Anapurna when he himself gets possessed by Kaam. The question remains will Anapurna be forced to marry the Maharaja?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?273571</url></doc>
