<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="273995">
  <docid>273995</docid>
  <title>Japanese Montage</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Egger, Anita</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>tokyo-japan</keyword>
    <keyword>cherry-blossom</keyword>
    <keyword>japan</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">5</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Egger, Anita</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Egger, Anita</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Matsumoto, Taro</composer>
    <composer>Walch, Roger</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>What do you see when you think of Japan? Do you see Temples and gardens, Geishas and cherry blossoms, high rise buildings and masses of people on streets and on trains? Japan is all that - and most amazingly - Japan is a combination of all that. This culture embraces the marriage of the traditional with the modern in a way that is unique and fascinating, awe-inspiring as well as frightening. This film shows Tokyo with its busy streets and chaotic architecture. Both in daylight as well as at night, this mega city is colourful and vibrant. Tokyo can be rather ugly with its seeming lack of urban planning, but viewed from above as well as at street level Tokyo is a fascinating city with many different facets. Then there is Kyoto, the old capital with its thousands of temples and shrines. In the film Kyoto takes on the traditional role with Maikos (young aspiring Geishas) on their "coming out day", temple gardens and its most famous symbol, the Golden Pavilion. The third aspect of Japan is its natural beauty, depicted in the film by cherry blossoms, fields of flowers and bamboo forests. Last but not least it is the music that gives the film its distinct form. The music is derived from the title melody of a Japanese TV series called "Zatoichi", about a blind Samurai who helps the poor and fights the bad.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?273995</url></doc>
