<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="274147">
  <docid>274147</docid>
  <title>Jasa Baap Tashi Poore</title>
  <year>1991</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Tawde, Dattaram</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Marathi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">1991</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Khande, Madanmohan</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Domane, Harish S.</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhalekar, Suhas</actor>
      <role>Bhujangrao Amrutrao Sahukar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deo, Ajinkya</actor>
      <role>Shekhar M. Thorat</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kharshikar, Avinash</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kubal, Alka</actor>
      <role>Pooja M. Thorat/Pooja T. Sahukar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Malhotra, Madhu</actor>
      <role>Ruby/Chandrabagha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Oak, Girish</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Parkhi, Chandu</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Saraf, Ashok</actor>
      <role>Raja</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shende, Sunil</actor>
      <role>Mangatram Thorat</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Surve, Chinmai</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Widower Mangalram Thorat lives a wealthy lifestyle in a small town in India along with his sons, Kumar and Shekhar, and a daughter, Pooja. He is a honest and principled man who has been the Sarpanch for many years. When Kumar falls in love with fellow medical-collegian, Anita, and brings her home to get his dad's blessings, Mangalram rejects her as she is the daughter of a prostitute, questions her character, forcing her to reject Kumar and leave. Kumar takes to alcohol in a big way and gets frequently into trouble at the local bar and subsequently with the Police. Shekhar then falls in love with Varsha, Raja's sister, and both get married with Mangalram's blessings. Then Mangalram's childhood friend, Bhujangrao, who runs the local bar, sexually molests and kills a woman named Kesar. Mangalram witnesses this and despite of Bhujrangrao's wife, Kalawati, and son, Toofan's pleas, testifies against Bhujrangrao, leading him to be found guilty and hanged. The past comes back to haunt Mangalram when Pooja falls in love with Toofan and gets married to him, not knowing that both Toofan and Kalawati have devised a scheme to get rid of the Thorat family one by one. When he hears that Pooja is being abused and beaten, Mangalram intervenes and attempts to bring her back home, he is viciously attacked by Toofan and his men and left on the street. He is subsequently hospitalized - and the doctor treating him is none other than Dr. Anita herself. Questions that remain unanswered are will Pooja be able to free herself from her cruel mother-in-law and husband, and will Anita actually treat the man who humiliated and rejected her?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?274147</url></doc>
