<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="275588">
  <docid>275588</docid>
  <title>Jenny's Journal</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>north-idaho</keyword>
    <keyword>sandpoint</keyword>
    <keyword>breast-cancer</keyword>
    <keyword>cancer</keyword>
    <keyword>idaho</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">25 August 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">26</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Bock, Jeff</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Meyer, Jenny (III)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In 2000, Jenny, was diagnosed with breast cancer...she also found out she was pregnant. Against doctor recommendations, she decided to carry the baby to term. During that time, she kept a journal of her thoughts...things she felt she couldn't tell anyone on account of the somber nature and depth of the valleys she encountered while battling cancer. I grew up with Jenny in the small town of Sandpoint, Idaho and hadn't seen her since graduation in 1992. During a visit with my high school journalism teacher, Marianne Love, we discussed Jenny's situation and felt so strongly about it that we decided we had to do something... anything. So, in the summer 2003, we began to document Jenny and her family, if for nothing else, for posterity. Over three years of filming, we all developed a close relationship and Jenny began to truly trust us with intimate details of her life. It is Jenny's hope, that her candid personal story will benefit others, and help them in some small way...to understand and validate their thoughts, their fears. Jenny's Journal is an emotional and sincere confessional, as she reveals what it feels like to live with cancer. The film illuminates Jenny's struggle using the beautiful scenery of her Northern Idaho home as a metaphor for her outward persona, in juxtaposition with her internal thoughts. Jenny's struggle inspires hope through the strong support of her friend April, her husband Jeff, and her now five-year-old daughter, Grace.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?275588</url></doc>
