<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="275577">
  <docid>275577</docid>
  <title>Jenny and Friends</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Grey, Ian (II)</editor>
    <editor>Simpson, David (XIII)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">6</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Torjussen, Ruth</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Peel, Phil</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Torjussen, Ruth</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Forsythe, Tracy</actor>
      <role>Trudi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Masterton, Leanne</actor>
      <role>Jenny</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Jenny's act as a Marie Osmond impersonator is proving increasingly unsuccessful. It seems the moment she starts to sing 'Paper Roses' everyone leaves for a cigarette outside. Her husband Lonny who is a big hit as Donny (despite being black) tells her to not take it personally, but Jenny finds it hard not to. Nothing is going her way these days. Her best friend has died, her other friends have moved away and she misses them so very much. And its not easy at 40 to conjure up a whole new social circle. Especially when you are such a complete and utter snob! Then one day Jenny sees Trudi coming down the college stairs towards her. Beautiful, glamorous Trudi... Jenny quickly makes it her mission to befriend this gorgeous woman. She arranges a make-over party and excitedly tells Lonny that she is inviting Truid to the big event. Alt least she is trying to tell him but is interrupted but the noise coming over the fence from her trashy neighbor Dawn and her kids and dogs. She slams the back door in an attempt to keep the noise out. Lonny wonders why she doesn't ask Dawn to the party - after all Dawn is always friendly to her. Jenny is outraged! Dawn is not her type and she won't be Trudi's either. But at the make-over party something happens to change her mind. Trudi doesn't show and Dawn turns out to have a lot more in common with Jenny than she could ever imagine...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?275577</url></doc>
