<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="276213">
  <docid>276213</docid>
  <title>Jesus, the Son of God</title>
  <year>1995</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Koford, James</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>bible</keyword>
    <keyword>cartoon</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>christian</keyword>
    <keyword>christianity</keyword>
    <keyword>kids-and-family</keyword>
    <keyword>jesus-christ</keyword>
    <keyword>new-testament</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 June 1995</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Rich, Richard</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Noss, Terry L.</producer>
    <producer>Tobin, Thomas J.</producer>
    <producer>Martin, K. Douglas</producer>
    <producer>Young, Seldon</producer>
    <producer>Brown, Jared F.</producer>
    <producer>Rich, Richard</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Nissen, Brian (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>de Azevedo, Lex</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bailey, Maikel</actor>
      <role>Joseph</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Best, Jonathan (I)</actor>
      <role>Young Jesus</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Crosland, Ivan</actor>
      <role>Jesus</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Farrell, Kevin (I)</actor>
      <role>Head Rabbi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hilsee, Joe</actor>
      <role>Young Pharisee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jackson, Pat (VII)</actor>
      <role>Mary</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Keeler, Daniel A.</actor>
      <role>The Voice of God</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lisell-Frank, Robert</actor>
      <role>Captain</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McCallum, Sandy</actor>
      <role>Priest</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Porter, Ray (I)</actor>
      <role>Satan/Narrator</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Jesus, the Son of God begins with Jesus, Mary and Joseph traveling to Jerusalem for the Passover in 13 A.D. Young Jesus, age twelve, walks behind His parents carrying a lamb. Jesus is to present the lamb to the priest as a sacrifice for sins. Once inside the busy, noisy city full of trading and bartering, Jesus and His family sell and buy the things they need before taking the lamb to the priest. Jesus presents the lamb to the priest, and the priest tests Him by asking some questions about the law. Jesus' answers are correct and the priest congratulates Him. Later, the family leaves Jerusalem to travel home only to find that Jesus is missing. Joseph and Mary return to the city after three days of searching and find Jesus talking with priests outside the temple. Jesus is confused that his parents are worried because He thought they would know He was about His Father's business. Jesus returns home with Mary and Joseph and grows into a caring young man trained in the art of carpentry. Joseph's death is shown as Jesus grows into an adult. Sadly Mary says goodbye to Jesus, and He walks into the wilderness. Jesus is baptized by John the Baptist. A white dove is shown flying above and the voice of God is heard saying, "This is my beloved Son in whom I am well pleased." Jesus is then led into the wilderness by the Spirit where He seeks wisdom from the Lord by fasting. While in the wilderness for 40 days, Jesus is tempted three times by Satan. Jesus rebukes Satan the final time by saying, "Thou shall not tempt the Lord thy God." Satan leaves as Jesus is worshiping His Father. A light from heaven descends upon Jesus. Angels come to comfort, feed and clothe Him. Jesus then returns to Galilee with the power of the Spirit.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?276213</url></doc>
