<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="276601">
  <docid>276601</docid>
  <title>Ji yin jue ding wo ai ni</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>bathtub</keyword>
    <keyword>deoxyribonucleic-acid</keyword>
    <keyword>fungus</keyword>
    <keyword>internet-chat</keyword>
    <keyword>ex-boyfriend</keyword>
    <keyword>car-crash</keyword>
    <keyword>diet</keyword>
    <keyword>biotechnology</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Mandarin</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Taiwan</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Taiwan">PG-12</certificate>
    <certificate country="Singapore">PG</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Taiwan">31 August 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Singapore">11 October 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Lee, Yun Chan</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Yeh, Michelle (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Lee, Yun Chan</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ho, Peter (I)</actor>
      <role>Anteater</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kwan, Terri</actor>
      <role>Gigi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Peng, Eddie</actor>
      <role>Teddy</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Gigi and Marlene, two single women both in their late 20's, work at a bio-technology company, researching and developing medicine to suppress specific genes and observe their effects on the human body. Gigi is born with the "clean-freak" gene and her obsession with keeping things tidy causes problems in her relationships. Marlene, on the other hand, is born with the "fat gene" and needs to regularly take pills to maintain her weight. Marlene panics when she learns that her "anti-fat" pills will be taken off the market. Their personal problems coincide with romantic ones. Marlene grows frustrated maintaining her long-distance relationships via the Internet, and Gigi leaves her boyfriend when she discovers he's cheating on her. One day, Gigi meets Anteater, her college sweetheart, and they start dating again. Things are going well, and Gigi just cannot remember why she had broken up with Anteater until the day they are about to consummate their passion, Gigi discovers Anteater's terrible secret -- he is a first rate slob! Meanwhile, Marlene is oblivious of the feelings Teddy, the landlord's son, has for her. Realising that their own genetic make-up is the cause of their relationship issues, Gigi and Marlene decide to take an "anti-clean gene" pill. Gigi and Marlene no longer care about their own appearances, but will the two women find true love and happiness without the help of technology?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?276601</url></doc>
