<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="276731">
  <docid>276731</docid>
  <title>Jibber Jabber</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>L'Hirondelle, Tyronne</editor>
    <editor>Payton, Trent</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="France">2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">22</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Bowes, David (III)</director>
    <director>Kyffin, Bronwen</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Poskitt, Patti</producer>
    <producer>Corbett, Jim (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bowes, David (III)</writer>
    <writer>Flanagan, Sandy</writer>
    <writer>Fordham, Dennise</writer>
    <writer>Fredericks, Roger</writer>
    <writer>Greenberg, Paul (I)</writer>
    <writer>Hagen, Annika</writer>
    <writer>Heaton, Dennis</writer>
    <writer>Kay, Edward (I)</writer>
    <writer>Nicolle, Victor (I)</writer>
    <writer>Slama, John</writer>
    <writer>Sullivan, Steven (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Plowman, Michael Richard</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ball, Ashleigh</actor>
      <role>Jabber (2007)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barr, Kathleen (I)</actor>
      <role>Jibber/Mom (2007)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bell, Dorla</actor>
      <role>Marcy (2007)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mondy, Bill</actor>
      <role>Jelly Roll/Dad (2007)</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"Race to the Red Planet" Captain Jib and Commander Jab blast off to be the first astronauts to land on Mars, and end up finding out that intelligent life does exist there. "Pride of Frankenstein" Dr Jibberstein and trusty assistant Jabgor give life to the ultimate creation: the Jessicastein Monster! "Pirates of Privacy" Pirates Captain Jib Beard, Long Jab Silver, and Jessica Anne Bonnie square off in their hunt for buried treasure. "Mutiny of Privacy" The search for Jessica Anne Bonnie's treasure continues, and the real culprit is revealed "Cartoon Satellite" When an SOS transmission comes in, Captain Jib and Commander Jab must brave a space walk in order to repair the cartoon satellite. "Flu Day" With Jabgor succumbing to the plague, Dr Jibberstein must concoct a cure to save him before it's too late. "The Wrong Stuff" Captain Jib and Commander Jab set off to find out what truly exists at the end of the universe... and beyond. "Do You See What I See" When Jibber and Jabber suddenly become invisible, they enjoy their newfound freedom - only it's not all it's cracked up to be. "Jelly's Belly" When Jelly Hound is struck with a mysterious illness, Dr Jibberstein and Jabgor attempt to diagnose and treat the patient - but is the problem too big for them to handle? "Pirates of Nowhere" Captain Jib Beard, Long Jab Silver, and eternal foe Jessica Anne Bonnie find themselves stranded on a deserted island, and must work together to save themselves from going mad. "Kung Food" Martial artists Jib Lee and Jabby Chan face off against the oppression of Jessica Feudal Lord's reign. "The Greatest Wall" Jib Lee and Jabby Chan build a wall to prevent Jessica Feudal Lord's bossiness from spreading to the other provinces. "Enter the Jelly" When Jabby Chan is falsely accused and imprisoned for breaking a priceless vase from the Mom Dynasty, Jib Lee must set off to save his brother from the perils of the Room of Doom. "Book of Endings" Superheroes Jib Man and Jab Boy battle the evil Jessica Villain for possession of the Book of Endings. "The Chamber of Perils" When the source of all their powers goes missing, Jib Man and Jab Boy must retrieve it before it's too late, or risk becoming mere mortals. "Brain vs Brawn" With the fate of the entire universe at stake, will it be brains or brawn that will save the day? "Night of the Werewolf" A werewolf is on the loose, and Sir Duke of Jib and his manservant Jabbury must track it down before the curse of the werewolf is passed on. "Lady Jess and Ms Hyde" When half-mad Lady Jess acts even stranger than usual, Sir Duke of Jib and Jabbury are determined to find out what causes her multiple personalities. "Night of the Vampire" Sir Duke of Jib and Jabbury must triumph over the evil Count Jessula before she turns the entire household into vampires. "No Such Things As Ghosts" When ghosts terrorize Jib Jab Manor, Sir Duke of Jib and Jabbury are on the case. "Space for Sale" Captain Jib and Commander Jab's scheme to sell land on Mars hits a snag when they come up against the Queen of Mars. "One Bad Asteroid" Jessica Alien's asteroid-shooting cannon threatens to end the world, unless Captain Jib and Commander Jab can save the day. "Pirates Plunder Blunder" Captain Jib Beard and Long Jab Silver must rescue their crew from the clutches of Jessica Anne Bonnie. "Attack of the Giant Worm-A-Noids" It's Halloween, and Dr Jibberstein and Jabgor's experiment to improve the life of worms goes horribly wrong. "April Fools Rules" When Jibber and Jabber's pranks go too far, they must become invisible in order to escape the wrath of the entire family. "Double or Nothing" Jibber and Jabber recount their adventures and argue over who always saves the day in this battle of egos.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?276731</url></doc>
