<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="277167">
  <docid>277167</docid>
  <title>Jimmy and Della</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Molina, Jorge (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">11</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Molina, Jorge (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Molina, Jorge (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Molina, Jorge (II)</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>"Jimmy and Della" tells the story of a young boy who wrongs his unsuspecting sister and pays for the misdeed with his greatest desire. The story begins with Jimmy and his sister, Della, heading home when he accidentally breaks his hand-held 'Gamebox' video-game system, revealing it is made of Lego bricks. Della innocently suggests to him he may receive a real Gamebox at Christmas. Jimmy's curiosity drives him to snoop for his gifts in his parent's room, only to realize there is no Gamebox in his future. By chance, Jimmy comes across a old Gamebox for sale at a secondhand shop. But he has no cash, only hope and desire. Jimmy scours his bedroom looking for enough money to buy the used Gamebox. During his search, he hears Della leave the house and Jimmy succumbs to the temptation to extend his search to Della's room which is when he sees her music player. At this point Jimmy makes a choice that affects him, his sister and their relationship; a choice that will lead to a series of disappointing ramifications but finally ends with a mature self-realization.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?277167</url></doc>
