<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="277761">
  <docid>277761</docid>
  <title>Joan of Arc</title>
  <year>1996</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 June 1996</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Rich, Richard</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Nissen, Brian (II)</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>As a young girl, Joan lived in the French countryside. One day, she heard voices from heaven talking to her. The voices told Joan that she was called to help fight for the freedom of France. They also told her that Prince Charles was to be anointed and crowned the rightful king of France. Joan went to see Prince Charles but the Prince said to send her away. The warrior, Le Hire, reminded Charles of a prophesy that said a young maiden would save France. Prince Charles agreed to see Joan but planned to prove that she was a fake. Charles switched clothes with his tailor and hid in the crowd of people when Joan entered the room. He believed if Joan had special powers, she would be able to identify him. Joan was not fooled and she quickly bowed before him. The Prince was convinced so he made her a commander in his army. Under Joan's command new supplies and soldiers made it into Orleans and the English fled. Talbot, the leader of the English military, believed Joan must be a witch because she could not have beat the English in battle without the help of the devil. Joan was captured and tried on the charges of witchcraft and heresy. Cauchon, a bishop of the church, found Joan guilty and sentenced her to death by fire. After Joan's death La Hire and Dunois asked King Charles for control of the army. They wanted to continue what Joan had begun. The war continued for twenty two years before Joan's people were set free. Twenty five years after Joan's death, the trial condemning her was pronounced invalid and her name was cleared.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?277761</url></doc>
