<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="278482">
  <docid>278482</docid>
  <title>John Osborne and the Gift of Friendship</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Palmer, Tony (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Biography</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">8 May 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">128</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Palmer, Tony (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Peat, Kim</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bloom, Claire (I)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Burton, Richard (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hare, David (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Heilpern, John</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Olivier, Laurence</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Osborne, John (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Richardson, Tony (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tynan, Kenneth</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In 1956 John Osborne changed the face of British theatre with his emotionally charged play, Look Back in Anger. Set in a scruffy flat in a typical town in the Midlands, and starring anti-hero Jimmy Porter as the first "angry young man" railing at national apathy, the play captured the imagination of the increasingly disillusioned post-war British public. A unique aspect of this two-hour film about the playwright is the recent discovery of extracts from some of the original stage performances of Osborne's most famous plays, material of great historical importance not seen for almost 40 years - Laurence Olivier in 'The Entertainer'; Albert Finney in 'Luther'; Nicol Williamson in 'Inadmissable Evidence'; Robert Stephens in 'Epitaph for George Dillon'; Jill Bennett in 'A Patriot for Me', with a very young John Osborne as Reidl, as well as behind-the-scenes footage from Osborne's Oscar-winning film Tom Jones. Contributions are from Richard Burton, David Hare, Kenneth Tynan, Tony Richardson, Claire Bloom, John Heilpern (Osborne's authorised biographer), Peter Nichols, Christopher Hampton, Jocelyn Herbert, Charles Wood, Kenneth Tynan, Tony Richardson, Natasha Richardson, Lindsay Anderson, Peter Bowles, Ben Walden, Terence Frisby, Bill Bryden, Sylvia Syms, Bill Kenwright, Robert Fox, Anthony Page, and the late Helen Osborne.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?278482</url></doc>
