<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="280106">
  <docid>280106</docid>
  <title>Joy in the Morning</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Atwater, Gina</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>sister-sister-relationship</keyword>
    <keyword>family-relationships</keyword>
    <keyword>male-female-relationship</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">April 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">17</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Atwater, Gina</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Atwater, Gina</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Atwater, Gina</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Bryan, Courtney</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hill, Stephen (VII)</actor>
      <role>Jonah</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McClyde, Nedra</actor>
      <role>Nikki</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Nikki is unhappy with her life and can't seem to walk away from her adulterous affair with her neighbor, with whom she's scheduled a life-changing appointment this afternoon. Nikki's plans are routed when her sister Sasha shows up at the door, bringing Joy, Nikki's 10-year-old autistic niece, whom she promised she would baby-sit. Nikki's tries to connect with Joy, who hides behind the sofa and quotes her favorite Biblical passages. Despite these difficulties, Nikki finds herself intrigued by her niece. When she confesses these feelings to Joy, Joy slaps her in response, thinking it all to be a joke. At the abortion clinic, Nikki confronts Jonah with her suspicions that she's just one in a long line of women he's brought there, and tells him she's thinking of becoming a mother. When he informs her that she's unfit for motherhood, Nikki realizes that he thinks nothing of her. She leaves the clinic to return to Joy. Joy is not home when Nikki returns. Nikki finds her in the park, desperately trying to catch fish in a frozen pond. Nikki successfully calms Joy down by finally learning to speak her language. In this moment, Nikki realizes that in her own special way, Joy does love her. When it's time for Joy to go home, Nikki tries to hug her, thinking they've found a connection. Joy is unresponsive. Nikki watches her niece and sister leave, not sure of what to do with the rest of her life.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?280106</url></doc>
