<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="280267">
  <docid>280267</docid>
  <title>Ju-yon-sai</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Japanese</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Japan</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Netherlands">28 January 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Netherlands">114</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Hirosue, Hiromasa</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Takahashi, Izumi</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fujii, Kaori (II)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hirosue, Hiromasa</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kagawa, Teruyuki</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Sensitive and refined drama in which experiences from the puberty of a female teacher and a piano student reflected in the world of the younger generation they have contact with. Ryo is a young teacher who, unlike her colleagues, does not adopt an authoritarian attitude to the adolescents she has in her care. She does not realise at first that, by doing this, she is putting herself at risk. The 14-year-olds feel misunderstood by the adults who insensitively snuff out their young ambitions. When their frustration grows, the adolescents turn into secretive and hard-bitten kids. As a result, Ryo is thrown back in time and confronted with her own dark past, in which she resisted the insensitive world of her superiors. Then she meets Koichi, a man she knows from her studies. He was a talented pianist in his youth, but his ambitions were also made impotence by an adult. Now he works for the local electricity company and he has allowed himself to be persuaded to give piano lessons to the son of a colleague. It becomes clear that Ryo and Koichi have shared experiences that they can only now relive and then come to terms with. Fourteen is an atmospheric and subtle drama in which two different generations mirror each other in the most vulnerable period of their lives</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?280267</url></doc>
