<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="281191">
  <docid>281191</docid>
  <title>Julian Fellowes Investigates: A Most Mysterious Murder - The Case of George Harry Storrs</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Mystery</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">24 September 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Santana, Dominic</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hamill, Sara</producer>
    <producer>Alan, Clare</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Fellowes, Julian</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Beare, Virginia</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>De Candole, Katrine</actor>
      <role>Maria Hohl</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fellowes, Julian</actor>
      <role>Himself - Presenter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kennedy, Helen</actor>
      <role>Kate Kenworthy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McCaul, Neil</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Miller, Sarah (IV)</actor>
      <role>Marianne</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Schofield, David</actor>
      <role>George Harry Storrs</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In this dramatic re-creation, Julian Fellowes presents the unsolved murder of George Harry Storrs. On November 1, 1909 an intruder killed Storrs during the family's evening meal. Storrs was very well off and very much a man for the 20th century. He was particularly interested in manufacturing automobiles. In middle age, he had become infatuated with and has an affair with Maria, the pretty young governess working for the family next door. They had planned a holiday together but suddenly, she ups and leaves for studies at Oxford. Maria returns but soon commits suicide and soon after Storrs begins to receive threatening notes. Storrs also had business disputes with his brother, a distant cousin to whom he had refused a job and a handyman, the friend of a household servant he fired when he caught them together. In two subsequent trials, the accused were acquitted but Fellowes presents his own views on the identity of the murderer.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?281191</url></doc>
