<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="281437">
  <docid>281437</docid>
  <title>Jump Britain</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Baldwin, Olivia</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>parkour</keyword>
    <keyword>free-running</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">6 January 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Christie, Mike</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Smith, Mike (XXXIII)</producer>
    <producer>Gallagher, Dominic</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Christie, Mike</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Beach, Thomas (II)</composer>
    <composer>Masterson, Ian (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Aoues, Jerome Ben</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Corkery, Paul</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Foucan, Sebastien</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kerr, John (VIII)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Milner, Ben (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Last year a team of French Free Runners captivated Londoners when they scaled some of the city's most famous landmarks from the Albert Hall to HMS Belfast for Channel 4's Jump London . This time they've decided to take on the whole country in a new project that ranges from Edinburgh to Cardiff. Free Running, or Le Parkour, involves literally leaping from roof to roof in a death-defying, yet beautiful, series of jumps, slides and somersaults. It is a discipline combining an extraordinary athleticism and lack of fear - created by Sebastien Foucan and his friends - that has spread across the world. Foucan sees Free Running as more than a spectacle, it is a way of life, with a spiritual dimension plucked from popular culture and allowing an escape from everyday reality. For Jump Britain , Foucan and his team are joined by members of the burgeoning UK Parkour scene as they tackle some of the UK's most iconic sites including Edinburgh Castle and the Forth Rail Bridge in Scotland, the Giant's Causeway and Derry's Walls in Northern Ireland, the Millennium Stadium in Cardiff, the Tyne Bridge in Newcastle and the ICC in Birmingham. Dir: Mike Christie; Prod: Dominic Gallagher; Exec Prod: Mike Smith; Prod Man: Nial Fulton</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?281437</url></doc>
