<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="282044">
  <docid>282044</docid>
  <title>Jurm</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Mehan, Kuldip K.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>arrest</keyword>
    <keyword>revenge</keyword>
    <keyword>suspicion</keyword>
    <keyword>stadium</keyword>
    <keyword>double-cross</keyword>
    <keyword>faked-death</keyword>
    <keyword>trial</keyword>
    <keyword>escape</keyword>
    <keyword>false-accusation</keyword>
    <keyword>shot-in-the-leg</keyword>
    <keyword>friend</keyword>
    <keyword>false-imprisonment</keyword>
    <keyword>malaysia</keyword>
    <keyword>lawyer</keyword>
    <keyword>paranoia</keyword>
    <keyword>water</keyword>
    <keyword>terror</keyword>
    <keyword>wrongful-conviction</keyword>
    <keyword>fugitive</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">A</certificate>
    <certificate country="UK">15</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">10 February 2005</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Kuwait">23 February 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Bhatt, Vikram</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Singh, Aashish</producer>
    <producer>Singh, Anurag</producer>
    <producer>Singh, K.P.</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Anand, Raj Anand</composer>
    <composer>Malik, Anu</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deol, Bobby</actor>
      <role>Avinash Malhotra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dutta, Lara</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Sanjana Malhotra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gunaji, Milind</actor>
      <role>Prosecutor Sanjay Pathak</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Shakti (I)</actor>
      <role>Chamanlal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shaq, Vivek</actor>
      <role>Harry (Taxi driver)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Soman, Milind</actor>
      <role>Rohit</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vidyarthi, Ashish</actor>
      <role>Inspector Vishnu Patnaik</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>An astrologer forecasts that wealthy industrialist Avinash Malhotra will find his soul-mate on new years' eve. Avinash disbelieves this, but does attend the party and he meets his dream-girl and soul-mate, Sanjana, and both in love with each other. They get married and settle down in a harmonious lifestyle. Shortly after this, Avinash notices very odd behavior on her part, as she leaves the house at very odd hours, and when he is not present, lies to him about where she has been, and does not answer the phone. He follows her. He finds out that she has a secret male lover. When he confronts her, an argument ensues, and Avinash drinks himself to sleep. The next morning he is woken up by Police Inspector Vishnu Patnaik, arrested and charged with killing Sanjana. On being questioned, Avinash admits that they did have an argument, but he does not remember anything thereafter as he had too much alcohol. Avinash's advocate friend, Rohit, does not think that he is a killer and is on the verge of proving it in court, when a man claiming to be Sanjana's maternal uncle, Chamanlal, gives evidence that he had seen Sanjana being killed at the hands of her husband, and that her body is buried in the backyard. The police locate the body, identify it as that of Sanjana, and the court sentences Avinash with the death penalty. While being transported to jail, Avinash manages to escape in order to try and find out who killed his wife, and who framed him. Only to run into Rohit - who wants Avinash dead, and take over his vast estate and property.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?282044</url></doc>
