<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="283532">
  <docid>283532</docid>
  <title>Kaash... Hamara Dil Pagal Na Hota</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Datta, Sanjib</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Anand, Mangal</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Harish (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Roy, Hirju</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ahuja, Mukesh</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Aneja, Chetan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Borade, Nigel</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Goyal, Ramesh</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Iyer, Divya</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Katariya, Geeta</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Afzaal</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Rashi</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mirza, Nasreen</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Purandare, Mithun</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Saxena, Rajeev</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sharma, Ajay (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Singh, Sunil (V)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tiwari, Mukesh</actor>
      <role>Commentator</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A reigning monarch, Raja Mahendra Pratap, in India has a problem, to be precise five problems, from five different wives, all deceased now, in the shape and form of his sons, Shiv, Veer, Gyan, Rudra, and Surya, who have grown up, are matured, but still behave like children. While one son is on the look out for a golden deer; the other goes through their swimming pool looking for a mermaid; the third is a walking talking Bollywood directory full of dialogs from Mughal-E-Azam and Sholay; the fourth is obsessed with Raat Rani; and the fifth with kites of all shapes and colors. In order to find a solution, the Raja consults with Dr. Lapadia, who advises him to get his sons married. For this purpose, Dr. Lapadia brings five women, namely Noorie Topaz, Geeta Delhiwali, Sita Devi, Julie Lele, and Bobby Veerappa. The five women befriend the five brothers, hot romance ensues, and soon the brothers believe that their problems have been solved and each has met his soul-mate. What Mahendra Pratap and his sons do not know is that these five women are nothing more than pick-pockets, con-women, prostitutes, and thieves, and their only goal is to marry the princes, with Dr. Lapadia's help, get hold of a map and a key that will lead them to the location of the royal treasure.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?283532</url></doc>
