<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="283626">
  <docid>283626</docid>
  <title>Kabhi Na Kabhi</title>
  <year>1998</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Gopalakrishnan, N.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">17 April 1998</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Priyadarshan</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Akhtar, Javed (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Rahman, A.R.</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anand, Tinnu</actor>
      <role>Chabiley</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bagga, Darshan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhatt, Pooja (I)</actor>
      <role>Tina</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hanifa, Cochin</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hattangadi, Rohini</actor>
      <role>Tina's aunt</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Anil</actor>
      <role>Rajeshwar 'Raja'</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kitty (V)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Menon, Suresh (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mohan, Mac</actor>
      <role>Tatya</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nath, Alok</actor>
      <role>Rajeshwar's Father</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rawal, Paresh (I)</actor>
      <role>Kachra Seth</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shroff, Jackie</actor>
      <role>Jaggu</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Kachra Seth (Paresh Rawal) runs an empire of collecting garbage, which is merely a front to cover-up for his other business - drug trafficking. He recruits a select group of people to carry out unpleasant tasks - such as beating someone up, or even killing someone. One of his recruits is Jaggu (Jackie Shroff), who will do anything for a price. Jaggu loves Tina (Pooja Bhatt) but is afraid to tell her. When Jaggu's mom is hospitalized, he comes to Kachra for monetary assistance, he is assigned to a task instead, and unable to complete the task he is apprehended by the police with the assistance of a librarian (Alok Nath), and is subsequently found guilty and sent to prison. Jaggu's place is taken by Rajeshwar alias Raja (Anil Kapoor), who is also attracted to Tina and even rescues her from one of Kachra's goons, Chabiley (Tinnu Anand), and they both fall in love. When Jaggu returns from prison, he finds his mom has passed away, and his sister is missing, believed to have committed suicide. In anger, he concoctes a fool-proof plan to kill the librarian, and he does so. Jaggu does not know that the librarian is none other than Raja's dad, and Raja has sworn to hunt down his dad's killer, no matter what.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?283626</url></doc>
