<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="286980">
  <docid>286980</docid>
  <title>Karearea: The Pine Falcon</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>wildlife</keyword>
    <keyword>new-zealand</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>falcon</keyword>
    <keyword>natural-history</keyword>
    <keyword>environment</keyword>
    <keyword>human-interest</keyword>
    <keyword>animal-behavior</keyword>
    <keyword>conservation</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>New Zealand</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">14 November 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="New Zealand">49</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Crichton, Sandy</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Thomas, Richard (XXV)</producer>
    <producer>Crichton, Sandy</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Crichton, Sandy</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Marsh, Nick (II)</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Whilst working as an optician during the 1970's George Chance develops an obsession: something that occupies every moment of his spare time for a whole decade. Through skills passed down from his father, George becomes the most accomplished photographer of the New Zealand falcon. He dreams of capturing his beloved falcons as moving images but, restricted by the cost of film equipment, he reluctantly gives up. Now some thirty years later the time has come to reawaken George's dream. At the age of 88 and going blind, George is being called upon one more time. In the winter of 2003 a film-maker from Scotland, looking to make a film on the New Zealand falcon, approaches George looking for advice; they quickly strike a deal. In return for George's help, film-maker Sandy Crichton will attempt to add movement to George's photographs. Set in commercial pine plantations, the film follows a remarkable wild population of falcons that have adapted to take advantage of this man-made habitat. Featuring completely new falcon behavior, and filmed over three breeding seasons, the film-maker gets ever closer to the falcons as he attempts to deliver his side of the bargain.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?286980</url></doc>
