<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="287765">
  <docid>287765</docid>
  <title>Katalog</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Geroulanos, Stefanos</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>futuristic</keyword>
    <keyword>sickness</keyword>
    <keyword>surveillance</keyword>
    <keyword>francis-bacon</keyword>
    <keyword>monster</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">20 August 2005</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">29 July 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">14</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Ajami, Rania</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ajami, Rania</producer>
    <producer>Burkholder, Tai</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Ajami, Rania</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Rocker, Matt</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Casey, John (VIII)</actor>
      <role>Mr. Nacob</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kryzaniwsky, Alexandria</actor>
      <role>Mira</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Malina, Judith</actor>
      <role>Nurse Ned</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Troya, Ilion</actor>
      <role>Mr. Yomkin</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In early 2006, in response to changing forms of international crime, the state renamed itself as The Organism and embarked on a bold project of biological cataloging and people management. To control citizens through their most minute biological details, the organism has created a group of highly skilled "Katalog Men" who are sent to empty homes in order to database the smears and banalities of citizen's daily existence. While looking for biological clues at the house of a state representative, expert katalog man Mr. Nacob finds himself at the mercy of the Organism and under surveillance by his superior. Accused of incompetence in identifying sexual crimes, and suffering from stomach pains, Mr. Nacob is sent to the Nurse in command. A notorious figure in the medical world and the owner of a slimy, cigarette-smoking, meat-blob monster, Nurse Ned diagnoses a serious malady that makes Nacob vulnerable to the Organism's new extermination program. She warns Nacob: he'd better shape up and stop his maladies "from eating away at his mind," or else he'll find himself looking like the slabs of meat hanging at the back of her office. At his next assignment, Nacob unexpectedly encounters a young woman. He instantly finds himself caught under the spell of this strange, beautiful girl who insists he not leave her. Why is this apartment occupied? Is she a cure for his stomach pains, or another tool for his demise? As time passes, the sense of fear and foreboding on the part of Nacob intensifies, until...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?287765</url></doc>
