<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="288780">
  <docid>288780</docid>
  <title>Keao</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Curtis, Dena (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">10</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Spenser, Emily Anne Kaliko</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Mita, Merata</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bantilon, Shelby</actor>
      <role>Dancer 3</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carter, Brandon (IV)</actor>
      <role>Tai</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Crabbe, Keaohiwahiwaokaluanui</actor>
      <role>Keao</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grieg, Napua</actor>
      <role>Chanter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kaiaokamalie, Nohea</actor>
      <role>'Awa man 1</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kaowili, Ipo-Lei</actor>
      <role>Tita</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Naho'olewa, Dale</actor>
      <role>'Awa man 3</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nakanelua, Kyle</actor>
      <role>'Awa man 2</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A young Hawaiian girl goes to work at the Hotel Lu'au show where she dances with a cast of other young Polynesian dancers. It appears to be a usual evening at work, backstage as she is getting ready, until she is interrupted by a new edition to their costumes. She is handed a coconut bra and told it is the new wardrobe requirement for some of the dances. She immediately feels uncomfortable as she holds the coconuts in her hands. She does not want to wear them, but she is unsure why she feels so uneasy about the situation. She looks at all the cultural motifs around her and back at the coconuts, they seem to be tormenting her. Then, deep in thought, she begins to have flashbacks of an 'awa ceremony steeped in sacredness and spirituality as she envisions the coconut cups being filled up with 'awa (cermonial drink of Hawai'I). Why would she put a sacred cup on her breasts? She puts down the bra and gathers up some of her things and walks out feeling happy and relieved to have come to a personal realization about portraying her identity and culture.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?288780</url></doc>
