<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="288999">
  <docid>288999</docid>
  <title>Keeping It Good</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Schofield, Scott (I)</editor>
    <editor>Willinger, Lisa</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>guildhall-school-of-music-and-drama</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">5 September 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">15</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Kinkaid, Samantha</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Gauthier, Brenda</producer>
    <producer>Kinkaid, Samantha</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Brewer, Richard J.</writer>
    <writer>Kinkaid, Samantha</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Holland, Paul Kessell</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kinkaid, Samantha</actor>
      <role>Cherry</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Salas, Jacob</actor>
      <role>Benjamin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Schilling, Stephen</actor>
      <role>Roy</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Looking to escape their criminal past, Cherry and her husband Benjamin have left the grubby street life of Los Angeles behind and settled into the small farming community of Visalia. Clean and sober for five years and expecting their first child, everything is looking up for the young couple. That is until Roy re-enters their lives. Roy, Benjamin and Cherry go way back. In fact, it is because of Roy that Benjamin spent several years in prison. Roy is a Sopranos wannabe who is always looking for the next big score. Now he has set up a meeting with Benjamin and is looking to suck him back into his former life. Unknown to Benjamin, Cherry sets out to meet with Roy on her own. Using every argument she can, she pleads with Roy to go away and leave them to their new life. He refuses. When it becomes clear that Roy is not going to leave them in peace, Cherry murders him and dumps his body along with his car into a local reservoir. She then returns to her home where she and Benjamin will continue in their new life.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?288999</url></doc>
