<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="290112">
  <docid>290112</docid>
  <title>Keynotes</title>
  <year>1992</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Music</genre>
    <genre>Game-Show</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Australia">1992</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Ots, Peter</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wilkins, Richard (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself - Compere</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Two teams of four people each compete in three rounds offering progressively larger amounts of money. In each round, the teams compete to see who can correctly guess a tune based on some or all of its first nine notes. Some of the notes (usually three or four) are automatically revealed at the start of the round. To reveal the other notes, players from each team compete in a face-off where one person selects a card to see which keynote they are playing to reveal. The two players then have to guess the next word of the song played to them, choosing from three possible answers. The person who selects the correct answer and is the first to do so wins control for their team, who then hear the revealed keynotes and have to guess what tune begins with them. The first team to guess correctly wins the money on offer. If no one can come up with the correct tune after all nine notes have been revealed, the money for that round goes begging. After the three rounds, the winning team plays for a major prize, again by having to correctly guess a tune. The team have 60 seconds of listening time to collect as many of the nine keynotes as they can. They have a button that they press to see which keynote they will play for, then after three possible answers are revealed, they listen to a piece of music, pressing the button again to stop it when they think they can guess which of the possible answers is the next word in the song. A note will appear in the spot if they are correct, but a blank appears there if they are wrong. When the team has heard nine music pieces or runs out of time (when any unrevealed notes become blank), they have to guess the tune with the notes that they have revealed, winning the major prize if their guess is correct.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?290112</url></doc>
