<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="290237">
  <docid>290237</docid>
  <title>Khamoshh... Khauff Ki Raat</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Khan, Asif (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">A</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">15 April 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Tijori, Deepak</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Saiyed, Shahid</producer>
    <producer>Singh, Sanjay (II)</producer>
    <producer>Aggarwal, Rahul</producer>
    <producer>Tijori, Deepak</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Adi (II)</writer>
    <writer>Jayarajan, Bijesh</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Pandit, Jatin (I)</composer>
    <composer>Pandit, Lalit</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ali, Shawar</actor>
      <role>Senior Inspector Jatin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bedi, Rajat</actor>
      <role>Varun</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chawla, Juhi</actor>
      <role>Dr. Saksi Sagar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deshpande, Makrand</actor>
      <role>Manas Dutta</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dorji, Kelly</actor>
      <role>Criminal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gill, Avtar</actor>
      <role>Justice D S Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hirjee, Vrajesh</actor>
      <role>Adi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Irani, Adi</actor>
      <role>Shekhar Menon</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pradhan, Vishwajeet</actor>
      <role>Sukhvinder</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shrestha, Raju</actor>
      <role>Advocate</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Singh, Rajiv</actor>
      <role>Avinash</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Haughty and arrogant Kashmira, a Bollywood movie actress, travels with her Secretary/Chauffeur, Avinash, through the Indian countryside on a night of heavy rains. Also traveling in the same area is a prostitute by the name of Sonia, who carelessly stops her car in the middle of the road, dropping a knife and a fork. The fork punctures the tire of another passing vehicle consisting of Sukhwinder, his wife, Mitali, and son. When Sukhwinder attempts to fix the tire, Avinash's car comes roaring by, hits Mitali, almost killing her. Avinash stops the car, gets Sukhwinder and his family in with a protesting Kashmira and stops at a motel for help. Once inside, they find out that there is only the Manager, Adi, and no one else, and due to the rains there is no working telephone, Avinash must now drive 20 km to reach a hospital to get help. He picks up Sonia, who car has stalled, and together they make their way to the hospital only to find that they cannot proceed any further due to floods. To make matters worse, their car breaks down, leaving them stranded. Another car driven by Varun, in the company of his wife, Mahek, comes on the scene, and they assist Avinash and Sonia to get back to the Motel. Also stranded at the motel are Senior Inspector Jatin and a murderous convict who is being transported to jail. It is at this motel that all of them will find that one of them is a killer - and the rest - his victims.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?290237</url></doc>
