<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="290239">
  <docid>290239</docid>
  <title>Khamoshi</title>
  <year>1969</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Musical</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>remake</keyword>
    <keyword>tragedy</keyword>
    <keyword>melodrama</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">127</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Sen, Asit (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Geetanjali (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Gulzar (I)</writer>
    <writer>Mukherjee, Ashutosh</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Mukherjee, Hemanta</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Advani, Bhudo</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhardwaj, Brahm</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dharmendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Mr. Dev (Patient #24) (Guest Appearance)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ghosh, Tarun</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hussain, Anwar (I)</actor>
      <role>Biharilal Gupta</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hussain, Nasir (I)</actor>
      <role>Dr. Colonel Saab</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Iftekhar</actor>
      <role>Doctor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khanna, Rajesh</actor>
      <role>Mr. Arun Choudhury (Patient #24)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Polson</actor>
      <role>Patient</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Verma, Deven</actor>
      <role>Patient #22</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Colonel Saab is also a doctor in a psychiatric hospital in India. His particular interest is in treating patients with a acute mania, which he describes is caused by the male child's longing for the unconditional love he gets from his mother, and after he separates from her, he searches for this love in other women, until he meets the one who he feels is capable of offering the same. But when that does not happen, the male child becomes cynical, full of hatred, and distrust and develops acute mania. His hospital nurse, Radha, had successfully treated one such patient by the name of Dev, and now they have another one by the name of Arun Choudhury. A reluctant Radha is asked to act as his caring mother-like nurse, to gain his trust, love him, and then make him ready to face everyday life. What Colonel Saab, Dev, and Arun do not realize what this is doing to Radha herself when she feels that she cannot act anymore and becomes more and more involved in her patients' lives, knowing fully well that she has to keep up a professional attitude, and that the patient is going to be discharged soon, and may not even remember the care, love and treatment he received from Radha. Radha has now to decide to carry on being a nurse, without being a woman, who is quite capable in falling in love with Dev, and again with Arun.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?290239</url></doc>
