<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="290689">
  <docid>290689</docid>
  <title>Kichiro</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Eipe, Tascha</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>killing</keyword>
    <keyword>blood</keyword>
    <keyword>singapore</keyword>
    <keyword>secondary-school</keyword>
    <keyword>massacre</keyword>
    <keyword>gore</keyword>
    <keyword>japanese</keyword>
    <keyword>violence</keyword>
    <keyword>pervert</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Japanese</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Singapore</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Singapore">R21</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Malaysia">30 November 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="China">December 2006</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Canada">5 April 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Singapore">20</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Sng, Kelvin</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Tan, Eugene</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Sng, Kelvin</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Gooi, Tah Choe</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chaar, Fish</actor>
      <role>Video Shop Boss</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chen, Andie</actor>
      <role>Alex</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Koh, Amy (II)</actor>
      <role>Kichiro's Mother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Liang, Stiven</actor>
      <role>Alex's Father</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Makio, Ken</actor>
      <role>Kichiro</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Phua, Joe</actor>
      <role>DJ</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Suziki, T.</actor>
      <role>Kichiro's Father</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Kichiro is an only child born to a Japanese father and a Chinese mother. As his father is the CEO of a top Japanese company and his mother is the principal of a prestigious secondary school, all his classmates and friends, including his teachers, never treat him with any sincerity. They are nice to him simply because of whom his parents are. In addition, Kichiro also feels estranged from his parents as they are always busy working and never really spend much time with him. They think that by giving Kichiro the best in terms of material needs, they will be able to make up for their lack of time spent with Kichiro. Due to lack of monitoring and lots of free time on his own (a common problem in today's society when both parents are working), Kichiro spends his time indulging in pornographic materials and twisted stuff. He soon develops a fetish for bodily violence and he really feels 'alive' when he tries to execute it on Dawn, one of the girls who turn up at his house party. However, nobody knows about this perverted side of his. One day at a video shop, Kichiro meets Alex, who happens to be similar in character and background to him. They hit it off immediately as Alex invites Kichiro back home to watch some banned DVDs of extreme violence. They soon discover that both of them have always fantasized about putting such graphic violence into reality. This mutual revelation further strengthens their resolve to put the wanton violence they have seen on videos into action...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?290689</url></doc>
