<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="291584">
  <docid>291584</docid>
  <title>Kill Your Inner Child</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Steinhoff, Laura</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">8 October 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Bernstein, Samuel</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Shore, Ronald</producer>
    <producer>Carrelli, Bari</producer>
    <producer>Krost, Barry</producer>
    <producer>Shevick, Jerry</producer>
    <producer>Knauff, Tim</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bernstein, Samuel</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bernstein, Samuel</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Garcia, Luz</actor>
      <role>The Maid</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Palmer, Steve J.</actor>
      <role>Adam</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vescio, Dave</actor>
      <role>Aaron</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The world of "Kill Your Inner Child" is based on the true tales of screenwriter/author Samuel Bernstein's mondo-beyondo childhood with his bipolar, explosive-yet-charming father, Adam. Sam is a six year-old Kidnap Victim, Texas Slave, Vegas Runaway, Jew in Egypt, Mama's Boy Without a Mom, and potential Homicidal Maniac with a tragic lack of mechanical reasoning skills. He brings a resourceful sense of feeling and fantasy to every situation, like an emotional MacGyver-no jury-rigged tools-but plenty of metamorphic ideas for making human contact. His father, Adam, the Naked Dad, is a self-proclaimed Socialist and the Smartest Person in the World. He'll tell you so himself. And after his divorce from Sam's mother he takes all the kids with him, though he doesn't have custody. As Adam supports various left wing causes in South America and the Middle East he takes the whole brood, three boys a little girl and his new young wife. He espouses Socialism and individual resistance while living the luxurious, single-minded life of a McDictator. Through the travels and self-contained adventures of Adam, Sam wants passionately to escape Adam and return to his mother-devising various paths to freedom that don't quite work out. For his part, Adam wants passionately to convince Sam that he is better off with him, traveling the world, absorbing his wisdom. Never mind that they don't see eye-to-eye, they aren't even looking at the same universe. Sam's take on the madness that was his childhood is boldly hilarious: Filled with adventures that keep you on the edge of your seat, peopled with sharply drawn characters that constantly flabbergast, and defined by the comical, oddball point of view that not only kept Sam alive, but makes his stories so unique.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?291584</url></doc>
