<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="291822">
  <docid>291822</docid>
  <title>Killerbus</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Fehse, Marc</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>German</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Germany">30 November 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">35</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Fehse, Marc</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bethmann, Andreas</producer>
    <producer>Block, Volker</producer>
    <producer>Fehse, Edgar</producer>
    <producer>Fehse, Marie</producer>
    <producer>Volger, Gerhard</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Block, Juliane</writer>
    <writer>Fehse, Marc</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gödde, Björn</actor>
      <role>Christoph</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jerome, Ingo</actor>
      <role>Eimar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kirbas, Sefik</actor>
      <role>Smutje in der Vargangenheit</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kümürcü, Orhan</actor>
      <role>Twoface</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lopez, Zoraya</actor>
      <role>Chantal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rampke, Jörg</actor>
      <role>Robert</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Scarpellini, Mario</actor>
      <role>Karl</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Schleberger, Reiner</actor>
      <role>Sergio Profit</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Yilmaz, Murat</actor>
      <role>Smutje Gegenwart</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Somewhere, in the midst of snowy peaks and monumental rocks three gangsters are cruising in one of the coolest vehicles the world has ever seen: the Killerbus! Twoface, Christoph and Chap, who's called Smutje by his two companions, carry out orders which are slightly outside the law. Chap is the new one of the team. Christoph and Twoface are telling him of his predecessor, the old Smutje. The target of the last order was Sergio Profit. Location: an old storehouse used by Profit for an illegal auction of fighting dogs. The signed up whore Chantal is seducing Karl, Profits bodyguard. Meanwhile the killers are breaking armed through the roof of the storehouse. The audience of the auction with Sergio Profit is trapped. Killerbus is one of the most innovative short films in 2004. Besides it's cool design and the fabulous vehicle of the gangsters, the movie is convincing with a high number of small details. There is the Trip in the brothel Balandros with it's fantastic animations or the Killerbus Street Pursuit, which take place first of all in the head of Karl, Profits Bodyguard. If you're a friend of dark humour and if you like cool guys, extremely cool guys;) Killerbus is the right movie for you!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?291822</url></doc>
