<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="293159">
  <docid>293159</docid>
  <title>Kiraware Matsuko no issho</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Japanese</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Japan</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Japan">12 October 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Sakai, Masahiro (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kijima, Seiichiro</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Yamada, Muneki</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Hasebe, Toru</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hamada, Manabu</actor>
      <role>Detective Goto Kouhei</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kaname, Jun</actor>
      <role>Ryu Youichi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Koike, Eiko</actor>
      <role>Sawamura Megumi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Koyanagi, Yû</actor>
      <role>Watanabe Sho</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nasubi</actor>
      <role>Ookura Shuji</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Satoh, Bsaku</actor>
      <role>Principal Tadokoro</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A dark melodrama about a woman whose life descends into a downward spiral due to love, ill fate and recklessness. It's 2006. The dead body of 56-year old Kawajiri Matsuko, is found in a downtown apartment where she lived alone. Asuka is surprised that she had an aunt by the name of Matsuko. Her father tells Asuka to clean up Matsuko's place. In Matsuko's trash-filled room, Asuka discovers a photograph.Why did someone, surrounded by her family looking so happy, have to be killed? Asuka starts to follow Matsuko's life. It's 1973. After graduating from a national university, Matsuko became a junior high school teacher. During a school trip, she covered up for a student who was caught stealing. But she suffered disgrace for her actions and was expelled from school. Driven into a corner, Matsuko choked her physically weak sister Kumi to death and fled from the house she was born and brought up in. Matsuko's father, Kozo, always doted on Kumi while he was severely strict with Matsuko. However, this was just the beginning of the downfall of a woman named Matsuko Kawajiri.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?293159</url></doc>
