<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="294169">
  <docid>294169</docid>
  <title>Klaustrophobie</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Dessbesell-Schüler, Carlos</editor>
    <editor>Herhoffer, Janina</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>German</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Germany">6</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Germany">4 July 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">13</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Dessbesell-Schüler, Carlos</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Chrystowska, Monica</producer>
    <producer>Dessbesell-Schüler, Carlos</producer>
    <producer>Chrystowska, Monica</producer>
    <producer>Dessbesell-Schüler, Carlos</producer>
    <producer>Schulze, Peter (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Chrystowska, Monica</writer>
    <writer>Dessbesell-Schüler, Carlos</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Cobo, Luis Miguel</composer>
    <composer>Wiese, Björn</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kiebranz, Johannes</actor>
      <role>Blinder</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Krause, Horst</actor>
      <role>Bauer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stadlober, Robert</actor>
      <role>Klaus</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A young rebel oversteps the border between stage and life on the trail of 'François Villon' (qv). The sensuous-poetic film is an appeal to dream and a homage to the great actor 'Klaus Kinski' (qv). Klaus is an actor and lives a life between attack and escape from love and desperation. He leaves the city while searching for expression and finds a place to hide that he uses as his stage. At this far away place he bares his inside. The farmer whom the barn belongs to is distraught and can't cope with the intruder's power of articulations. He tells him to get off that place. The young man keeps searching and finds an oasis of freedom in a sunflower field. While lying in the middle of those flowers he devotes to his yearning for love. He speaks Villon's poem "I fell in love with your red hair". Because of being deeply moved by the sunflowers' beauty, he takes one of them as a sign for his love back to the city. On his way he gets again and again into situations of obsessive self-uncovering. The borders between life and stage merge and makes him to the mockery of his fellow human beings. Klaus changes into a tragic-funny figure. His odyssey finally leads him onto a theater stage. But his yearning for expression, love and devotion stays unsatisfied.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?294169</url></doc>
