<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="296395">
  <docid>296395</docid>
  <title>Koning van de wereld</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>boxing</keyword>
    <keyword>bare-butt</keyword>
    <keyword>gay-sex</keyword>
    <keyword>love-scene</keyword>
    <keyword>bathrobe</keyword>
    <keyword>road-accident</keyword>
    <keyword>male-nudity</keyword>
    <keyword>pow</keyword>
    <keyword>sauna</keyword>
    <keyword>sex-scene</keyword>
    <keyword>male-rear-nudity</keyword>
    <keyword>gay-interest</keyword>
    <keyword>tv-mini-series</keyword>
    <keyword>sidecar</keyword>
    <keyword>towel</keyword>
    <keyword>kissing</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Dutch</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Belgium</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Belgium">6 December 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Belgium">55</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Henderickx, Guido</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Corbin, Greg (I)</producer>
    <producer>Hamelinck, Bert</producer>
    <producer>Van Passel, Frank</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Didden, Marc</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Helewaut, Hans</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Broods, Natali</actor>
      <role>Julie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Claessens, Benny</actor>
      <role>Fabien</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Damen, Katelijne</actor>
      <role>Moeder</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>De Bouw, Koen</actor>
      <role>Romain Vandewalle</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>De Pauw, Josse</actor>
      <role>Oom Platon</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>De Schrijver, Damiaan</actor>
      <role>Dumont</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Decleir, Jan</actor>
      <role>Trainer Max</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Degand, Stefaan</actor>
      <role>Aloïs</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dottermans, Els</actor>
      <role>Nancy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Goossens, Carry</actor>
      <role>Vader Miel Vandewalle</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Janssens, Kevin</actor>
      <role>Stan Vandewalle</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vercruyssen, Frank</actor>
      <role>Kets</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Verstraete, Mark</actor>
      <role>Dr. Wolf</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>van Dijck, Rikkert</actor>
      <role>Bernier</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>[PART 1] During World War II, Stan Vandewalle saves boxing trainer Max from the bombed German war prisoners camp, and shoots two German soldiers while escaping. After the war, Stan resolves to put all his frustration over the death of his slow-witted brother Aloïs, who dreamed of becoming an opera singer, with his side-car against a farmer's truck in making come true Aloïs other dream, to see Stan becoming 'king of the world' as boxer. After Max introduces him to wealthy, greedy gay manager Dumont, his career takes a rocketing start, but he gets none of the proceeds. Stan's elder brother Romain, an honorless philanderer, finds out the cheating but prefers to demand his cut instead as exclusive bookie... [PART 2] Now sonny Fabien Dumont understands, like trainer Max, reminding Stan of Alois's death awakes enough hatred to make him win, he becomes Belgian national champion. After bookmaker Bernier takes revenge for Romain's betting exclusivity by having manager Dumont's boxing license revoked by the Belgian federation 'because of his war collaboration past', the cheaters who keep even dad Miel -who now has an open affair with a prostitute- at arms-length sell Stan to manager Kets, another shark, while keeping a stake. Mother Françoise's idea to go with her and Max to Cuba and stay with Miel's estranged brother Platon, another wheeler-dealer who had to flee Belgium but hopes to return, is accepted for a month. A local 'easy' girl proves a romantic bonus for Stan, but is actually part of a plan to make him lose a match after an overdose of night life to break his pride. [PART 3] Platon has recruited Romain to help awake the worst in Stan- he says to have fucked Stan's thus scorned ex Martha in Belgium, which induces a non-requited declaration of love to Julie. The brothers embrace each-other and nightlife although Stan realizes Romain is parasitic scum. Max makes him train hard again. After a loss against a black Cuban, Stan decides to return to Belgium, where Bernier has Dumont killed. Kets arranges a European title fight and top sport doctor Wolf for him, no more women allowed. Julie expects his baby but they decide not to keep it. Dad Miel's prostitute mistress Annie sends him back to his wife. Kets and Romain plan Stan wins now but loses the rematch, to make a bundle on bets. [PART 4] ???? The nasty game is played according to plan. Max worries about the hormonal preparates the quack gives Stan ... [PART 5] The big fight ...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?296395</url></doc>
