<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="297976">
  <docid>297976</docid>
  <title>Kristo</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Filipino</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Philippines</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Philippines">2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Espiritu, Jerwin D.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Maceda, Carlo</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Espiritu, Jerwin D.</writer>
    <writer>Gohetia, Charliebebs</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bovick, Aleck</actor>
      <role>Barbie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>De La Paz, Dido</actor>
      <role>Hudas</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Del Rosario, Monsour</actor>
      <role>Kapitan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fermo, Steven</actor>
      <role>Andrew</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lucero, Weng</actor>
      <role>Magda</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Luna, Katherine</actor>
      <role>Lina</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Manalo, Jay</actor>
      <role>Pedring</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vasquez, Christian</actor>
      <role>Karyo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Webber, Herman</actor>
      <role>Johnny</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>del Moral, Vaness</actor>
      <role>Mary</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Sabong or cockfighting is a national pastime in the Philippines. The bloody game knows no boundaries; economic classes merge, holidays are not recognized and the addiction inflicts anyone. Boundless as it seems, there is a seemingly incorruptible form of power struggle that goes on between the roosters fighting for their lives. This reflects the struggle that afflicts the lives of the gamblers who make money out of them. Within the noisy walls of the cockpit, the smell of money, power and testosterones echo the aggression of two roosters trained to kill its opponent. Word of honor and honesty are major elements in the cockpit's unwritten Code of Ethics. KRISTO is about three cunning kristos whose lack of honesty in collecting bets causes them hard lessons. Set in the rural barangay of San Pedro Cutud in Pampanga, the area's colorful celebration of the Holy Week becomes the backdrop of the film. KRISTO mirrors the struggles and dilemmas of a Filipino family. It also tackles issues on betrayal, greed, the dysfunctional hierarchical society and the gamblers' fixation towards barbarianism.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?297976</url></doc>
