<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="297920">
  <docid>297920</docid>
  <title>Krishnagudiyil Oru Pranayakalathu</title>
  <year>1997</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <editors>
    <editor>Rajagopal, K.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Malayalam</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Kamal (V)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Mohan, R. (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Kamal (V)</writer>
    <writer>Renjith</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Vidyasagar</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Augustine (I)</actor>
      <role>Gangadharan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jagadish</actor>
      <role>Jose Abraham</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jayaram (I)</actor>
      <role>Giri Menon</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Vineeth</actor>
      <role>Balan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Madhavan, Kavya</actor>
      <role>Anjali</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Menon, Balachandra</actor>
      <role>Pavi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Menon, Biju</actor>
      <role>Akhilachandran</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Prasad, Narendra</actor>
      <role>Meenakshi's Father</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Siddique (II)</actor>
      <role>Renji</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Meenakshi's and Akhilachandran's marriage is fixed by their family. Akhil is a spoiled brat and his behavior towards Meenakshi and her family is always very rude. Still Meenakshi's father decides to go ahead with their wedding as he has a guilty feeling that it is because of him that Akhil has no parents now. Meenakshi's father dies and she comes to Krishnagudi with her sister Uma and family. Giri is the railway stationmaster at Krishnagudi and a close friend of Uma's family. Meenakshi, who is always moody gets back to her life with the little jokes and the nice behavior of Giri. Giri starts to have a liking towards Meenakshi and he says this to Uma's husband Pavi. But Meenakshi rejects his proposal saying that though she likes Giri, she has to keep the word that her father had given to Akhil. Giri asks Meenakshi to write to Akhil about Giri's proposal and if he doesn't come before the next six months, Meenakshi will decide to marry Giri. Will Akhil come or not forms the rest of the story.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?297920</url></doc>
