<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="299074">
  <docid>299074</docid>
  <title>Kung aagawin mo ang lahat sa akin</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Filipino</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Philippines</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Philippines">22 June 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Gacho, Rommel</director>
    <director>Lee, Topel</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Asuncion, Rich</actor>
      <role>Joyce</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Blanco, Jackie Lou</actor>
      <role>Doña Clara Andrada</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Buencamino, Noni</actor>
      <role>Don Gilbert Andrada</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Flores, Jace</actor>
      <role>Dino</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Garcia, Emilio</actor>
      <role>Victor Samaniego</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Garcia, Patrick (I)</actor>
      <role>Arvin Samaniego</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Magalona, Maxene</actor>
      <role>Maureen Andrada</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tiuseco, J.C.</actor>
      <role>Troy Samaniego</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>de Castro, Glaiza</actor>
      <role>Gladys Andrada</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Don Gilbert Andrada and his wife Doña Clara Andrada always wanted to have children. But due to Doña Clara's heart problem, conceiving a child would prove fatal for her. One stormy night, a mysterious woman gave two baby girls to Don Gilbert in a relief operation. He named them Maureen and Mercedita. Don Gilbert arranged the papers so the children would be legally theirs. But Doña Clara cannot accept the children. She said they are not hers. She became pregnant with Don Gilbert, he tried to convince her to abort but she didn't agree. Surprisingly, she actually survived the pregnancy and bore a baby girl named Gladys. Gladys always envied her sisters because of their father's attention. She tormented her sisters, while Doña Clara encourages her to maltreat them even more. She was encouraged even more when she learned that they where adopted and she's the only real daughter. Gladys cannot comprehend why everything she wanted falls to Maureen, so she tries to ruin Maureen's life with schemes, try to get Maureen's love away from her and use Mercedita against her own sister. Gladys tries to take away everything from her sister, but unknown to herself, she is only taking away her own joy and happiness.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?299074</url></doc>
