<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="299169">
  <docid>299169</docid>
  <title>Kunku Zale Vairi</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Doke, Shailendra</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Marathi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Darak, Nagesh</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Deshmukh, Deepak Vilasrao</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Dhumal, Dhananjay</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ambole, Raja</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Amrapurkar, Sadashiv</actor>
      <role>Tatya</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhonsle, Nagesh</actor>
      <role>Satish Rao</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jodha, Samrudh</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kiran, Prema</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mahabole, Kishor</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sathi, Surendra</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shinde, Sayaji</actor>
      <role>Arjun Maane Patil</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Kamal lives a poor lifestyle with her widowed mom in Padgaon, Maharashtra, India. She is an excellent student and was awarded the best chess player. When she returns home her mother wants her to get married to Arjun Maane Patil of Adgaon Village to which she consents. The marriage takes place and Kamal re-locates to live with Arjun and his parents, who own acres of farm-land, but are unable to grow anything due to poor monsoons and Arjun's lack of interest, as he wants to utilize this land to build a school. Kamal takes it upon herself to plant a variety of chilies, tomatoes, ginger, etc. and even markets them. With the money coming in, she is encouraged by her in-laws to dig a well with considerable success. Arjun is however dissatisfied. He finds out through a local politician, Tatya, that the State Government has reserved some seats for women to preside on the local council. Generally Tatya hand-picks people to sit on this council, and when he meets the seemingly demure and arrestingly beautiful Kamal, he does not hesitate in throwing in his support for her as the new Chairperson. Kamal does reluctantly accept this position, is elected, manages the farmland, household chores, and is all set to start setting things right. She does not realize that Tatya wants to rule over the Council through her; the Deputy Chair, Satish Rao, is more intent on seducing her; while Tatya's opponent, Sopan Shinde, is all set to poison the water reservoir; and her alcoholic husband has a separate agenda of his own - which includes abusing and sexually molesting her, and forcing her to obey his and Tatya's instructions as for him politics is nothing but 'pure cheating'. The question remains will Kamal be able to persist and do some good for Adgaon?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?299169</url></doc>
