<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="299251">
  <docid>299251</docid>
  <title>Kunwara Baap</title>
  <year>1974</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Deshpande, Bhagwant</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>social</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">U</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">23 November 1974</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Mehmood (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Chhabria, Amarlal P.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Quaisi, Aziz</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Roshan, Rajesh</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ali, Abbas (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ali, Mumtaz</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bachchan, Amitabh</actor>
      <role>Augustine (Guest Appearance)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bali, Yogeeta</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bharathi (I)</actor>
      <role>Radha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dharmendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself (Guest Appearance)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hussain, Nasir (I)</actor>
      <role>Principal of Bishop Cotton Junior College</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khanna, Vinod</actor>
      <role>Police Inspector Ramesh (Guest Appearance)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Sanjeev (I)</actor>
      <role>Doctor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Malini, Hema</actor>
      <role>Herself (Guest Appearance)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Manorama (II)</actor>
      <role>Sheela</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maruti (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mehmood (I)</actor>
      <role>Mahesh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mehra, Vinod</actor>
      <role>Vinod (Guest Appearance)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mikki (III)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mukri</actor>
      <role>Hawaldar (Constable)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sen, Asit (I)</actor>
      <role>Referee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Singh, Dara (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself (Guest Appearance)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sunder (I)</actor>
      <role>Pandit (Priest)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tiwari, Bhushan</actor>
      <role>Kalu Dada</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Born without any knowledge of his parentage, Mahesh drives a bicycle rickshaw for a living in a town in India, prays to Bhagwan Shri Kishan, and lives in an unhealthy shanty hut. He is friendly with Sheela, who works as a maidservant, hopes to marry her someday, much to the chagrin of Kalu Dada, who lusts after Sheela. One night while returning home he comes across an abandoned male baby near Bhagwan Shri Ganesh's Mandir. He looks for the family of this child, asks for help from the Mandir's Poojary, as well as a Mullah and a Hawaldar, all in vain. When he tries to abandon the child, he is literally forced to adopt him, and when he does so, he faces considerable opposition from his neighbors, and ends up hating the child. He neglects the child, and as a result the child gets inflicted with polio. Mahesh has a change of heart, decides to look after the child, names him Hindustan, starts his treatment, gets him crutches, and after facing many hurdles, gets him admitted in Bishop Cotton Junior College. 12 years later Hindustan has grown up, overweight and still dependent on Mahesh and needs a bone stimulant surgery to keep the equal lengths of his limbs. Mahesh needs 1000 Rupees, and attempts to wrestle, Dara, as well as run in a rickshaw race, all in vain, as he is severely beaten and injured by Dara, and Kalu respectively. He decides to work day and night to earn this amount. But before he could even start saving any amount, he is arrested by Police Inspector Ramesh for kidnapping Hindustan, and may end up losing Hindustan to Vinod and Radha, who claim to be his biological parents. Watch what happens when Mahesh is compelled to testify in Court and comes face to face with the witnesses who have come forward to testify against him.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?299251</url></doc>
