<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="299955">
  <docid>299955</docid>
  <title>Kya Kehna</title>
  <year>2000</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Musical</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>class-differences</keyword>
    <keyword>abortion</keyword>
    <keyword>tradition</keyword>
    <keyword>playboy</keyword>
    <keyword>shame</keyword>
    <keyword>pregnancy</keyword>
    <keyword>seduction</keyword>
    <keyword>taboo</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby SR</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">UA</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">19 May 2000</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Shah, Kundan</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Taurani, Kumar S.</producer>
    <producer>Taurani, Ramesh Sadhuram</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Irani, Honey</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Roshan, Rajesh</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhaduri, Rita</actor>
      <role>Ajay's mom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jalal, Farida</actor>
      <role>Rohini Baxi (Priya's mom)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Saif Ali</actor>
      <role>Rahul Modi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kher, Anupam</actor>
      <role>Gulshan Baxi (Priya's dad)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lagoo, Reema</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mamik</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Singh, Chandrachur</actor>
      <role>Ajay</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vashist, Puneet</actor>
      <role>Priya's brother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Verma, Deven</actor>
      <role>Rustom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Verma, Rajeev</actor>
      <role>Mr. Modi</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The story is about Priya Bakshi (Preity Zinta), the daughter of Gulshan (Anupam Kher) and Rohini Bakshi (Farida Jalal). Priya has her parents, brothers and best friend, Ajay (Chandrachur Singh) who all love and support her. She enters her first year in college and catches the eye of Rahul (Saif Ali Khan) who quickly becomes attracted to her. She succumbs to his charm but her brothers and parents are not sure about Rahul. His womanizing nature worries them and they tell her to stay away from him. However, Priya is unable to leave Rahul. She convinces her parents to meet him but when they talk about marriage he backs off and he leaves Priya. Priya is devastated but moves on with her life. In one sweep she learns that she is pregnant with Rahul's child. Her parents go to Rahul to talk about marriage but to their shock he refuses to marry her. Priya is faced with a decision, and she chooses to keep the child. Her decision prompts her father to chuck her out the house. Alone and neglected Priya is devastated, but her parents and brothers find it hard to live without her and they bring her home. She now has to face society and try to overcome the disdain of her neighbors, among others. Society virtually ostracizes her and her family. She eventually gains the support of those who had earlier disrespected her. At the same time she manages to change Rahul's views as well and he decides to marry her. However, Priya has already given her heart to Ajay and they get married.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?299955</url></doc>
