<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="304882">
  <docid>304882</docid>
  <title>L-Evated: The Blunt Truth</title>
  <year>1997</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">September 1997</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">24</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Walls, Rick</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Curvey Jr., Troy</producer>
    <producer>Juzang, Ivan</producer>
    <producer>Juzang, Ivan</producer>
    <producer>Walls, Rick</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Juzang, Ivan</writer>
    <writer>Walls, Rick</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Curvey Jr., Troy</actor>
      <role>Barbershop owner</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Howell, William (V)</actor>
      <role>Raheem's son</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Snake (III)</actor>
      <role>Raheem's friend</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>L-Evated: The Blunt Truth uses the language and culture of urban youth to de-glorify the marijuana phenomena. The overall message is: Stop Using Marijuana, If You've Started; Don't Start If You Haven't; and Realize You Can Always Quit. An urban radio DJ hosts the show from his booth and speaks to young people using their language, music, and attitudes. He introduces different segments of the show including an original vignette, popular scenes from the movie 'Friday', and interviews with youth and health experts to counter marijuana propaganda. The DJ addresses the reasons urban youth give for using marijuana. The provocative, dramatic vignette is interwoven into the show in four acts. The drama takes an insider's look at the paths of two best friends, Maal and Raheem. As they reach their late teens, Maal is trying to move on to a positive path. However, his friend, Raheem, becomes a 'buster' (a heavy user). He can't wake up in the morning without reaching for a blunt, can't help raise his son and his girlfriend, Neeka, becomes disgusted with him. In the end, will Raheem see that weed is taking him down and that it's time for a change, or will he just stay L Evated?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?304882</url></doc>
