<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="312600">
  <docid>312600</docid>
  <title>La noche de los castillos</title>
  <year>1995</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Game-Show</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Spain">22 September 1995</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Spain">120</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Alvés, Luis Fernando</actor>
      <role>Himself - Host</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cifuentes, Juan Manuel</actor>
      <role>Juglar (1995)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dogar, Víctor Manuel</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Priego, Luis Ángel</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Quinn, Anthony (I)</actor>
      <role>Rey Falop</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This was a show and an adventure at the same time. In each program, one of King Falop's (Anthony Quinn) daughters was kidnapped by a bad wizard and taken to a castle. He asked three couples to go to the quest of getting the princess back. Each program was divided in three stages. In the first stage, the three couples had to go through a car race, with many different obstacles they had to pass as fast as they could. They had to go through a road which had differente bifurcations, each one leading to an obstacle. They had to choose one way, and with luck they could find the easy obstacle. Some obstacles were dificult, others made the couple loose time, and so on. They would be guided by radio by the host and his assistant (Marta de Pablo). Only the winning couple, the one who reached the castle in the first place, would go on to the second stage. In this stage, the couple went through a short of "role playing", in a style very similar to the "Knightmare" program, but with real backgrounds, inside the castle (all the castles in the series were real, in different parts of Spain). They had to talk to the inhabitants in the castle, get objects if they had to, and solve puzzles, in order to get to the dungeon where the princess was hidden. They would be guided in every moment by the host of the program (Luis Fernando Albes) They only had one hour to reach her, because if they didn't manage to find her, she would be killed and the game would be over. During the quest, there was an important rule: they could never be touched by the wizard that kidnapped the princess (I forgot his name, sorry) or the quest would be over, so when the wizard appeared, they had to run away as fast as they could. If they rescued the princess, they had to escape with her and go to the third stage of the show, where they had to go to a tower. There, they had to answer an amount of questions. If they did so, the princess would reach her father and the rescuers would earn an amount of money.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?312600</url></doc>
