<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="313060">
  <docid>313060</docid>
  <title>La parapluie fantastique</title>
  <year>1903</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">7 November 1903</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Méliès, Georges</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Méliès, Georges</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The scene is similar to that seen at Coney Island, where a number of shows are constantly going on. A Juggler enters, dressed in promenade costume, with an overcoat hanging over his arm, a silk hat on his head and carrying a cane. Laying down his coat and cane, he uses his hat for some of his juggling feats. Throwing the hat to the ground, it suddenly becomes a balloon, which he catches and balances on the end of the cane. The balloon turns into a piece of cloth, which in turn becomes an umbrella cover on the end of the cane. Concealing himself behind the umbrella for a moment, he suddenly comes forth clothed in the costume of a young Greek. He draws out of the umbrella a beautiful woman in Algerian costume. One after the other, he takes from the umbrella a Swiss, Spanish, Russian, Italian, Turkish, Holland, Swedish and Gypsy Maiden, and, as a finish, a beautiful Fairy appears, the latter dropping out of a bunch of roses as they fall from the umbrella. Thus there have been produced by one umbrella, ten beautiful maidens which our Juggler poses in a charming group. He causes each one to jump to the floor, but in their descent each one changes her costume to that of an up-to-date coquette. They all engage in a dance, and the scenery changes. The Juggler assumes his original costume. He tears the umbrella apart and the latter again becomes a cane. He misses his hat. Perceiving the balloon in the corner, he seizes it, and it again becomes a high hat, which he dons and bows himself out of the picture.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?313060</url></doc>
