<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="318921">
  <docid>318921</docid>
  <title>Lands End</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Grey, Ian (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">73</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Torjussen, Ruth</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Torjussen, Ruth</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Torjussen, Ruth</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Addey, Sitembile John</actor>
      <role>Nadine</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bettany, Lisa</actor>
      <role>Clare</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cheriton, Stephen</actor>
      <role>Sebastian</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gilligan, John (III)</actor>
      <role>Rory</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Masti, Pano</actor>
      <role>Rezza</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"Lands End" tells the story of Clare, a new mother with post-natal depression who spends much of her time sobbing under the kitchen table. On Christmas Eve in a desperate bid to escape her cheating husband Sebastian and get to the safety of her wealthy father's house for Christmas, she enlists the help of two homeless men, Reza and Rory, to drive her from London to Lands End in Cornwall. Despite Reza's lack of recent driving experience and Rory's constant thirst for alcohol the two men eventually prove worthy escorts. The adventures on the journey, including the pit-stop at Granny's house where Granny comforts Clare and treats the men as heroes, all contribute to her increasing recovery and the precious bond with her baby Becky is formed. But when the journey is almost over a chance meeting with her scheming husband and his lover who steal the baby away, means Clare has to look to her own resources to rescue Becky and escape Sebastian forever. Christmas Day sees her well and happy and dancing on top of the table in Lands End.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?318921</url></doc>
