<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="320764">
  <docid>320764</docid>
  <title>Last of the Romantics</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Senn, Elijah</editor>
    <editor>Wheeler, Tad Michael</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">27 March 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">89</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Regensburger, Vohn</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Regensburger, Vohn</producer>
    <producer>Bruno, Chris (I)</producer>
    <producer>Gillam, Gregory C.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Regensburger, Vohn</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Regensburger, Vohn</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bailey, Scott (IX)</actor>
      <role>Waiter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bruno, Chris (I)</actor>
      <role>Parker Graves</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bruno, Dylan</actor>
      <role>Chet Dickman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bruno, Scott (I)</actor>
      <role>Mr. Catrell</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Caponigro, Michelle</actor>
      <role>Record Store Clerk</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Daniel, Brittany</actor>
      <role>Sarah Xavier</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>LaBriola, Lisa</actor>
      <role>Hope</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lange, Ted (I)</actor>
      <role>Cole Henderson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Margolis, Morgan H.</actor>
      <role>Miles Bender</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Marlier, Brittany</actor>
      <role>Punker</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Marlier, Tia</actor>
      <role>Ms. Royale</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mendillo, Stephen</actor>
      <role>Mr. Xavier</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>O'Toole, Matt (I)</actor>
      <role>Priest</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The saddest thing in life is to fall for someone you can never have. Welcome to the world of PARKER GRAVES. Consumed with his legacy, Parker spends his idle time reading obituaries and walking through the cemetery pondering his existence. Lacking inspiration, he looks to the past for answers. One day, his life takes a dramatic turn, when out of morbid curiosity he wanders anonymously into a funeral and becomes entranced by HOPE, a deceased ballerina. She immediately leaves an indelible imprint on his soul. Driven by her memory, Parker begins to question his path in life to the dismay of those closest to him. As his obsession grows for her, the shortcomings of his own life begin to magnify. Once a composer filled with great promise, Parker now toils away unfulfilled, writing jingles for an advertising agency. He can't get past the question, how does one make a living as an artist in today's society? He fares no better at his relationship with SARAH, a career girl caught up in the mores of our modern culture: appearance, money, and power. His best friend MILES watches this all unfold and attempts to help navigate Parker's ship through stormy waters. He proves no match for what is about to occur. To complicate matters, Parker befriends COLE, a homeless jazz pianist on the brink of self-destruction. The two forge an unlikely friendship with music as the catalyst. In symbiotic fashion, they begin to transform each other's lives. Parker has lost all patience with the "status quo world" he inhabits. On the outside, he appears to have lost a grip on reality. On the inside, he desperately longs for the beautiful, yet unattainable Hope. Having reached a crossroads in life, Parker has some critical decisions to make. Where does he go from here? Last of the Romantics challenges us to look within ourselves, past societies' conventions, to find our true calling in life. It's a gentle reminder, that if we follow our heart's desire, what we find just might surprise us.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?320764</url></doc>
