<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="320784">
  <docid>320784</docid>
  <title>Lasting Images: Alternatives to Traditional Burial</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Pires, Angela (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>death</keyword>
    <keyword>green</keyword>
    <keyword>cremation</keyword>
    <keyword>burial</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">31 August 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">52</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Hendrix, Hammond</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hendrix, Hammond</producer>
    <producer>Hendrix, Joan</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Hendrix, Joan</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Milligan, Malford</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Beach, Alice</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kovack, Rose</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"LASTING IMAGES-contemporary choices in human disposition" I. Three main modes of human disposition A) Traditional Burial- 1. Casket, embalming, 6 foot burial 2. Burial at sea with coffin B) Cremation- 1. Eternal Reefs- using cremains to create an ocean reef 2. LifeGem- using cremains to create a diamond 3. Space Services- shooting cremains into space 4. Sea Services- traditional scattering of ashes at sea 5. Karen Medicus- mixing cremains in blown glass 6. Eternally Yours Memorials- painting with cremains 7. Angels Flight- shooting cremains with fireworks 8. Sea Services- burial of cremains on the ocean floor C) Green Burial- 1. Memorial EcoSystems-Green burial 2. Promessa- traveled to Sweden to interview Susanne Wiigh-Masak who has developed a process of accelerated decomposition through cryogenics. These three modes are broken down even further with four components to each mode: 1. Business- The technical and intricacies of each mode of disposition. 2. Emotional- The emotional side to each mode of disposition for consumer and business alike. 3. Global/Environmental- the global benefits of each mode of disposition 4. Families- family feelings about each mode of disposition, personal stories, as well as their opinions.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?320784</url></doc>
