<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="321876">
  <docid>321876</docid>
  <title>Lazer's Night Moves</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Selvarajan, Sai</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">25 May 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">6</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Patterson, Gabe</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Finley, Tony (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bear (V)</actor>
      <role>Biker Man</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Briso</actor>
      <role>Briso</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chapman, Lou Ann</actor>
      <role>Dolly Holstein</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cruz, Jonny</actor>
      <role>Corey Lujan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Elliot, Danna</actor>
      <role>Biker Woman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hammel</actor>
      <role>Hammel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lambert, Mike (VII)</actor>
      <role>Dusty Holstein</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Leach, Chris (V)</actor>
      <role>Bartender</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mooney, Boyd</actor>
      <role>Dean Foster</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Novey, David</actor>
      <role>Manny Ibarra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Russell, Larry (II)</actor>
      <role>Randy Lockhart</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>There's no escaping the sexy and danger as LAZER (Rhineland's sensational techno/hip-hop group) storms an unsuspecting honky-tonk somewhere in Texas. Catch Speedo-clad rappers BRISO and HAMMEL commanding a crowd of confounded country cowpokes to do the 'NIGHT MOVES' and delight in the drama as dolled-up dames desert their dismayed dudes to dance onstage! Behold the breathtaking blitzkrieg that is ninja/guitarist ICE VON SHREDULA and blurt out 'Boffo!' as he blasts blasé bikers and overwhelms ornery onlookers with lethal, lightning-laced guitar licks! Witness all this and more from the bird's-eye-view of bionic band bodyguard and mascot LAZER CROW. Oh...yes! Forget everything you know about music films. Captured in glorious Super-16mm by University of Texas at Arlington student Dick-Gabe Patterson during Lazer's first U.S. tour, 'Night Moves' gives audiences a front-row seat at one of the most memorable concerts in music history. For the uninitiated, the piece serves as an introduction to the band that has already achieved fame, fortune and multi platinum status overseas. As anyone who has seen them live can attest, Lazer pulls no punches, and this performance of their monster crossover single from their debut album 'Let Me Dance You' is no exception.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?321876</url></doc>
