<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="328663">
  <docid>328663</docid>
  <title>Legendary</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Huey, David (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">107</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Huey, David (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Wiwasuk, Mongkhon</producer>
    <producer>Huey, David (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sasiprapa, Malaipet</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>An inspiring true story that spans eight years &amp; five continents. Malaipet retires after losing his championship title to live with his father on his struggling rice farm. For this Thai boxer, being sent away to a Muay Thai camp meant leaving his home at age 6. For his father, sending his son away meant giving him a chance to fight for a better life. Now back home, he starts rebuilding family relationships. An American fight manager recruits Malaipet to come live &amp; fight in the USA. Making a tough decision, Malaipet leaves his father once again. Malaipet begins the American dream, easily winning fight after fight. While Muay Thai fighters are looked down upon in Thailand, they are heroes &amp; stars throughout the world. The sensational &amp; flashy life style of America takes its toll on the boxer. From excess drinking, womanizing to no training, he loses as many fights as he is winning. Desperate for money, Malaipet accepts an offer to fight Mixed Martial Arts in the Octagon. He thrills the audience &amp; secures a national TV contract. Feeling homesick &amp; patriotic, Malaipet fights for his country in battle billed as "Holland vs. Thailand." Now back on the top of his game, he is given a chance to fight again for the World Title, but this time against a fellow Thai teammate &amp; friend, Yodsaenklai. Malaipet loses his bid for the championship &amp; is broke once again. After investigating Malaipet's bank accounts, his manager discovers all these years Malaipet has been sending his fight purse back to his father. With this final championship fight, he finally pays off his father's farm.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?328663</url></doc>
