<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="330200">
  <docid>330200</docid>
  <title>Les carottiers</title>
  <year>1931</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Currier, Richard C.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>actor-shares-first-name-with-character</keyword>
    <keyword>dog</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>French</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="France">63</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Horne, James W.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Roach, Hal (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Walker, H.M.</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>De Briac, Jean</actor>
      <role>Cookie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>De Neel, Germaine</actor>
      <role>Mme. Hardy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dorety, Charles</actor>
      <role>Drunk</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Garvin, Anita</actor>
      <role>Mme. Laurel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hall, Charlie (I)</actor>
      <role>Bellboy/Landlord</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hardy, Oliver</actor>
      <role>M. Hardy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Laurel, Stan</actor>
      <role>M. Laurel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Llaneza, Luis</actor>
      <role>Dress extra</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This film combines the French language versions of two Laurel &amp; Hardy short films, Be Big and Laughing Gravy, into a pseudo-feature in which the actors speak phonetic French. Commencing with Be Big: the boys fail to join their wives for a weekend in Atlantic City because they've been invited to a stag meeting of their lodge...but they never make it to their lodge, either, because Ollie gets his feet stuck in Stan's too-small boots. A title card explains that the boys have subsequently been kicked out by their wives, and are left with only their little dog, at which point begins Laughing Gravy: on a wintry night in an apartment house where pets are forbidden, the boys attempt to hide their dog, Laughing Gravy, from the landlord, but are threatened with expulsion. However [in a plot twist not found in the original English language version], Stan then receives a letter saying that he will inherit a fortune from his uncle if he leaves Ollie forever; the uncle blames Ollie for Stan's low standing in the world. Stan refuses this condition-- but only so he won't have to give up his dog.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?330200</url></doc>
