<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="333612">
  <docid>333612</docid>
  <title>Let's Stay Friends</title>
  <year>2000</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Vandome, David</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>black-comedy</keyword>
    <keyword>cumbria</keyword>
    <keyword>northern-england</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">8 September 2000</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">26</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>von Uthmann, Nikolaus</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hall, Sara (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>von Uthmann, Nikolaus</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Laverty, Jamie</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Blyth, Mark Stephen</actor>
      <role>Andrew</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Emerson, Steve (I)</actor>
      <role>Jeffrey Lloyd</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fisher, Tom (VII)</actor>
      <role>Max</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hadaway, Sarah</actor>
      <role>Alyssa</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McDermott, Mark (I)</actor>
      <role>Tony</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Reina, Robert</actor>
      <role>Michael Harker</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>von Uthmann, Nikolaus</actor>
      <role>Ulf</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Alyssa has no luck with the opposite sex. One boyfriend after the other has dumped her. According to the advice of her best friend Jodie there are only two solutions to the problem: killing all the ex-boyfriends, or looking for professional help. So Alyssa takes on counselling. The young analyst Michael initially finds it difficult to determine the cause of AlyssaÕs problem - but he is intreagued with his new patient. Since Michael seems to be clueless how men and women live together - or apart - in today's world, and Alyssa doesn't dare to socialise without a protector, they agree to an unusual therapy approach: Michael takes out Alyssa to teach her to enjoy life again, strictly as a professional exercise of course... Michael and Alyssa get along well - actually too well. But at one of their "professional dates" she bumps into one of her ex-boyfriends, and all the bad memories come flooding back. Michael urges Alyssa to rid herself from the demons of her past, an advice she takes on literally: With increasingly inventive methods she kills off her boyfriends, one after the other.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?333612</url></doc>
