<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="335460">
  <docid>335460</docid>
  <title>Life After Death: The Movie</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Prescott, Tristan</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>lil-kim</keyword>
    <keyword>the-notorious-big</keyword>
    <keyword>diddy</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Singapore">M18</certificate>
    <certificate country="Australia">M</certificate>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">15 May 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">75</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Maiya, April</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Williams, Kalefe</producer>
    <producer>Butler, Damion</producer>
    <producer>Maiya, April</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bully, Invisible</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Combs, Sean 'P. Diddy'</actor>
      <role>Principle</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hector, Jamie</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jones, Kimberly 'Lil' Kim'</actor>
      <role>Principle</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The Notorious B.I.G. was shot and killed on March 9, 1997, two weeks later his album Life After Death was released and went on to sell over 10 million records. Ten years later, Life After Death The Movie chronicles the music family he left behind from 1997-2007 in an epic story of friendship and betrayal. After B.I.G.'s death, his right hand man, D-Roc, manages Lil' Kim and Junior Mafia through a decade of triumph and tragedy as they live, work and travel the world together ending with the infamous HOT 97 New York City radio station shootout that landed Lil' Kim and D-Roc in Federal Prison and labeled their former friends as snitches. This true story is told solely from never-seen video footage shot from the crew themselves and takes us through the "golden age" of New York hip hop with vintage footage of the hip hop's biggest stars from Diddy, The Lox, Mase, Jay-Z and more. Includes footage of the HOT 97 shootout with an end-all exclusive interview with D-Roc, who refused to testify in Lil Kim's perjury trial for his alleged involvement in the shootout and until now, declined to be interviewed. Narrated by Jamie Hector aka Marlo Stansfield of The Wire.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?335460</url></doc>
