<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="335589">
  <docid>335589</docid>
  <title>Life Is a Dream: A Street Poet in New York</title>
  <year>2000</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Stobbs, Charlotte</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>poetry</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">10 July 2000</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">55</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Rossier, Nicolas (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Rossier, Nicolas (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Rossier, Nicolas (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Block, Isidore</actor>
      <role>Main protagonist</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Isidore Block is an 80 years old Jewish street poet who lives in New York. The youngest of four children, Isidore (aka Poet-o) was born in Central Park on Sheep Meadow field in 1920. At the age of five Isidore was placed in institutions after his mother was put into a psychiatric institute and his father left for Arizona with the family's money. He lived in various Foster homes until the age of 16 when he was left alone in the streets. Since then, Isidore, best known today as Poet-o, has been entertaining the visitors of Central Park by reciting his own poetry and by giving wishes out with his famous Unicorn Bell. To this day, Isidore has written more than 1000 poems and met millions of people who come every years to visit Central Park. He has also performed in various off-Broadway shows in New York. Poet-o is famous, but as he told us often, famous in a very strange way. Famous but very poor. He survives thanks to the generosity of the Central Park's visitors who buy his poems for a few dollars. The filmmakers attempt to capture the poet's originality and philosophy of life. This documentary is also maybe a thought-provocative reflection on the state of the American dream at the dawn of the new millennium.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?335589</url></doc>
