<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="335916">
  <docid>335916</docid>
  <title>Life's Chronicles</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bresnik, Danny</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">22</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Baylor, Ryan</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Baylor, Ryan</producer>
    <producer>Ceraulo, Rich</producer>
    <producer>Dean, Alissa</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Baylor, Ryan</actor>
      <role>Pat</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ceraulo, Rich</actor>
      <role>Jordan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dean, Alissa</actor>
      <role>Annie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fink, Mitchell (I)</actor>
      <role>Keith</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hallows, Jason</actor>
      <role>Gus</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Reetz, Michael</actor>
      <role>Seth</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Welzbacher, Craig</actor>
      <role>Matt</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In hopes of having a great time and making lots of money in the process, Jordan persuades his six lifelong friends, 3 guys and 3 girls, 2 couples and 2 singles, to help him with a reality television project he's producing. If they agree, they will have their lives taped everyday for an entire year. With the incentive of some 'cold hard cash', the six friends agree to the plan. Within the first two months of shooting, Matt and Rachel, one of the two committed couples in the tight nit group, break up. The remaining friends must choose sides, even Seth and Denise, the only married couple of the group. Tension builds as the girls, Denise and Annie, take Rachel's side and the guy's, Seth and Pat support Matt, leaving Jordan in the middle worrying about the outcome of the show. After an argument, Denise allows her husband, Seth, to let Matt stay with them until he can find a place of his own. Matt and Rachel seemed to have moved on, even going on dates set up by their best friends. All is well, or at least appears to be, until Matt, on his first date since the breakup, runs into Rachel and her new beau. Are Matt and Rachel really over one another or are they just pretending?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?335916</url></doc>
