<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="340131">
  <docid>340131</docid>
  <title>Lock Speed Action</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Driscoll-Luttringer, Brandon</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Griffith, Russell</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bokides, Rich</producer>
    <producer>Heath, Jason (II)</producer>
    <producer>Naab, Chris</producer>
    <producer>Bokides, Rich</producer>
    <producer>Griffith, Russell</producer>
    <producer>Litt, Adam</producer>
    <producer>Heath, Jason (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bokides, Rich</writer>
    <writer>Litt, Adam</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Aaron, Mark (II)</actor>
      <role>Uncle Ron</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Crane, Dani</actor>
      <role>Rocker Girl</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Davis, Jason (XIX)</actor>
      <role>Studio Security Guard</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Delio, Drue</actor>
      <role>Holt</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Duvall, Vincent</actor>
      <role>Nick del Rey</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gatica, Luchana</actor>
      <role>Waitress</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hume, Patrick</actor>
      <role>Marley</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>In-q</actor>
      <role>Randy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Litt, Adam</actor>
      <role>Hot Dog Man</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maggio, Natalina</actor>
      <role>Rocker Girl</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Marie, Audra (II)</actor>
      <role>London Kalling - Pizza girl</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Martinez, Chris (IX)</actor>
      <role>Brutus - Pizza guy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mccullough, Amber</actor>
      <role>Brianna's friend</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Strohman, Mark (I)</actor>
      <role>Cadillac Jack</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Waterman, John E.</actor>
      <role>Diner Patron</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Holt Holiday and Randy Thyme have been musicians then roadies since the time they could walk. Having just completed another tour with a no name band they remember fondly their days as roadies with the Rolling Stones and how things seemingly will never be the same as they ponder their future. Returning home full-time to Hollywood for the first time in over a decade, the pair seeks out Holt's Uncle Ron, a semi-celebrity in Tinsel Town with an unknown but shady past, in the hopes Uncle Ron will be able to set them up with a place to crash and some hold over cash until their next big tour comes along. But Uncle Ron has other arrangements in mind when Holt and Randy come knocking on his doorstep. Referencing a promise that he made to Holt's mother before she died years earlier to watch over his wayward nephew, Uncle Ron offers Holt, and by proximity Randy, a chance to run a abandoned film studio that recently fell into his possession. By managing the studio, Uncle Ron tells the boys they might finally be able to settle down and learn some responsibility. Holt and Randy are reluctant to accept Uncle Ron's offer, until they discover the studio has a complete recording studio and an unbeatable sound system. The guys know they can't let the place go, despite the fact they know nothing about the film business. Holt also sees the studio as a chance to possibly reconnect with his estranged uncle, as Uncle Ron is the only family he has left now. Holt and Randy enlist the aid of a Hollywood veteran in their struggle to clean up the place and bring in business: a hobo named Marley who lives secretly in the studio's second and a half floor. Marley relates to Holt and Randy how his life fell apart years earlier when the popular television show on which he was working was canceled and how as a result he took refuge in the abandoned studio. Holt and Randy reach a tentative agreement with Marley: if Marley shares his intricate knowledge of Hollywood with them and helps bring in business, then they'll let him stay in the building. Marley agrees and a shaky alliance is born. Marley secretly has sinister plans of his own however to use the reopened studio as platform to seek revenge on those who canceled his show in the first place. Adding to the boys' worries is Uncle Ron's fiancée Brianna Silvers, a beautiful but diabolic gold digger from the Valley with an ulterior motive as well: to wrestle away control of the studio from the boys. Brianna sees ownership of the studio as her chance to rub elbows with Hollywood's rich and famous and sees Holt and Randy as little more than imbeciles to be overcome in her quest toward stardom. All the while, Uncle Ron checks in on Holt and Randy from time to time, acting more as a silent but supervising partner in the business as opposed to an active owner. But as the studio books its first clients and begins to turn a profit, Randy questions if Holt and he are becoming too corporate - especially as some of the musicians from their past are rumored to be starting up a big tour in the near future and are looking for roadies.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?340131</url></doc>
