<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="342466">
  <docid>342466</docid>
  <title>Los fusiladitos</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Argentina</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Argentina">Atp</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Argentina">19 August 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Argentina">57</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Miljiker, Cecilia</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Miljiker, Cecilia</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Miljiker, Cecilia</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Argento, Florencia</actor>
      <role>Interviews</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Portaluppi, Carlos</actor>
      <role>Rodolfo Walsh</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In September 1955, a group of militaries overthrows the democratic government of Juan Domingo Peron. Peron is forced to flee into exile. In Argentina, there begins an era of persecution, torture and deaths of the peronists and of all who opposed to the new regime. On 9 June 1956, a group of militaries and civilians try to regain democracy. But the revolutionaries didn't succeed. That night the military forces of the government, capture 12 civilians who had participated in the insurrection. They take them to a dump in the neighborhood of Josea Leon Suarez where they proceed to execute them. But some years later, five "executed" appeared alive. By the time the documentary was made, one of those survivors was still alive, and he gives his testimony in the film. The documentary is about the massacre of Jose Leon Suaez but it is also about the thoughts of the filmmaker and the problems she had during the investigation and the shooting of the film. Finally, it is a reflection on the peronist phenomenon and the Argentinian History between 1956 and 1973, years of persecution, imprisonments and exiles, exiles that the filmmaker compares with her own.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?342466</url></doc>
