<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="342571">
  <docid>342571</docid>
  <title>Los hijos de nadie (Dos caminos)</title>
  <year>1952</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Savage, Carlos</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Mexico</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Mexico">1 September 1952</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">85</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Véjar hijo, Carlos</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Gutiérrez Roldán, Mário</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Villatoro, Carlos H.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Baena, Federico (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Blanco, Victorio</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bravo Sosa, Guillermo</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Curiel, Federico</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fernández, Agustín (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Funes hijo, Miguel</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>González, Carmelita</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hernández, Ana María</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Herrera, Marina (I)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jiménez, Mario (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Landa, Rodolfo (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Martínez, Pepe (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mateos, Héctor</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Meyer, Roberto</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Montesco, Ofelia</actor>
      <role>Rosa</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mussot, Luis</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Muñoz, José (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Osuna, Humberto</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rodríguez, Dagoberto</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rodríguez, Humberto (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Silva, David (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>de la Parra, Javier</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A man is making a research about the importance of familiar environment in children's future. First, he interviews a prostitute, Rosa, who's in jail because of the murderer of her pimp. She was a poor child, living only with her father. He wants to send his daughter to school, but they don't find place and the father has to leave the child with the neighbour, while he's working. But the man is hit by a car and dies. Years later, Rosa finds herself alone after her adoptive mother dies. A young man from his same vicinity, wants to help her, after hearing her singing. But the truth is that he wants to turn Rosa into a prostitute and live from her money. The other story is about a boy, who goes with his father to sign up in the school. But the father leaves the boy at the line waiting, while he prefers to have some drinks at the bar. A friend and his father see that the boy has been waiting for hours and help him to find his father. After drinking the entire bottle of tequila, the drunk father dies of an alcoholic congestion. The kid never was able to go to school. When he grows up, he (David Silva) and his mother, live in poverty. He never learned to write or read, and he works independently, fixing all kind of things door by door. He hasn't been able to find a formal job, in part, because he prefers to spend time playing billiards. He's very good at billiards and earns some money from the bets. One day, he sees a sign in front of a house, wanting a maid. So, he tells his girlfriend that she should go and ask for the job. The girl gets the job and now is the maid of a big residence. But the plans of the young man is to use the girl to break into the house and steal. He says his girlfriend that the money could be to marry with her. But the idea doesn't like her and one night he enters by the force, threatening her with a pistol. The house owner faints at the sight of the burglar, who steals some money and jewels. At a hotel, he and the girlfriend decide to wait, while he participates in a billiard tournament. But she regrets and decides to go with the police and tell everything. The police finds our young man playing billiard, but he escapes, in front of his scared mother. The tragedy will overcome, with a message about the importance of child education.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?342571</url></doc>
