<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="344168">
  <docid>344168</docid>
  <title>Louise Bourgeois: The Spider, the Mistress and the Tangerine</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kobland, Ken</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Greece">20 March 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="France">9 December 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">25 June 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">99</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Cajori, Marion</director>
    <director>Wallach, Amei</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Griffin, George (IV)</producer>
    <producer>Savoie, Kipjaz</producer>
    <producer>Cajori, Marion</producer>
    <producer>Wallach, Amei</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Asbaghi, Pandora Tabatabai</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bourgeois, Jean-Louis</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bourgeois, Louise</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Girls, Guerilla</actor>
      <role>Themselves</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gorovoy, Jerry</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kotik, Charlotta</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Storr, Robert</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A journey inside the world of a legend of modern art and an icon of feminism. Onscreen, the nonagenarian Louise Bourgeois is magnetic, mercurial and emotionally raw-an uncompromising artist whose life and work are imbued with her ongoing obsession with the mysteries of childhood. Her process is on full display in this intimate documentary, which features the artist in her studio and with her installations, shedding light on her intentions and inspirations. Louise Bourgeois has for six decades been at the forefront of successive new developments, but always on her own powerfully inventive and disquieting terms. In 1982, at the age of 71, she became the first woman to be honored with a major retrospective at New York's Museum of Modern Art. In the decades since, she has created her most powerful and persuasive work, including her series of massive spider structures that have been installed around the world. Filmed with unparalleled access between 1993 and 2007, Louise Bourgeois: The Spider, the Mistress and the Tangerine is a comprehensive and dramatic documentary of creativity and revelation.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?344168</url></doc>
