<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="344532">
  <docid>344532</docid>
  <title>Love Happens</title>
  <year>1999</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Mitchell, Shannon (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>toe</keyword>
    <keyword>australian</keyword>
    <keyword>male-female-relationship</keyword>
    <keyword>nose</keyword>
    <keyword>carpenter</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Germany">2 July 2001</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">4 June 1999</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">88</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Cookson, Tony</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>McSweeney, Tom (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Cookson, Tony</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Reynolds, David (II)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bergere, Jenica</actor>
      <role>Amy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bollman, Ryan</actor>
      <role>Billy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Coster, Nicolas</actor>
      <role>Charles</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Curtis Brown, Robert</actor>
      <role>Stephen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Donnellan, Sean</actor>
      <role>Roger</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grant, Vince</actor>
      <role>Simon</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lackey, Elizabeth</actor>
      <role>George</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Marino, Ken</actor>
      <role>Mike Parker</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>What do animals, allergies and a bet have in common? A commitment-phobic woman named Lisa Harris. Lisa may hold the record for most failed short-term relationships in modern history. It's not that she doesn't want to find her true love, it's just that she doesn't seem to know what true love means. It's with the idea of helping Lisa that her mom, Gwen bets her she won't be able to stay with her current boyfriend, Simon through Thanksgiving, a record three weeks away. From the moment Lisa accepts the challenge, her life changes. No sooner has Lisa made the bet than Simon is unexpectedly called away on business. Determined not to lose, Lisa lets her roommate Amy talk her into substituting another man for Simon a handsome carpenter named Mike. But life's not so simple... not only does Lisa have to contend with Mike's allergy to her pet rabbit but with the unexpected return of Mike's beautiful but manipulative ex-girlfriend George. While George poses a threat, it soon becomes clear to Lisa that the main obstacle to a meaningful relationship with Mike is the bet. She wants to tell him about it but every time she tries, she digs herself into a deeper hole. The day before Thanksgiving, Mike finds out about the deception by accident. He steams out of Lisa's life and into George's welcoming arms. Mike's buddy Billy does his best to keep Mike from taking off with George on a cross-country train trip but George is hard to resist and Mike's not exactly rational. Although things look bleak, Lisa has discovered something amazing... what it feels like to be truly in love. She races to the train station, hoping to catch Mike before he's gone but she gets there just as the train's leaving. She's lost him. Dejected, Lisa wanders out of the station, then sees Mike, alone. Lisa pours out her heart in apology but Mike isn't buying it...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?344532</url></doc>
