<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="344617">
  <docid>344617</docid>
  <title>Love Is Work</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Schlimme, Roland</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">75</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Kalangis, John</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Binney, Christopher</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Kalangis, John</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Sherlock, John Mark</composer>
    <composer>Underhill, Richard (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Filippo, Fab</actor>
      <role>Victor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gamelin, Joa</actor>
      <role>Sarah</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kalangis, John</actor>
      <role>Terry</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>MacDonald, Shauna</actor>
      <role>Celia</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McCord, Scott</actor>
      <role>Jeff</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McVittie, Ryan</actor>
      <role>Charlie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vibrant, Kyree</actor>
      <role>Harley</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Love is Work is a feature film that follows the intense moments in the lives of five couples Shauna MacDonald plays Celia, a personal assistant of a powerful executive. She's intelligent, straight talking and finds herself on her fourth date with Victor, a marketing man who plays his cards close. She weaves a masterful conversation in pursuit of her real goal.... Charlie is a struggling writer. While his career has just taken a turn for the better, his relationship with Samantha is going downhill. He believes she's cheating on him and is desperate to keep her. Can money and success keep them together or will it drive them apart? Is his instinct worth following, or is his intense paranoia his fatal character flaw? Now that Terry's brother Nick has died suddenly from a heart attack, Terry's girlfriend Sarah has a lot of work to do to hold everything together. She become an instant mother to Terry's nephew Josh and subject to Terry's sudden swings between calm, anger and grief. They're not married yet and Sarah's starting to wonder if she's running out of the strength and will to give. Zoe is beautiful, pregnant and has always been a winner in life and love. As her best friend Katherine and her plan Zoe's baby shower an old issue between them resurfaces: Their past 'experimental' love affair. Zoe, unable to fully embrace her feelings for Katherine in the past, now finds herself married, starting a family and unhappy. Can Katherine be convinced to come back as a part-time lover? Harley and Jeff make beautiful music together. As partners in love and song, they relax hours before an important gig. Convinced the neck injury keeping Geoff on the sidelines is his way of sabotaging their career, Harley embarks on a mission to rid him of his fear and get his ugly neck brace out off their act.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?344617</url></doc>
