<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="344620">
  <docid>344620</docid>
  <title>Love Is a Crime</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>St. James, Crafty</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">25 October 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>St. James, Crafty</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>St. James, Crafty</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>St. James, Crafty</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brantley, Frank</actor>
      <role>Ned</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carver, Casey Alan</actor>
      <role>Police Cheif</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hayes, Janeline</actor>
      <role>Tiffany Hines</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Masterson, Katt</actor>
      <role>Bartender</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McClain, Shannon</actor>
      <role>Stacy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>St. James, Crafty</actor>
      <role>Steve Wallach</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wolf, Andy (I)</actor>
      <role>The Rocket</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wood, Robb (I)</actor>
      <role>Red Ex Employee</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>After a string of dating mishaps, detective Lori Malloy decides to start a dating website of her own. More confused than ever, Lori has no luck, while her partner Tiffany finds the "man of her dreams". Tiffany tries to point out to Lori that she should lighten up on men. Unaware of her own self-sabatoging ways, Lori puts all her focus instead on solving a series of bank robberies that have her completely puzzled. Down the hall, detective Steve Wallach, once jilted by Lori herself, investigates a stolen auto scheme that seems to be fool-proof. Scarred by his over-bearing mother who died two years ago, and frustrated by his lame love-life, Steve is cynical. His partner, Rick tells him about Lori's website, but Steve shuns the idea, until he learns that Lori herself has a profile there. It finally takes an awkward exchange in the hallway to get things moving between Lori and Steve, but then they both leave, not knowing exactly what just happened. Clues to the bank robberies and car thefts take Lori and Steve to the same location, where they catch the perpetrators, and finally come clean about their feelings for one another.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?344620</url></doc>
