<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="344722">
  <docid>344722</docid>
  <title>Love Liberty and the Pursuit of Happiness in the Land of Limited Impossibilities</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Prielozny, Igor</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Slovakia</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">102</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Prielozny, Igor</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Wang, Tao (V)</producer>
    <producer>Prielozny, Igor</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Prielozny, Igor</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Alan, Scott (I)</actor>
      <role>Car Buyer/Camera operator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kendall, Kimberly</actor>
      <role>Girlfriend</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Prielozny, Igor</actor>
      <role>Himself/Narrator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Yukon</actor>
      <role>Butkiss</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The film follows the struggles of a foreign man who has come to the land of the free on a collegiate athletic scholarship, discovers his desire to act, and stumbles upon the "goodies of the American Dream". After traveling back to his homeland for a routine Christmas vacation, he is blindsided when he is unable to obtain a new visa that would grant him access to return legally to the states. In his desperation, he somehow miraculously finds his way back across the border to America. Ultimately, due to his expired documents, finding employment becomes almost impossible. So, yet again he is faced with the fear of his imminent departure after discovering the true opportunities this country actually offers are much different than the media and government has advertised. Eventually, he discovers in his pursuit that his true happiness lies within himself and his French girlfriend, the love of his life, that he found in the states during his college years.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?344722</url></doc>
