<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="345323">
  <docid>345323</docid>
  <title>Love at the Twilight Motel</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kazala, David</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>little-havana</keyword>
    <keyword>infidelity</keyword>
    <keyword>addiction</keyword>
    <keyword>confession</keyword>
    <keyword>love</keyword>
    <keyword>prostitution</keyword>
    <keyword>motel</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby SR</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">3 May 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">82</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Rose, Alison E.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Rose, Alison E.</producer>
    <producer>Flahive, Gerry</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Myhr, Ken</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>The motel presents a veneer of everyday normalcy. Chambermaids go about their chores in the hot Miami light. A green gecko poses against pink stucco. A retro neon sign looms over the lazy hum of city traffic. But behind the row of uniform doors an all-too-human drama is playing out in the shadows. In one room, an elderly Cuban American, the very image of traditional breadwinner, waits for one of his several, younger girlfriends. In another, a newly married young guy lamely justifies his serial cheating. Next door an aging blonde, wearily preparing for the next john, wonders about the direction her life has taken. With Love at the Twilight Motel, filmmaker Alison Rose enters this world of duplicity and dysfunction, fashioning a compassionate and stylish account of love, loss and the human condition. Through a gallery of strikingly conceived character studies -- sharply etched yet achingly universal -- she captures the pathos and pain of her subject's damaged lives. Rose, broken and beautiful, reveals a heart-rending story of abuse and delusion. Richard, a study in a macho bravado, happily pursues his destiny bedding married women. While Cadillac, an ex-pimp and thief, assesses his life spent in pursuit of the next crack hit. Love at the Twilight Motel draws upon a rich documentary tradition to reflect upon the secrets we conceal and the tangled webs we weave.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?345323</url></doc>
