<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="346165">
  <docid>346165</docid>
  <title>Lowlight</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>dance</keyword>
    <keyword>essay-film</keyword>
    <keyword>experimental-film</keyword>
    <keyword>mixed-media</keyword>
    <keyword>house-music</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
<plot>Nightlife Research in Post 9-11 New York. Looking for a magic moment in nightlife Julian Neville returns to New York, where as a teenager he had intense dance experiences at raves and clubs. But dancing is prohibited now. This is no joke! Rudolph Giuliani reactivated an old law from 1926 as a part of his quality of life campaign and delivered club land to the yuppies. This is only the tip of the iceberg in the City that used to never sleep. Instead of entering a lustrous sphere Neville finds himself in a kind of nightlife shopping mall: everywhere the music is more or less the same Using the video camera as his companion Neville takes the viewer along on the journey. He has strange, funny, charming, threatening and surreal encounters, and finally finds some pearls in the underground House dance scene. The dancers welcome him and we see into their breathtaking world, where they incessantly develop their dance styles. It is a kind of Utopian enclosure, where young and old people from all walks of life congregate and dance together. Why regulate such a thing? And not only in New York City, but in the US altogether: The R.A.V.E. Act was enacted in 2003 and effectively eradicated raves. There are multifaceted reasons, ranging from racism and monopoly interests to deep-rooted fears of social dancing. A lawyer on behalf of a group of dancers is fighting these absurd mechanisms. He and other experts provide insight into the legal and commercial world behind the scenes of New York City nightlife.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?346165</url></doc>
