<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="346129">
  <docid>346129</docid>
  <title>Low and Slow</title>
  <year>1997</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Delgado, Monica (I)</editor>
    <editor>Hougaard, Wynn</editor>
    <editor>Van Wagenen, Michael</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>lowrider</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 May 1997</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Delgado, Monica (I)</director>
    <director>Van Wagenen, Michael</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Dearden, James</producer>
    <producer>Delgado, Monica (I)</producer>
    <producer>Van Wagenen, Michael</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Delgado, Monica (I)</writer>
    <writer>Van Wagenen, Michael</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kreutz, Paul</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Delgado, Monica (I)</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In the 1930s a new cultural practice emerged in the Mexican barrios of Los Angeles. Flamboyant horsemen began trading in their horses for highly customized automobiles with lowered suspensions. The practice of "lowriding" was born. Film director, Monica Delgado was raised with the stories of LA's lowriders and her father's own LA car club in the 1950s. The film begins with the photos and paraphernalia of Delgado's father. Delgado then explores the roots of the practice by interviewing her 87 year old great-uncle, Pete Martinez. Pete's family has lived in Los Angeles since it was part of Mexico and he still lives on a small ranch in the midst of the urban sprawl. Pete recalls the days when he and his friends would "cruise" the dirt roads of East Los Angeles on highly decorated horses. He compares the antics of his generation to the following generation who continued this practice in lowriders. The film then follows the life of the Ruelas family, long considered the "godfathers" of lowriding in Los Angeles. Their passion for family unity and cars has spread across generations and cultures, bringing peace and improvements to their South Central neighborhood.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?346129</url></doc>
