<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="346441">
  <docid>346441</docid>
  <title>Lucid</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Roth, Brandon Garet</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Mystery</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>avant-garde</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>hardcore-filmmaking</keyword>
    <keyword>surrealism</keyword>
    <keyword>experimental-film</keyword>
    <keyword>low-budget-film</keyword>
    <keyword>rebel-cinema</keyword>
    <keyword>abstract-film</keyword>
    <keyword>neo-noir</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
    <language>Dutch</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Netherlands">27 February 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">95</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Anderson, Brandon Garet Roth</director>
    <director>van Schijndel, Ferry</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hill, Thee Greg</producer>
    <producer>Anderson, Andy (XXIX)</producer>
    <producer>Anderson, Brandon (II)</producer>
    <producer>Rozendaal, Jeroen</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Anderson, Brandon G.R.</writer>
    <writer>van der Vliet, Thomas</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>G'Ro</composer>
    <composer>Hill, Greg (XVII)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bakema, Dragan</actor>
      <role>Jimmy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Crane, Kelsey</actor>
      <role>Violet</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hicks, Susannah</actor>
      <role>Nikki Xavier</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hill, Greg (XVII)</actor>
      <role>Chance Walker</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Roth, Garet</actor>
      <role>Trabuco</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>de Schepper, Peggy Jane</actor>
      <role>Dina</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Chance Walker is celebrating a one year anniversary of sorts, with his beloved Nikki. An anniversary that haunts him, each and every day. He can no longer bear the burden of her nor the memories they shared, so he retreats away to the attic, where he discovers a box of lost possessions and forgotten trinkets. Within the box's contents, each article holds some insight to what may or may not have happened to the troubled man in his past and what the future may hold for him. Chance slowly becomes obsessed with the contents, alienating everything and everyone around him that he holds so dear, causing him to create a not so lucid reality to be very own existence. He meets Violet, a strange woman that reads in the neighborhood cemetery, near the grave Chance visits on a daily basis. More bizarre than the woman's behavior, is the relationship Chance has with her, he seems to already know her and the two share a past. Then there's Trabuco, a larger than life man, that seems to hold all the answers to each and every question Chance has ever had. The giant man guides Chance through his own delusional maze, finding pleasure in his misery as reality slips further and further away from him. But the connection between the two is deeper than any could expect as Trabuco seems to represent everything Chance holds deep within his own conscience. And with each relived memory sparked by an article taken out of the box, Chance slips deeper and deeper into his past addictions and unyielding passions, leading him down a road of madness before discovering his true self and existence.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?346441</url></doc>
