<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="349768">
  <docid>349768</docid>
  <title>Maa Tujhhe Salaam</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Sankla, Sanjay</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">25 January 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Verma, Tinnu</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Dhariwal, Mahendra</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Jaiswal, Ravi Shankar</writer>
    <writer>Verma, Tinnu</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arora, Malaika</actor>
      <role>Special Appearance</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bedi, Rajat</actor>
      <role>Capt. Naseer Khan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Berry, Sudesh</actor>
      <role>Gul Mastan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deol, Sunny (I)</actor>
      <role>Major Pratap Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Arbaaz (I)</actor>
      <role>Albaksh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, Om</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Verma, Tinnu</actor>
      <role>Lala</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A group of Indian soldiers assigned duty near the India-Pakistan border with on-going conflict over Kashmir. Pratap Singh (Sunny Deol) is in charge of a battalion seeking to stop influx of terrorists and Pakistani soldiers from entering India's borders. He loves beautiful Sonia Khanna (Tabu), who is also stationed at the same battalion. On the side of the Pakistanis, a leader Gul Mastan (Sudesh Berry), is interested in liberating Kashmir from India, and will leave no stone unturned in order to achieve this. His motive is to rule Kashmir as his own state. He enlists his loyal mercenary Albaksh (Arbaaz Khan) to achieve this objective. But events turn Albaksh against his master, and gets him on the run, first from the Pakistanis, and then on touching India's border, by the Indian soldiers. Pratap captures Albaksh and promises he will be taken to safety in India. But with sentiments and anger running high against Pakistani soldiers and extremists, Pratap may not be able to keep his promise.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?349768</url></doc>
