<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="349745">
  <docid>349745</docid>
  <title>Maa Ka Chamatkar</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>History</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Magudi, Nagendra</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Nair, Mohan</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Hamsalekha</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jayapradha</actor>
      <role>Jogan Maa Parvati</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Raj, Charan</actor>
      <role>Ramesh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sapru, Tej</actor>
      <role>Tantrik</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Shanti lives a wealthy lifestyle along with her parents and several cousins and their respective wives. While on a pilgrimage, she meets with a writer, Ramesh, and both fall in love with each other. Her parents arrange their marriage and Ramesh moves in to live with them. Their lives are harmonious, and the couple soon give birth to twin sons, Joginath and Eknath. Then Ramesh takes to alcohol and women in a big way, and asks Shanti to leave after he sees her in their bathroom with a male. Shanti takes the two children and goes to live with Jogan Maa Parvati near Devi Maa Ambe's Mandir. Years pass by, Eknath and Joginath grow up, are devotees of Devi Maa Ambe, recite scriptures, and act as tourist guides. When someone asks them about their father, they question their mother, but she refuses to tell them anything. Then Shanti finds out that her husband is dead, and dons the colorless garb of a widow. When her sons find out, they persuade her to live like a Suhagan - as they find out that Devi Maa Renuka had also lived as both. Watch what impact this has on Shanti, and how Renukaji was both a Widhwa and Suhagan at the same time.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?349745</url></doc>
