<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="351138">
  <docid>351138</docid>
  <title>Madhavi</title>
  <year>1969</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Chanakya, Tapi</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Radhakrishna, B.</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kudalkar, Laxmikant Shantaram</composer>
    <composer>Sharma, Pyarelal Ramprasad</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deepa (I)</actor>
      <role>Rajkumari Madhavi R. Bhupathi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hussain, Nasir (I)</actor>
      <role>Chola Naresh's Maharaja</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Irani, Aruna</actor>
      <role>Chanchal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Sanjay</actor>
      <role>Senapati Jai Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kishore, Raj</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Roopesh</actor>
      <role>Dapathi Pratap Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mehmood (I)</actor>
      <role>Khadak Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mukri</actor>
      <role>Kaviraj</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Murad</actor>
      <role>Chalukya Naresh's Maharaja Rajendra Bhupathi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pran (I)</actor>
      <role>Dalpathi Vikram Singh</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Neighboring counties of Chola Naresh and Chola Chalukya are in a state of war, however, the might of the Chola Naresh overcomes that of Chalukya, captures Maharaja Rajendra Bhupathi, and his daughter, Madhavi, bind them in chains and bring them for justice before Maharaja of Naresh, who under advise from his Senapati, Jai Singh, decides to set the father and daughter free, and signs a peace treaty with them. It is now time for Madhavi to get married and a contest is arranged between Pratap Singh, Vikram Singh and Jai Singh. The winner is Jai, and a marriage date is fixed. Embittered that he did not win the contest, Vikram arranges for Madhavi's abduction, but instead Mangala, the adopted daughter of Maharaja Naresh is brought before him. In order to redeem himself in her father's eyes, he agrees to marry her. Soon the two marriages take place, and the two Maharajas announce that they will make Suraj the Crown Prince and go on a holy pilgrimage. The two women soon become pregnant and give births to two boys. Then Jai is sent to hunt down some wild animals. When he returns after a few weeks, nothing is the same anymore. Madhavi has been arrested for poisoning Suraj, and is held in a dark dungeon. When Jai fights for her, he is captured and blinded. Vikram takes over the throne, and tells Madhavi that she is to get married to him without 24 hours or he will kill her son. The question remains with no one to come to her aid, will Madhavi accede to Vikram's demands?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?351138</url></doc>
