<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="352257">
  <docid>352257</docid>
  <title>Mahabharat</title>
  <year>1965</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Karkhanis, Kamlakar</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>History</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="India">163</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Mistri, Babubhai</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Nadiadwala, A.A.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Madhur, Pandit</writer>
    <writer>Mast, C.K.</writer>
    <writer>Pande, Vishwanath</writer>
    <writer>Vedavyas</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Gupta, Chitra</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Begum, Mumtaz</actor>
      <role>Gandhari</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhattacharya, Abhi</actor>
      <role>Bhagwan Shri Kishan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Desai, Manher</actor>
      <role>Karn</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jeevan (I)</actor>
      <role>Shakuni</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Joginder, Tiger</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kala, Jeevan</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Anoop</actor>
      <role>Uttara's brother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Pradeep</actor>
      <role>Arjun/Brihanalla</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Madhumati</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moolchand</actor>
      <role>Maharaj Jarasandh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rao, Maruti (II)</actor>
      <role>Uluk</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Singh, Dara (I)</actor>
      <role>Bhimsen/Vallabh 'Bhim'</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tiwari, Bhushan</actor>
      <role>Duryodhan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Whisky, Johnny</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Pandu and Dhirtrashtra are two brothers who rule Hastinapur. Pandu gets married to Kunti, who conceives five sons and names them Yudhister, Bhimsen, Arjun, Nakul and Sahdev, while Dhirtrashtra, who is blind, gets married to Gandhari, and gives birth to a 100 sons, including Duryodhan and Dushasan. Gandhari's brother, Shakuni, also resides with them. After Pandu passes away, Dhirtrashtra decides to bequeath the empire to Yudhister much to the chagrin of Duryodhan, who plots with Shakuni to kill them in a palace made of wax, but the brothers and Kunti manage to escape and live incognito in a forest where Bhimsem meets with, Hidimba, slays her demon brother, Hidimb, gets married to her and sires a son, an illusionist, Ghatotkach. The brothers do reveal their identity when Arjun wins a competition at Panchal to wed Draupadi defeating Duryodhan, Dushashan, Jarasandh and others. Kunti unwittingly asks the brothers to share Draupadi, as she had in a previous birth as Devi Maa Parvati, prayed to Bhagwan Shri Shivji five times for a husband. Dhirtrashtra acknowledges the enmity between the cousins and asks five brothers to re-locate to Khandavprasth, which is subsequently transformed by Bhagwan Shri Indra's aide, Vishwakarma, and re-named Indraprasht. Duryodhan is then humiliated by Draupadi, who mocks him and tells him that sons of a blind man are also blind, when he stumbles in the Maya Mahal, and he takes a vow to humiliate her. Shakuni then invites the five brother to gamble at Hastinapur where Yudhister ends up losing Indraprasht, his brothers, his wealth as well as Draupadi herself. Bhagwan Shri Kishan comes to her aid when Dushashan publicly disrobes her as no one comes to her defense. The Pandavas are then sentenced to 13 years in exile, which will be extended by 12 years more if they are discovered during the 13th year. The 13 years pass by, Arjun also gets married to Subhadra and sires a son, Abhimanyu. When the Pandavs return to claim Indraprasht, the Kauravas oppose and challenge them to a war in the Kurkshetra. Duryodhan chooses Bhagwan Shri Kishan's armies, while Arjun chooses Kishanji, who decides to only be the charioteer for Arjun. And it is here that Kishanji who shows his true self to Arjun when he hesitates to kill his relatives, cousins, and gurus. It is here that Gandhari will bless Duryodhan with a body of steel, Kunti will go to plead with Karan to show mercy to her five sons, and Bhagwan Shri Hanuman, the elder brother of Bhimsen, decides to make an incognito appearance, in this epic battle between Good and Evil.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?352257</url></doc>
