<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="352420">
  <docid>352420</docid>
  <title>Mahfil</title>
  <year>1981</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Dhaimade, Das</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">1981</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Kumar, Amar (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Pankal, Jaikishan Dayabhai</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chandulkar, Mohan</actor>
      <role>Pritam</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dhawan, Anil (I)</actor>
      <role>Advocate Amarkumar Dindayal Saxena</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Ashok (I)</actor>
      <role>Raghunath</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Roopesh</actor>
      <role>Babanlal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Merchant, Mushtaq</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Widower Raghunath lives a very wealthy lifestyle with his daughter, Shalini. While making a presentation on the importance of being a woman, he is shot at by a woman, but is uninjured. Shortly thereafter, Shalini introduces him to her boyfriend, Advocate Amarkumar Saxena, who turns out to be the son of Dindayal, Raghunath's childhood friend. Raghunath subsequently hires Amar to train Shalini to be a good businesswoman, and expects both to marry soon. Then Shalini finds out that there she has a twin in a Courtesan named Ratnabai, who is the daughter of a Courtesan who had been intimate with Raghunath, and was responsible for the attempt on Raghunath's life. She brings Ratna to her home, much to the chagrin of her dad. Soon Ratna starts to make herself at home in her new surroundings, and her demands start to increase - from mimicking Shalini, to flirting with Amar. Before Shalini could assert herself, Ratna delivers a letter from her ailing mother - a letter that will turn their lives upside down, result in Raghunath's death, and the roles of Shalini and Ratna being reversed - with Ratna all set to get married to Amar.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?352420</url></doc>
