<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="352601">
  <docid>352601</docid>
  <title>Maia and Jonah</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Brownley, Emil</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>swimming-underwater</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">13</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>McLaughlin, Michael Robert</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Sacha, Jason</producer>
    <producer>Garneau, Jeff</producer>
    <producer>McLaughlin, Michael Robert</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Zang, Adam</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brown, Diane (IV)</actor>
      <role>Maia's Mother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Corness, Robert</actor>
      <role>Teacher</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hardy, Richard (VI)</actor>
      <role>Jonah's Father</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kaminsky, Cindy</actor>
      <role>Jonah's Mother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mackie, Alex D.</actor>
      <role>Tour Guide</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McKoen, Robert (II)</actor>
      <role>Maia's Father</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Turner, Samantha (II)</actor>
      <role>Maia</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Viau, Daniel</actor>
      <role>Jonah</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Situated in the early 90's, a young defined girl meets a socially awkward boy, and the offbeat romance that ensues brings about the memory of the pains and happiness of first love. Maia is a young girl who grew up in the suburbs of a main city. One day while on a field trip at the planetarium, she is asked to help with a demonstration. The other kid that is asked is a boy named Jonah, who is the quiet boy that sits at the back of her class. Maia is not impressed by this decision but sticks with it due to the fact she wants good grades. A few days later, Jonah shows up unannounced at Maia's house with a firefly necklace he purchased with his Mom's recycling money. Confused and a bit empathetic, Maia accepts the gift and asks Jonah if he wants to hang out with her. Their friendship begins to blossom as they hang out in the forest, go swimming at the pool and even play at a local playground. One day while climbing trees, Maia mentions that her Dad is moving the family to Vancouver for work. Jonah uses every ounce of heart to prove to Maia that she cannot leave, due to the gravity they share but to no avail. The same force that started their friendship, follows Maia to adulthood when she travels back to where it all started, eighteen years prior.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?352601</url></doc>
