<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="353289">
  <docid>353289</docid>
  <title>Make Pretend</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Mendel, D.J.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">21 August 2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">105</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Mendel, D.J.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Nunes, Cristina (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Mendel, D.J.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Hopkins, Cynthia J.</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Borgerhohh, Ledlie</actor>
      <role>Ma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Champagne, Margaret Rose</actor>
      <role>Baby</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cote, David</actor>
      <role>Junior</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hickman, Lisa</actor>
      <role>Becky</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mendel, Alice</actor>
      <role>Little Girl</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mendel, D.J.</actor>
      <role>Skeeter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Neumann, Frederick</actor>
      <role>Jeeter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stark, Josh (I)</actor>
      <role>Rusty</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Baby, a small town woman stuck in a dead end job and in a loveless relationship with her boyfriend, decides she's ready to become a woman and create a new life for herself. Unable to escape her empty past and frustrated by her stagnant present, Baby realizes it's time for her to grow-up. It's time for her to become a woman. Baby decides that to become a 'real' woman she needs to have a baby. So she does. But it's not a real baby. It's a doll, a plastic doll. Feeling left out and lonely since the arrival of Baby's plastic doll, Becky, Baby's best friend, decides she wants to be the kind of woman who has a lover. So she creates an imaginary lover to help hide from the disappointments in her real life. When Baby's older sister Sissy discovers the new baby, she becomes jealous of her sister and decides to steal the baby. As the women delve deeper into their worlds of 'make pretend' the realities of life begin to tear holes into their fantasies. Ultimately, everyone must decide if they are willing to find the strength and faith needed to stop pretending and take a chance at finding real happiness.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?353289</url></doc>
