<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="353643">
  <docid>353643</docid>
  <title>Making Wolvy</title>
  <year>1996</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Wolfenden, John</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">7 July 1996</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Essman, Scott</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Essman, Scott</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Essman, Scott</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kiss, Louis</actor>
      <role>Willy Weasel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mullenax, Jody</actor>
      <role>Baby Mulligan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Steele, Brian (I)</actor>
      <role>Gus</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tucker, Todd (I)</actor>
      <role>Wolvy</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In February of 1996, makeup effects artist Todd Tucker filmed a creature-oriented fantasy called WOLVY over two days in the San Fernando Valley. Including makeup effects, sculpted characters and articulated otherworldly creatures, the effort was a massive undertaking. This 24-minute DVD documents the entire process from behind-the-scenes, including interviews with Tucker, detailed step-by-step makeups, and exclusive on-set footage from both key production dates. This documentary was the first in a series of behind-the-scenes of makeup effects films by Scott Essman and Visionary Cinema under the banner of CREATURE PEOPLE. Tucker spent years researching and designing the six characters for the show, then created them in his free time using the skills which got him key jobs on films such as "The Mask," "Mrs. Doubtfire," and "Thinner." Among his characters are a seven-foot-tall, four-armed, childlike abominable snowman named Gus, a pair of monstrous body-guards named the Thug Brothers, and a marsupial wrestling manager named Willie Weasel. The live-action comic book footage was edited and planned as a feature film project. Todd's story centers around the lead character Wolvy, a cocky, flamboyant, upright, wrestling werewolf. It seems that Wolvy must wrestle Baby Mulligan before he is challenged to a big match by Gus. The focus of the project, according to Todd, is about fun and comedy, but he hopes for a slightly adult sense of humor amidst the chaos of his over-sized wrestling characters. Featured in this documentary are detailed step-by-step behind-the-scenes account of the special makeup effects, animatronic creatures and full-body costumes realized for this project. Additionally, on-set footage details the entire filming process. Bonuses include interviews with Tucker and his key production crew, and comments by Academy Award-winning makeup artist Greg Cannom.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?353643</url></doc>
