<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="353622">
  <docid>353622</docid>
  <title>Making Still Green</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Petty, Stephen</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Petty, Stephen</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ajemian, Andrea</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Artigo, Jon</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Castineira, Gricel</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Costa, Paul</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jones, Sarah (VIII)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kelley, Ryan (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lloyd, Doug</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Menides, Georgia</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Meyer, Brandon (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Morash, Tom</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Segan, Noah</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Spain, Douglas</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Strynkowski, Michael</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This documentary shows what REALLY happens behind the scenes of movie being made without the sugar coating. From day one, the production of the independent feature, "Still Green" was, as some people would say, 'cursed'. Without the money even most Indies have to help them out when things went askew, these filmmakers were hit with obstacles that ranged from the annoying, to the horrifying, to the heartbreaking, to just plain bizarre. The producers had to fire their lead actress 10 hours before principal photography began because of racial tension. They faced threats of fines and imprisonment in order to shoot on the beach at night due to baby sea turtles. Hurricane Katrina almost shut the production down. Red tide infected the ocean and heaping piles of dead fish covered the beach. People were hospitalized. Parties got out of control. Sex and romantic drama erupted between the cast and crew, overheating on a daily basis. Friendships were lost. Relationships were slaughtered. A producer got fired for starting a fight. And worst of all, their high definition camera, lighting equipment, and precious film footage was stolen from the production van 2 days before wrapping production and their insurance company refused to cover the loss. This documentary will also take you on the journey after production is wrapped, as they struggle with post-production, running out of money again, trying to get into festivals and most importantly trying to get a distribution deal.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?353622</url></doc>
