<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="354711">
  <docid>354711</docid>
  <title>Mama &amp; Son</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Monserrate, Rafael</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Smith, Denise (II)</producer>
    <producer>Lewis, Brooke (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Taglianetti, Alan</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Acuna, Wanda</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brooks, Sylvia (II)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Caridi, Carmine</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Castronovo, Carlo</actor>
      <role>Mario</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hawkes, Katherine</actor>
      <role>Guest star</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Marks, Annika</actor>
      <role>Ramona</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McCracken, Kelly (I)</actor>
      <role>New York City Police Commissioner</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sabatino, Bud</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Simonini, Rico</actor>
      <role>Dr. Alex</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Williams, Johnny (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A SITCOM SERIES MAMA AND SON is a series based on a relationship between a father, ARTIE CILENTO and his loving daughter, RAMONA. Away after four years at BC's Business School, RAMONA returns home to her dad, ARTIE, the cook owner of MAMA AND SON Restaurant. The reunion pits the loving daughter and her business ideas of how to run a restaurant against her all knowing dad, the jack of all restauranteurs and master of none. The series explores an old time DAD who is up against the new world of computers, Internet, ipod, and all the tecno rap that is representing the new age world brought into his life in the restaurant by his all loving daughter Ramona. The resistance to change, the stalwart of the old neighborhood method of doing things, and the utmost regard for what relationship was at one time in this old neighborhood in New York sets the backdrop for all the differences to take shape. Beside the trailer on this site, Mama and Son Productions has a DVD of twenty-six minutes and a completed pilot episode, along with a five year proposal for this show. For inquiries please refer to the CONTACT link on our website.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?354711</url></doc>
