<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="355162">
  <docid>355162</docid>
  <title>Man Ki Aankhen</title>
  <year>1970</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Prabhavalkar, Madhu</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">U</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <directors>
    <director>Jhalani, Raghunath</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Nadiadwala, I.A.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bhakri</writer>
    <writer>Jwalamukhi</writer>
    <writer>Santoshi, P.L.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kudalkar, Laxmikant Shantaram</composer>
    <composer>Sharma, Pyarelal Ramprasad</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhardwaj, Brahm</actor>
      <role>Rai Bahadur</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chitnis, Leela</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Dinanath</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dharmendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Rajesh Agarwal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Faryal (I)</actor>
      <role>Vandana N. Agarwal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Krishna, Manmohan</actor>
      <role>Master Dinanath</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Sujit (I)</actor>
      <role>Naresh Agarwal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sherry, Mohan</actor>
      <role>Mr. Keshav</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>After working as a teacher in Delhi for several years, Master Dinanath decides to re-locate to a small village to spend the rest of the days teaching in a nearby school, his pay is the livelihood on which he, his wife and his daughter, Geeta alias Guddi, depend on for their survival. When one of his ex-students, Rajesh Agarwal, arrives from Delhi to look after his fruit and plantation business, Dinanath welcomes him home. Shortly thereafter, Geeta and Rajesh fall in love and are married in a simple ceremony. Rajesh wanted to marry Geeta first before telling his mother and elder married brother, Naresh, as he is afraid that his dowry-seeking mom, may forbid him from marrying Geeta. He hopes that she will ultimately give-in and accept Geeta as her daughter-in-law. With this hope they depart for Delhi. A few months later, Dinanath and his wife receive a letter from Geeta informing them all is well and that her mother-in-law's anger has subsided. Delighted with this news, Dinanath decides to visit Geeta in her palatial house, not knowing that this visit will change his life forever.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?355162</url></doc>
