<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="355157">
  <docid>355157</docid>
  <title>Man Jaiye</title>
  <year>1972</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Ishara, B.R.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Pandey, B.D.</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Verma, Jaidev</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Agha, Jalal</actor>
      <role>Ashok</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Madhumati</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mishra, Leela</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pandey, Rakesh</actor>
      <role>Ajay Sharma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sen, Asit (I)</actor>
      <role>Jathashankar Bholenath</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>College Lecturer Ajay Sharma has fixed views on the role of a woman, that is she must be subordinate to males during her entire lifetime, and publishes this article, much to the chagrin of Suman Acharya, who challenges him, photographs him in a compromising position, and threatens to expose him if he does not withdraw his anti-feminist comments. After a confrontation, both decide to let bygones be bygones, fall in love with each other, and get married in a temple. Their marriage does not last long and soon they consult an advocate, who instructs them to live apart for two years, and then file for divorce, to which both agree. Circumstances force them to meet each other in a train compartment, and they must enact the roles of loving spouses in order to fool Ajay's friend, Ashok, as well as Suman's maternal uncle Jathashankar Bholenath and his wife. The question does remain how long will the couple continue to pull wool over others' eyes, and it will not be long before everyone comes to know that their marriage has failed.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?355157</url></doc>
