<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="355429">
  <docid>355429</docid>
  <title>Man of the Soil</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Astenius, Stacy</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">19 September 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">26</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Astenius, Stacy</director>
    <director>Weaver, Chloe (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Astenius, Stacy</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Red River</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Ben leads a simple life in the small desert town of Vail, Arizona. At age thirteen he started mowing lawns, and by the time he was in high school was running his own landscaping company. After decades of heading up the same business, ultimately it is Ben's unique adventure-loving personality that keeps him from suffering from the tolls of monotony. Over the years he has concocted unique marketing schemes including a "Friday the 13th" ad campaign and outdoor festivals held on his property. As if this weren't exciting enough, it is his lifelong passion for sprint car racing that keeps his life interesting. Ben's good-humored wife, Susan would say that he "lives dangerously," yet to Ben there is no other way to live. The ultimate summation of this is his "one year plan," which entails living each day to its fullest, even if it is his last. Ben's passion for life is apparent and his joking personality allows him to maintain a fun and long-lasting relationship with his best friend Ron.While Ben's life appears simple from the periphery, it is evident that his world is nothing short of unique. Like his lifelong hero Louis Unser once told him, "never quit." And he never will. At the end of the day, Ben's excitement for life is irrefutable, his view of the world nothing short of inspiring.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?355429</url></doc>
