<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="356549">
  <docid>356549</docid>
  <title>Mann to Mann</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bond, Jay</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>male-stripper</keyword>
    <keyword>sister-sister-relationship</keyword>
    <keyword>father-daughter-relationship</keyword>
    <keyword>strip-club</keyword>
    <keyword>dead-father</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">27 October 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Diorio, Derek</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Diorio, Derek</producer>
    <producer>Gaudet, Aurèle</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Lalande, Dan</writer>
    <writer>Muggleton, John</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Burns, David (III)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ansell, Lorraine (I)</actor>
      <role>Victoria Mann</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ansell, Lorraine (I)</actor>
      <role>Victoria Mann</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Berketa, Norman Mikeal</actor>
      <role>Ventriloquist</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Clements, Christopher Lee</actor>
      <role>Ty Lennox</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Diorio, Derek</actor>
      <role>Serge</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dobbin, Michael (I)</actor>
      <role>Veronica's Ex</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hammond, Tori</actor>
      <role>Veronica 'Ronnie' Mann</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hammond, Tori</actor>
      <role>Veronica 'Ronnie' Mann</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kelly, Don (VIII)</actor>
      <role>Billy Broadfoot</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kidd, Douglas</actor>
      <role>Ed Shuster</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lawson, Jeff (II)</actor>
      <role>Paramedic</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McKenna, Patrick (I)</actor>
      <role>Jerry Riggins</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Simpson, Daniel (III)</actor>
      <role>Benoit</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"Mann To Mann" is the story of the Mann sisters, blustery Veronica, who insists on being called "Ronnie", and beleaguered Victoria, who insists on being called "Victoria." When their father, Alfred "Bud" Mann, lapses into a coma, his living will dictates that Victoria, the eldest, run Hot Shots; the male strip club that is the family cash cow. Victoria, a scion of rectitude who works at a reputable law firm, is appalled. Her sister Ronnie is incensed. The club should have gone to her; an opinion she maintains despite a past that includes alcoholism, bankruptcy, and, allegedly, arson. Forced despite her best efforts to helm Hot Shots, Victoria soon finds herself in over her head. Ronnie comes to the rescue and the two are forged into a reluctant partnership. Alternately helping and hindering are Jerry Riggins, the small time talent agent who provides the strippers... Ty Lennox, a high maintenance feature who would rather dance in "Stomp" on Broadway... and Billy Broadfoot, a.k.a. Billy Two Jokes, a native stand up who plays MC. Watch the Mann sisters as they try to "take it all off": familial obligation, dysfunctional behavior, the cursed and comic compromises of conducting business; struggles that pit Ronnie and Victoria "Mann To Mann." Episode One - When their father, Alfred "Bud" Mann, lapses into a coma, his living will dictates that Victoria, the eldest, run Hot Shots; the male strip club that is the family cash cow. Victoria, a scion of rectitude who works at a reputable law firm, is appalled. Her sister Ronnie is incensed. The club should have gone to her, but her father had other plans. The two come together in a clash of cultures and styles. Episode Two - When the regular club DJ is out of town, Jerry Riggins signs up long- winded, ex-public broadcaster Barry Hobarth to fill in. Hobarth's meandering style clashes with the clubs party culture with unfortunate consequences. Meanwhile, Ronnie is courted by a long forgotten childhood friend and an unexpected relative arrives on her doorstep. Episode Three - An old beau of Victoria's, Don returns to find her running a sleazy Male strip club, while Ty Lennox, the clubs new star attraction is assailed with a series of mysterious letters from a stalker. Episode Four - As Valentine's Day approaches all members of the Hot Shots staff are in a funk and bereft of new ideas for the "Hallmark Holiday". Ronnie would Love to have a boyfriend on Valentine's Day something she's never had, Billy Broadfoot would love to have some new stand-up material, Ty would love to have a new routine and Victoria would love to be making more money. But as we all know, Love often goes unrequited. Episode Five - An old friend of Jerry's, who is now a successful Los Angeles talent agent, offers him a new job and a huge salary. All he has to do is sell out his roster and his friends. Episode Six - Revenues are down at the club so Victoria institutes a series of cost cutting measures including "F.U.B.S. Night" and "Amateur Night", a move that has serious financial repercussions for the dancers, Billy, and their agent Jerry. Jerry solution is to bring in a long forgotten stripping legend, Rex Latouche, who's long in the tooth, but can do amazing things once he's packed away some French pastries.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?356549</url></doc>
