<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="357344">
  <docid>357344</docid>
  <title>Marca de agua</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Salzman, Iván</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Argentina</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">13</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Salzman, Iván</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Henriquez, Alejandro</producer>
    <producer>Salzman, Iván</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Salzman, Iván</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Fontana, Nicolás</composer>
    <composer>Spiller, Pablo</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cabrera Cantó, Lucas</actor>
      <role>Empleado</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lanfranchi, Eduardo</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>An office employee, trapped into a routinary and cyclical life, starts perceiving after some episodes and observing the alienated people's behavior, that he lives a fake life. He begins his search for his identity unearthing his repressed memories from a mental place represented by a nocturnal sandbox. On his journey to discover real life he confronts the Ticket-seller, who lives imprisoned in that fake life too, but prefers the security that routine provides. The employee begins unearthing superficial memories, which correspond to his fake life. Each confrontation with the Ticket-seller allows him to reach every time a deeper memory. He finally finds his identity at the bottom of the pit, represented by his childhood's objects and family photos. On the other side of the sandbox he sees the Ticket-seller burying something. The Employee runs to the place, where he unearths several identical clocks and puts in evidence the Ticket-seller's fake life. Ticket-seller and Employee go on with their normal life, but conscious of their condition now.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?357344</url></doc>
