<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="357602">
  <docid>357602</docid>
  <title>Mardon Wali Baat</title>
  <year>1988</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>plainclothes-officer</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">22 January 1988</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Brij (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Brij (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Azmi, Shabana</actor>
      <role>Seema</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Denzongpa, Danny</actor>
      <role>Raja Sunder Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dharmendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Yadvinder Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dutt, Sanjay</actor>
      <role>Tinku</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jayapradha</actor>
      <role>Asha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Pinchoo</actor>
      <role>Surajmal (Asha's dad)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kaul, Satish</actor>
      <role>Inspector Deepak</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Verma, Deven</actor>
      <role>Chaila</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Yadvinder Singh and his brother Tinku are career criminals in Bombay, India. They have always managed to elude the police, and continued with their way of life. Then one day, they receive a letter from a blackmailer, who claims that there is evidence that can send them to jail for a long time unless and until they go to a village named Kashipur and protect a boy named Rahul and other villagers from being killed by a gang of bandits led by Raja Sunder Singh. Fearful of being apprehended by the police, the duo decide to follow the blackmailer's instructions. They travel to Kashipur and tell the villagers that they are police officers in plainclothes sent to protect them against bandits. The simple-minded villagers accept this explanation, and both are accepted into the community. They find out that Rahul knows of a truck that contains millions of rupees of arms and ammunition, and it is for this reason that Raja Sunder Singh has been threatening them. At first they attempt to protect Rahul and the villagers against Raja's men, but eventually greed takes over and they agree to negotiate a deal with Raja for a large sum of money, little knowing that they are putting themselves under attack at the hands of the blackmailer. But Yadvinder and Tinku have a master plan - a plan that will change theirs' and the villagers lives forever.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?357602</url></doc>
