<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="358280">
  <docid>358280</docid>
  <title>Marilyn</title>
  <year>2000</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Adult</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>humor</keyword>
    <keyword>film-review</keyword>
    <keyword>satire</keyword>
    <keyword>sex</keyword>
    <keyword>marilyn-monroe</keyword>
    <keyword>porn</keyword>
    <keyword>hardcore</keyword>
    <keyword>parody</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Danish</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Denmark</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Denmark">2 September 2000</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Barbano, Nicolas</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Barbano, Nicolas</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barbano, Nicolas</actor>
      <role>Himself - Host</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Although an insightful and informative film review program in its own right, "Marilyn" was also a wicked satire on the famous Danish review program _"Bogart" (1985)_ (qv). For almost two decades, _"Bogart" (1985)_ (qv) was hosted by film critic 'Ole Michelsen' (qv), famous for his somewhat "artsy-fartsy" approach and love of French cinema. Each week on "Marilyn", in a setting evocative of Hollywood circa 1950, host 'Nicolas Barbano' (qv) would review and analyze hardcore videos, applying the eloquent language and scholarly approach associated with 'Ole Michelsen' (qv), while gesturing authoritatively with an unlit pipe. 'Nicolas Barbano' (qv), a film graduate of the University of Copenhagen and himself a widely published film critic, had previously appeared as a guest on _"Bogart" (1985)_ (qv), as part of a special report on the Cannes Film Festival. The press responded well to the program's satirical tone, frequently referring to "Marilyn" as "Bogart's naughty cousin". In spite of its explicit content, "Marilyn" was broadcast on a public, uncoded channel. Rating figures went sky-high, and the program was also made available world-wide via the Internet. It eventually folded because sponsors were reluctant to be associated with a sexually explicit program.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?358280</url></doc>
