<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="359816">
  <docid>359816</docid>
  <title>Mary's Laughter</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Eckhardt, Bret (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Paxton Jr., John</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Pappalardo, Thomas</producer>
    <producer>Paxton Jr., John</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Paxton Jr., John</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Livingston, Aaron</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gilbert, Allen</actor>
      <role>Jacob</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gustin, Gary</actor>
      <role>Cryus</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kaye, Jordan</actor>
      <role>Little Mary</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lagos, Penelope</actor>
      <role>Meredith</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rudasill, Jerry</actor>
      <role>Donnie</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Welcome to Amwell County, a little place that time has forgotten about. God couldn't have painted a more beautiful canvas but as with all beauty it's more important to know what is on the inside, even though most people don't care to always investigate that fact. Those who flock to this little piece of the world come to bask in its peacefulness and solitude, completely unaware of the area that is no longer on the map. Amwell County has a secret, the one that the developers of Serenity Hills forget to tell their patrons about. The Mitchum Family has watched as their once prosperous lifestyles have been extinguished and the town they once controlled slip into the hands of greedy northern interest. Since the major diversion of the main road, they have been left to wither away. You can have all that you want in this burg if you actually make it to your destination. It is a place for reflection and a timeout from all the madness that world can bring. But madness can be derived from isolation as well. There are a few rules when you head to Serenity... 1. Leave your cell phone at home it won't work out here 2. Make sure you have solid navigational skills 3. Keep a full tank of gas And most importantly never deviate from the main highway because out there in the blackness and desolation of it all Cyrus is waiting, and no one will come for you.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?359816</url></doc>
