<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="360796">
  <docid>360796</docid>
  <title>Matchbox Circus Train</title>
  <year>1997</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Memory, J. William</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">83</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Beizer, Chanan</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Miller, Karen (IV)</producer>
    <producer>Beizer, Chanan</producer>
    <producer>Rosen, Craig (I)</producer>
    <producer>Ryan, Maureen A.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Beizer, Chanan</writer>
    <writer>Pruitt, Bill</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>DeMartino, Mike</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Curry, Christopher (I)</actor>
      <role>Frank Sanders</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dancer, Paul C.</actor>
      <role>Petey</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kilroy, Colette</actor>
      <role>Claire Bowman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lehman, Benjamin</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mungovan, Jack</actor>
      <role>Jason Sanders</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Smith, Tristan (I)</actor>
      <role>Ben Sanders</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Treece, T. Ray</actor>
      <role>Park guide</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A complicated and unusual story about a lonely widower with two teenage sons who live on beautiful Mackinac Island. The widower (Frank) invites his girlfriend (Claire),to stay with them for the summer. She quickly becomes the hit of the household and life for the three guys starts to improve as she infuses their home with maternal touches. Claire, however, has dreams of her own. It turns out she is a singer whose career is in the doldrums. She wants to jump start things by performing at one of the Island's venues. Frank can help her since he owns he place and can also provide her with an opportunity to gain wider attention by setting her up to perform at the annual governor's banquet. When he realizes her act is not appropriate for the event, he pulls the rug out from under Claire and cancels her gig. Claire gets even by - what else - seducing his elder son. Things fall apart when the tryst is discovered by the younger son. The tragedy unfolds and things fall apart. This little flick is destined to be a camp classic.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?360796</url></doc>
