<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="361109">
  <docid>361109</docid>
  <title>Matok Ve'Mar</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Asher, Tova</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hebrew</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Israel</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Israel">15 May 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Canada">27 August 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">101</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Benvenisti, Doron</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Benvenisti, Doron</writer>
    <writer>Ganihar, Alma</writer>
    <writer>Safdie, Oren</writer>
    <writer>Vujic, D. Daniel</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Bar-Giora, Jonathan</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grant, Tzufit</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ravitz, Nati</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shehter, Eyal</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Ran directs a successful international investment company. He is married to Dana and they have two children. Keren, a musician, is married to Leon, an attorney. David is a successful gynecologist, who lives with his boyfriend Gal. No one knows his true sexual identity, so Ran sets him up with Daniella, his secretary. A quiet evening together is interrupted by the unexpected arrival of a fortune teller. Her prophecies disturb the group's fragile harmony and each of these people's lives begins to unravel. Ran is faced with an unnerving request: his 82-year-old mother is suffering from Alzheimer's and asks her son to help her end her life. Dana must decide whether to keep the child she is carrying and tell her husband that he is not the father. Keren and Leon are at a crossroads; Leondoesn't want to have children, Keren does. David needs to choose between Gal and his desire for a conventional family and children. Daniella is tired of looking for love and must decide whether David is the one.The emotional chaos in these people's lives forces them to account for their actions. Will they be able to live with their decisions?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?361109</url></doc>
