<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="362359">
  <docid>362359</docid>
  <title>Mazdoor</title>
  <year>1983</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Chopra, Ravi (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Chopra, B.R.</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Burman, Rahul Dev</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Agnihotri, Rati</actor>
      <role>Smita Batra/Smita Ramesh Saxena</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Babbar, Raj</actor>
      <role>Ashok Mathur</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bakshi, Arun</actor>
      <role>Mill worker</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hussain, Nasir (I)</actor>
      <role>Sinha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Iftekhar</actor>
      <role>Kundanlal Batra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kiran, Raj</actor>
      <role>Ramesh Saxena</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kolhapure, Padmini</actor>
      <role>Meena Saxena/Meena Ashok Mathur</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Dilip (I)</actor>
      <role>Dinanath Saxena</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Oberoi, Suresh</actor>
      <role>Hiralal Sinha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Parvez, Yunus</actor>
      <role>Yunus</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, Madan (I)</actor>
      <role>Daulatram (Hiralal's Manager)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, Rajesh</actor>
      <role>Mill worker</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Raj, Jagdish</actor>
      <role>Police Inspector</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Walker, Johnny (III)</actor>
      <role>Govinda</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Kind-hearted and compassionate Mr. Sinha runs a textile mill in a city in India, and shares his profits by paying generous wages and bonuses to his grateful workers. But when he unexpectedly passes away, his son, Hiralal, takes over and changes everything in order to maximize profits. This brings him into conflict with his employees, including a long-time employee named Dinanath Saxena. When Dinanath openly confronts Hiralal in a public meeting, Hiralal wants him to tender a written apology, but Dinanath instead resigns and decides to open his very own mill with the help of a struggling Engineer, Ashok Mathur. After some struggles, they do open a mill, and get help from some employees of Hiralal's mill. Soon they earn a good reputation, get more orders than they bargained for, and the money starts pouring in. Dinanath finds out that his daughter, Meena, has fallen in love with Ashok, and is delighted. He asks Ashok for his consent, and thereafter the marriage takes place. What Dinanath does not know that Ashok is in love with Smita Batra, the only daughter of multi-millionaire and Dinanath's benefactor, Kundanlal, but is afraid to tell this. An angry Smita is all set to avenge herself, and she does so by marrying Meena's brother, Ramesh, with a view of creating discord in Ashok's marital life, and bringing him to ruin. Things go according to Smita's plan and soon Ashok is cast out of the Saxena family; Meena distrusts him; Ramesh would like to see him behind bars, and the only one who wants to help Ashok is Hiralal - but he does have a secret agenda surrounded by lies, deception, and treachery.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?362359</url></doc>
