<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="362918">
  <docid>362918</docid>
  <title>Me, Joe &amp; B.T.K.</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Grana, Raphael</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">10 August 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
<plot>ME, JOE &amp; B.T.K. is the debut feature documentary from Paul Nixon and Matthew Clyde. Part road movie, part investigation, it tells the story of the filmmakers' journey to the heart of America's most shocking modern-day murder mystery. In January 1974, notorious serial killer, the B.T.K. Strangler, claimed his first victims in Wichita, Kansas. A present day Jack the Ripper, the Strangler would Bind, Torture and Kill seven victims over the next five years, writing gleeful letters detailing his crimes to a police force in utter turmoil. The letters and killings then ceased completely. No sooner had the Strangler arrived, than he had vanished into thin air. In March 2004, 25 years later, a local newspaper receives a letter - B.T.K. is back. This compelling documentary follows the B.T.K. story from the first brutal murders through to the present day, revealing both the complexity of the case and the scale of impact on the local community. Extensive interviews with law enforcement, former suspects and a criminal profiler provide a reliable tip-off as to the identity of the Strangler, suddenly taking the filmmakers out of their comfort zone and into a heart-racing manhunt. Compelled by mounting evidence, Nixon and Clyde take matters into their own hands and team up with private detective Angela Byrd in a bid to locate and confront their suspect Joe Grill. Believing they might just have their man, they engineer a face-to-face meeting. Is this really B.T.K? Or has their tireless quest compromised their subjectivity?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?362918</url></doc>
