<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="364102">
  <docid>364102</docid>
  <title>Mehndi</title>
  <year>1983</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Sen, Asit (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Khayyam (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Babbar, Raj</actor>
      <role>Ajit Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Birbal</actor>
      <role>Langotiprasad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bothra, Raj</actor>
      <role>Dr. Rajan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Choti, Mohan</actor>
      <role>Shakti's friend</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deo, Seema</actor>
      <role>Lisa</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Goswami, Bindiya</actor>
      <role>Gauri</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Shakti (I)</actor>
      <role>Shakti Ratan Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kaur, Ranjeeta</actor>
      <role>Madhuri 'Madhu'</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kiran, Usha</actor>
      <role>Gautam's mom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mehra, Vinod</actor>
      <role>Gautam</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, Madan (I)</actor>
      <role>Madhuri's dad</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Gautam is an Officer in the Indian Army, and is very friendly with another Army Officer, Ajit Singh. Both are assigned tasks that take them to the battlefront. Gautam's senior officer asks him to deliver an urgent letter to the Colonel, on the way, Gautam is injured and is helped by a local belle, Gauri. After he recuperates under her care, both fall in love with each other. When he fully recovers, he promises to return as soon as possible to marry her. He does return after a few days, and finds her lifeless and sexually molested body. He hunts down the culprits, turns them over to the law, and returns home to his mom, who has arranged a marriage for him with a woman named Madhuri. Initially he refuses to marry, but when his mom has a heart attack, he relents and marries Madhuri. Then he gets more devastating news when he is told that Ajit is missing and believed to be dead. Several months later, while celebrating Madhuri's birthday, Gautam is overjoyed to find that Ajit is alive and has returned home in one piece. What Gautam does not know is that Ajit and Madhuri had been lovers, his re-appearance may well result in Madhuri leaving him, and it looks like Gautam may lose yet another love of his life.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?364102</url></doc>
