<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="364104">
  <docid>364104</docid>
  <title>Mehndi</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>tv-mini-series</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Urdu</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Pakistan</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Pakistan">June 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">480</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Fazil, Javed</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Ghazal, Seema</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ali, Abid</actor>
      <role>Hassan Ali</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ali, Fiza</actor>
      <role>Laiba</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Aslam, Aijaz</actor>
      <role>Rameez</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hai, Jahanara</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Haq, Aminah</actor>
      <role>Alishba</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hussain, Amna</actor>
      <role>Malaika</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jillani, Kamran</actor>
      <role>Ayaad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Ayesha (I)</actor>
      <role>Sajjal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Saeed, Humayun</actor>
      <role>Shahzaib</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Siddiqui, Adnan</actor>
      <role>Taha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wajid, Qazi</actor>
      <role>Father of Rameez</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Abid Ali and Jahanara Hai have four daughters, Malaika (Amna Hussain), Sajjal (Ayesha Khan), Alishba (Aminah Haq) and Laiba (Fiza Ali), who are all getting married on the same day. Three of them, Malaika, Sajjal and Laiba have chosen their own partners while Alishba's wedding is an arranged one, to her father's friend (Qazi Wajid's) son Rameez (Aijaz Aslam). They get married and then each has to face their own difficulties, in marriage. Malaika's husband, Adnan Siddiqui, is a financially weak person and wants Malaika's father to set him up financially. His demands start from the very beginning, creating problems for Malaika. Rameez was in love with another girl Ramsha and was forced by his parents, Qazi Wajid and Ayesha Khan, to marry Alishba. He marries her and then leaves the house on his wedding night. Both Laiba and her husband Ayaad (Kamran Jillani) are very childish in their attitude and start fighting from the first day. Sajjal, who gets married to her cousin Shahzaib (Humayun Saeed) is the only one without any difficulties in marriage, or will she have some problems too.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?364104</url></doc>
