<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="364245">
  <docid>364245</docid>
  <title>Mein Ek Din Laut Kay Aaoon Ga</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Zafar (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Urdu</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Pakistan</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">August 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Pakistan">1 August 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">158</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Fazil, Javed</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Alam, Shoaib</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Ahmad, Jawad</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Butt, Ahmed</actor>
      <role>Zoheb</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gul, Ajab</actor>
      <role>Babar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kanwal, Pooja</actor>
      <role>Sheeza</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nadeem (II)</actor>
      <role>Dr. Azim</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pervaiz, Saba</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Haroon</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Saeed, Humayun</actor>
      <role>Babar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sheikh, Javed (I)</actor>
      <role>Mr. Khan</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Mein Ek Din Laut Kay Aaoon Ga, essentially revolves around a typical family setup. But the film has too many songs and twists and turns at regular intervals. As a result, the average person in the audience ends up getting lost in the subtle confusion. Zoheb runs his late father's business with the help of Mr. Khan. His mother, Mrs. Haroon, is busy preparing for her daughter's wedding while also on the lookout for a suitable match for her son. Meanwhile, Zoheb chances to meet Sheeza and a song or two later, falls madly in love with her and marries her without his mother's consent. But once she finds out, Saba's character asks her son to bring his wife home. While driving back home with his bride, Zoheb is pushed over a cliff by Sheeza. Hence, the first twist Sheeza is actually Mr. Khan's daughter, who had suffered insult at the hands of Zoheb's father when the latter refused to give him his share in the business. Sheeza married the son to avenge her father's mistreatment, and the father-daughter duo then force Zoheb's family out of the house and forcibly take possession of all the property. But unknown to the Khans, Zoheb survives the fall at the cost of having his face mutilated. Enters his savior, plastic surgeon Dr Azim, who not only gives him a new face but a new name as well, Babar. But Zoheb's new identity also has a past and it is only when Sherry enters the picture that he finds out about it. After some more unexpected twists, Sherry falls in love with Babar and helps him avenge himself from the likes of Mr. Khan and Sheeza, thus leading to a reunion with his family.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?364245</url></doc>
