<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="366175">
  <docid>366175</docid>
  <title>Mera Karam Mera Dharam</title>
  <year>1987</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Guha, Dulal</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Lalwani, Mohan</producer>
    <producer>Lalwani, Prem (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kudalkar, Laxmikant Shantaram</composer>
    <composer>Sharma, Pyarelal Ramprasad</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bali, Yogeeta</actor>
      <role>Neela</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhardwaj, Brahm</actor>
      <role>Surendra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhatt, Urmila</actor>
      <role>Shivani Sharma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhattacharya, Abhi</actor>
      <role>Purohit</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brahmachari</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chatterjee, Moushumi</actor>
      <role>Mala</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dharmendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Ajay Shankar Sharma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Haksar, Rajan</actor>
      <role>Chowkidar Ram Bhajan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hingoo, Dinesh</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khanna, Padma</actor>
      <role>Courtesan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Uttam (I)</actor>
      <role>Deviprasad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lagoo, Shreeram</actor>
      <role>Sarjuprasad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mehra, Raj</actor>
      <role>Doctor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Merchant, Mushtaq</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Raj, Jagdish</actor>
      <role>Police Inspector</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sajjan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sen, Asit (I)</actor>
      <role>Headmaster</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Walker, Johnny (III)</actor>
      <role>Taraknath</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Ajay Shankar Sharma and his mom, Shivani, live a poor lifestyle until one day when Shankar's maternal uncle, Deviprasad, comes to visit them and bequeaths a a large estate and wealth for their well-being, on the condition that they improve their home-town Sundergarh, the responsibility of which lies on Deviprasad's son, Sarjuprasad. Ajay and his mom agree to do so. Shortly thereafter his mom and Deviprasad pass away. Ajay manages the Bombay-based business, and frequently sends large sums of money to Sarjuprasad for the development of roads, and a new school building. He then receives a number of anonymous letters informing him that Sarjuprasad has not been putting the money to good use. Ajay decides to pay Sundergarh a visit, and is shocked to find that the money has been misappropriated. He decides to work with the villages to build a new school building. This does not auger well with Sarjuprasad, who vilifies Ajay's name, making him look like a big city Casanova. Matters do not improve when Ajay is caught red-handed with a local village belle named Mala, and it is no secret that Ajay has a girlfriend by the name of Neela. Under the circumstances, the villagers believe that Ajay is here merely to molest village belles, and refuse to have to do anything with him. What will make the villagers see the light? Where has Sarjuprasad been spending all the money?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?366175</url></doc>
