<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="366178">
  <docid>366178</docid>
  <title>Mera Lahoo</title>
  <year>1987</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Mayekar, V.N.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">13 March 1987</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Veerendra (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Malik, Anu</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Birbal</actor>
      <role>Raunaki</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dhawan, Sunil</actor>
      <role>Senior Police Inspector</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Govinda</actor>
      <role>Govinda Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grover, Gulshan</actor>
      <role>Dhaneshwar 'Dhanu'</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Guddu (I)</actor>
      <role>Preeti</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Katkar, Kimi</actor>
      <role>Pavitra D. Singh/Geeta</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Huma</actor>
      <role>Dancer - Singer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kiran, Raj</actor>
      <role>Dharam Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shivraj (I)</actor>
      <role>Pavitra's dad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Walia, Harjeet</actor>
      <role>Daaku Vikram</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Widowed Avanti Singh lives a poor lifestyle in an Indian village, along with two sons, Dharam and Govinda, and a daughter, Preeti, who is married to a Police Inspector. Dharam gets married to Pavitra, who has a look alike sister, Geeta, who meets with and falls in love with fellow collegian Govinda. Pavitra has an admirer in Dhaneshwar, a local wealthy Zamindar and aspiring politician, but Pavitra shuns him. Govinda and Pavitra share a special relationship and Dharam suspects them of having an affair, arguments ensue and Govinda is asked to leave. He re-locates to live with a former enemy, Chennu, and returns home to find that Avanti had prevented Dhaneshwar from molesting Pavitra, and Dharam, who went to avenge this humiliation, was killed. Enraged, Govinda rushes to kill Dhaneshwar, but ends up killing Raunaki, and after a chase is arrested and lodged in a cell. With Dharam dead and Govinda behind bars, Dhaneshwar seizes this opportunity and this time does sexually molest Pavitra. Who will now avenge Pavitra and Dharam?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?366178</url></doc>
