<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="366408">
  <docid>366408</docid>
  <title>Meres orgis, ena rekviem gia tin Evropi</title>
  <year>1995</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bitsakakis, Tassos</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>experimental-film</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Greek</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby SR</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Greece</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">73</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Mazomenos, Vassilis</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Mazomenos, Vassilis</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Mazomenos, Vassilis</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Natsios, Christos</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sfikas, Kostas</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stefanakis, Kostas</actor>
      <role>Rebel</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Man's will to rise above his earthly self and to soar into the abysmal confusion at all our pasts provides the material for a monstrously ambitious plan to create a World City. The journey of Daedalus into myth and history is likened to the birth, the rise and the fall of western civilization and becomes the form taken by the film, an allegory on man's place in the modern chaos of civilization. DAYS OF RAGE, attempts an introduction into a new method, into what is known as "documentary animation". The accepted term "poetic animation with elements of fiction" might perhaps describe what we are aiming at. And this because the film does not completely follow the methods of classical animation . With this method movement is not always used except when the subject itself demands it in order to create tension of a dramatic type but also as a bridge between two scenes. This movement might be the fluttering of Daedalus' wings, the fall of an angel and the coexistence of the animated and the static images in the same shot (newsreel). It is, in other words, an attempt to see a modern explorations in the field of the audiovisual language compressed into the film without subordinating poetry to technology but rather the reverse</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?366408</url></doc>
