<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="368442">
  <docid>368442</docid>
  <title>Micheal's Storm</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Juncker, Andrew</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">11 November 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">21</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Juncker, Andrew</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Juncker, Andrew</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Juncker, Andrew</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Juncker, Andrew</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Austin, Phil (II)</actor>
      <role>Eric</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Coughlan, Matt (III)</actor>
      <role>Micheal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>DeRuvo, Fred</actor>
      <role>TV Repairman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Franzen, Mark</actor>
      <role>Caller</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Northcott, Marc</actor>
      <role>Man on TV</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sellen, Andrew</actor>
      <role>Timothy</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Micheal is an obsessive-compulsive agoraphobic whose fear is so great that he dares not admit it, even to himself. The seclusion and apparent sanctuary of his home is shared with two people. His house mates are Timothy, a spirited freelance photographer, and Eric, a conflicted businessman on the verge of cynicism. Micheal spends most of his time keeping up the house and watching TV, until he receives an anonymous threatening phone call that coincides with bizarre cable problems. Instead of addressing this mysterious threat, he decides it might be best to ignore it and let it resolve itself. In a moment of vulnerability, an ominous life-or-death encounter forces Micheal to either act or resign himself to fatalism. In an encounter with a shadowy intruder, Michael is thrust beyond the mundane and material, beyond creed and ideology, into a direct experience of transformation and self-discovery. Illuminated in his darkest hour, he finds his own personal power and the meaning of grace and forgiveness. This beautifully shot drama, with its haunting original score, invokes both terror and the exquisiteness of being.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?368442</url></doc>
