<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="368851">
  <docid>368851</docid>
  <title>Midlife Crisis</title>
  <year>2011</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Romare, Deborah</director>
    <director>Wiley, Vincent J.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Wiley, John C.</producer>
    <producer>Romare, Deborah</producer>
    <producer>Wiley, Vincent J.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Romare, Deborah</writer>
    <writer>Wiley, Vincent J.</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>When Jack Wiles, a man in his early forties loses his job, his wife, his best friend and ultimately his dignity all in one day, he spirals into an abyss, better known as a mid-life crisis. Jack seeks every kind of help to get through the debacle; a priest; hey maybe it's spiritual, a shrink; could it be all in his head; and finally an eccentric Guru. They all put in their two-cents trying to rescue Jack, unfortunately it adds up to big trouble when Jack is liquored up, drugged out and utterly mystified into a series of mind altering events that launch him into the head-trip of a lifetime. Jack's head-trip takes him back in time to the 70's when he was young and care-free; just one small problem; he's not young or carefree, he's in his forties and on the verge of a nervous breakdown! So while he's thrown into the old life of young girls, parties and absolutely no responsibilities he ultimately realizes that what he really needs to find, is the answer to one of life's most enigmatic questions; Where the hell did I go wrong? But like any mid life crisis, it's simply all a state of mind so when Jack awakens to the reality of his situation and back to present day, he desperately attempts to catch up with his destiny. Unfortunately, the only things he has waiting for him is no job, no wife and no friends. Welcome back, Jack!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?368851</url></doc>
