<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="369422">
  <docid>369422</docid>
  <title>Miilee</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Kumar, Raman (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Nanda, Vinta</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Kumar, Raman (I)</writer>
    <writer>Torres, Enrique (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gehi, Ajay</actor>
      <role>Rahul</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kahn, Imran Mashkoor</actor>
      <role>Karan Mehra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Kiran (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Malhotra, Shonali</actor>
      <role>Neena</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sheikh, Aashif</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Verma, Rocky</actor>
      <role>Municipal Officer</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Miilee is the story of a young orphan girl, living in a convent in Shimla. Living amongst the nuns, young Miilee leads a very simple and carefree life loved and adored by all around her, she often gets off with little impishness that irritates the mother superior in the convent. Yet, she is so adorable that everybody who gets to know her grows fond of her. Miilee has a very intriguing personality. She can be a complete tomboy, is an incorrigible prankster who has several friends, a game of soccer never ceases to excite her. On the other hand, there is this extremely native, sensitive and caring girl who is so different from the brash tomboy! Life is so comforting and happy until Miilee's greatest fears come true. She is asked to leave the convent on turning eighteen. Her life takes the most unexpected turn as she sets foot into the Rastogi household headed by the rich industrialist Vishal Rastogi. Miilee is brought in as a companion to the old and irritable grandmother who has lived as a recluse since many years. Miilee is like a breath of fresh air in the Rastogi household where she adds colours and cheers up the otherwise mundane life of the family members. There is never a dull moment with Miilee around in the Rastogi household until a shocking truth from the past is revealed...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?369422</url></doc>
