<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="370111">
  <docid>370111</docid>
  <title>Millennium Factor: The Truth About Y2K</title>
  <year>1999</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kennedy, Sheri</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>conspiracy</keyword>
    <keyword>y2k</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">23 November 1999</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Rayburn, Les</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Rayburn, Abby</producer>
    <producer>DeBardeleben, Henry</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Rayburn, Les</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Cotter, Tom (IV)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wescott, Don</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>PBS documentary that debunked the so called "Millennium Bug" that was feared would cause massive chaos on January 1, 2000. This high stylish documentary featured interviews with experts like Senator Bob Bennett, MIT professor Robert Alloway, FAA administrator Jane Garvey, and others. Lensed by Commercial director, Les Rayburn, this documentary is a departure from the standard fare of interviews and clips;instead relying on beautifully lit visuals of computer parts, an eerie musical score and even shots of beautiful Asian women that look more at home in a Science Fiction piece. The techniques work well though, providing insight into not only the highly technical world of software programming, but also the hysteria that surrounded this event. The film makes it case by first over-stating the problem and dwelling on the conspiracy theories of Y2K, then breaking them down one by one with interviews and striking visuals. At the end of the film, the viewer not only could sleep at night but might even be tempted to chuckle at the well meaning but misinformed people who dug shelters, stockpiled food, and purchased firearms.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?370111</url></doc>
