<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="371255">
  <docid>371255</docid>
  <title>Miracle Cure</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Albarian, John</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">30 September 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">40</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Albarian, John</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Albarian, John</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Albarian, John</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Miracle Cure is an in-depth discussion of the restoration process of the legendary Who film, The Kid's Are Alright. John Albarian, the producer in charge of the film's restoration for DVD, describes what his original intent for the project was, and compares it to what it became. The film covers the many efforts made by various industry artists and technicians to remedy problems non-theatrical versions of the film have had including sound and speed issues, aspect ratio glitches, dirt and scratch problems and several other things attributed to the poor condition of this incredible film by first time director Jeff Stein. The film also includes an interesting piece on DRS (Digital Restoration Services) and highlights some of the more severe visual problems with the film and the efforts needed to clean them up. Sound aficionados will appreciate the discussion of going from 2.0 mono to a 5.1 Digital track as well as hearing about the joys of obtaining and using the original Shepperton multi-track mixes. This is an exhaustive documentary and one of the best yet presented on DVD as regards the restoration of a film for release on DVD.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?371255</url></doc>
