<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="372010">
  <docid>372010</docid>
  <title>Miss Carrie Ann's Boarding House</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Arguilo</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>feminization</keyword>
    <keyword>femdom</keyword>
    <keyword>bdsm</keyword>
    <keyword>cross-dressing</keyword>
    <keyword>dominatrix</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">5 April 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">75</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Arguilo</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Arguilo</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Arguilo</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brown, Carrie Ann</actor>
      <role>Miss Carrie Ann</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kade</actor>
      <role>Kade</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Long, Devaun</actor>
      <role>Devaun</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Miss Carrie Ann's Boarding House, a full-length girls feminizing men movie, will satisfy your femdom fantasy. Travel back to an innocent time where a rebel shreds her petticoats and turns a rambunctious boy into a well behaved girl. In 1954, girls were girls and men were men... but at Miss Carrie Ann's Boarding House we find out what happens when those roles are reversed . The strict head mistress, Miss Carrie Ann, has recently taken on two new boarders. Devaun, a fiery young debutant, refuses to be sugar and spice and everything nice and begins to push the rules of society. Kade, a mechanical engineering student, discovers that everything he believes in is challenged by the sweet and seductive Devaun. As they struggle for dominance, Devaun seduces away Kade's masculinity. Then with the help of Miss Carrie Ann, Devaun shows Kade that females aren't always the weaker sex. The scared and defeated Kade finds himself as the only boy enrolled in a girls finishing school - as he is trained to live as a woman.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?372010</url></doc>
