<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="373604">
  <docid>373604</docid>
  <title>Mnemonica</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Deleo, Chris</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Mystery</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>adult-film</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>surrealism</keyword>
    <keyword>experimental</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">86</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="USA">85</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Deleo, Chris</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Deleo, Chris</producer>
    <producer>Deleo, Chris</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Deleo, Chris</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Deleo, Chris</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Casto, Sal</actor>
      <role>Young Bucky</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chaffin, Callie</actor>
      <role>Alice Klosterman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Decamps, Eric</actor>
      <role>Mr. Klosterman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dorian, Bob</actor>
      <role>Richard Ellison</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gallo, George (III)</actor>
      <role>Man in Bar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Garbarino, Robert</actor>
      <role>Crusher</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Holland, Richard (V)</actor>
      <role>Lloyd</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lombardi, Paul (V)</actor>
      <role>Tommy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mandel, Zach</actor>
      <role>Bucky Kaps</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mcneely, Terry</actor>
      <role>Shane</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rigano, Joseph</actor>
      <role>The Messenger</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Santoro, Brenda</actor>
      <role>Young Meghan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stengel, John</actor>
      <role>Scooch</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Lone boiler technician, Bucky Kaps is a level headed young man. He holds only one important memory: Meghan Connor. He remembers his childhood crush and the day she leaned in and kissed him. Tommy was there as well, watching from behind a tree. The kiss was golden, but Tommy intervened and took Meghan away while Bucky watched, paralyzed by his inability to act. It was a terrible day. Ten years later, and Bucky is a now technical whiz. His work down at the city power plant is important and rewarding. His employer, Mr. Klosterman gave Bucky a chance. He saw potential in the young man. Alice Klosterman also sees Bucky's potential. And she makes her feelings clear. But Bucky is a company man. He will not jeopardize his position at the work place by dating the bosses daughter. So he avoids Alice, hoping she will go away. Through a questionable reality, Meghan rocks Bucky's world by turning up in his bedroom one afternoon. A ghost of sorts, Meghan advises Bucky to "look deep" into his past. There are dark secrets beneath the surface. Bucky remembers several disturbing events involving Meghan and her drug dealer boyfriend, Shane. In a rash decision, Bucky quits his job and dives head first into his murky past. Refusing to give up on the guy she loves, Alice continues to hold Bucky in the present. Bucky rejects Alice's help, but his rejection only fuels her. Competition quickly turns fierce between this loner, his ghost, and the girl who loves him.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?373604</url></doc>
