<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="374062">
  <docid>374062</docid>
  <title>Modern Motherhood</title>
  <year>1934</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>doctor</keyword>
    <keyword>movie-theater</keyword>
    <keyword>motherhood</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>mother</keyword>
    <keyword>abortion</keyword>
    <keyword>pregnancy</keyword>
    <keyword>parent</keyword>
    <keyword>childbirth</keyword>
    <keyword>child</keyword>
    <keyword>lost-film</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">16 November 1934</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Esper, Dwain</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Esper, Dwain</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bradford, Gardner</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Molly and Ted Wayne, a young, newly married couple, plan to live their lives in the fast lane. The have no desire for children. At first. Soon, Molly wonders about the positive aspects of kids. Ted on the other hand, finds he is growing to hate children more with each passing day. They visit their friends Bob Helen, who have a lot of kids, and agree that their friends are "tied down" by their brood. Soon, Molly discovers she is pregnant. She considers getting the child aborted until she visits the local movie house and sees a film about sex higene. She is so upset by the movie, particularely an abortion scene, that she decides to keep the child. Returning home to Ted, she informs him of her condition. He goes out drinking for several days, until he does to his mother's house, where she tells him Molly is worried about him. He goes back to the bar, where he saved a boy who is getting beat up. He realizes his place is with his wife and their child. Molly gives birth to a boy, and they live happily ever after.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?374062</url></doc>
