<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="374534">
  <docid>374534</docid>
  <title>Mojito - L'altra luce del cinema</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Salvi, Irene</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>blind-man</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Italian</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Italy">T</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Italy">9 September 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">20</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Bruno, Stefano</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Rosada, Nicola</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Di Fonzo, Giulia</actor>
      <role>Anna</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Horvat, Igor</actor>
      <role>Paolo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Marascalchi, Luciano</actor>
      <role>Baker</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Paolo, an energetic and fit young man in his thirties, alone in his room keeps on living over again the fatal car crash that caused him a partial sight loss. Despite his parent are overprotective to him, Paolo has found the strength to respond to his condition. On the other hand what really makes him feeling cripple and roughly reacting is other people's commiseration which he cannot bear. But Anna, a young painter, will be the one to remind him that he's not allowed to be rude to all the world just because he's blind. Paolo then agrees to take her challenge and wants Anna to try what being in a dark world means: she only has noises and sounds amplification to orient herself. they therefore hang around together in the streets to discover the beauties of Venice up to feel the liberating emotion of a run in a slightly one meter and a half narrow street. This experience represent a sort of rebirth for both of them, even thought she has to leave for Paris where a medical équipe is waiting for her. She will found out lately to have a glaucoma, a pathology that, if untreated, will bring her to blindness. Whatever is going to happen now, thanks to Paolo, Anna is no more afraid of the dark since she understood that the best way to keep on seeing is just dreaming.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?374534</url></doc>
