<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="376424">
  <docid>376424</docid>
  <title>Monty Alexander Trio: The Paris Concert</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>jazz</keyword>
    <keyword>piano</keyword>
    <keyword>paris</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">8 July 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">110</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Alexander, Monty</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shakour, Hassan W.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Thomas, Bobby (XI)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This magical concert from the New Morning in 2001, finds the magnificent Monty Alexander accompanied by Bobby Thomas, Jr. and Hassan W. Shakour. The life &amp; career of pianist great and groove master Monty Alexander is a dream come true... Born in Kingston, Jamaica, on D-Day, this formidably gifted &amp; happy child prodigy soon directed his feet to the sunny side of the street, like Louis "Satchmo" Armstrong, his first hero, sang. His lucky star showed up before he was twenty years old, when Frank Sinatra produced him in that temple of fifties and sixties pop music, Jilly's Bar in New York. After Ray Brown invited Monty to sit in, he was ready to go. He never looked back. Monty's swing &amp; lyricism inspired such giants as Milt Jackson, Clark Terry, Dizzy Gillespie and a whole pantheon of stars, who he accompanied to the four corners of the Earth... - in the course of an exemplary musical journey both as monster pianist and subtle composer. These days, he revisits Randy Weston and Bob Marley for an irresistible return to his Jamaican roots.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?376424</url></doc>
