<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="377009">
  <docid>377009</docid>
  <title>More Abandon</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Abel, Katie</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 December 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">18</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Haley, Brett (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Corwin, Kelley</producer>
    <producer>Ferris, Joshua</producer>
    <producer>Halabi, Kenan</producer>
    <producer>Lobel, Gilana</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Ferris, Joshua</writer>
    <writer>Haley, Brett (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>English, Bill (III)</actor>
      <role>Joe</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ward, Keith (III)</actor>
      <role>Electrician</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>One night in an advertising agency, after everyone has gone home, Joe stays behind to catch up on work. Joe's a hard worker, well-liked and even-tempered. But on this night something inexplicable happens. He takes a small hiatus from work to roam the agency's corridors. As he moves from office to office, Joe starts to take stock, perhaps for the first time, of how his co-workers live in this 9-to-5 space: the stuff they hang on their walls and the memorabilia that litters their desks, and how it relates to their private lives. Joe's wanderings bring him to one office in particular, where he calls the office line of his colleague, Genevieve. His first few calls are merely to hear her voicemail. But the night's accumulation of silence and desolation has worked a spell on Joe, and he makes a simple decision he can't retract, which will change the course of his personal and professional life. MORE ABANDON is a short film about breakdowns and breakthroughs. The story of a well-respected member of the professional community taking a momentary respite from common sense and self-composure, MORE ABANDON is the very human story of the disconnectedness that creeps up in cubical space, and Joe's poignant and sadly humorous attempts to defy it.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?377009</url></doc>
