<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="378436">
  <docid>378436</docid>
  <title>Mothers of Today</title>
  <year>1939</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Foster, Harry (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>yiddish</keyword>
    <keyword>jewish</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Yiddish</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 March 1939</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">93</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Lynn, Henry</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Lynn, Henry</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Lynn, Henry</writer>
    <writer>Wolf, Simon (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Field, Leon</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Epstein, William (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Field, Esther</actor>
      <role>Esther Waldman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Goldstein, Louis</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Krause, Gertrude</actor>
      <role>Anna</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Krause, Solomon</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lehrer, Sam</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lubelski, Paula</actor>
      <role>Breindl 'Beatrice' Boxer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lubow, Vera</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Marks, Philip</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rosenblatt, Max</actor>
      <role>Solomon Waldman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Seidenberg, Leon</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shargel, Jack</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Winters, Arthur</actor>
      <role>Izzie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wolf, Simon (I)</actor>
      <role>Getzel Boxer</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Mothers of Today includes the sole motion picture performance of radio star Esther Field, who was well known on the airwaves of the 1930s as the 'Yiddishe Mama.' The film exemplifies the Yiddish film genre of shund, a brand of popular entertainment which appealed to working-class Jewish-American immigrant audiences with broadly-drawn, sentimental stories that reflected the daily life and culture of a distinctively American Yiddish community. While the shund films were invariably low-budget (and low-brow) affairs, these humble productions formed an important part of life in the United States for their audience. For actresses such as Field or Celia Adler (star of Where is My Child?, also directed by Lynn in 1939), shund offered one of the few opportunities to play strong leading roles. In retrospect, Mothers of Today is an important cultural artifact expressing the anxieties of Jewish immigrant families faced with the younger generation's increasing assimilation into mainstream American society. Shund often dealt with the plight of the Jewish mother, recognizing the important role women played in Jewish family life during the difficult period of immigration. Such is the case with Mothers of Today, in which Field plays a mother coping with her children's troubles resulting from their straying from Jewish tradition. In one subplot, a cantor's son led astray by a woman of "questionable morality" becomes involved with gangsters and ends up stealing the deed to his mother's store. On March 14, 1939, Film Daily reviewed Mothers of Today as follows: "Heavy tragedy, which seems to be an essential basis of all Yiddish dramas, is done to a turn in this new film and it should please the dyed in the wool Yiddish fans. Produced on a small budget with a hurried shooting schedule, the film has considerable merit. Cast members, with the exception of the talented Esther Field, were recruited from the stage for their initial appearance on the screen, and they give Miss Field adequate support. Henry Lynn directs the film feelingly. The story deals with the tragedies which beset Miss Field as her children get in trouble."</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?378436</url></doc>
