<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="381550">
  <docid>381550</docid>
  <title>Munimji</title>
  <year>1955</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Musical</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">163</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Mukherji, Subodh</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Burman, Sachin Dev</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ameeta (I)</actor>
      <role>Bela</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anand, Dev</actor>
      <role>Amar/Raj/Kala Ghoda</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dayal, Prabhu</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jaywant, Nalini</actor>
      <role>Roopa</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mohan, V. Madan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pran (I)</actor>
      <role>Ratan/Kala Ghoda</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, S.L.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Roy, Kanu</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Samar (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Roopa lives a wealthy lifestyle with her widowed dad, Captain Suresh, and brother, Shekhar. After she returns from abroad, she is told that she must now prepare to get married to her betrothed, Ratan, who is the son of a close friend of Suresh. Everything changes suddenly when Roopa meets with a handsome young man, Raj, and both fall in love with each other. Raj then breaks her heart when he tells her that his mother, Malti, who works as a maidservant in Suresh's household, has always favored Ratan over him, has made him promise to step out of Ratan's way. Before she could find out whey Malti prefers Ratan over Raj, a bandit, Kala Ghoda, who has been terrorizing the region asks Suresh to pay up Rs.50,000/-. The Police lay a trap for this extortionist and capture him red-handed - and he turns out to be none other than Suresh's Munim. Surprises are in store for everyone when they find out that Munim is none other than Raj, who has been masquerading as the Munim for many years, and may also have embezzled another Rs.50,000/-.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?381550</url></doc>
