<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="381638">
  <docid>381638</docid>
  <title>Muqadama</title>
  <year>1996</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Dalwadi, Govind</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">19 July 1996</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Bokadia, K.C.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bokadia, K.C.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bokadia, K.C.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Lahiri, Bappi</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anand, Mahesh</actor>
      <role>Balbira</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bakhtiar, Zeba</actor>
      <role>Chanchal Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grover, Gulshan</actor>
      <role>Shyam Kalan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harish (I)</actor>
      <role>Dancer (song "Naya Maal")</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khanna, Vinod</actor>
      <role>Captain Ajit Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maruti, Guddi</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Satya Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pancholi, Aditya</actor>
      <role>Inspector Manoj Saigal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Raj, Jagdish</actor>
      <role>Jailer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rindani, Shiva</actor>
      <role>Bablu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sheikh, Aashif</actor>
      <role>Monty</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Talsania, Tiku</actor>
      <role>Satya Singh</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Captain Ajit Singh from the Indian Army meets with a beautiful and naive village belle, Chanchal, and both fall in love with each other. They decide to get married, and do so. They spend the next several months in mutual harmony. One day Ajit has to go out of town for army business, and he leaves Chanchal alone in the house. Chanchal gets two uninvited guests, Balbira and Bablu. She wants them to leave, but they refuse to do so, until she has sex with them. She runs from the house, and meets Police Inspector Shyam Kalan. Instead of helping her, Shyam also joins the two in raping her. After the rape, Chanchal kills herself, just in time for Ajit to arrive and watch helplessly. He swears to avenge her death, and hunts down and kills Bablu immediately. Before he could hunt down Balbira and Shyam, Ajit is arrested, tried in court, and sentenced to be hanged. He makes a dramatic escape from prison, and shortly thereafter the police find his dead body, with his face battered beyond recognition. When news gets out, Shyam and Balbira are both relieved that Ajit is dead. A few days later, Balbira gets killed in mysterious circumstances, while Shyam awaits his death at the hands of an unknown assailant, who has brought it upon himself to end fulfil Ajit's incomplete task.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?381638</url></doc>
