<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="381722">
  <docid>381722</docid>
  <title>Murder After Dark: Part 2</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Burke, Mike (VII)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Mystery</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2 May 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">85</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Burke, Mike (VII)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Burke, Mike (VII)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Burke, Mike (VII)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Burke, Mike (VII)</actor>
      <role>Detective William Stockwell/Proctor/Leland Brown/Brando/Tubby Wilson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Burke, Ryan (III)</actor>
      <role>Alana Ray</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mannachia, Candice</actor>
      <role>Marissa/Cecilia Ray</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Peterson, Karl</actor>
      <role>Sheriff Bob Shirley/Dr. Lawrence Meyers</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Our story starts off where the first one ended. The murder of Margaret Ray was not just a random killing but part of a large local government conspiracy. Things begin to happen which blow a hole in the solved case of the Margaret Ray murder. With the killer behind bars everyone should be safe, right? Officer Nicholson doesn't think so. She tries to convince Sheriff Bob Shirley that the killer behind bars is working with someone or may even be innocent. Sheriff Bob doesn't want to hear it. But while he ignores officer Nicholson the body count rises. No one is safe in the town of Deep Woods. No one! The killer escapes and claims innocence. No one believes him. His only proof is in a coma and dying. He finds out the Margaret Ray was not a random murder but instead killed because she knew something about certain town officials. Officials who have enough power to destroy anyone they want. To create a cover-up that is flawless. What they don't realize is that someone is on to them and lurks in the forest waiting for the right time to expose them. Time is delicate and life is too short. If this case isn't solved quickly a lot of people will end up dead.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?381722</url></doc>
