<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="381729">
  <docid>381729</docid>
  <title>Murder Before Dark</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Burke, Mike (VII)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Mystery</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2 May 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">131</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Burke, Mike (VII)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Burke, Mike (VII)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Burke, Mike (VII)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Burke, Mike (VII)</actor>
      <role>Detective William Stockwell/Leland Brown/Tubby Wilson/Panda/Proctor/Mr. Ponderperelli/Sen. Mitchell</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Peterson, Karl</actor>
      <role>Sheriff Bob Shirley/Dr. Lawrence Meyers</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In 1998, Margaret Ray was brutally murdered but it was the conspiracy that surrounded the death that was most shocking. Now for the first time go back in time and see the story unfold as it leads up to the point where the first film began. Our story takes place from 1991-1998 and leads up to the murder of Margaret Ray. We begin with Detective William Stockwell and his partner Detective Laura Brown being called back to their hometown to investigate a mysterious disappearance. Sheriff Bob (Karl Peterson) hopes they will find the missing person as well as to how he became missing. They will go through all sorts of twists and turns. Each road leading them nowhere. The case just gets more bizarre by the minute. Meanwhile Margaret Ray, who has no self control, finds herself sleeping around town. Three of these men she would develop a strong relationship with. One of these men, unknown to her, is full of pure evil and would kill her without a second thought! Mayor Tubby Wilson has a secret of his own. He is involved in a big drug cartel that involves top town officials and a US Senator! The mayor is only a puppet though. A puppet for a mysterious person who only appears in dark shadows never revealing their identity. When this person's identity is finally revealed it will be shocking.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?381729</url></doc>
