<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="382007">
  <docid>382007</docid>
  <title>Murderers on the Dancefloor</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Mister, John (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>youtube</keyword>
    <keyword>dance</keyword>
    <keyword>prison</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Filipino</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">2 January 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">23</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>McCarthy, Sarah (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Higgs, Anna</producer>
    <producer>Shearman, Nick</producer>
    <producer>Bootle, Jack</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>Murderers on the Dance Floor tells the story behind a YouTube clip that has now been viewed by over 9 million people. In this incredible clip 1500 inmates of a Filipino prison dance to Michael Jackson's Thriller. But Thriller isn't the only dance the inmates perform; their dazzling repertoire includes Giorgio Moroder's Electric Dreams, a rock version of Canon in D and numbers from Sister Act. Director Sarah McCarthy went to the Philippines to discover why on earth a prison full of murderers, rapists and drug dealers were dancing to 80s pop. The dance spectaculars are the brainchild of Byron Garcia. Byron was appointed Head of the Prison in 2004 by his sister Gwendolyn, who is governor of the province. When Gwendolyn requests a special performance by the prisoners as part of her birthday celebrations, Byron adds one more dance to the programme - Vanilla Ice's Ice Ice Baby. Murderers on the Dance Floor follows the creation of the newest dance in a jailhouse that seriously rocks. Along the way we meet the stars of the Thriller clip; Wenjiel, a lady boy who one day dreams of starting his own beauty parlour, and Crisanto, an accused drug dealer whose son is incredibly proud of his Dad's YouTube fame. But the star of this show is Byron, a man who's managed to turn his prison into a dance studio. He claims that since the dancing started there hasn't been a single violent incident. But how does he get his prisoners to dance? And what happens if an inmate refuses? A bizarre mix of glitz and grit, this film is a tale of spectacle and intrigue, of power and pop, of Murderers on a Dance Floor.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?382007</url></doc>
