<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="383199">
  <docid>383199</docid>
  <title>My Actions Smack of the Soil</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Forster, Catherine</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>nature</keyword>
    <keyword>earth</keyword>
    <keyword>environment</keyword>
    <keyword>experimental</keyword>
    <keyword>art-video</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 October 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">179</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Forster, Catherine</director>
  </directors>
<plot>The piece was inspired by essays and poems of Ralph Waldo Emerson, and by the escalating global debate on global warming. I live in a rural setting and for the past two years I have been documenting the "wilderness" on my property, filming seasonal changes, both of nature and of man's intrusions. Ralph Waldo Emerson's first book, "Nature" (1836), eloquently delivers passages that peruse our determination to connect with nature: "In the woods, is perpetual youth." "In the woods we return to reason and faith"; "I am not alone and unacknowledged. They nod to me and I to them". The word wilderness is derived from the notion of wildness, uncultivated, uninhabited, in other words without human modification. The social and political realities of "nature verses economics" makes defining wilderness in the 21st Century ever more elusive. What is "wild", what can be called "wilderness", what is the measure of human "influence" that defines wildness? In "... my actions smack of the soil" seasons change while human activity is ever present as cars go by, planes fly overhead, and lawn mowers and snowmobiles seem to be in the woods or just on its edge. The forest in this piece is surrounded, quiet, and almost silent as compared to the sounds of man. The forest is captivating, resilient, and besieged.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?383199</url></doc>
