<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="384919">
  <docid>384919</docid>
  <title>My Son the Pornographer</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>pornography</keyword>
    <keyword>family-relationships</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">7 October 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">45</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Campbell, Peter (III)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Campbell, Peter (III)</producer>
    <producer>Holbrook, Arthur</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Holbrook, Arthur</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Art, a Victoria filmmaker, struggles with his conservative moral values when he visits his son Kole who works as a writer and actor in the pornography business in Prague. Appalled by the sexual abuse Kole experienced as a child, Art believes Kole's current lifestyle is directly linked to that sad event. Art wants to get Kole out of an existence that, in his eyes, is soul-destroying. Amidst the hard-core pornography industry, Art and Kole strive to reconcile their relationship and their perceptions of a difficult past. As we follow their story, Art finds a surprising humanity in the world of porn even as he attempts to convince Kole to return to Canada and confront the past. Art hires a private detective to track the abuser down and, as the detective unearths clues that bring them nearer to the pedophile, Art discovers how close to violence he himself can come. MY SON THE PORNOGRAPHER follows the journey of two men as they reflect on the stresses and strains that tear families apart, on moral values, guilt and life choices. Ultimately, it is a story about the love between a father and a son.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?384919</url></doc>
