<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="385287">
  <docid>385287</docid>
  <title>Mymym</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Jago, Eran</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>israeli-army</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hebrew</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Israel</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">18 September 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Israel">49</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Gatt, Yarden</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Gatt, Yarden</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Lass, Eli</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gold, Lyle (II)</actor>
      <role>Sharon</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lidakhov, Dim</actor>
      <role>Andrei</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wolpe, Ben</actor>
      <role>Boris</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Eight young Israelis find themselves at a life's crossroads. Their common ground is being out of place in their surroundings and they all long for a sense of wholeness and integrity which eludes them. Even so they unconditionally delve into a final delusional quest in search of a satisfying solution to their loss. MYMYM is a journey which concludes by intersecting their paths for the first and last time. Amnon and Miko drive from one end of the country to the other for an underpaid concert. Committed in pursuing their long coveted dream of becoming Rock Stars. Shimrit helps Sharon escape a mental asylum. Together they set out in search of Sharon's son who has been separated from her. Boris, a successful D.J., who has had enough of the party scene, encouraged by his over zealous drug dealer Andre, sets off alone into the desert in search of the comforting sound - silence. Left behind, his girlfriend Ma'Mayan, is quick to console herself in romance with a dreamy street musician. Each person and the path they take. Each path and the surprises at its bend. With some of Israel's less known scenery at the background and exercising free cinematic expressions, the characters' exploits run parallel to each other, crossing back and forth those refined borderlines that seem to persist within our minds - those between reality and imagination.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?385287</url></doc>
