<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="387566">
  <docid>387566</docid>
  <title>Naatigothi</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Ahire, Gajendra</editor>
    <editor>Choudhury, Shivaji</editor>
    <editor>Paraskar, Mahesh</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Marathi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Ahire, Gajendra</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Sathe, Balasaheb</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Bhadkamkar, Kamlesh</composer>
    <composer>Bhidey, Narendra</composer>
    <composer>Modak, Anand</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Desai, Mangesh (III)</actor>
      <role>Sadanand 'Sada' - Kusum's brother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gajendra, Vrunda</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gauri (V)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kale, Ravi</actor>
      <role>Vithal 'Vithu' 'Vithala'Rao</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kubal, Alka</actor>
      <role>Kusum V. Rao</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mankani, Shruvat</actor>
      <role>Raghav V. Rao</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Narkar, Avinash</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shinde, Milind</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Vithal Rao lives a poor lifestyle in rural Maharashtra along with his widower dad, a younger brother, Purshotam, and an elder sister. Farming is their main occupation, but his father asks him to till the land so that his siblings could study and better everyone's lives. Accordingly, his siblings do get a better education - while Purshotam re-locates overseas for his studies with money being arranged by selling a few acres of their farmland, and his sister gets married to a Mumbai-based doctor, after they pay him a dowry by selling some more acres of their land, leaving them with only 12 acres. Their father passes away, Vithal gets married to Kusum, and they become parents of Raghav. Purshotam, now a Professor, does not return home, instead gets married to Suman and settles in Pune, and his sister demands a share of the property. Initially Vithal refuses, but relents and allots her 4 acres. Purshotam then demands his share, and Vithal sacrifices another 4 acres. Since Raghav is studying to be a Scientist, he needs Fifty Thousand Rupees. Even after tilling their land, working as laborers and being employed part-time in a restaurant, the couple are not able to raise this amount. A desperate Vithal decides to radically raise money - with life-changing results.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?387566</url></doc>
