<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="389052">
  <docid>389052</docid>
  <title>Naming Pluto</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Laker, Richard</editor>
    <editor>Watmough, Hal</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>pluto-the-planet</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">15 November 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Ireland">7 November 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">17 October 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">13</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Jimenez, Ginita</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Jimenez, Ginita</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Jimenez, Ginita</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Schmittat, Moritz</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chapman, Allan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Goldstein, Edward (IV)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Massey, Robert (III)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moore, Patrick (V)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This is the story of Venetia Phair, who as an 11-year-old Oxford schoolgirl in 1930, came up with the suggestion for the name of the newly discovered Planet X over a family breakfast, making her inspiration to name it Pluto a unique contribution to scientific history. 77 years later, Venetia is yet to see Pluto through a telescope and in the recent light of its demotion in 2006, she's invited by Sir Patrick Moore to view the planet she named through his telescope. The sighting proves unsuccessful and Venetia waits a year before a second opportunity is extended, this time by the Science Observatory in Herstmonceux. Coincidentally the viewing happens on the eve of her 89th birthday. Pluto's demotion has divided the scientific community and undone 70 years of learning for millions of children around the world. Before scientific technology takes us to the next chapter of planetary discovery and introduces further wonders to us, Naming Pluto looks back at the extraordinary way a young girl came to name a planet and witnesses her long awaited reunion with planet she named.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?389052</url></doc>
