<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="391107">
  <docid>391107</docid>
  <title>Natutulog pa ang diyos</title>
  <year>1988</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>based-on-comic</keyword>
    <keyword>based-on-novel</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Tagalog</language>
    <language>Filipino</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Philippines</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Philippines">11 October 1988</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Brocka, Lino</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Marcelino, Ruben</writer>
    <writer>Nadres, Orlando</writer>
    <writer>Tagasa-Gil, Gina Marissa</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Bartolome, Jose</composer>
    <composer>Buencamino, Nonong</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Belmonte, Ricky</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Davao, Ricky</actor>
      <role>Andrew</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Godinez, Tina</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Locsin, Michael</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rivero, Dante</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Valenciano, Gary</actor>
      <role>Mark</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Everyone notices how different Andrew and Gillian looked from their respective sets of parents but no one really made a fuss about it. What is even more surprising is that the two never close with the families they grew up with. Instead, Gillian became more attached with Andrew's parents and Andrew felt the same about Gillian's parents. Little did they suspect that it was because Andrew and Gillian were switched at birth. Andrew's real father a poor family driver decided that Andrew would have a better life growing up with his rich bosses. So he made sure that only he and his wife Gina know that he switched babies when the two mothers gave at a provincial hospital. No amount of pleading from Gina would make him change his mind. Out of frustration, Gina resorted to maltreating Gillian. The latter found comforting arms in Marita, Andrew's mother. And later on with Mark a rich suitor. Jealous at Gillian's new found attention, Andrew decided to forced himself on Gillian. An act which would lead to revelation of the secret of their parentage.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?391107</url></doc>
