<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="391954">
  <docid>391954</docid>
  <title>Neat Freak</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Emetaz, Greg</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>overeating</keyword>
    <keyword>promiscuity</keyword>
    <keyword>obsessive-compulsive-disorder</keyword>
    <keyword>alcoholism</keyword>
    <keyword>homosexuality</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">23 August 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">42</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Emetaz, Greg</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Arlen, Sarah</producer>
    <producer>Consilvio, Cara</producer>
    <producer>Emetaz, Greg</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Emetaz, Greg</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brown, Gary (XXVII)</actor>
      <role>Party Guest 6</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Colucci, Michael</actor>
      <role>Mark</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Consilvio, Cara</actor>
      <role>Mia</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Delaney, Annie</actor>
      <role>Party Guest 1</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dinoia, Jennifer</actor>
      <role>Angela Pearl</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Emetaz, Greg</actor>
      <role>Gore</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fitzgerald, Corey</actor>
      <role>Party Guest 5</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>James, Kahan</actor>
      <role>Trask</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lee, Adriane (II)</actor>
      <role>Alexis</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Meyer, Nancy (III)</actor>
      <role>Katya</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rimalower, Ben</actor>
      <role>Party Guest 2</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sharon, Yuval</actor>
      <role>Party Guest 3</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tena, Paul</actor>
      <role>Hunky Guy at Party</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Four roommates: Mia, a promiscuous sweetheart; Katya, an alcoholic ice princess, Alexis, a jaded ice cream addict, Gore-obsessive compulsive homosexual, find an unbelievably reasonable apartment in Manhattan. They celebrate with a housewarming party that trashes their new home. The roommates return the next evening to find the apartment spotless. The three women are satisfied that someone from the party did it as a nice gesture. Gore can't live with the mystery and calls his friend Zelda, an amateur psychic. He tells her what happens and she proposes they hold a reading. The girls agree to it if there will be a 'Post-Séance Party'. On the morning of the séance/party, Mia's latest boyfriend is attacked by the vacuum cleaner and asphyxiates while she's in the shower. The roommates conference and at the urging of Gore, decide not to involve the police (for fear that they would be accused) and instead continue with the séance as a way to defend their low-rent habitat from the now homicidal cleaning. Zelda -homely and casual- arrives and is told nothing of the recent death. The séance halts when Zelda decides they just have a ghost with a cleaning fetish. Mia shows Zelda her dead boyfriend in hopes of pushing the séance along. Zelda tries to escape the apartment, but finds the door locked. One by one the roommates and guests are homicidally cleansed of their vices (alcoholism, homosexuality, etc.) as those remaining try to get to the bottom of the mystery.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?391954</url></doc>
