<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="392887">
  <docid>392887</docid>
  <title>Nemocnice na konci sveta</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Vynikal, Tomas</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Czech</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Czech Republic</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Czech Republic">2 December 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Sterba, Otakar</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Sterba, Otakar</producer>
    <producer>Vynikal, Tomas</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Sterba, Otakar</writer>
    <writer>Sterbova, Dina</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Gruz, Jiri</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>In 2005 Dina and Otakar Sterba studied socio-ecologic conditions in villages Askole, Chongo, Arandu, Kurfe and Hushe and while at it, they donated their private funds for creation of water conduit which brings drinking water from mountains to the villagers of Chongo and to the summer pasture in Askole. In 2006 international humanitarian organization Oneness Heart - Tears and Smiles carried out action Kids to Kids. Czech and Slovak children created thousands of gift packages with their address and photography dedicated to children living in area hit by massive earthquake in Pakistan. These packages were given to children in schools and refugee camps which were visited by Vitezslav Dokoupil and Dina Sterbova during the search of good location for the next deed. The same year, Czech humanitarian organization Hand for Help bought creatable building of small hospital of value of 7 million CZK, which were collected with admiration of Czech citizens and organizations. It presents 16 tons of panels, machines, document's and furniture. V. Dokoupil and D. Sterbova voluntary accepted the uneasy task to move it into mountains, build it and bring it to life. Hospital stands at Arandu Village, situated at the bottom of Chogo-Lungma Glacier. No child died during the harsh winter time in the first year of the hospital's existence.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?392887</url></doc>
