<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="393770">
  <docid>393770</docid>
  <title>Never Say I do...</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Roth, Brandon Garet</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>sex</keyword>
    <keyword>spoof</keyword>
    <keyword>beautiful-woman</keyword>
    <keyword>mockumentary</keyword>
    <keyword>rebel-cinema</keyword>
    <keyword>pregnancy</keyword>
    <keyword>male-female-relationship</keyword>
    <keyword>christopher-guest</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">95</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Anderson, Brandon Garet Roth</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Anderson, Andy (XXIX)</producer>
    <producer>Anderson, Brandon (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Anderson, Brandon G.R.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>G'Ro</composer>
    <composer>Hill, Greg (XVII)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>De La Ossa, Christina</actor>
      <role>Bambi The Bed Buddy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hicks, Susannah</actor>
      <role>Kady The Baby Mama</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>James, Remy</actor>
      <role>Renauld The Filmmaker</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kayso, Anfer</actor>
      <role>Pastor Doug Douglas</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kenny, Amber</actor>
      <role>Charlie The Fiancee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lee, Danny (XV)</actor>
      <role>Phuck The Soundman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nunez, Miguel (IV)</actor>
      <role>Guillermo The Cameraman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Roth, Garet</actor>
      <role>Jack The Crazed Ex</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Pastor Doug Douglas is neither a minister nor a man of God. He is however a Ladies Man. A man to three ladies to be exact. There is the Baby-Mama, Kady, Pastor's former roommate, now pregnant with his first child. Also Charlie the out-of-state high school sweetheart turned last option fiancée and last but certainly not least. Finally Bambi, the nymphomaniac bed buddy with a crazed ex named, Jack, always stalking outside in her shrubbery. What makes Pastor's situation even the more outrageous is his blatant honesty. Each one of his women knows about the other and is absolutely content with their respected role in his life. This seemingly absurd notion attracts a devious French documentary filmmaker named Renauld and his crew of foreign misfits, who are currently shooting a documentary about love and dating in America. Finding himself obsessed with Pastor's own love-story, Renauld focuses all his resources and attention onto his new subject and the people involved in his ongoing love-life. Thus a proposition occurs between Renauld and Jack after a fateful meeting, in exchange for getting the latter more involved within the disruptiveness of Renauld's documentary, Jack will be given a heart-to-heart taped interview with his beloved Bambi, in order to patch things up. This scheming makes Renauld not only a part of his own artificial love-story but the vindictive narrative for Pastor's now troubled relationships and ultimately his questionable future.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?393770</url></doc>
