<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="395289">
  <docid>395289</docid>
  <title>Nichts von Bedeutung</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bialas, Barbara</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>German</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Germany">31</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Bialas, Esther</director>
    <director>Nill, Nathan</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bialas, Esther</producer>
    <producer>Nill, Nathan</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bialas, Esther</writer>
    <writer>Nill, Nathan</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Steinke, Andrej</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Berg, Moritz</actor>
      <role>Alleinunterhalter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dietrich, Matthias (I)</actor>
      <role>Paul</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ehlers, Lena</actor>
      <role>Bäckertochter Rippich</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Schmid, Jürgen F.</actor>
      <role>Arzt</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wewerka, Christian</actor>
      <role>Leo</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Paul lives alone in Frankfurt, he has never met his father. Paul is now 22 years-old and he is going on a 10-day journey to Brandenburg, to meet his father, who is living in a tiny weekend-house. It is a journey on the tracks of his own origin and a finding of his own identity In a small village father and son face each other as strangers. Their timid trials of approach seem to fail, because of communication problems, cultural differences, and their missing common past. At that, father and son are going on a trip together across the region. The past rests and only the future matters. An amicable relation arises in this new situation of the here and now.. Pauls father shows him his life and culture. Common experiences in the provincial life are binding them together. However, the differences and the past do not pass out of their minds. After a night in the pub father and son get into a heavy fight. As the father gives in, their relation becomes even more intense. Shortly after reaching this emotional peak, father and son get involved in a crash. Both of them retrieve in a hospital and the sense of responsibility changes. Paul looks after his bed-ridden father. He gives him the care he has always missed. During the medical treatment Paul gets to hear, that he and his father are not related to each other. Paul yet stays at his father's side As he leaves, he decides to keep the truth for himself. Nothing matters anymore</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?395289</url></doc>
