<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="396396">
  <docid>396396</docid>
  <title>Nightingale in a Music Box</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>McDermott, Hurt</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby SR</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Greece">22 September 2004</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">June 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">96</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>McDermott, Hurt</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Jones, Leigh (I)</producer>
    <producer>Slotten, Todd</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Eno, Brian</composer>
    <composer>Fripp, Robert</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Blass, Jane</actor>
      <role>Genevieve</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dirks, Jillian</actor>
      <role>Charlotte</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grams, Deron</actor>
      <role>Ridley</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grove, Taylor</actor>
      <role>Florence</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hazen, Kelley</actor>
      <role>Burke</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Krukowski, Andrzej</actor>
      <role>Sowa</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>O'Rourke, Ed</actor>
      <role>Killer</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Imagine a technology which has the potential to change what it means to be human. New Garden Technologies has just patented a new life form, microbes made to be inserted in the brain to control memory. The nations of the world want this technology controlled; so when New Garden apprehends someone trying to steal these genetic blue prints, the UN is quick to send Burke, a legendary female operative who has been debriefing tainted spies since the Cold War. But Robin McAlister is not your typical thief; she is a Chicago real estate agent and mother of two. So how could she possibly be involved in this crime? Unfortunately, this question may take some time to answer, because Robin claims not to even remember who she is. Burke must pick her way through Robin's mind, figuring out what is real and what has been manufactured. Burke realizes that stakes are high: How easily can our minds be taken away from us? How quickly can our identity be changed? Do we even have a self to lose? Agent Burke is about to find out.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?396396</url></doc>
