<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="398415">
  <docid>398415</docid>
  <title>No Movie</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>La Ponsie, Steve</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>chicano-art</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>La Ponsie, Steve</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>La Ponsie, Steve</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>La Ponsie, Steve</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>La Ponsie, Steve</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gronk (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Drawing from Gronk's extensive personal archive of photos and drawings, and narrated by the artist himself, No Movie takes viewers on a journey through a diverse and prolific artistic career. No Movie begins with Gronk's participation in the conceptual art group Asco, documents his collaborations with Jerry Dreva, Tomata du Plenty, James Bucalo, and others, then continues to more recent installation paintings and the acclaimed set design for the Santa Fe Opera's production of Ainadamar. The film offers an intimate portrait of a unique, multi-faceted artist who has worked across the boundaries of punk art, mail art, Chicano art, performance art, and gallery painting, defying categories and challenging convention in the process. Steven La Ponsie Since 1980, La Ponsie has been creating works in various media (video, music, painting, set design, and photography) that examine the social and physical implications of the urban experience. La Ponsie's media works include Daly Grind, In the Streets, Dominance and Terror, Nuevo Pop, Gronk's Brainflame, and Crossing Boundaries.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?398415</url></doc>
