<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="398593">
  <docid>398593</docid>
  <title>No Return</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Sylla, Tom</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>supernatural</keyword>
    <keyword>ghost</keyword>
    <keyword>suspense</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="UK">15</certificate>
    <certificate country="Australia">M</certificate>
    <certificate country="USA">PG-13</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">28 July 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">86</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Sylla, Tom</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Egan, Virginia</producer>
    <producer>Nelson, James (VIII)</producer>
    <producer>Nelson, Mary-Armour</producer>
    <producer>Sylla, Rebecca</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Sylla, Tom</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Nilsen, Spencer</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Colet, Stephanie</actor>
      <role>Alice</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Henninger, Corie</actor>
      <role>Kelly</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McCain, Frances Lee</actor>
      <role>Mother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Palcic, Timothy</actor>
      <role>Michael</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Willat, Wendell</actor>
      <role>Steve</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Alice Darrow's terminally ill husband whispers 'I'll come back' just before he dies. Puzzled but determined to get on with her life, Alice starts to see subtle signs that her husband may be trying to communicate with her from beyond the grave. Alice's fear is magnified by the guilt she feels about having fallen in love with another man before her husband passed away. As she starts developing a new romantic relationship, strange occurrences and visitations begin to worsen. Her mentally ill mother claims to have seen the dead husband. When a stranger appears outside Alice's house, she takes a photo of him that seems to change every time she looks at it. Alice explores several explanations, including the possibility that she is losing her mind, or that someone is playing practical jokes on her. A chance encounter leads Alice to discover that one of her husband's last wishes wasn't fulfilled. She attempts to correct the transgression, hoping this will put to rest any unresolved issues. However, as she begins to feel confident about the direction of her life, new evidence casts a disturbing and potentially dangerous light on her situation. Alice's life turns upside down as her friends and enemies suddenly switch sides, creating a game of deception and revenge that culminates in one last chance for Alice to end her nightmare.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?398593</url></doc>
