<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="400073">
  <docid>400073</docid>
  <title>Non-Disclosure: Haunted</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>paranormal-phenomena</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <producers>
    <producer>Nelson, Ray (III)</producer>
    <producer>Brown, Steven J. (II)</producer>
    <producer>Engert, Peter</producer>
    <producer>Fenton, Nanette</producer>
    <producer>Lawrence, Sheri</producer>
    <producer>Reeves, Zachary</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Fenton, Nanette</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Fenton, Nanette</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>When recently divorced Kyle Stark saw the Realtor's sign posted: House for Rent -he knew it would be a perfect place for him, his twelve year old son, his bird and his dog! But what was not disclosed in the rental contract was his family would not be the only occupants. At first, Kyle thought he was imagining things, yet in a short period of time he realized that these unexplainable events had taken on an evil and frightening detour, progressing to poltergeist activity, voices, footsteps, slime puddles, putrid odors, physical and sexual assault, illness, and anomalous visual manifestations permeating every room of the house - and him! Who were they? Where did they come from? How were they able to do these evil things? Kyle's investigation leads him to the three families who were former renters who validated his claims, and the help of paranormal investigators who discovered a portal in the upstairs closet. Kyle's personal struggle involved fighting for his sanity in dealing with the entities, the maniacal property manager, the Sheriff's Office who thought he was a nut case, his paranoid ex-wife, and the two women who became involved with Kyle during the 'alleged' haunted house investigation. These events catapulted him into unchartered realms and shocking revelations of murder, conspiracy, and the adverse psychological and physical impact of all who dared to enter the house. Renter and buyer beware!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?400073</url></doc>
