<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="400410">
  <docid>400410</docid>
  <title>Normal People Scare Me</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bluth, Richard</editor>
    <editor>Dahlberg, Chad</editor>
    <editor>Jean, Erica (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>teenager</keyword>
    <keyword>autism</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">5 May 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Travolta, Joey</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cross, Taylor</actor>
      <role>Interviewer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gravino, Amy</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Based on the 10 minute award winning short film of the same title, Normal People Scare Me is a feature-length documentary sharing first-person accounts of life and living with autism. Created by Taylor Cross, a 17 year old aspiring film maker with high functioning autism, Normal People Scare Me highlights 65 interviews conducted over the past two years by Cross, with interview subjects representing different levels of abilities on the autism spectrum. The film's interview subjects range in age from 9 to 57 years. Cross asks subjects questions such as "What does autism look like from your perspective? Do you like or not like being autistic?; What do you want to be when you grow up?; to Have you ever been teased? The courageous kids, teens and adults Taylor interviews offer powerful, poignant, and deeply moving insight to life and living behind the many faces and mysteries of autism. In one of Cross' most moving interviews, he connects with surfing champion, Izzy Paskowitz of Surfers Healing. Izzy is revealing in his honesty and perspective on raising his son, Isaiah who suffers from severe autism. Other interviews feature young aspiring artists, poets, actors, college students, and a quirky special ed. bus driver. These are among the fascinating subjects this film explores. Cindy and Janice are no exception. Both of these mothers have autism and have kids with autism. Four sets of siblings with autism are interviewed. Graham Nash provides narration in the film, and singer/songwriter, Taylor Dane sings film's theme song "Locked Inside of Me", written by Joey Travolta and Jeff Less. Cross' mother, Keri Bowers, a disabilities advocate, author, speaker and founder of PAUSE4kids a non-profit serving the developmentally disabled joins her son Taylor and Joey Travolta in the making of this film. The threesome continue to speak and share the upcoming feature film throughout the country. Panel discussion includes Q&amp;A about the making of the film; alternative interventions for supports; and social and life skill training for those with autism in the dramatic and fine and musical arts.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?400410</url></doc>
