<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="400607">
  <docid>400607</docid>
  <title>North Shore Stories</title>
  <year>1996</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">22</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Rasmussen, Walter</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Rasmussen, Walter</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Rasmussen, Walter</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>A thirty-minute adventure and cultural heritage series, produced with exceptional digital cinema production, and beautifully shot by some of the most accomplished photojournalists and cinematographers in the world. Six-time Emmy Award winning Kent Westberg as Director of photography teams up with Emmy nominated Walter Rasmussen, Producer and Director, to produce this series for distribution in several states, and now on the worldwide web. Unique recollections of historical memories come alive with each program. We explore different adventures and visit significant locations, weaving in rare photographs and footage seldom ever seen by anyone before, documenting some of the early pioneers and their descendants. Come aboard a three masted schooner, sleep in a haunted lighthouse, dive on a shipwreck, get next to a black bear, or try out a 19th century recipe for steaming hot homemade raisin rye bread. Shipwrights, hospitality houses, chefs, geologists, explorers and natural wonders all tell their stories through richly worded narratives and stunning photography. Most of all, this great land of shimmering rivers, majestic forests, and rough hewn cliffs which plunge into the inland sea called Superior, beckons you to come along, and stay awhile. For once, the relentless crash of surf on craggy shores and the magic of an early morning rainbow crowning the misty outreach of a woodland waterfall can be experienced by anyone who has only dreamed of such things before. Welcome to North Shore Stories.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?400607</url></doc>
