<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="400865">
  <docid>400865</docid>
  <title>Nosferatu's Crush</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Burke, Mike (VII)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>vampire</keyword>
    <keyword>dark-comedy</keyword>
    <keyword>dracula</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">7 August 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">93</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Burke, Mike (VII)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Burke, Mike (VII)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Burke, Mike (VII)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Lucibelli, Peter</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Altovise, Lady</actor>
      <role>Special Agent Green</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Burke, Mike (VII)</actor>
      <role>Vladimir Dracula III</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Desgrottes, Xaviera</actor>
      <role>Serena</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gaydos, John</actor>
      <role>Tony</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gray, Mac</actor>
      <role>Dexter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jones, Priscilla</actor>
      <role>Renee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kovacs, Sylvia</actor>
      <role>Eliza</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Longo, Malissa</actor>
      <role>Rebekah</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Malin, Sami</actor>
      <role>Mel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Marie, Angalisha</actor>
      <role>Electra/Evil Vampire Woman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mendez, Chiko</actor>
      <role>Leo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rickenbaker, Robert</actor>
      <role>Thomas</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Vladimir Dracula III is a relative to the original Dracula of Transylvania. He lives in the US in the 21 century and has a big problem. First of all he is bald, has pointy elf like ears, fangs, he is very pale, hunched over, and can not get a woman to save his life! Secondly people are being attacked and killed by vampires and the police think he is doing it only because of who he is related to. They have no evidence but continue to harass him. So Vlad decides to get a lawyer. That is when Rebekah arrives to represent him and she take Vlad's heart. He falls madly in love with her, but with everything else in his life, another problem appears. Tony, her obnoxious, idiot boyfriend! Not only is he disrespectful to Rebekah, he wastes no time making fun of Vlad's appearance. Vlad is not the only vampire in town. He lives with three beautiful vampire women who find victims for him. He doesn't like to attack any more so they do it for him. They don't kill though. Someone else is doing that. People are being killed by a vicious and evil vampire who sneaks around the woods at night while Vlad gets the blame from two moron detectives. Vlad fights his hardest to get Rebekah but will have to fight even harder when Rebekah is eyed by the Evil Vampire Woman and must face trouble from a jealous Tony. Will he get the girl of his dreams? Will he prove his innocence? Will he stop the vicious vampire? Will he save the one he loves before it is too late? Will he grow hair? Find out in the very funny and spooky Nosferatu's Crush</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?400865</url></doc>
