<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="404246">
  <docid>404246</docid>
  <title>O Dia em Que o Brasil Esteve Aqui</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Corbett, Doca</editor>
    <editor>Dias, André (III)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>brazil</keyword>
    <keyword>soccer</keyword>
    <keyword>haiti</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>French</language>
    <language>Haitian</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Brazil</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Brazil">5 May 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Brazil">72</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Civita, Adriano</producer>
    <producer>Civita, Francesco</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Altman, Fabio</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brazilian National Soccer Team</actor>
      <role>Themselves</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dumont, Patrice</actor>
      <role>Haiti's main sports journalist</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gabart, Fenelon</actor>
      <role>Haiti national soccer team golie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lula (III)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Namphy, Joseph</actor>
      <role>Fan of brazilian soccer team</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>How can a game of football change a nation's destiny? How can the passion for another country's national team surpass the personal and collective conflicts of everyday life? Now imagine the Five Time World Champion Brazilian team playing with Haiti's national team to promote peace in a country going through a period of atavistic misery. UN troops, led by Brazil, try to maintain peace and order. The informal economy rules the streets. Hunger rages. Only music and faith, seems to keep them alive - and football. In this environment, the presence of the Brazilian National Team served as an excuse for hope and euphoria - and it is important to ask, what other purpose will it serve? What kind of peace can come out of this match? From any perspective, it was a unique encounter, of football with politics, of superstars with simpletons, of countries with similar histories and societies. An inexplicable passion that Haiti feels for Brazil that does not need to be understood, but incorporated. After all - as a common Haitian might say - "After seeing Brazil play, I can die!"</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?404246</url></doc>
