<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="406169">
  <docid>406169</docid>
  <title>OMG! Sextuplets!</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Perniciaro, Tim (II)</editor>
    <editor>Stepp, Mark</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">18 June 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">44</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Schiff, Eric</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Appleyard, Leslie</producer>
    <producer>Schiff, Eric</producer>
    <producer>O'Rourke, Shannon</producer>
    <producer>Stroupe, Dawn</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>O'Rourke, Shannon</writer>
    <writer>Schiff, Eric</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Bourne, Martha</composer>
    <composer>Licari, Michael</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>After a three-year struggle to conceive, Jenny and Bryan Masche find their wishes have multiplied when the news that they're expecting six babies rocks their world. Jenny's contractions come way too early, and she is admitted to the hospital where she remains under close observation. As the weeks turn into months, the confinement and medication takes its toll - Jenny is challenged mentally and physically. When the big day finally comes, the sextuplets hold their own after birth, but Jenny goes into heart failure and must be rushed to Intensive Care. She fights for her life. Five days later she's recovered enough to visit her six tiny babies in the NICU for the first time. Newspaper headlines about the birth of the sextuplets draw the attention of the DEAL OR NO DEAL casting team, and Jenny is selected to compete on the show. She and the entire family head to Hollywood, where the babies make their television debut. Jenny wins more than one hundred thousand dollars for the babies' college fund and she and Bryan head home to Arizona to continue their ever-changing adventure as a family of eight.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?406169</url></doc>
