<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="407561">
  <docid>407561</docid>
  <title>Of Unknown Etiology</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>medical-profession</keyword>
    <keyword>doctor</keyword>
    <keyword>student</keyword>
    <keyword>suffering</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>disease</keyword>
    <keyword>illness</keyword>
    <keyword>physical-deteroration</keyword>
    <keyword>chronic-pain</keyword>
    <keyword>hope</keyword>
    <keyword>friend</keyword>
    <keyword>frustration</keyword>
    <keyword>first-person</keyword>
    <keyword>friendship</keyword>
    <keyword>autobiographical</keyword>
    <keyword>mysterious-illness</keyword>
    <keyword>documentary-filmmaking</keyword>
    <keyword>pain</keyword>
    <keyword>family-relationships</keyword>
    <keyword>starvation</keyword>
    <keyword>thesis</keyword>
    <keyword>healthcare</keyword>
    <keyword>anguish</keyword>
    <keyword>graduate-student</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">26 November 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">96</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Fowler, John J.</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fowler, John J.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>What if you had a disease doctors had never seen before? What if it couldn't be diagnosed or treated? What if you were starving because of it? What if you had disabling muscle pains? What if you skin burned constantly? What would you do? Would you give up or would you continue to search for answers? In the documentary 'Of Unknown Etiology', a graduate film student struggles to find answers to his health problems while simultaneously trying to document it for his thesis project. He faces challenges not only from his deteriorating health, but also from the mounting costs and frustrations of dealing with the American healthcare system. As his isolation and physical condition worsens he begins to wonder if he's even going to survive his disease at all, and, if he does, will he still be the same person? 'Of Unknown Etiology' is a first-person documentary that intimately explores the physical pain and psychological anguish that comes with suffering from a long-term chronic disease; yet it also shows that humor, friends, and family are vital to keep pressing ahead when all hope seems lost.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?407561</url></doc>
