<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="407536">
  <docid>407536</docid>
  <title>Of One Blood: Returning Home to Africa</title>
  <year>1999</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Berg-Morrow, Nanahemaa Kosua Brenda</editor>
    <editor>Morrow, Nana Kwasi Scott Douglas</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>africa</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Akan</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Ghana</country>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Germany">30 April 1999</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">14 May 2000</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">29</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Berg-Morrow, Nanahemaa Kosua Brenda</director>
    <director>Morrow, Nana Kwasi Scott Douglas</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Berg-Morrow, Nanahemaa Kosua Brenda</producer>
    <producer>Morrow, Nana Kwasi Scott Douglas</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Berg-Morrow, Nanahemaa Kosua Brenda</writer>
    <writer>Morrow, Nana Kwasi Scott Douglas</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>An American husband and wife, who have embarked on a pilgrimage to Ghana, West Africa, present a special gift of dance performance to the Asante people, symbolizing their ancestral kinship with Africa and their gratitude for all the beauty and wisdom Africa has given the world. This film chronicles the day's historically unprecedented events as they occur. At the palace of Nana Barimah Abeyie Ntori Nimpah II, the King of Sekyere Kwamang Traditional Area, the King and his court perform dances of great dignity, elegance and beauty. And the Morrows present their gift of dance to the King and the people of Sekyere Kwamang, who accept the couple's gift on behalf of all the people of Africa. Never before has such a gift been given to a traditional Asante ruler. Following this "dialogue in dance," the couple is warmly welcomed into the Asante family. Then, an astonishing moment occurs. The Morrows are made a Traditional Chief and Queen Mother, the first individuals of "white" complexion to receive this sacred honor in Sekyere Kwamang Traditional Area. "OF ONE BLOOD: Returning Home to Africa" documents an extraordinary moment in time, when two cultures embrace each other, transcending their seemingly different worlds to discover in one another the true essence of humanity - a sense of underlying oneness and love - and to recognize their common genesis - that they, and indeed, all people of the world are Of One Blood!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?407536</url></doc>
