<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="407890">
  <docid>407890</docid>
  <title>Offline</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Santoro, Matthew</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Santoro, Matthew</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>O'Donnell, Liam (III)</writer>
    <writer>Santoro, Matthew</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Santoro, Matthew</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>"The future is not some place we are going to, but one we are creating." In this future, the world is dying a slow and ugly death. In an effort to cope or out of pure denial, humanity has become increasingly obsessed with mass media. The Internet has morphed into an all-consuming visceral experience where every one's perception of the world around them is fully customized. The brown smog in the sky can easily be ignored when a beautiful sunset can be projected through your optic nerve, courtesy of the Naneuron Corporation. But like all systems there are glitches and exceptions. Someone or something is disrupting the feed; a Ghost in the machine. A group of extremists have risen up, led by young man named Maro. Defiant and charismatic, he has seemingly endless promise until he unexpectedly surrenders. All enemies of the state are processed for reprogramming. Those like Maro who are physically and mentally gifted enough are transformed into counter-terrorism soldiers. His memories are erased. His body is enhanced. His humanity is destroyed. Or is it? Maro begins communicating with the glitches, hearing whispers that lead him on a journey through the depths of his own subconscious. Trapped in the midst of a hellish nightmare, he must find a way to regain his identity and take down the system once and for all. But at what price comes freedom?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?407890</url></doc>
