<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="409586">
  <docid>409586</docid>
  <title>Old Warrior</title>
  <year>1994</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Robinson, Richard D. (I)</editor>
    <editor>Seftel, Joshua</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">3 October 1994</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">28</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Seftel, Joshua</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Marino, Leah</producer>
    <producer>Robinson, Richard D. (I)</producer>
    <producer>Seftel, Joshua</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Seftel, Joshua</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dukakis, Michael</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kennedy, Ted (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lurtsema, Robert J.</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>O'Neill, Dapper</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>O'Neill, Thomas P. 'Tip'</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The second film by Joshua Seftel traces the forgotten history of the Senior Citizens Power Movement and its fiery founder, Frank J. Manning (1902-1986). In 1967, Frank Manning, a 66-year-old retired union organizer, began stirring up the previously silent masses of New England's elderly. Within three years, he had traveled the entire state of Massachusetts, attempting to create a social movement to demand elderly rights. For the next fifteen years, Frank Manning's activism set the pace for the United States. Almost single-handedly, Manning transformed his home state of Massachusetts into a beacon for the nation, boasting the country's largest budget and most progressive programs and services for the elderly. Old Warrior is a half-hour film documenting this important, yet forgotten chapter in history. The film begins in Boston in the mid-sixties and travels through two decades in New England. There are appearances by Senator Edward Kennedy, Governor Francis Sargent, City Councilor Dapper O'Neil, Congressman Claude Pepper, Governor Edward King, Governor Michael Dukakis, and a final television interview with Speaker of the House Tip O'Neill.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?409586</url></doc>
