<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="412309">
  <docid>412309</docid>
  <title>One Lucky Elephant</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Amend, Kate</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Leeman, Lisa</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Cutler, Miriam</producer>
    <producer>Friedman, Lizzie</producer>
    <producer>Little, Greg (III)</producer>
    <producer>Colissimo, Cristina</producer>
    <producer>Glick-Franzheim, Jordana</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Colissimo, Cristina</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Cutler, Miriam</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Nine years in the making, ONE LUCKY ELEPHANT follows the poignant journey of circus producer David Balding as he tries to find a nurturing and permanent home for Flora, the 18-year-old African elephant that he rescued as an infant, raised as his "daughter" and made the star of his circus. David's love for Flora is put to the ultimate test when he realizes he made a terrible mistake keeping her as a solo elephant, and decides to retire her from the circus after 17 years of performing. Knowing Flora will outlive him, and with his health and finances becoming an issue, David sets off on a quest to find a home for Flora can live freely with other elephants. This complicated task begins with Flora's final circus performance in St. Louis and takes us on an emotional trek across America, then to Africa and back. We follow David's journey as he discovers just how difficult it is to find a proper home for an elephant in a world that reveres these animals for their majesty yet slaughters them for their ivory, adores them as cuddly Dumbos yet brands them "rampaging creatures". ONE LUCKY ELEPHANT raises critical issues about the well-being and future of the hundreds of thousands of endangered and exotic animals kept in captivity, the over development and destruction of their natural habitats, our intense and often damaging relationship with wild animals, and how all these issues have impacted the life of one very lucky elephant.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?412309</url></doc>
