<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="412708">
  <docid>412708</docid>
  <title>One Thousand Years</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Fleming, Gabriel</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>no-budget</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">6 February 2002</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">10 March 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">98</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Fleming, Gabriel</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Fleming, Gabriel</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Fleming, Gabriel</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gerstein, Mara</actor>
      <role>Maria</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gray, Soren</actor>
      <role>Keith</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hearn, Kara</actor>
      <role>Alien Theory Woman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lee, Daniel (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Madden, Maura</actor>
      <role>Angela</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Matthews, Mary C.</actor>
      <role>Emma's Housemate</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Young, Phil (II)</actor>
      <role>Man from One Thousand Years in the Past</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>One Thousand Years tells two different stories; in the first, Maria develops a crush on cool-kid Keith, an unattainable hipster far out of Maria's league. Maria's best friend Emma swallows her own feelings for Maria as she patiently listens to her obsessive meanderings. Woven into this triangle, Emma tells Maria the second story, a tale of two time-travelers, one from one thousand years in the past, and another from one thousand years in the future, who meet in the here and now to find a mysterious book that ostensibly saved our own times from the millennial apocalypse of Y2K. After searching unsuccessfully, the two travelers become absorbed in the trappings of modern times, slowly to drift apart from each other. Rather than using these stories as a platform for witty dialogue, One Thousand Years instead delves into the details of day-to-day life. Filmmaker Gabriel Fleming's intimate, personal camera examines the mundane yet beautiful moments of living we usually take for granted. Reflected sunlight off a CD, running wild through dark city streets, or the quiet intensity of playing with a cat.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?412708</url></doc>
