<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="412878">
  <docid>412878</docid>
  <title>One by One</title>
  <year>2010</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">1 December 2010</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Fraiman, Ed</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Newmark, Jason (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Fraiman, Ed</writer>
    <writer>Kernick, Simon</writer>
    <writer>Staheli, Paul (II)</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>"Just stay put and make sure no one jacks the tires" says Detective McCloud to his partner, John Cone, as he gets out of the car and heads to the Ruby Rose nightclub. The problem is, Cone doesn't. He's got a nasty drink habit and he's thirsty. As he downs a double whisky at the Ruby Rose bar, a burst of gunfire erupts from the back room. Cone goes to investigate. Caught by surprise, he shoots at a man who appears to be reaching for a weapon. Cone's shot's on target but his judgment isn't - an asthma inhaler rolls from the dead man's hand... John Cone's life hits rock bottom. He's discharged from the Albuquerque Police Dept (APD) and his wife leaves him. Bankrupt and lonely, his alcohol dependency deepens. 9 months later the phone rings and he's offered a way back from the abyss: A chance to pay off his creditors and put his life back on track. Cone's offered a place in a 6 person 'spring team' that will ambush a prison van transporting a violent criminal across state. The team will abduct the prisoner and deliver him to an abandoned logging station for hand-over to their 'contact', then go their separate ways. The team will operate anonymously and are given codenames to hide their identities. After careful deliberation, Cone accepts. All goes according to plan until the team arrives at the logging station to discover the 'contact' is not there. He's left word that the exchange will occur the following morning. But as the sun goes down, distrust and suspicion set in. -A distrust and suspicion that spills over into recrimination as the group discovers their prisoner has escaped and seems to be stalking them. When one of the group members is found dead and another is shot it appears that the prisoner is taking revenge, targeting them one by one. The hunters have become the hunted. As the surviving members of the group barricade themselves in for the night, it becomes clear that not all is as it seems. Paranoia reigns, fostered by suspicions of an inside job and the discovery that they must have something in common. Something that connects all of them, something worth killing for... -They just don't know what it is yet and they don't have long to figure it out.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?412878</url></doc>
