<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="413171">
  <docid>413171</docid>
  <title>Ongewisse tijd</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Vinken, Dorith</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Sranan</language>
    <language>Papiamento</language>
    <language>Dutch</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Netherlands">26 November 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Netherlands">64</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Pos, Diego</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Betsalel, Annette</producer>
    <producer>Peters, Maria</producer>
    <producer>Pos, Hans</producer>
    <producer>Schram, Dave</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Pos, Diego</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Beenen, Ofra</actor>
      <role>Jonge Rebecca</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Eyl, Noa</actor>
      <role>Mathijs</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ivanov, Dimitri</actor>
      <role>Hartogh Simon</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Juurlink, Helen</actor>
      <role>Rebecca</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Landveld, Alida</actor>
      <role>Clarijntje</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Smits, Dries</actor>
      <role>Oude Hartogh Simon</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Uncertain Times tells the story of a Jewish family in the former Dutch colony of Suriname in South-America. Suriname had a significant Jewish population dating back to the very beginning of the colony. These Jews became well to do plantation owners. In the film director Diego Pos follows the trail of his first two ancestors in Suriname, the brothers Hartog Simon and Matthijs. Being orphans they were send to this unknown colony to start a new life in 1774. They were gifted musicians and made their living giving concerts and lessons. Director Diego Pos was the last born member of the family to leave Suriname in 1962. With his departure to Holland the family story in Suriname ended. In the film he travels back to Suriname with the diary of one of the two brothers as a guide. He looks for signs of the brothers and their lives, searches for his own roots and explores the sorry state of the still existing tiny Jewish community struggling to survive. In the partly dramatized film the amazing story of the Surinamese Jews is the background of this compelling family history.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?413171</url></doc>
