<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="413967">
  <docid>413967</docid>
  <title>Oops!</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>punctuation-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>one-word-title</keyword>
    <keyword>exclamation-point-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">A</certificate>
    <certificate country="UK">15</certificate>
    <certificate country="Singapore">NC-16</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">109</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Tijori, Deepak</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Jayarajan, Bijesh</writer>
    <writer>Tijori, Deepak</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Pawar, Ravi (II)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Adyasha</actor>
      <role>Nikki</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Janjani, Kiran</actor>
      <role>Jahaan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Kiran (I)</actor>
      <role>Mr. Rai</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sethi, Vikas</actor>
      <role>Akash Rai</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Thakur, Amit Singh</actor>
      <role>Jahaan's father</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Dancer, Jahaan (Kiran Janjani) and his group, which includes his girlfriend, Nikki (Adyasha), and bosom pal Akash Rai (Vikas Sethi). While Nikki and Akash are content to wait for their big-time, Jahaan wants it now. He gets a break when Sonia (Mink Singh) is impressed with him. He does not hesitate in the least when Sonia asks him to strip-dance for a group of wealthy women, for a tempting price. Jahaan does so. And he soon becomes popular, and gets invititation from several women who lust for him and his youth. One such woman is Sharon (Mita Vashisht), cold, sexy, and much older than Jahaan. He is drawn to this mysterious woman, and falls in love with her. After sometime, she gets bored of Jahaan, and ends the affair, but Jahaan is unable to get her out of his mind. As a result Nikki leaves him, Akash encourages Jahaan, and envies Jahaan, but Akash does not want to strip in front of any more women. And then Akash's Dad (Kiran Kumar) invites Jahaan over for dinner, and that's where Jahaan gets the suprise of his life, when he meets Sharon again, this time in her real shocking identity.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?413967</url></doc>
