<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="414325">
  <docid>414325</docid>
  <title>Opening of the Pan-American Exposition Showing Vice President Roosevelt Leading the Procession</title>
  <year>1901</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>News</genre>
  </genres>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">8 June 1901</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>White, James H.</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Babcock, Louis L.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Diehl, Conrad</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gallinger, Jacob</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hanna, Marcus</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Odell Jr., Benjamin B.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Roosevelt, Theodore</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This is a great historical event. Our cameras were stationed in the center of the Esplanade looking toward the Main Approach to the Pan-American Exposition, with the Triumphal Bridge, and the entrance in the foreground. The procession, headed by Vice-President Roosevelt, enters the main approach, in front of our camera, then it wheels to the left and passes into the Temple of Music. The participants in the head of the parade are made up of distinguished people, such as Senator Hanna, of Ohio, Senator Gallinger, of New Hampshire, Governor Odell, of New York, and Mr. Conrad Diehl, Mayor of Buffalo. The military division of the parade is headed by Louis L. Babcock, Grand Marshal of the Exposition parade, followed by his aides, Lyman M. Bass, Dr. John A. Smith, Sherman R. Hall, Dr. Harry Meade, Evan Hollister, Frederick DeP. Townsend, Robert W. Pomeroy, Henry Robbas, Captain H. A. Bull, James McC. Mitchell, Roland Crangle, George W. Gillette, Edward M. Mills. These are followed by the first division, consisting of the 71st Regiment Band, Brigadier General S. L. Welch, commanding the 4th Brigade, N.G.N.Y., and staff. This picture was taken on the official opening day, May 20th, when there were 106,000 people on the grounds, and the picture is greatly enhanced by the great crowds passing to and fro.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?414325</url></doc>
