<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="415431">
  <docid>415431</docid>
  <title>Organics</title>
  <year>1999</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>None</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Austria</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">18</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Brehm, Dietmar</director>
  </directors>
<plot>Since 1996, parallel to all the other paintings and film work I made hundreds of pictures each with the title 'Organics', and each on the same size of paper - 61 x 43.5 cm. It is from this drawing phase that the film Organics (1998) developed. I already had the perfect found-footage lead whom I named 'Hey Joe'. Round 'Hey Joe', who appears repeatedly as an observer, I constructed a matrix of body details which are broken up by a number of explosions. Organics begins with the observation of a Zorro mask and a distorted / veiled woman's face. A shot of Notre-dame Cathedral in Paris develops into a women's foot scene which leads to a longer kiss scene punctuated by an explosion, falling leaves, a tank, touching hands, a hand in a plaster cast, bunches of grass and a dark cellar door. After observation of a skeleton detail, the found footage actors become involved in slowly feeling each others body. A man swings a necklace back and forth like a pendulum, a head being bandaged, attempts at face make-up, details of operations.... in a flickering, pumping screen light until, in the end, 'Hey Joe' centres the picture briefly with his penis. After the hand movements which follow, the veiled face of a woman appears again, longer this time, to be observed by 'Hey Joe' until the film floodlight is turned off. The Organics sound track is paired down to a few slow note combinations. (Dietmar Brehm)</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?415431</url></doc>
