<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="415959">
  <docid>415959</docid>
  <title>Oru Naal Oru Kanavu</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Sekhar, T.R.</editor>
    <editor>Shankar, Gowri (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Malayalam</language>
    <language>Tamil</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="UK">PG</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">26 August 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">146</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Fazil (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Muralitharan, K.</producer>
    <producer>Swaminathan, V.</producer>
    <producer>Venugopal, G. (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Fazil (I)</writer>
    <writer>Krishnan, Gokula</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Ilayaraja</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Agarwal, Sonia</actor>
      <role>Maya</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ganesh, Shyam</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Illavarasu</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Madhupal</actor>
      <role>Sekhar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ravi, Nizhalgal</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sathyam (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Srikanth (III)</actor>
      <role>Seenu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sukumar (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The story revolves around Maya (Sonia Agarwal), a college student, who always wants to triumphs in all her endeavors. She comes across a middle class youth, Cheenu (Srikanth), a happy-go-lucky-youngster, who strives to work hard to get his sisters married well. A few encounters (Maya and Cheenu) results in wordy duels between them leading to Maya challenging Cheenu that she will make him fall in love with her. Her further course of action to achieve her challenge leaves Cheenu frustrated and he decides to take revenge on her by pretending to fall in love with her. Maya who starts to spend more time with Cheenu comes to know of his kind heart and his good nature and eventually develops an honest love towards him. She even helps him in setting his own business house.Slowly Cheenu too comes to know of Maya's nobleness and generosity land falls in love with her. Trouble comes in the form of her brothers who threaten Cheenu of dire consequences. Cheenu resolves to earn more and become rich and then hold the hands of Maya. But Maya has plans otherwise. Do the couple get married in the end? Watch for yourself and find out!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?415959</url></doc>
