<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="417440">
  <docid>417440</docid>
  <title>Our Bodies, Our Minds</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>sex-worker</keyword>
    <keyword>dominatrix</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">March 2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Alvin, Rebecca M.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Alvin, Rebecca M.</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Alvin, Dave (III)</composer>
    <composer>van Bork, Mark H.</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Alexander, Priscilla</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hartley, Nina</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Leigh, Carol (IV)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Our Bodies, Our Minds is about feminists who work as prostitutes, exotic dancers, and in other areas of the adult entertainment industry. How can these women be feminists, you ask? That's exactly what the seven women featured in this video are asked. Actress, Nina Hartley defends her career choice by stressing that it is a choice, one not coerced or forced as other feminists might imply. Erotic filmmaker, Candida Royalle expresses her brand of feminism by creating her own erotic films, "from a woman's point of view." And dominatrix Mistress Delilah uses her earnings to pursue a Ph.D. Alvin's interest in the subject matter arose out of an experience with a friend of hers from high school. "She told me she was working part-time as a stripper, but I had always thought of her as such a feminist person" she says. After going to see her friend perform at a gentlemen's club in New York, Alvin realized that there was more to the issue than what anti-pornography feminists might lead you to believe. The result was Our Bodies, Our Minds , a provocative documentary that allows these unusual feminists to discuss their perspectives on pornography, free expression, and prostitution, without resorting to cheap exploitation.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?417440</url></doc>
