<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="419775">
  <docid>419775</docid>
  <title>Paappi Devataa</title>
  <year>1995</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Malhotra, Harmesh</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Malhotra, M.M.</producer>
    <producer>Pushkarna, Baldev</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kudalkar, Laxmikant Shantaram</composer>
    <composer>Sharma, Pyarelal Ramprasad</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ashalata</actor>
      <role>Rosie's mom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bedi, Rakesh</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhatt, Urmila</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Khan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Birbal</actor>
      <role>Havaldar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chaturvedi, Shail</actor>
      <role>Train passenger</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dharmendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Rahim Khan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dixit, Madhuri</actor>
      <role>Reshma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jayapradha</actor>
      <role>Rosie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jeetendra (I)</actor>
      <role>DCP Ram Kumar Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Satyendra</actor>
      <role>Niranjan Das</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Roopesh</actor>
      <role>Kundan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nagpal, Vinod</actor>
      <role>Pandu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Parvez, Yunus</actor>
      <role>Kelaram</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, Amrish</actor>
      <role>Ratan Seth</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Saxena, Sharat</actor>
      <role>Ratan's employee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Singh, Gurbachchan</actor>
      <role>Gulzar Singh</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In search of better employment prospects, Ram Kumar Singh leaves Allahabad and re-locates to Bombay by train. Upon arrival, his wallet and clothes are stolen, he manages to sneak out of the railway station, chased by a Police Constable and takes shelter in a taxi-cab belonging to kind-hearted Rahim Khan, who takes him home, provides him food, shelter, as well as a taxi-cab so that he can earn money while looking for a job. Both Rahim and Ram become close friends. While driving his taxi on his first day, Ram meets with Reshma, who studies in Mithibai College and both fall in love with each other. Things change for the better when Ram gets a well-paying job, quits his taxi driving as well as the room with Rahim, and moves out to his own apartment. What Ram does not know is that Rahim works for an underworld Don, Ratan Seth, and has also killed a man named Niranjan Das. And what Rahim does not know is that Ram is really the Deputy Commissioner of Police who suspects Ram of killing Niranjan Das. Watch what happens when Rahim finds out about Ram's true identity; and also when Ram comes to arrest him without realizing that Reshma is Rahim's sister; as well as the impact this arrest will have on their friendship.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?419775</url></doc>
