<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="420119">
  <docid>420119</docid>
  <title>Padikkathavan</title>
  <year>1985</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Mohan, S.B.</editor>
    <editor>Vittal, R.</editor>
  </editors>
  <languages>
    <language>Malayalam</language>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Rajasekar (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Ilayaraja</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ambika (II)</actor>
      <role>Manju S. Pandey</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ganesan, Shivaji</actor>
      <role>Baldev Kashiram Pandey</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jaishankar</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Krishna, Ramya</actor>
      <role>Raja's girlfriend</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nagesh (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rajnikanth (I)</actor>
      <role>Rajkumar 'Raja' K. Pandey</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Baldev Pandey lives a middle-class lifestyle in Mughalsarai near Banaras, India, along with two school-going brothers, Rajkumar and Shivkumar, who walks with a limp. Baldev is studying law, and eventually gets married to Radhika. He goes out of town for further studies, leaving his brothers under Radhika's care. After he leaves, Radha neglects and then abuses them, forcing them to run away to Bombay, where they fall in the clutches of a man who forces them to beg. Both get rescued by a devout and kind-hearted Muslim widower, who adopts them and lets them live along with his son, Anwar, and daughter, Fatima. Rajkumar massages Shivkumar's leg and cures him of his limp. Years later both brothers have grown up, while Rajkumar drives a magical taxi named Shaniya, Shivkumar is a student in college. Shivkumar falls in love with wealthy Manju, the daughter of Ved Prakash, gets married to her, and moves in to live with his in-laws after compelling Rajkumar to sell his taxi to pay for the wedding expenses. Anwar falls into bad company, is shot and mortally wounded, and when he gets abducted, his dad tries to stop the men, but instead gets shot dead. Anwar eventually passes away, leaving the onus on Rajkumar to look after Fatima. Baldev, in the meantime, is the Judge in the city, and will soon hear the testimony of Shivkumar, who will be testifying against the killer of his father-in-law - and the man accused of this killing is none other than Rajkumar himself.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?420119</url></doc>
