<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="420394">
  <docid>420394</docid>
  <title>Pai an jing qi</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>courtesan</keyword>
    <keyword>china</keyword>
    <keyword>magistrate</keyword>
    <keyword>murder</keyword>
    <keyword>martial-arts</keyword>
    <keyword>beautiful-woman</keyword>
    <keyword>law</keyword>
    <keyword>historical-fiction</keyword>
    <keyword>male-female-relationship</keyword>
    <keyword>love</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Mandarin</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Taiwan</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Taiwan">1 July 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">43</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Huang, Xiaoming</actor>
      <role>Tian Long Tai Zi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kou, Zhenghai</actor>
      <role>The Emperor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Su, Alec</actor>
      <role>Hang Tie Sheng</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Su, Alec</actor>
      <role>Hang Tie Sheng</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tong, Ruixin</actor>
      <role>Yan Feng</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wang, Ban (II)</actor>
      <role>Yi Zhi Mei</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zhao, Yi (I)</actor>
      <role>Lu Yan Qing</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Opening this historical drama is the arrival in the small town of Zhu Shan of Hang Tie Sheng, a talented young magistrate, to take up his new official position. Accompanied by his stepmother, Yu Hui Xin, and his close friend and advisor Lu Yan Qing, Hang Tie Sheng's appearance immediately stirs up trouble. Tie Sheng's compassion and sense of justice leads to conflicts with corrupt local officials, eventually involving the kingdom's Crown Prince. In an early episode, Tie Sheng meets a mysterious and lovely young woman with impressive martial arts skills and a murky past (her mother having developed amnesia many years back). Ning Xiang and Tie Sheng's encounters and their shared desire to help the oppressed soon lead to mutual attraction and a strong bond. However, although Tie Sheng's honest and incorruptible nature earns him the respect of the Emperor and the people, he and his comrades must overcome the schemes of villainous factions to survive. The story includes three cases. The first case involves the identity of Ning Xiang and her mother, and their connection with the royal court. Case two is divided into two parts, both of which include attempts to overthrow the Emperor through assassination and devious alignments with warlords and bandits, as well as the secret background of the Emperor's favorite concubine. The final case is a convoluted story of murder, medical experiments, hidden identities, and thwarted love.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?420394</url></doc>
