<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="420518">
  <docid>420518</docid>
  <title>Paint Job</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Austin, Steven</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>street-painter</keyword>
    <keyword>painter</keyword>
    <keyword>confrontation</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>goodbye</keyword>
    <keyword>creativity</keyword>
    <keyword>change</keyword>
    <keyword>color</keyword>
    <keyword>art</keyword>
    <keyword>paint</keyword>
    <keyword>male-female-relationship</keyword>
    <keyword>street</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">31 May 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Primig, Dieter</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Primig, Dieter</producer>
    <producer>Barish, Howard</producer>
    <producer>Godovich, Nelly</producer>
    <producer>Primig, Dieter</producer>
    <producer>Godovich, Nelly</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Michaels, Nic</writer>
    <writer>Shonkoff, Adam</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Beck, Michael (VI)</actor>
      <role>Daniel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Daly, Matthew John</actor>
      <role>Jim</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Haling, Dutch</actor>
      <role>Jonah</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Daniel is a street painter. Together with his work partner Jim he paints lines and lines everyday on the streets. Jim always tries to get Daniel out of his old house where he is living but Daniel prefers to lives a gray colorless life in his old house in the forest. One day, a strange girl named Ruby popped into his life and just showed up at his place. She founded his old house as an abandoned place and wasn't expecting anybody living in there. After the first confrontation Ruby sees that Daniel is living a colorless life but has an art guided potential. She literally starts to color his gray life and changes his world. Daniel doesn't (want) to understand and of course they experience confrontation. Daniel learns to think 'out of the box'. In a lovely way Ruby colors his home and invites him to join her. First he starts to paint a straight line, as he always is doing it but he understands her words and tries a new unexperienced way that gives him new perspectives. His way of working in daily life is the last thing that gets changed in the end. Inspired by the new things he learned from Ruby he is living the new painting ideas....which leads to new undiscovered conclusion for Daniel.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?420518</url></doc>
