<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="421373">
  <docid>421373</docid>
  <title>Panaah Baroye Zinda Mondan</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Mohnot, Sundeep</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Pashtu</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Afghanistan</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">PG-13</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Afghanistan">1 May 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Mohnot, Sundeep</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Sikander, Asad</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Mohnot, Sundeep</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sikander, Asad</actor>
      <role>Ghulam</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Ghulam had a bright future in his country, Afghanistan, but for some reasons had to leave it to become a transporter in Bulgaria. He works for a mafia don called Kayuum who has many illegal interests, and one of which is human trafficking. Ghulam does this work in a very mechanical &amp; robotic manner. He is very loyal to Kayuum and has always completed the assignment given to him. He is softhearted and has always helped people to reach their destinations, though illegally. His colleague Tanya has a soft spot for him, but he has always treated her as a good friend. A family from Mazhar-e-sharif comes via Bulgaria to London. This family consists of an aged couple with their young and beautiful daughter called Mariam. They want to travel to London but have been asked to wait by the immigration authorities. Here they meet a tout called Hamid who organizes their trip with the help of Ghulam. So Ghulam takes them through the jungles to cross the border and onwards. On the way he gets a call from Kayuum, asking him to abandon the family in jungle and return to the city. Ghulam is shocked by this and revolts and suddenly has troubles waiting for him from both sides of the law.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?421373</url></doc>
