<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="421552">
  <docid>421552</docid>
  <title>Pandit... Ek Yodha</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Rao, J. Sreeniwas</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Khagwal, Rahul R.</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Rajkumar, S.A.</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Akkineni, Nagarjuna</actor>
      <role>Surja Pandit/Satya Pandit</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Nasir (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Surya Pandit lives a very wealthy lifestyle in India along with his parents, his niece, Neetu, and a younger look-alike brother, Satya. His parents would like him to get married, but he refuses until Satya, who himself is anxious to get married to his devastatingly beautiful girlfriend, Sree, selects a bride named Vasundhara. Events prove that Vasundhara is indeed the ideal bride for Surya, and both get married. Shortly after the marriage, a large amount of jewelry is stolen, as well as a servant attempts to burn down the farmland. A thief is apprehended with the stolen jewelry by the local police, which leads to Satya making a confession that he was the one who hired the thief. This breaks down the harmony in the family and a rift is created between the two brothers. Little do the two brothers know that the theft of the jewelry and the arson was caused by Surya's bride - who has a score to settle with Surya, who had humiliated her sister, Bhavani, and had manipulated Satya to accept the blame. Watch how Vasundhara goes about to destroy the prestige and peace of this idealistic family.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?421552</url></doc>
