<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="422194">
  <docid>422194</docid>
  <title>Pants in the Family</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Finberg, Adam</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">TV-PG</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 February 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">27</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="USA">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Collins, Sheldon (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Johnson, Jan (I)</producer>
    <producer>Hilliard, Lionell</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Hilliard, Lionell</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Goldberger, Joe</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Baker, Sheila (III)</actor>
      <role>Ms. Hunt</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Blankson, Rosemary</actor>
      <role>Dr. Coswell</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Braydon, Iris</actor>
      <role>Nurse</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dunn, Rae</actor>
      <role>Brenda</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Figueiredo, Craig</actor>
      <role>Clyde</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>O'Sullivan, Patrick (II)</actor>
      <role>Officer Boyd</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Porter, R.J.</actor>
      <role>Marcus</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Poth, Philip</actor>
      <role>Business Man</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Scott, Spencer (II)</actor>
      <role>TV Announcer/Cellmate/Mr. Hutcherson</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>So who really wears the Pants in the Family? Clyde Singletary, father of two and husband to stay-at-home wife, Brenda, believes he does. As the sole bread-winner and recipient of a new promotion, and of the coveted corner office, this Brooks Brothers suit-wearing corporate executive also believes Brenda should have his dinner hot, ready and waiting for him the moment he gets home. But that rarely happens; a phenomenon that he has yet to comprehend, being that she has "practically nothing to do all day." Things come to a head one particular day after Clyde has battled with office politics, dealt with his rush hour commute home and is met with a lack-luster greeting from his children, Marcus (4) and Brianna (15). Once again, Brenda has not completed dinner. Additionally, she's seems more interested in finishing her telephone gossip session than with greeting her husband. Clyde explodes. Brenda endures Clyde's venting initially, offering her usual light kiss, loving look and his favorite beer from the fridge to pacify him. But when his protests turn into personal attacks, Brenda stops him cold with a colorfully illustrative kitchen maneuver using a large butcher knife and a zucchini squash, leaving little to the imagination. Clyde retreats to the living room. While channel-surfing, he happens across an episode of "The Darkest Hour," a half-hour suspense program with very hypnotic effects on its audience. Clyde dozes just as the show begins, only to wake up long after Brenda has served dinner to the family and shut down the kitchen for the night. Looking at his watch, he also discovers that he's spent the entire night in the living room. Angry and frustrated, he stomps toward his bedroom to make ready for work. Passing a full-length mirror, he is startled to see Brenda's reflection instead of his own. A moment later, Brenda emerges from the bedroom dressed for work, as him! He is now she and she is now he. He speechlessly watches as Brenda leaves in his car, but is snapped back to life as the children now call him 'mama' and launch him into Brenda's daily routine of driving them to school, going to the market, etc. Awkward at first, Clyde handles the change with stride, believing that he may have gotten the better end of the deal. After all, a day away from the office would give him the chance to relax, fire up the grill and catch the game, right? However, his dreams of relaxation are threatened when Brianna fools him into allowing her to ditch her school uniform in favor of a much cuter outfit (and consequently receiving detention from doing so) and Marcus nearly burns down the kitchen while trying to make breakfast for everyone. After fielding these attacks, Clyde is now on full alert and ready for anything, except of course for the phone call reminding him of Brenda's gynecological appointment. He quickly learns that being a woman in a man's world is no easy existence as later he is also propositioned by an overtly flirtatious grocery store manager and ends up in jail due to a snowballed traffic misunderstanding with a highway patrol officer. So much for catching the game over grilled steaks. After posting bail and picking up Brianna, a mentally, emotionally and physically drained Clyde finally heads for home. A slightly impatient Brenda is there, looking for (what else?) dinner, of course! Again, Clyde explodes, only this time berating about all the things he has to deal with as a woman. He sobers, mid-rant, at the sound of Brenda's almost exact words from their previous day's argument emerging from his own mouth. He now has a renewed appreciation for his wife. But this life lesson isn't done, as later Brenda, still operating as Clyde, gets frisky in their bedroom and Clyde, still operating as Brenda (though tired and worn from the day), must endure those lengthy two minutes without complaining.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?422194</url></doc>
