<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="422672">
  <docid>422672</docid>
  <title>Papua gegen uns</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>regional</keyword>
    <keyword>globalization</keyword>
    <keyword>indigenous</keyword>
    <keyword>dani</keyword>
    <keyword>tribe</keyword>
    <keyword>travel</keyword>
    <keyword>natives</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Indonesian</language>
    <language>German</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Germany">4 February 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">87</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Schulze, Heizo</director>
  </directors>
<plot>Parts of the globe previously only accessible to expeditions, move, in times of globalization, ever closer for the adventure traveler and can be booked online. The common goal of this very mixed group of holidaymakers (including a doctor, a gardener and a civil servant) is to meet one of the last remaining primitive peoples on our planet. Through conversations with three very different personalities from the hospitable Dani and Lani tribes we learn about the thoughts and ways of the people of this virtually untouched part of the world. They give us their views on traditions, belief, money, sexuality and partnership, and juxtaposed with the reflections of the travelers we experience the contrast of cultural perspective in the breathtaking natural scenery. Despite the efforts of the curious German travelers to gain the trust and friendship of the primitive tribe however, they remain strange visitors from another world. West Papua, unnoticed by the eyes of the outside world and without regard for the natural habitat of the increasingly christianized tribes, is one of the main sources of raw materials in Indonesia. This poses the question whether the gradual growth in tourism represents a chance for the preservation of the local culture, or is itself a part of the problem. Deep within the jungle of west Papua they are still there: The last native peoples of our planet, cut off from civilization, and with a natural habitat that shrinks by the day.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?422672</url></doc>
