<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="424388">
  <docid>424388</docid>
  <title>Particle Fever</title>
  <year>2010</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>cern</keyword>
    <keyword>particle-physics</keyword>
    <keyword>big-bang-theory</keyword>
    <keyword>physicist</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">23 January 2010</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Levinson, Mark (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Sax, Wendy (II)</producer>
    <producer>Solomon, Carla</producer>
    <producer>Cange, Brian David</producer>
    <producer>Kaplan, David (VII)</producer>
    <producer>Miller, Andrea (V)</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>For nearly twenty years, physicists have been building the largest experiment in history, an experiment of such ambition and complexity that it has required the collaboration of 10,000 scientists from over 100 different countries. The Large Hadron Collider is a 17-mile ring buried beneath the countryside of Switzerland and France. Designed to smash trillions of protons together at nearly the speed of light, the LHC will recreate the extreme conditions that existed a fraction of a second after the Big Bang. The stakes are enormous. What the LHC reveals could change our understanding of everything. Failure could leave us in the dark for generations to come. The documentary feature, Particle Fever, captures this unfolding drama by focusing on the personal stories of several of its key figures - passionate, funny, brilliant spirits standing at the threshold of discovery. These modern adventurers have faced impossible technical challenges, risked careers, sacrificed personal relationships and continually struggled with government support in their single-minded quest to understand the nature of the universe.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?424388</url></doc>
