<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="425082">
  <docid>425082</docid>
  <title>Pass the Buck</title>
  <year>1978</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Gargiulo, Mike (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Clayton, Bob (I)</actor>
      <role>Announcer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cullen, Bill (I)</actor>
      <role>Host (1978)</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>On "Pass the Buck", this 13-week game show that aired in the spring of 1978, four contestants competed to list off items in a certain category to win money in a progressive jackpot. An example question would be "Name someone who would wear a hat or head covering on the job". Each contestant would then give an answer, and for each acceptable answer, $25 was added to that game's pot. If an unacceptable answer was given, however, the next player could give an answer, and if accepted, eliminate the other player from the game. The player who was out would then go to "The Bullpen", which was located on the left side of the stage next to host Bill Cullen. The last player remaining would win the jackpot and then play the "Fast Bucks" bonus round for a possible $5,000. In this round, the player faced 4 columns of answers. The bottom level had four correct answers, the next level had three, the next level had two, and the top level had one. The player had 15 seconds to give as many answers as they could in a certain subject read by Bill Cullen. A player could win two ways: either getting all correct answers on any of the four levels, or giving at least one correct answer on each of the first three levels, and giving the one correct answer at the top of the board. If the player wins the round, they get $5,000, and their other three opponents are eliminated, with three new opponents coming in. If the player doesn't win the bonus round, they get $100 per correct answer on the whole board, and played against the same three opponents from the last game to try and get back to the bonus round. The program was produced by Bob Stewart Productions, and aired on CBS from April 3, 1978-June 30, 1978. The show was seen in repeats on Game Show Network in the fall of 1997, and has occasionally popped up on the network since then.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?425082</url></doc>
