<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="425084">
  <docid>425084</docid>
  <title>Pass the Buck</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Game-Show</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Australia">G</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Australia">11 February 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Trippett, Scott</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Thomson, Andrew (II)</producer>
    <producer>Callaghan, Rory</producer>
    <producer>Black, Julie-Anne</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Lim, Chong</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Burgess, John (III)</actor>
      <role>Himself - Host</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fleming, Joel</actor>
      <role>Himself (2002)</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The Australian version of the British game show. The game begins with ten contestants, and one of them is asked a question that has more than one correct answer (eg: "Give me a former Australian Prime Minister"). If that contestant can gave a correct answer, they are said to "pass the buck" and the next contestant then has to give another correct answer. When a contestant answers incorrectly, cannot give an answer in the required time or repeats a previous answer, the buck stops with them and they are eliminated. Two of the questions require the contestants to remember a number of words one at a time. When there are fewer than five contestants remaining, a correct answer allows that contestant to choose who to "pass the buck" to. The final two contestants go head to head by being asked a number of questions for which they alternate in giving answers, with each contestant scoring one point for every correct answer. When a contestant gives the last possible correct answer, known as a "lockout", or the buck stops with them, the next question goes to their opponent. The contestant with the higher score at the end of 60 seconds wins, and is then shown ten prizes and given 30 seconds to remember as many as they can, winning whatever prizes they can remember.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?425084</url></doc>
