<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="425789">
  <docid>425789</docid>
  <title>Pataal Bhairavi</title>
  <year>1985</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>K., Gopal Rao</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>remake</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">3 May 1985</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Bapaiah, K.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ghattamaneni, Hanumantha Rao</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Khan, Kader (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Lahiri, Bappi</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anand, Shoma</actor>
      <role>Goddess</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Asrani</actor>
      <role>Sadajappa</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bindu (I)</actor>
      <role>Maharani Swarnapati Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Choti, Mohan</actor>
      <role>Palace Attendant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jayapradha</actor>
      <role>Rajkumari Indumati Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jeetendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Ramchandra (Ramu)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapadia, Dimple</actor>
      <role>Yaskankya</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Shakti (I)</actor>
      <role>Hanuman (Ramu's friend)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Amjad (I)</actor>
      <role>Vishvanath Chanchal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Kader (I)</actor>
      <role>Mantrik</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khote, Viju</actor>
      <role>Chanchal's attendant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pran (I)</actor>
      <role>Maharaja Vijay Singh</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Ujjain's Raja Vijay Singh presides over his region and rules it with his Maharani Swarnapati, and daughter Rajkumari Indumati. During the annual arena games a challenger by the name of Pitamber from out of this region challenges anyone to a duel with him, and the only one to accept it is Ramchandra alias Ramu. Ramu overcomes Pitamber and is felicitated by Indumati. Ramu falls head over heels in love with Indumati, and even saves her life when she is bitten by a snake. But the Raja does not approve of this match as he would like Indumati to marry a wealthy man, he accordingly instructs Ramu to get rich first before he can even consider marrying Indumati. It is then a magician named Mantrik comes to Ramu's aid, and shows him how to attain wealth. Ramu has to travel many miles, go underground into a deep dark cave, &amp; free a Goddess from a curse of living eternally as a crocodile. It is here that Ramu learns that Mantrik has an ulterior motive in assisting him, so he beheads him, gets a lot of precious stones, jewelery, etc. and heads over to Ujjain to get the Raja to get him married to Indumati. The Raja readily agrees and a wedding is arranged with great pomp, ceremony, and festivities. But Ramu is in for a shock when Indumati disappears during the wedding ceremony, and Ramu undertakes to go and look for her. What Ramu does not know is that Mantrik has resurrected himself and now not only wants Indumati for himself, but has also planned a painful death for Ramu.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?425789</url></doc>
