<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="428106">
  <docid>428106</docid>
  <title>Penguin: The Musical</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kontogiorgis, Jerry</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Musical</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">8 December 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">8</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Metzger, David William</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Soria Jr., Mel</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Metzger, David William</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barrett, Moses</actor>
      <role>Abe</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Curry, Cody</actor>
      <role>The Penguin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Danish, Karis</actor>
      <role>Lily</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pagel, Aaron</actor>
      <role>Grant</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Penguin: The Musical is a delightful fantasy about sacrifice in the name of True Love. Abe has a problem: in times of stress, he disappears into a secret, magical world of musical fantasy. He's madly in love with his girlfriend Lily, but fears she won't understand his fantastical departures into song. When Lily is offered an internship tagging penguins in Antarctica, Abe is forced to make a decision: commit to the woman of his dreams, and literally follow her to the ends of the earth; or allow his lack of trust in her to destroy his love forever. Alone and depressed, Abe disappears into a song about his troubles - joined by a singing stuffed penguin! Through song, the energetic bird councils him to follow his heart to true love in the freezing cold. Abe is conflicted at first, but when his flightless companion entreats him to "Trust Me; I'm a Penguin!" Abe's heart is swayed. The pair burst out in joyful conclusion - much to the shock and amusement of the café patrons looking on. Undeterred, Abe rushes home. Finding his girlfriend distraught and apologetic, he allays her fears before confronting his own: he begins to sing to her, and let her in on his secret world. Lilly is surprised at first, but to Abe's delight, she soon joins in on the song and the magic. Suddenly, the two find themselves transported to their new home in Antarctica, where they are joined by their new friend the penguin, along with dozens of his pals. As the film comes to a close, the two look out over their magical new life together, and share a sweet Eskimo kiss.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?428106</url></doc>
