<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="429361">
  <docid>429361</docid>
  <title>Perishing Solicitors</title>
  <year>1983</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">1983</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">23</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Crichton, Charles</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Cleese, John</producer>
    <producer>Jay, Antony</producer>
    <producer>Peacock, Michael (II)</producer>
    <producer>Robinson, Peter (VI)</producer>
    <producer>Cawston, Richard</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Norden, Denis</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cole, George (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cornwell, Judy</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hunter, Russell (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lipman, Maureen</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Uses a humorous story to correct popular misconceptions of the legal profession, and promote a better understanding of the everyday problems that can be easily solved by a solicitor. Intended for general audiences. Given the attitudes of most people to solicitors, it's hardly surprising to hear that the solicitors have got together to produce a 23-minute film, appropriately entitled "Perishing Solicitors" which seeks to entreat us all to beware the nightmare that will befall us if we don't use their services. George Cole, Maureen Lipman, Patsy Rowlands, Judy Cornwall and Russell Hunter star in the film made by Video Arts for the Law Society which aims "in a humorous way to correct popular misconceptions of the legal profession and to promote a better understanding of the everyday problems easily solved by a solicitor". Tales of do-it-yourself Wills that are illegal and fail therefore to deliver the goods are followed by a tail (or trail) of tragedy involving a wife who is hospitalised after breaking a leg, workmen who succeed in damaging another man's house and an unfortunate collision with a police car in a one-way street - all of which demonstrate that a few words with a solicitor would have resulted in a valid Will, compensation for the injury, no threat of eviction and an easier time at the local nick. As building societies lobby for a lucrative slice of the property dealing and conveyancing market, no doubt the solicitors are hedging their bets, but bearing in mind the cost and complexity of soliciting a solicitor and the public attitude to them generally, it will be interesting to see whether this film encourages more of us to take the plunge...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?429361</url></doc>
