<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="430708">
  <docid>430708</docid>
  <title>Petrovaradinsko pleme</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Knezevic, Ivan (II)</editor>
    <editor>Vukmirovic, Vuk</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>History</genre>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>montenegrin-history</keyword>
    <keyword>serbian-history</keyword>
    <keyword>petrovaradin</keyword>
    <keyword>tribe</keyword>
    <keyword>exit</keyword>
    <keyword>festival</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Slovenian</language>
    <language>Serbo-Croatian</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Serbia and Montenegro</country>
    <country>Slovenia</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Serbia">15 December 2005</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Slovenia">26 October 2005</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Germany">20 November 2006</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Italy">January 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
<plot>Project Petrovaradin Tribe is based on a video workshop that will deal with unusual phenomena in which participate young people from the states of EX-Yugoslavia and regions of South-East Europe. Since the year 2000 in July more than 300.000 of young people gather at the EXIT festival in Novi Sad in Serbia and Montenegro. This phenomenon is a fact that self-initially derives from a generation who has lived trough conflicts and has witnessed the fall of the old system and ethical wars. Information which they received growing up (trough media, school history, ...) were overseen and don't correspond with the information they receive from their parents, friends, ... Aim of the project was not filming the festival itself, but the exploration of the newly established bonds and energies of the young generation that doesn't want to live in the shadow of the past war, judgments and feelings of guilt. The main goal of the workshop is to produce a documentary and other video and press material for public demonstration.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?430708</url></doc>
