<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="431399">
  <docid>431399</docid>
  <title>Phool</title>
  <year>1993</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Rao, Singeetham Srinivasa</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kumar, Rajendra (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Chitragupth, Anand</composer>
    <composer>Chitragupth, Milind</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Alagh, Maya</actor>
      <role>Savitri B. Choudhary</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Behl, Naina</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dixit, Madhuri</actor>
      <role>Guddi B. Choudhary</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dutt, Sunil</actor>
      <role>Balram Choudhary</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gaurav, Kumar</actor>
      <role>Karamraj 'Raju'/Gopal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Shakti (I)</actor>
      <role>Munna</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khurana, Akash</actor>
      <role>Rajeshwar Dayal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Rajendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Dharamraaj</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mohan, Ram (I)</actor>
      <role>Lalaji - Munna's dad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mukherjee, Babloo (I)</actor>
      <role>Karamraj's friend</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rohera, Ghanshyam</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shrestha, Raju</actor>
      <role>Daboo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Singh, Gurbachchan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Talsania, Tiku</actor>
      <role>Santosh</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Farmers Dharamraaj and Balram Choudhary are two friends who live in Ram Nagar in scenic Ooty. While Dharamraaj is widowed and lives with his mom and son, Raju, Balram lives with his wife, Savitri and a daughter, Guddi. Both Guddi and Raju share the same day of birth, though Raju is two years older. Dharamraaj and Balram arrange their marriage so as to cement their friendship even more, much to everyone's delight. This event is blessed by Mouni Baba from the local Shiv Mandir, whose predictions have never been proved to be wrong. Dharamraaj then re-locates to Bombay as he wants to be a businessman, while Balram wants to continue farming. Raju is sent to a hostel, and then subsequently to America for further studies. Years later, Balram goes to Dharamraaj to confirm Raju and Guddi's marriage, but Dharamraaj informs him that the marriage cannot take place. Balram returns home and relays this news to his wife, who has a stroke, becomes mentally unstable and subsequently passes away. Guddi swears never to speak with or about Raju or his family again. Then romance enters her life when she meets with a Journalist named Gopal. Balram is introduced to Gopal and does take a liking to him, but disapproves of his meeting Guddi on the sly. Gopal promises that he will not meet Guddi again until they are married. When Gopal does not return, Guddi goes to Mouni Baba and is told that Gopal has not been true to her. Will a hurt and confused Guddi now face heartbreak for the second time? Who exactly is Gopal and why hasn't he returned?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?431399</url></doc>
