<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="431582">
  <docid>431582</docid>
  <title>Piaf: Her Story, Her Songs</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Dummler, Scott</editor>
    <editor>Ladevich, Laurel</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>singing</keyword>
    <keyword>paris-france</keyword>
    <keyword>singer</keyword>
    <keyword>song</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>French</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="France">17 May 2003</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">July 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">95</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Elder, George (II)</director>
    <director>Salzmann, Bernard</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Prolman, Gerald</producer>
    <producer>Fuchs, Fred</producer>
    <producer>Polhill, Larry</producer>
    <producer>Rogers, Terrance</producer>
    <producer>Elder, George (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bitton, Raquel</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bitton, Raquel</actor>
      <role>Performer</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>French jazz singer Raquel Bitton is internationally praised as the greatest interpreter of music from the Edith Piaf repertoire. Bitton's critically acclaimed hit show, Piaf: Her Story...Her Songs, celebrates Piaf's extraordinary life through stories and songs that reflect the major episodes in her life from singing in the streets of Paris as a child to becoming the highest paid singer in the world at that time. Bitton's heartfelt renditions (sung in French) and her powerful delivery takes her audience on an intensely moving and emotional journey. Woven into the live concert is a luncheon where noted composers, authors, friends and family of Edith Piaf came together at a small bistro at the foot of Pere la Chaise, the cemetery where she is buried, to share intimate personal stories offering a rare look into the true life and persona of Edith Piaf. As the wine poured, the stories flowed. The film includes a new original song by two of Piaf's favorite composers, Francis Lai and Michel Rivgauche, writing together for the very first time.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?431582</url></doc>
