<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="431994">
  <docid>431994</docid>
  <title>Pictionary</title>
  <year>1997</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>non-fiction</keyword>
    <keyword>based-on-game</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">9 January 1998</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Angel, Rob</producer>
    <producer>Gill, Richard (VII)</producer>
    <producer>Kline, Richard S.</producer>
    <producer>Langston, Terry</producer>
    <producer>Jones, Nancy (II)</producer>
    <producer>Maxwell-Smith, Mark</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cipriano, Joe</actor>
      <role>Announcer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dolenz, Micky</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Frank, Shannon</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hall, Edd</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Thicke, Alan</actor>
      <role>Host</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In the mid-to-late 1980s, "Pictionary" was among the hottest board games among teen-agers and adults; frequently, stores sold out of the popular game based on pictorial charades. The board game spawned two attempts to bring the game to the small screen; the 1997 five-a-week syndicated game was the second of those attempts. Two teams of three members (each having a contestant and two celebrities) competed in a series of rounds based on guessing phrases, people, places, things, etc., based on pictorial charades. In the first round, the teams have 45 seconds to convey phrases sharing a common word (e.g., "wheat bread" and "bread basket"), with $100 per correct guess. In the second round, the teams have three minutes to guess as many phrases, with each phrase connected by one word (e.g., "Bengal tigers, " "Lions, tigers and bears, oh my!" "Detriot Lions, " etc). ; the team members rotated duties after each phrase, with correct answers worth $100. The team leading at the end of the second round won and advanced to the bonus round. In the bonus round, one member of the winning team had 90 seconds to draw as many words as possible, with each word being related in some way to the one previous (e.g., red, riding, hood, wink, eye, brow, beat, egg, etc).. The first four words were worth $100, the second three worth $300 and all subsequent words $1,000 (up to a maximum of $10,000).</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?431994</url></doc>
