<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="432251">
  <docid>432251</docid>
  <title>Piede di dio</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Sarandrea, Bruno</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Italian</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Italy">28 August 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Italy">106</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Sardiello, Luigi</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Porcelli, Enzo</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Sardiello, Luigi</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Terrinoni, Andrea</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bouryka, Elena</actor>
      <role>Vittoria</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Catania, Antonio (I)</actor>
      <role>Maestro</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gasparini, Paolo</actor>
      <role>Giulio</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gentile, Gaetano</actor>
      <role>Cameriere Bar Roma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Molteni, Luis</actor>
      <role>Dottor Romano</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pucillo, Filippo</actor>
      <role>Elia</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Quintozzi, Guido</actor>
      <role>Direttore di banca</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Solfrizzi, Emilio</actor>
      <role>Michele Corallo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stornaiolo, Antonio</actor>
      <role>Mago Raian</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Elia has a talent. He has never missed a penalty. He has a magic foot... Very few people play football like he does. Elia's got a problem, though. He is 18 years old but he acts like a 12 year old: his father had left him and his mother when he was that age, to go back to Rome and work as a manager. Michele's got a problem. When he was young he had an accident and had to give up the dream of becoming a football player. Now he works for local football teams looking for new talents: he goes around, lives high, wheeling and dealing, lying to himself and the others. However Michele has a talent too: he is able to recognize a champion. During one of his trips to the South of Italy, Michele meets Elia by chance on the beach, and he is struck by his talent. Cynically, the boy is the solution to all his problems. Thanks to his persuasive skills, he talks to his mother and become the manager of the boy. So, the odd couple starts a journey of hope through the big city and the football world, with its arrogant agents and all-powerful managers. One day, at last, there is the trial match to enter a great football team...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?432251</url></doc>
