<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="433237">
  <docid>433237</docid>
  <title>Pinjar</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Saluja, Ballu</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>partition</keyword>
    <keyword>based-on-novel</keyword>
    <keyword>hindu</keyword>
    <keyword>india</keyword>
    <keyword>pakistan</keyword>
    <keyword>muslim</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Urdu</language>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>DTS</soundmix>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">188</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Dwivedi, Chandra Prakash</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Dwivedi, Chandra Prakash</writer>
    <writer>Pritam, Amrita</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Singh, Uttam</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bajaj, Savita</actor>
      <role>Nurse (Dai)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bajpai, Manoj</actor>
      <role>Rashid</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Biswas, Seema</actor>
      <role>Mad woman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chatterjee, Priyanshu</actor>
      <role>Trilok</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chauhan, Vijay (II)</actor>
      <role>Alladitta</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dubey, Lillete</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Mohanlal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jalal, Farida</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Shyamlal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kazmi, Pratima</actor>
      <role>Alladitta's mom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kharbanda, Kulbhushan</actor>
      <role>Mohanlal (Puro's dad)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Koppikar, Isha</actor>
      <role>Rajjo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Matondkar, Urmila</actor>
      <role>Puro/Hamida</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nath, Alok</actor>
      <role>Shyamlal (Ramchand's dad)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rana, Adil</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Singh, Samar Jai</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Suri, Sanjay</actor>
      <role>Ramchand</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Hindustan (Urdu name for India) used to a vast territory and countries' like Pakistan, Sri Lanka, Nepal, Bangla Desh, and Bhutan were all it's provinces. All this changed when the British established their rule over India, and promoted their policy of hatred, and division - mainly between the Hindus and the Muslims. After their departure in 1947, the celebrations of a independent India were short-lived, and the divisions created by the British stayed on and flourished with extremists from both sides ready to kill anyone from the other side. While the Muslims under Jinnah wanted a separate country, which they would like to call Pakistan, the Hindus wanted the Muslims to leave this country and go to Pakistan. Clashes followed, millions fled, millions more were killed, Very little is known of mankind's heinous behavior in this circumstances, such as looting, raping, and kidnapping. Lajjo was one such woman who was recently married to Ramchand, and then abducted by a man named Rashid, who gets her to Pakistan, where she is to be second wife of an abusive and controlling male. Her sister-in-law, Puro, distraught at losing her Bhabhi in such short a time, sets out to search for her, encouraged by her brother, but cautioned by her parents, who would not prefer to lose another child. Puro begins her task of locating Lajjo and calls herself Hamida, ironically assisted by none other than a much changed and remorseful Rashid, and goes from door to door as a petty saleswoman and cleaner. Then one day she finds Lajjo. Not quite the fun-loving and exuberant Lajjo she knew, but a much subdued one - trapped and under the 24/7 control of "Amma" and her alcoholic husband. Puro does get to speak to her in private, and both conspire to escape, hopefully back to her husband and their family. The question remains will Puro be successful in getting Lajjo to escape, or will she herself be entrapped in a hopeless situation.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?433237</url></doc>
