<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="433317">
  <docid>433317</docid>
  <title>Pink Outs</title>
  <year>1967</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Gunther, Lee</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>pink-panther</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Argentina">Atp</certificate>
    <certificate country="USA">G</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">27 December 1967</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">6</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Chiniquy, Gerry</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>DePatie, David H.</producer>
    <producer>Freleng, Friz</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Leonardi, Art</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Greene, Walter (II)</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>This cartoon consists of a series of bizarre black-out gags with the Pink Panther. In one, he is a painter who finds that his paint bucket is dry and screws a hole in the scaffolding above and through the bottom of the bucket belonging to the painter on the next level, whose paint pours into the panther's bucket. Unbeknownst to the panther, a painter underneath him has the same idea! In another gag, the Pink Panther is relaxing on what appears to be a beach, but he sinks into the sand and falls into what is revealed to be the bottom of an hourglass. In yet another gag, the Pink Panther folds a backdrop into a finger-sized square and eats it, and the backdrop springs back to full size inside the panther's stomach! Another gag involves the Pink Panther attempting to demolish a condemned building, but the wrecking ball crumbles to pieces after striking the building, as does the panther, his vehicle, the building, and the whole scene itself! A recurring gag has the panther on a lawnmower. He finds what appears to be a large weed and attempts to clip it, to find it is either a long-legged bird, or a string whose cutting causes the entire scene, panther included, to fall into darkness.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?433317</url></doc>
