<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="433437">
  <docid>433437</docid>
  <title>Pinky Promise</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <producers>
    <producer>Davidson, Mark E.</producer>
    <producer>Allen, Kent (I)</producer>
    <producer>Gimbal, Peter</producer>
    <producer>Clark Jr., Richard</producer>
    <producer>Conlon, Brian (III)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Davidson, Mark E.</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>KYLE (15), RUDY (16) and FRANK (15) want what most healthy Texas boys want: sex, beer, football, beer, and sex -- and not necessarily in that order. New kid in town AZIZ SHAHEED (16) has just moved in from Houston to Livingston, Texas. Even though the big city's only 90 miles south, Aziz has entered a different world. His father, ALI (37), moved the family to Livingston to teach high school in a less chaotic setting with "small town values". He encourages Aziz to join the football team. GINA BEASLEY (25), so young looking that she could almost pass for a high school student, is the newest history teacher at Livingston HS. Her scarred past includes sexual abuse at the hands of her father that she's mostly repressed. Gina's not beyond using her good looks -- even if subconsciously -- to get what she wants out of life. This later becomes evident when her looks become a focal point for both the students and her peers. Back on the football field, the domineering militaristic COACH DRISCOLL (45) introduces the team to Aziz and reminds the team about the things that count: honor, discipline, conduct, and relying on your team to help you when the chips are down. Kyle, Rudy and Frank discuss Ms. Beasley while fishing. Kyle thinks that he has a chance of getting to know her on a more intimate basis and Rudy and Frank proclaim that a conquest of that proportion would make him God-like in their eyes. Kyle accompanies Ms. Beasley on a trip to Houston. During the trip, Ms. Beasley acts more like a girl than a woman and Frank seizes the moment to seal the deal. Kyle, ever the braggart, tells his friends about his encounter and suggests that they may be able to get in on the action. On a trip to a concert she shows her affection for all of the boys in the backseat of her car. Later, the boys boast of their conquest. Aziz overhears and immediately senses the impropriety. Kyle, Rudy and Frank swear Aziz to secrecy -- they want to protect their golden goose. Even though Aziz swears to not tell, the boys distrust him. Later, in the football locker room, they confront Aziz and even though he protests his innocence, they kill him and stuff his body in the lockers. They confess their crime to Ms. Beasley who panics and tells them to get rid of the body. They use Frank's fathers wood chipper to dispose of Aziz's body in the middle Lake Livingston but are soon caught by the police. The boys and Gina are interrogated by the police. The boys maintain their innocence with the mantra "no body, no crime" while Gina decries that she's "too pretty" to be convicted. The small town continues on as they deal with the scandal. At the high school football game they take a moment to recognize their missing team mates while Ali Shaheed mourns his son.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?433437</url></doc>
