<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="433898">
  <docid>433898</docid>
  <title>Pirkle Jones: Seven Decades Photographed</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Reed, James (X)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby SR</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">28</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Reed, Jane Levy</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Reed, Jane Levy</producer>
    <producer>Phillips, Sandra (VI)</producer>
    <producer>Reed, Jane Levy</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>Pirkle Jones: Seven Decades Photographed profiles an artist who has helped define the San Francisco Bay Area's dual photographic traditions of elegant landscapes and biting social documentation. Incorporating some 150 of Jones's black-and-white photographs and interweaving archival footage and recent interviews, the film allows the photographer to tell us story, highlighting his collaborations. For Jones, taking a photograph is always a political act. That philosophy underlies his contributions to the 1956 Death of a Valley project, for which he and Lange recorded the last year of the Berryessa Valley prior to its being flooded by a new dam constructed to quench the thirst of California's growing population. It is just as clear in A Photographic Essay on the Black Panthers, the groundbreaking project he and Baruch undertook in the 1960s. Pirkle Jones: Seven Decades Photographed adds a new dimension to the public's understanding of the life and work of this eloquent Bay Area photographer through the context of Jones's commentary and his reminiscences about his life in photography.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?433898</url></doc>
