<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="434297">
  <docid>434297</docid>
  <title>Pizza Girl</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Murphy, Brian Scott</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>pizzeria</keyword>
    <keyword>pizza-delivery</keyword>
    <keyword>pizza</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">10 June 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">95</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Murphy, Brian Scott</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Gross, Robin (III)</producer>
    <producer>Norton, Robb</producer>
    <producer>Pokorny, Frank</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Murphy, Brian Scott</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Fraser, Sam (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Badley, Boe</actor>
      <role>Max</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carranza, Jose</actor>
      <role>Ferris</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Collins, Reyanne</actor>
      <role>Winnie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Flanagan, Christopher</actor>
      <role>Anthony</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hawkins, Mike (III)</actor>
      <role>Panda</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jamieson, Mackenzie</actor>
      <role>Winnie's Friend</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jenkins, Brad (I)</actor>
      <role>Guy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lim, Jennifer (II)</actor>
      <role>Betsy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Newcomb, Steve</actor>
      <role>Bill</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Pizza Girl follows Delilah (Amy Wray), a pizza delivery driver, on her last day of work. She juggles the usual assortment of oddball customers while trying to tie up loose ends with the people who depend on her. As a tough and aging hipster, Delilah provides a breath of humanity to people who can no longer see themselves in a media-drenched world. One of those people is Bill (Steve Poizat-Newcomb), an unemployed dot-bomber who is afraid to leave his house and spends all his time playing video games. Another is Ferris (Jose Carranza), a washed up baseball player and junkie that can't function without Delilah in moments requiring responsibility. And finally Winnie (Reyanne Collins), who is an anime freak in denial about her relationship with an abusive and psychotic jerk (Mike Hawkins). Of course, Delilah's last day doesn't seem any worse than usual until she gets dumped by her long-term boyfriend (Boe Badley) after a sexually repressed loser (Chris Flanagan) falls in love with her. Writer/Director Brian S. Murphy uses stunning visual style and skillful storytelling to make Pizza Girl deliver an edgy, yet touching tale about overcoming personal stagnation and maintaining relationships despite the digital residue of a world infatuated with superficial images and consumption.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?434297</url></doc>
