<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="434515">
  <docid>434515</docid>
  <title>Plain Ride Penn</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Trusso, John</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">23 October 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">12</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Clayton, Kyia</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Hurah, Hurah</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>During Penn's Freshman year at the Metropolitan Learning Center in Portland, Oregon, an alternative public school grades Kindergarten through 12th, she decides that something has to be done about the 180 polystyrene trays that they throw away each day. She asks the Principal if she can take on the project of ridding the school of this waste and finding a viable alternative. She is given the okay and expected to take the project and run with it. Six months of emails and phone calls ensue, while she tries just to get people to take her seriously. Eventually she gets Metro Waste to give her a grant and the real challenge begins. Now armed with washable trays and donated mismatched silverware, she needs to get students to volunteer to wash the trays. But some of the teachers don't want to send their students out of class. It takes nearly a year to find a working system. Yet, in midst of all of this process, Penn remains unruffled and focused. Behind this determined and good hearted young woman is a family that respects her and supports her independence and a school that fosters the individuality of each child within it walls. This is a story about the will of one 15 year old girl, to do what she felt was right and the unique and touching people in her life who helped to shape her. This film gives the clear message that one person, can indeed, make a difference.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?434515</url></doc>
