<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="435528">
  <docid>435528</docid>
  <title>Player</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Fleet, Robert</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>sting</keyword>
    <keyword>gambling</keyword>
    <keyword>character</keyword>
    <keyword>neo-noir</keyword>
    <keyword>one-word-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">100</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Szpak, Alina</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Szpak, Alina</producer>
    <producer>Szpak-Fleet, Stephan</producer>
    <producer>Fleet, Robert</producer>
    <producer>Szpak-Fleet, Stephan</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Avital, Natalie</actor>
      <role>Princess</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carlson, Elizabeth (I)</actor>
      <role>Marie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Day, Dion</actor>
      <role>Older boxer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Enci (I)</actor>
      <role>Insa</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fleet, Robert</actor>
      <role>Sam</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Herman, Stanley</actor>
      <role>Bill</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Krause, Brandon</actor>
      <role>Young Boxer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McCallum, Nick (I)</actor>
      <role>Jack</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rayman, Cliff</actor>
      <role>The Trainer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Silva, Federico</actor>
      <role>Beck</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Szpak-Fleet, Stephan</actor>
      <role>Smith</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Sam is a professional gambler, complete with the whole package: highs and lows in fortune, an ex-wife with money, and an estranged son, Jack, who lives solid-citizen but tries to rival his father. The rivalry comes to a head when Sam starts living with a much-younger woman nicknamed Princess that he picks up in the desert town of Indio on his way back from a mediocre gambling jaunt in Laughlin, Nevada. At first distrustful of Sam, their relationship grows unexpectedly warm - except that, while she appears to love Sam, Princess also sleeps with Jack. Meanwhile, Sam teaches Princess the skills of the gambling trade: Sam's reputation is that "He always wins when it counts." Their fortunes take a nosedive, though, when Sam makes a wrong calculation on a low-end bet and winds up with both his knees smashed - just after he'd lined-up Insa, a female connection to a dangerous high stakes gambling syndicate. Now, needing the rush of that high stakes gambling to make himself feel alive, Sam uses Princess to place a bet with the syndicate. It's a bet that Sam knows, and Princess doesn't, that he can't cover without manipulating Jack to "borrow" from his ex-wife's business. It's a life or death bet now for Sam and Princess - and the odds get worse when Princess, trying to protect Sam, bets against him - and Jack can't come up with the money.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?435528</url></doc>
