<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="435951">
  <docid>435951</docid>
  <title>Please Report Any Suspicious Activity</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Persley, Erin</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>airplane</keyword>
    <keyword>airport</keyword>
    <keyword>experimental-film</keyword>
    <keyword>security</keyword>
    <keyword>film-permit</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">21 March 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">5</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Persley, Erin</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Persley, Erin</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>Please Report any Suspicious Activity is an experimental film and meditation on the airport space. Without ever gaining permission to film inside, the film aims to explore the heightened security measures and increased hostility that have transformed the airport into a locale that no longer wants to be visually recorded. As the film moves back and forth trying to find entry into the airport structure, heavy fortified fences, cold cement walls, unwelcoming signs and aggressive security cameras frustrate the viewer, preventing any access or understanding. The soundtrack adds to the aggravation and tension with haunting intercoms, irritating security checkpoint beeping, AirTrain announcements, and raucous traffic noise. Answer machine recordings echo this frustration and emphasize the spiraling voyage into gaining airport admission. These elements along with filming from a claustrophobic car, creates a sensory experience that opens up a discourse on the thin and shifting line between the desire for security and the need to preserve personal freedoms. It begs the question, "how do you construct a film around a space that refuses to be filmed?"</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?435951</url></doc>
