<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="437199">
  <docid>437199</docid>
  <title>Points of View</title>
  <year>1998</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Swiczinsky, Nana</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>None</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Austria</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">6</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Swiczinsky, Nana</director>
  </directors>
<plot>A film is not a picture book. And why? Because it moves. In real time. Because you can't turn the pages yourself. A successful film has timing. Rhythm. Rhythm is structured time. Intervals of "nothing" and "something". Movement in film cannot be seen in the individual frames nor in their sum total. Is it perhaps to be found between the frames? But there, as we know there is nothing. Let it flicker, baby. Faster than the blink of an eye. (Nana Swiczinsky) Nana Swiczinsky photocopied her original, geometric cell (a black ellipse) and during the process moved it around resulting in deformations. The images so formed are put into short series, so that the order given to the variations result in more or less continuous movement. It is a re-translation of the manipulation during the photocopying process into cinematographic movement. The animation results in vibrations and distortions of the graphic screen, it warps the two-dimensional surface into quixotic impressions of space and at times completely dissolves the strict geometry into flowing lines. The rhythmic pattern of images, laid down in loops, is reflected structurally in the sound track with "machine" music, which, in it raw smoothness would be too seductive were it not regularly interrupted. Often, during these breaks, a single frame-filling ellipse can be seen - an eye. Sometimes a motionless single frame, occasionally enlivened and breathing in cinematographic movement. The different points of view are aspects of the elementary game of perception and association which are here on offer. (Thomas Korschil)</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?437199</url></doc>
