<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="437304">
  <docid>437304</docid>
  <title>Poker</title>
  <year>1992</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Hernandez III, Gaspar</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 May 1992</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">21</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Hernandez III, Gaspar</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Gatzen, David</producer>
    <producer>Norton, Robert A.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Hernandez III, Gaspar</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Bowers, Richard (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Briggs, Dean Rupert</actor>
      <role>Joe</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harrison, Jack (IV)</actor>
      <role>Al</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hutchinson, Jeffrey</actor>
      <role>Scott</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Masters, Rick (IV)</actor>
      <role>Frank</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In a remote wilderness cabin, four friends unite once a year to play a friendly game of poker and reminisce on old times. But this time, there is something else... Frank, shaken, arrives early and tells Joe that Scott's car was in the canyon and that some creature had Scott. Joe, not buying Frank's story, but thinking that something may have happened to Scott , nonetheless decides to go back to the canyon. But Al's arrival and hesitation to waste any time, wanting to get the game going, convinces Joe that the entire story is delusional. When Scott, unharmed, finally arrives, Al and Joe lay Frank's story to rest and they begin their annual game of poker. But Frank, having seen the actual creature, is not convinced. Refusing to partake in the game he begins to accuse Scott of an extra-terrestrial possession. As the cards are then dealt a psychological thriller unfolds. Frank consistently raises questions about Scott, then shifting suspicion onto Al. But Joe recalls that something strange did happened earlier, before anyone had arrived. A strange phone call that didn't sound human... In the end the situation goes out of control and the friendly game of poker becomes a game of wits, accusations, and eventually violence.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?437304</url></doc>
