<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="437348">
  <docid>437348</docid>
  <title>Poker: A Fairy Tale</title>
  <year>2012</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">14 February 2012</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <producers>
    <producer>Jackson, Charlie (II)</producer>
    <producer>Maine, Mark</producer>
    <producer>Diamond, Kevin</producer>
    <producer>Maine, Brise</producer>
    <producer>Nickell, Steve</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Maine, Mark</writer>
    <writer>Terrell, Mike (IV)</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Poker is Jack's passion. Unfortunately it cost Jack his house, his family and his marriage to his wife Jill. Poker: A Fairy Tale is a comedy of errors following Jack's attempts to strike it rich playing cards. But the deck seems stack against Jack. Maybe with a little help and a great group of friends Jack can play the "cards he's dealt" for a chance to get himself out of the trouble he seems to have gotten himself in. Once Upon A Time, in a run of luck, Jack successfully won the inaugural average Joe Poker tournament only to be awarded with a bad check in place of his prize money. Confronting the promoter Johnny Knight, Jack finds himself owner of the entire Joe Poker venture. High hopes quickly turn south when Jack finds the organization is overwhelmingly in debt to every shady "organized lender" in Vegas. Rival groups kidnap Jack's wife, his kids and yes even his dog, in order to be the first to get paid-off from the proceeds. Against a wall, and against all odds Jack plays the cards he is dealt. And with his best friends organize a new average Joe Poker tournament, allowing average Joe players a chance to win the prize of a lifetime. Jack saves the day, pays off the bad guys and rescues his family, or does he?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?437348</url></doc>
