<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="440439">
  <docid>440439</docid>
  <title>Post House</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>high-definition</keyword>
    <keyword>satire</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>bar-mitzvah</keyword>
    <keyword>pilot</keyword>
    <keyword>sitcom-writer</keyword>
    <keyword>sitcom</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">TV-14</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">8 March 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">34</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Compton, Rebecca</actor>
      <role>Virginia Ace</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Conway, Neil (I)</actor>
      <role>Rolf Cak</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lampasone, Don</actor>
      <role>Dick Post</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nelson, Fred (VII)</actor>
      <role>Walt Flagen</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"Post House" is a 30-minute situation comedy pilot. It is the story of Post House Productions, a low-end bar mitzvah and wedding production company which, through a series of miscommunications, is given a contract to produce a high-end television ad campaign. Richard Post, the owner, is a 30-something wanna-be film director. The reality is Richard isn't good enough for anything more than a bad wedding video or a local cable commercial. In comes Walter Flagen, lead partner in the metro area's largest, most successful Ad firm (Flagen, Cak, and Ace.) When a young intern is asked to get a very important contract signed nothing goes right for Walter. Flagen's 20 million dollar contract falls on Richard's desk instead of the intended shop. Richard signs it, ecstatic about finally getting his big break. The comedic tension comes from three sources: the ineptitude of Post House Productions, the antagonistic relationship between Post House and the Ad agency that owns the campaign, and the odd cast of regular and guest characters. The remaining 12 episodes of season one will follow Richard's attempt to become a legitimate producer and Walter's attempt to sabotage Richard's efforts.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?440439</url></doc>
