<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="441256">
  <docid>441256</docid>
  <title>Power Rangers Wild Force: Curse of the Wolf</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">80</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Crouch, Ann Marie</actor>
      <role>Princess Shayla</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Guzman, Jack</actor>
      <role>Danny Delgado/Black Bison Wild Force Ranger (Iron Bison)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jeanmarie, Phillip (I)</actor>
      <role>Max Cooper/Blue Shark Wild Force Ranger (Surging Shark)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lang, Lex</actor>
      <role>Zen-Aku</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Leisure, David</actor>
      <role>Bus Org</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mallow, Dave</actor>
      <role>Vacuum Cleaner Org</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Medina Jr., Ricardo</actor>
      <role>Cole Evans/Red Lion Wild Force Ranger (Blazing Lion)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Merckx, Ken</actor>
      <role>Nayzor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Thornton, Kirk</actor>
      <role>Motorcycle Org</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Volok, Ilia</actor>
      <role>Master Org</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wayne, Danny (I)</actor>
      <role>Jindrax</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Woren, Dan</actor>
      <role>Zen-Aku</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Intent on defeating the Rangers once and for all, Master Org releases an Org General, Nayzor, from his stone tomb. Nayzor in turn releases Zen-Aku, a wolf-like mechanical beast who has been imprisoned for 3,000 years, and Zen-Aku traps Elephant Zord! His true identity unknown to him, Zen-Aku at times, seems to be the Rangers' enemy, and at times, a friend. He also commands three Wild Zords of his own. After the Rangers defeat Vacuum Org and later Bus Org, Zen-Aku combines his Dark Wild Zords to form Predazord, which defeats Megazord, and Zen-Aku gains controls of Giraffe Zord! As Taylor and Princess Shayla search for clues about Zen-Aku, the strange wolf creature suddenly shows up with Motorcycle Org. Although the Rangers defeat the Org, Zen-Aku gains control of the Bear Crystals, and thing look bad for the Rangers. The only sign of hope comes when Zen-Aku remembers parts of his past and he become friendlier. Could it be that Zen-Aku was once a friend to the Rangers?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?441256</url></doc>
