<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="442334">
  <docid>442334</docid>
  <title>Prem Shakti</title>
  <year>1994</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kumar, Nand (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">25 February 1994</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Mitra, Shibu</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Parkar, Nasir</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Joshi, Madan</writer>
    <writer>Mittra, Jyothika</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Patil, Vijay (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bharadwaj, Nitish</actor>
      <role>Naagraj</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deshpande, Sulabha</actor>
      <role>Krishna's foster mother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Govinda</actor>
      <role>Gangwa/Krishna</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Issar, Puneet</actor>
      <role>Mahabali Tantrik</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kamaldeep</actor>
      <role>Kamaljeet</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Karisma</actor>
      <role>Gauri/Karisma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Satyendra</actor>
      <role>Shastriji</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Shakti (I)</actor>
      <role>Hoshiyar Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khakhar, Sameer</actor>
      <role>Kewalchand</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Kader (I)</actor>
      <role>Romeo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khote, Viju</actor>
      <role>Kewalchand's Manager</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Murad, Raza</actor>
      <role>Kewalchand's maternal uncle</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Talsania, Tiku</actor>
      <role>Mannequin Maker</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Gangwa lives a poor lifestyle in a village in India. He is in love with Gauri and both want to get married. Gauri's dad, an astrologer, approves of Gangwa, but predicts that they will never get married. They decide to stay together and the night of Poornima, come to the rescue of Naagraj, who is being mesmerized by a Tantrik, who wants to steal a Mani, which will absorb the moonlight, enabling him to make a concoction, and after drinking this, will become immortal and invincible. Furious by their interference, he turns Gauri to stone, and unable to withstand the shock, Gangwa passes away. 25 years later Gangwa is re-born as Krishna, and lives a poor lifestyle with his foster mother. She wants him to get married to Pinky, but Krishna wants to establish himself first. He finds a job with a mannequin maker, and with Naagraj's help, creates a near-lifelike mannequin of Gauri. His employer sells this mannequin to Romeo, who is an employee with a fledging department store run by Kewalchand. Krishna finds employment in this store just to be near the mannequin, which comes to life only when he is alone with her, and calls itself Karishma. Little does Krishna know that on the next Poornima, his beloved will again be turned to stone by the very same vengeful Tantrik, who will not only have Naagraj in his control, but also will ensure that Krishna does not survive thus enabling him to make and drink the concoction that will make him immortal and invincible.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?442334</url></doc>
