<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="443273">
  <docid>443273</docid>
  <title>Price of Life</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Furrer, Jason</editor>
    <editor>Mahoney, Ryan</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby SR</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">4 September 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">39</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Hunt, Dan (I)</director>
    <director>LaPointe, Margaux</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>McWilliams, Stephen (II)</producer>
    <producer>O'Leary, John (IX)</producer>
    <producer>Campbell, Trish</producer>
    <producer>Durkin, J.D.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Durkin, J.D.</writer>
    <writer>Malinowski, Liz</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Quinn, Shea</composer>
    <composer>Wright, Topher</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Asante, Kofi</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Childs, Robert</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shakur, Muhammad</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"Price of Life" chronicles the inspiring story of Robert 'Ali' Childs, an ex-offender from South Philadelphia. For two decades, Ali terrorized the streets of Philadelphia as a criminal, engaging in violence, illicit sales of guns and drugs, and threatening the well being of everyone in his community, including his mother, his sister and his son. From a very young age Ali was exposed to a great deal of violence and drugs. As he grew up, he was shown the more adult aspects of life at his grandmother' speakeasy in the basement of her South Philadelphia home. His warped childhood led to a life of violence and crime. His life revolved around making money and feeding his addictions in any way possible without regard to anyone else. In time, Robert began to realize the consequences of his actions, people were making threats against his family, many of his friends had fallen victim to the violence and his future would either result in life in jail or death. "Price of Life" follows Robert Childs through the realities of the life on the street and the struggles to leave destruction behind at the National Comprehensive Center for Fathers. He is the voice of the reformed ex-offenders of Philadelphia who have given up makin' a killing on the street to repay their debts to their children and society one day at a time.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?443273</url></doc>
