<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="443847">
  <docid>443847</docid>
  <title>Prince Henry (of Prussia) Visiting Cambridge, Mass. and Harvard University</title>
  <year>1902</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">March 1902</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
<plot>Picture No. 1 shows Prince Henry escorted by a Troop of Cavalry arriving at the City Hall, Cambridge, Mass., where he is greeted by the Mayor, and where 2,000 school children sing German and American songs for him. A remarkable and brilliant piece of photography, giving a clear and well defined view of probably the greatest crowd that assembled on a small area to greet the German Prince during his stay in America. Picture No. 2 shows Prince Henry leaving Memorial Hall at Harvard University. Here we present probably the best view obtained during Prince Henry's entire tour. He leaves Memorial Hall at the Harvard University accompanied by Prof. Muensterberg, the German Counsul, Count Von Holleben, offices of the Prince's suite and representatives of the United States Army and Navy. As the Prince takes his seat in his carriage he is within ten feet of our camera, and an absolutely life like picture is secured. Picture No. 3 shows the Prince leaving the Harvard Club, Harvard University. Another remarkably fine view. Chief Wilkie of the U. S. Secret Service is observed standing on the high stone steps of the Harvard Club and signaling for the Prince's carriage. The carriage draws up and the Prince marches from the club house accompanied as usual by his suite and offices of the United States Army and Navy. After touching his hat respectively to the crowd, who cheer him, he immediately steps into his carriage and drives away.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?443847</url></doc>
