<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="446032">
  <docid>446032</docid>
  <title>Project: Adam</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Buchheit, Jake</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">19 October 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">13</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Buchheit, Jake</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Buchheit, Blaine</producer>
    <producer>Buchheit, Jake</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Buchheit, Jake</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Buchheit, Jake</actor>
      <role>Dr. Leopold Rancid</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dietz, David</actor>
      <role>Mac</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gerhardt, Harry</actor>
      <role>Arcon</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Herbert, Crystal</actor>
      <role>Eve</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Litten, Steve</actor>
      <role>Seizure Man</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mucha, Joey</actor>
      <role>Young Adam</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Willoughby, Aaron</actor>
      <role>Adam</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>ARCON oversees Project: Adam in which a boy was raised from birth in a facility, educated in all basic knowledge and isolated from most outside contact. From then on ADAM is given the freedom to pursue his education in whatever means he wishes. Adam quickly adapts to any subject and cracks some of the biggest problems in society like cancer and cold fusion all the meanwhile developing a Father/Son bond to Arcon who he has never actually seen in person, but speaks to him through a speaker which Adam dressed up using construction paper when he was a child to make him appear more personable. On Adam's 20th birthday he is released from the facility where he is greeted by a man named MAC who's job it is to help Adam assimilate into society. During his first day in the outside world Adam experiences all the nuances of the outdoors that he was denied from knowing for his life so far. All is not perfect in this world, as Adam discovers that the society that had been waiting for his release is not what is appears to be in this Sci-fi short.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?446032</url></doc>
