<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="448720">
  <docid>448720</docid>
  <title>Purnima</title>
  <year>1965</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Suri, Narendra</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Shah, Mahipatray</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Shah, Anandji Veerji</composer>
    <composer>Shah, Kalyanji Veerji</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Babloo (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dharmendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Prakash</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Guha, Anita</actor>
      <role>Vandana Mehra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hussain, Nasir (I)</actor>
      <role>Ratan Lal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khote, Durga</actor>
      <role>Sharda R. Lal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumari, Meena (I)</actor>
      <role>Purnima V. Lal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mehmood (I)</actor>
      <role>Chimanbhai 'Kafanwala' Suratwala</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Orphaned Purnima lives a poor lifestyle with her maternal uncle and cruel aunt. She is in love with Prakash and both plan to marry soon. when she goes to meet Prakash at his place of employment to seek a donation, she meets with Vasant, the son of the owner of Ratan Lal &amp; Co., who takes an instant liking to her. Vasant convinces his mom, Sharda, to approach Purnima's aunt and convince her that he is the most suitable groom for her - by hook or by crook. Sharda succeeds in doing so, and shortly thereafter Purnima and Vasant get married. Purnima convinces Prakash to marry Vandana Mehra who is in love with him, and he does so. Shortly thereafter both Purnima and Vandana get pregnant and give birth to sons, Anil and Sunil respectively. Following a violent altercation, Vandana and Vasant are killed in a car accident, Ratan is forced to pay off Vasant creditors and as a result loses everything and moves into a small hut. He convinces Purnima to re-marry Prakash, but leave Anil with them, and she does so. Five years later, Sharda passes away, and Ratan asks Purnima to take Anil with her. Both Anil and Sunil get along well, however, one day Prakash sees Anil stealing money from his coat, and it is then he asks Purnima to make a choice between Anil and him. The question remains who will Purnima choose?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?448720</url></doc>
