<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="449583">
  <docid>449583</docid>
  <title>Pyaar Karke Dekho</title>
  <year>1987</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">27 February 1987</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Babu, D. Rajendra</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Palchandani, Kishanchand</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Lahiri, Bappi</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anand, Vikas</actor>
      <role>All India Talent Association's Director</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anuradha (X)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chandrashekhar</actor>
      <role>Doctor who treats Ravi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Choti, Mohan</actor>
      <role>Man selling tickets in black</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Govinda</actor>
      <role>Ravi Kumar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Irani, Aruna</actor>
      <role>Sampat's wife</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jamshid</actor>
      <role>Ravi's competitor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Geeta (II)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Veena</actor>
      <role>Talent Association's Member</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Kader (I)</actor>
      <role>Sampat Srivastav</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mandakini</actor>
      <role>Urvashi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shivpuri, Om</actor>
      <role>Thakur</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Orphaned Ravi Kumar lives in Poona, India, with his maternal uncle. As he wants to pursue a career as a singer/dancer, he re-locates to Bombay, so that he could audition for the All India Talent Association. In Bombay he meets with his uncle's friend, a fast-talking conman, Sampat Srivastav, who not only arranges his audition, but also gets him a job with the Talent Association. Sampat also assists him getting accommodation, albeit with hilarious results, as one landlady wants to rent only to bachelors so that she could have her way with them, while another, Lilavati, will only rent to married couples. Ravi decides that he will be better off with Lilavati, so he rents a room from her and assures her that his wife will be arriving shortly. When that does not happen, Lilavati insists on seeing her photograph, so Sampat and Ravi select a random photo from a studio, make a copy, and show it to Lilavati. Shortly thereafter a woman resembling the one in the photo shows up at Ravi's doorstep claiming to be his wife, Urvashi. A baffled Ravi comes up with novel schemes to get rid of Urvashi, but only ends up offending Lilavati. With the talent contest closing in, Ravi must now tidy up his personal affairs and prepare himself - but will he succeed, and who exactly is Urvashi, why is she claiming to be his wife, and what is her background?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?449583</url></doc>
