<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="449642">
  <docid>449642</docid>
  <title>Pyar Kiye Jaa</title>
  <year>1966</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Shankar, N.M.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Sridhar, C.V.</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Gopu, Chitralaya</writer>
    <writer>Krishan, Rajendra</writer>
    <writer>Sridhar, C.V.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kudalkar, Laxmikant Shantaram</composer>
    <composer>Sharma, Pyarelal Ramprasad</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bedi, N.S.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kalpana (I)</actor>
      <role>Malti</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Shashi (I)</actor>
      <role>Ashok Verma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Kishore</actor>
      <role>Shyam/Rai Bahadur Ganga Prasad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumari, Veena</actor>
      <role>Shyam's mom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mehmood (I)</actor>
      <role>Atma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Prakash, Om (I)</actor>
      <role>Ramlal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puranik, V.D.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, Chaman</actor>
      <role>Devraj</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shivraj (I)</actor>
      <role>Verma 'Guruji'</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shyamlal</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Widower Ramlal lives a wealthy lifestyle near Poona, India along with two daughters and a son. His daughter, Malti, is a Science Graduate; Nirmala, a matriculate, and the son, Atma, who wants his dad to finance a Hindi film which he himself will produce under the banner of 'Wah Wah Productions', he even signs up a nubile and sexy Meena Priyadarshini, the daughter of Ramlal's Estate Manager, to play the female lead role. Ramlal would like to get his daughters married to families that are wealthier than him. He hires an Assistant Manager, Ashok Verma, to look after his estate, but fires him when he finds out that he has misbehaved with his daughters. Ashok protests by putting up a tent in Ramlal's front-yard. Then an elderly male comes to visit Ramlal, he identifies himself as Rai Bahadur Ganga Prasad, claims he is very wealthy, and the estranged father of Ashok. Ramlal seizes this opportunity and asks Rai Bahadur to get Ashok to marry one of his daughters. Ashok and his dad reconcile, and Ashok decides to marry Nirmala. Then Ramlal gets another visitor, a wealthy elderly male by the name of Devraj, who used to know Ramlal during his school-days. Ramlal and Devraj talk about old times, and end up fixing up the marriage of Malti with Devraj's son. Ramlal introduces Devraj to Rai Bahadur and starts preparations for both marriages - little knowing that soon he will find out that Devraj's son has gone missing, perhaps refusing to marry someone his dad has chosen for him; Rai Bahadur is not who he claims to be; and that Ashok maybe the son of a poor school-teacher.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?449642</url></doc>
