<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="450533">
  <docid>450533</docid>
  <title>Qing ding ai qin hai</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>shanghai</keyword>
    <keyword>greece</keyword>
    <keyword>santorini</keyword>
    <keyword>friendship</keyword>
    <keyword>male-female-relationship</keyword>
    <keyword>love</keyword>
    <keyword>melodrama</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Mandarin</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Taiwan</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Taiwan">13 April 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Lu, Jiang</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Liu, Jianli</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Chen, Jing Hua</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chae, Rim</actor>
      <role>Guan Xiao Tong</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chae, Rim</actor>
      <role>Guan Xiao Tong</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ho, Peter (I)</actor>
      <role>Li Yao Xiang</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ho, Peter (I)</actor>
      <role>Li Yao Xiang</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Su, Alec</actor>
      <role>Lu En Qi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zhao, Liang</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Guan Xiao Tong, a top student at Shanghai Conservatory, is about to leave for a vacation in Greece when her cousin unexpectedly cancels, claiming illness. Li Yao Xiang, recruited through the internet, becomes Xiao Tong's travel companion, but the two young people with completely opposite personalities clash from the start. Then Xiao Tong accidentally meets Lu En Qi, who is accompanying his mother on business to an antiques auction in Athens. En Qi feels trapped by his family obligations, which include the assumption that he will marry the daughter of a powerful family friend to strengthen the business. Attracted by Xiao Tong's cheeriness and determination to make the best of things, En Qi joins her on a day trip to the island of Santorini, where their relationship deepens. However, circumstances prevent their next meeting, and both parties return home to their separate lives. Xiao Tong and Yao Xiang eventually sort out their differences and become friends, staying in touch after their return to Shanghai. Some time later, En Qi also comes to Shanghai and, again, meets Xiao Tong by accident. This time, the couple are able to start a real romance, until En Qi finds himself in an impossible conflict between his family's expectations and his own emotions.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?450533</url></doc>
