<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="451805">
  <docid>451805</docid>
  <title>Quest for Glory V: Dragon Fire</title>
  <year>1998</year>
  <type>VideoGame</type>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>video-game</keyword>
    <keyword>sequel</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <producers>
    <producer>Alexander, Craig (III)</producer>
    <producer>Usher, Jay</producer>
    <producer>Zechiel, Mark</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Cole, Lori (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Thomas, Chance</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Alan, Jane</actor>
      <role>Ann Agrama</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Apostolina, Stephen</actor>
      <role>Cerberus 3</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Baxter, Carol</actor>
      <role>Queen Of Atlantis</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Billingslea, Beau</actor>
      <role>Rakeesh/Shakra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Blancfield, Marc</actor>
      <role>Pretorious</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Blum, Steve (IX)</actor>
      <role>Abduel/Andre/Kokeeno/Magnum Opus/Parrot/Salim</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bulen, Steve</actor>
      <role>Abdim/Bruno/Cerberus 2/Erasmus/Minos</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carvin, Michael</actor>
      <role>Banker</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cutler, Wendy</actor>
      <role>Erana/Sarra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fathy, Charles</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gabrielli, Elisa</actor>
      <role>Nawar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jaimes, Marabina</actor>
      <role>Sibyl</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kurtz, Joyce</actor>
      <role>Julanar/Katrina</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lee, Roy (II)</actor>
      <role>Cloud/Weaponer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Michelle, Diane</actor>
      <role>Budar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moss, Larry (III)</actor>
      <role>Logos</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>O'Neill, Greg (I)</actor>
      <role>Mobius/Toro</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Poletti, Stephen</actor>
      <role>Fenris/Marrak</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ruskin, Ian</actor>
      <role>Head Of FACS</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sorich, Michael</actor>
      <role>Abdum/Cerberus 1/Ferrari/Guards/Guardian</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stone, Doug (I)</actor>
      <role>Abdull/Arestes/Gort/Ugarte/Wolfie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tomko-Pavia, Greg</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Having foiled the plans of the Dark Master in Mordavia, the hero is magically summoned by a group of his longtime friends to the island realm of Silmaria (richly modeled after the culture and folklore of our own world's ancient Greece). The realm is in bad shape: the old king has very recently been brutally murdered by an unknown assassin; the coastline villages have been raided, ransacked and occupied by invading Hesperian mercenaries; wild animals and ravenous monsters roam the land and sea; and an ancient prophecy, foretelling the reawakening of a terrible dragon that had ravaged the land ages ago, arises once again. The centaur Logos, previously the late king's chief counselor and now the acting ruler of the realm, has decreed that the ancient ceremonial Rites of Rulership be opened to those who wish to contend for the kingship. Encouraged by his old friend, the noble Liontaur paladin Rakeesh, the hero enters the rites and finds himself racing to complete noble quests of bravery and honor around the realm, before they are accomplished by such other worthy contenders as Elsa von Spielburg (the Baron's daughter from QfG1); Magnum Opus, a vainglorious Roman warlord; or the brutish humanoid giant Gort. While on these quests, the hero will encounter many old friends and familiar faces, and will possibly even get the chance to rekindle the flame of an old romance. But meanwhile, in the shadows, an invisible hand aids the success of one of the contestants, and is constantly working to disqualify - or eliminate - all others. Thus, while treachery and death hide around every corner, an ancient evil is about to be unchained, the land about to be blasted once again by dragon fire...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?451805</url></doc>
