<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="452479">
  <docid>452479</docid>
  <title>R U There</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>intentionally-misspelled-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
    <language>Dutch</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Taiwan</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Verbeek, David</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Devillers, Natacha</producer>
    <producer>Maat, Judy</producer>
    <producer>Visser, Eva</producer>
    <producer>van Gestel, Frans</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>de Blok, Rogier</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Lim, Giong</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Callegari, David Eugene</actor>
      <role>John</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>De Hoog, Tom</actor>
      <role>coach Luc</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ke, Huan-Ru</actor>
      <role>Min Min</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Koomen, Stijn</actor>
      <role>Jitze</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ngyuen, Phi</actor>
      <role>Hai Li</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Jitze is a twenty three year old Dutch professional gamer. He's one of the best in the world and makes a good living from it. His actual life however feels like a continuous series of trips around the world, he sees the same things everywhere and they all look alike. Jitze is not interested in the real world. Jitze feels completely happy in the virtual game-world. During his first days at a tournament in Taipei Jitze witnesses an accident on the street. A young girl is hit by a car and lands close to Jitze on the sidewalk. She dies right there. The shocking incident makes little impact on Jitze at first. He doesn't mention the incident to anyone and continues on gaming. The next day however suddenly his arm starts to hurtand consequently starts to lose matches in the game tournament. He is forced to take a few days rest. One time late at night, Jitze meets a girl in the hotel. He asks her to massage his arm. Afterwards she leaves him a note with her name and phone number on it, her name is Min-Min. When he goes to meet her, he finds out that her daytime job is working as a 'betel nut beauty'. The two meet several times, but the relationship remains strictly businesslike. One time Jitze notices that Min-Min has an "avatar" in Second Life. Jitze's problem persists and his entire reality starts to crumble. He cannot compete anymore; therefore his reason for being in Taipei is gone. He meets Min-Min in Second Life. Here Min-Min's avatar, Lilly-Rukai, tells him that she has nothing to do with the real life Min-Min. After several meetings their characters in Second Life starts to develop feelings for each other and one night they kiss. Back in the real world, nothing happens between the two of them. When she says she will go to the south of Taiwan for the weekend to see her family, Jitze becomes desperate and pays her a large sum to go with her. During this stay in the inland something happens that shakes the very core of Jitze's existence. Back in Taipei Jitze is allowed to join the tournament again, but somehow can't really get into it anymore. He starts looking for Min-Min but can't find her, until one night he sees her in the hotel restaurant with an older rich man. She ignores Jitze which offends him greatly. Jitze's team plays the finals. During this game Jitze drifts off and lets his team down. The day before leaving Taipei Jitze finds Lilly-Rukai in Second Life. It's peaceful and friendly but when Jitze tries mentioning Min-Min, she doesn't want to talk anymore. Before he definitely leaves Taipei Jitze finds Min-Min at the betel nut shop. She treats him like any other customer. Jitze is terribly upset and walks the streets of Taipei until sunrise. He ends up at the same place where he witnessed the accident. There is nothing referring to the tragedy any longer. But something about him has changed. He looks different, more aware somehow... Before he gets on the plane Jitze says goodbye to Lilly-Rukai in Second Life, while waiting at the airport. He closes his laptop and gets on the plane.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?452479</url></doc>
