<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="452761">
  <docid>452761</docid>
  <title>Raakhi Ki Saugandh</title>
  <year>1979</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Mitra, Shibu</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Seth, B.S.</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Sharma, Om Prakash (I)</composer>
    <composer>Sonik, Master</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ajit (I)</actor>
      <role>Chamanlal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Haksar, Rajan</actor>
      <role>Georgy Dada</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Helen (I)</actor>
      <role>Sweety</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jankidas</actor>
      <role>Paro's potential father-in-law</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Amjad (I)</actor>
      <role>Jagganath 'Jagga'/Yahwar Pahwar Khan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mehra, Vinod</actor>
      <role>CID Inspector Shankar Verma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, Madan (I)</actor>
      <role>Bachchan Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ranjeet</actor>
      <role>Ranjeet</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Taneja, Sunder</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Shankar lives a poor lifestyle along with blind sister, Paro. He works as a locksmith. When his company shuts down he works freelance and is anxious to save enough money so that Paro can regain her vision and get married. He gets involved with thugs who ask him to break into a safe, but after doing so attack and leave him in the middle of the road. Jagganath, a truck driver, assists him and gets him safely home. Chamanlal, a Director at Metro Bank, and his henchmen, Georgy Dada and Bachchan Singh hire Ranjeet to break into the bank, steal cash and jewelry. After successfully carrying out this heist, they stop at Jaganath's house, sexually molest his sister, Munni, who subsequently kills herself, and then abscond. A visibly upset Jaganath, who was all set to get Munni married to Shankar Verma, sets out for vengeance but unknowingly befriends Paro and treats her as a sister. It is only later that he realizes that she is Ranjeet's sister and Ranjeet was one of Munni's molesters. Jaganath eventually locates and kills Georgy Dada and Bachchan Singh and is all set to do away with Ranjeet - but will Paro prevent him from killing her brother?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?452761</url></doc>
