<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="453037">
  <docid>453037</docid>
  <title>Race to Equality</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>education</keyword>
    <keyword>equality</keyword>
    <keyword>human-rights</keyword>
    <keyword>machinima</keyword>
    <keyword>right-to-education</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 June 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">7</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Akter, Nafiza</producer>
    <producer>Araujo, Michael</producer>
    <producer>Arvelo, Justin</producer>
    <producer>Begum, Jamila</producer>
    <producer>Cruz, Mathew</producer>
    <producer>Freytes, Vanessa</producer>
    <producer>Htay, Thein</producer>
    <producer>Lee, Jin (IX)</producer>
    <producer>Lewis, Tarana</producer>
    <producer>Randolph, Christopher (II)</producer>
    <producer>Rivera, Yessenia</producer>
    <producer>Rodriguez, Brian (VI)</producer>
    <producer>Runa, Sabina</producer>
    <producer>Siriwongsa, Doldechl</producer>
    <producer>Zuluaga, Juan</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>Race To Equality is the culmination of the year-long Virtual Video Project, an after-school program conducted by Global Kids, Inc. The students gathered regularly during the past year to learn about film production, global access to education, and virtual worlds. Their knowledge and efforts resulted in the production of Race To Equality, a year-end project on the struggle of individuals from Brazil, Tibet, and the United States to overcome racism in higher education. Race To Equality is a short video that displays the students' impressive understanding of both digital media and important international issues. Through Race To Equality, the 15 young creators illustrate a poignant story about the struggle of three individuals in Tibet, Brazil and the U.S. to overcome institutional racism in their respective countries. While the stories are fictional, they are based on research with the U.N. about unequal access to education and financial aid in China, Brazil and the U.S. In the film, the characters document their experiences at the U.N. Headquarters, underlying the film's central message about the necessity to take social action to overcome such obstacles.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?453037</url></doc>
