<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="453071">
  <docid>453071</docid>
  <title>Racetrack</title>
  <year>2010</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Murphy, Michael David</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>sting</keyword>
    <keyword>horse-racing</keyword>
    <keyword>double-cross</keyword>
    <keyword>brothers</keyword>
    <keyword>suspense</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">3 July 2010</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Feifer, Michael</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kelly, John J.</producer>
    <producer>McCready, Helen</producer>
    <producer>McDaniel, Tamara (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>McCready, Helen</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Burkey, Bobby</actor>
      <role>Roley</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tyson, Richard (I)</actor>
      <role>Jake Sconato</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Racetrack is a story about a professional gambler, Bill McKirch, whose brother, a track jockey, is killed in a horse race set up by the Mafia, namely Jake Sconato. Bill exacts the ultimate revenge against the mobster whose greed caused his brother's death. In Bill's attempt to kill Jake, he himself takes a bullet to the side of his face. He manages to drive himself to his best friend's house, track vet, Fred Noble. Fred nurses Bill back to recovery enough to get Bill out of the country and to a doctor that can reconstruct his face. Bill has plastic surgery on his face, now not recognizable and comes back to Phoenix, Arizona for revenge. He gets a job with Jake placing bets and making money for the mob. While working for Jake, he seeks his revenge by plotting an explosive sting against the family business. Bill, with the help of his track friends, manages to set Jake up to be killed by his own mob family. Bill sets up a corrupt betting scheme to look like Jake has stolen money from the family by placing illegal bets through the bookie's offices across the country. What Bill did not expect was for Jake to find out his true identity.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?453071</url></doc>
