<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="453396">
  <docid>453396</docid>
  <title>Radio Mania: An Abandoned Work</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>3d</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">26</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Forsyth, Iain</director>
    <director>Pollard, Jane</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Lake, Kirk</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Plytas, Nick</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Catz, Caroline</actor>
      <role>Mary</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Crompton, Ben</actor>
      <role>Martian X</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Eldon, Kevin</actor>
      <role>Arthur</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fielding, Fenella</actor>
      <role>Mrs Langdon</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hardiman, Terrence</actor>
      <role>Mr Sterling</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lee, Iain</actor>
      <role>Martian Y</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moor, Ben (I)</actor>
      <role>Martian Z</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Radio Mania: An Abandoned Work is a 3D film by Iain Forsyth &amp; Jane Pollard. It takes as its starting point one of the first 3D films ever made - The Man from M.A.R.S. It was made to demonstrate 'Teleview', a stereoscopic motion picture system invented by Laurens Hammond. Following a premiere in New York, the show closed 24 days later, after which 'Teleview' and the film were never seen again. Hammond continued as an inventor and created the Hammond organ. The artists have set about creating a contemporary adaptation of this silent film in which an inventor succeeds in building a radio transmission device capable of communicating with intelligent life on Mars. He receives a scientific formula to turn coal into diamonds, only to have his new-found wealth disappear when he wakes up, finding that his dreams had been inspired by newspaper reports of Marconi's experiments with radio signals. Radio Mania: An Abandoned Work is a work in progress caught in stereoscopic limbo. Having set about their reworking of the film the artists then staged and filmed a rehearsal for their adaptation using contemporary 3D video technology, capturing the actors, directors and musicians working on the script and score. The rehearsal is stuck on repeat, like a locked-groove record. Their entertaining, stark and compelling odyssey recalls Beckett, creating an atmosphere that oscillates between the theatricality of the stage and the illusionism of cinema. The work focuses on the 'between states', between reality and artifice, dream state and hallucination.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?453396</url></doc>
