<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="454115">
  <docid>454115</docid>
  <title>Rainbow's Children</title>
  <year>1975</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Williams, Lloyd Michael</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">12 August 1975</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">24</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Williams, Lloyd Michael</director>
  </directors>
<plot>"It is the nature of dreams to fade away upon the awakening of their creator/dreamer. Dreams are pushed into the back of the mind, kept in the dark corners under guard of the alert mind. When night comes the body sleeps, the heart continues to beat, the mind lets down its day barrier and as if Pandora's Box were opened, arise all the forbidden thoughts and ideas, distorted and strange even to ourselves... THE ANSWER, ONLY THE TRUTH DISGUISED IN A DREAM LLOYD WILLIAMS is a film creator who has been deeply influenced by his own dreams, and who is unique in having set about consciously to recreate them on film. In RAINBOW'S CHILDREN, LLOYD WILLIAMS reveals the dreamer awakening; erotic displacements of dreams are transformed into the erotic realities of life itself - although still poetically suffused with a dream like languor which the filmmaker cannot escape. The texture of flesh, the ambiguity of longing and the colors of psychedelic apotheosis all merge into a languorous ecstasy which LLOYD WILLIAMS is adept in translating into the medium of film. All the varieties of film technique: slow motion, multiple-exposure, fast motion, camera in full flight and frozen image, he uses for the revelation of his intense fantasy, whether from dreams or from real-life or from hallucinated contemplation. His work shows that the dreamer is, indeed, awakening into a whole new world of erotic fantasy, muted with desire. If hard core films shock you, the films of LLOYD WILLIAMS will caress you."</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?454115</url></doc>
