<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="455329">
  <docid>455329</docid>
  <title>Rani Rupmati</title>
  <year>1957</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Tripathi, S.N.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Madloi, R.N.</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Tripathi, S.N.</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Amarnath (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhushan, Bharat (I)</actor>
      <role>Shehzada Wajid Khan/Sultan Bhag Bahadur</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chonkar, Nalini</actor>
      <role>Hamida H. Khan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moolchand</actor>
      <role>Sher Khan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Raje, Babu</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ulhas (I)</actor>
      <role>Subedar Hafiz Khan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vyas, B.M.</actor>
      <role>Adam Khan</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>During Akbar's rule over Hindustan, the Mughal's considered Pathans their enemies and vice versa. As a result there was a war-like relation between Mandva's Sultan Sujat Khan and Akbar. But Sujat's son, Wajid, was a peace-maker and a lover of the arts. He befriended a Hindu Kshtriya, Rajkumari Rupmati, of Mandhavghar, and despite protests from her parents, brothers, and to-be husband, Baldev Singh, she re-located to Mandva, where Wajid build her a tower so that she could view and seek blessings from holy river Narmada, who had gifted her to Mandhavghar. She became instrumental in diverting Narmada to bring water to her drought-stricken hometown. After Sujat passes away, Wajid becomes the Sultan and is called Bagh Bahadur. Akbar hears about this and sends Sangeet Samrat Tansen to check out Rupmati as well as find out if they wanted peace or war. Tansen was welcomed, and assured that Wajid wanted nothing but peace. But their peaceful lives will soon be turned upside when Tansen gets abducted by Subedar Hafiz Khan, is held against his will. An enraged Akbar asks his Chieftain Adam Khan to storm Malwa and free Tansen. In the meantime, Hafiz' daughter, who is in love with Wajid, gets into Rupmati's palace - with one intent - to kill her. Watch the outcome as the Pathans together with their Hindu allies, amidst mixed chants of 'Allah O Akbar' and 'Har Har Mahadev' prepare themselves for Akbar's armies, and how Rupmati defends herself against Hamida.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?455329</url></doc>
