<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="455320">
  <docid>455320</docid>
  <title>Rani Hindustani</title>
  <year>1995</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Dardeh, Santosh</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">1995</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Pandit, Anil</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Raja, Naresh</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Lahiri, Bappi</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ali, Ishrat</actor>
      <role>Choudhry Devkirai</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bahadur, Rana Jung</actor>
      <role>Chopra's lawyer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dasgupta, Poonam</actor>
      <role>Julie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deepshika</actor>
      <role>Ganga/Mohini</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dheer, Pankaj</actor>
      <role>Royce</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dhillon, Deep</actor>
      <role>Inspector Rawat</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gill, Avtar</actor>
      <role>Mohini's lawyer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Murad, Raza</actor>
      <role>Thakur Shamsher Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Raaj</actor>
      <role>Shankar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ranjeet</actor>
      <role>A.K. Chopra</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Sweet, attractive and naive Ganga lives in a small village in India, with her mom. She is in love with Shankar, who has gone to the city at the recommendation of Thakur Shamsher Singh, and would like to marry him soon. Her dreams and innocence come to an end when she is lured by Shamsher to his mansion so that she can sleep with Minister Choudhry Devkirai. She manages to get Choudhry drunk and manages to escape to Bombay. Upon arrival, she is molested, and sold at a brothel, but she manages to escape with the help of a cripple named Royce, who assists her in locating Shankar. Shankar is overjoyed to see her, introduces her to his boss, A.K. Chopra, and they begin plans for their marriage. Chopra takes an unusual interest in Shankar's career and not only promotes him, but gives him an apartment in a posh locality. Before the marriage could take place, the police find Ganga disheveled and hysteric laying next to Shankar's lifeless body. She is arrested, charged with murder, and sentenced to a life in prison. She escapes with the help of Royce, and sets about planning her vengeance against Chopra, Shamsher Singh, Police Inspector Rawat, and Choudhry. What caused Shankar's death? Why was Ganga hysterical and disheveled? And why does she want revenge against Shankar's well-wisher, Chopra?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?455320</url></doc>
