<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="455822">
  <docid>455822</docid>
  <title>Rassvet/Zakat. Dalai Lama 14</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Vazhnina, Elena</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>dalai-lama</keyword>
    <keyword>environment</keyword>
    <keyword>buddhism</keyword>
    <keyword>india</keyword>
    <keyword>tibet</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Russian</language>
    <language>English</language>
    <language>Tibetan</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Russia</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Netherlands">26 January 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Russia">21 June 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">7 August 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">72</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Mansky, Vitali</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kucherenko, Alexey</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>Twenty four hours in the residence of His Holiness the Dalai Lama, from the beginning of his day which starts, at 3 am till dusk when he goes to bed. During that cumulative day, the Dalai Lama carried out his morning fitness training, his walk along the residential alleys, his prayers and meditations. These are followed by audiences, press-conferences and giving blessings to pilgrims. On the same day the Dalai Lama gave his teachings to the Buddhists from Russia and Mongolia. And at the end of the day, when the Buddhist leader returned to his personal quarters, the Buddhist leader touched upon the essence of the Universe and the role an individual has to play in religion and contemporary society. Also, we see a travelogue compiled by the filmmakers slowly going back from India, though China, to Russia. On the way back home, they keep on recalling their evening discussion with the Dalai Lama which they had just before they left his residence. Quite surprisingly, the issues discussed with the Dalai-Lama overpopulation, a gap between rich and poor, ways to avoid global conflicts had been confirmed by striking images of what they saw on the road.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?455822</url></doc>
