<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="456135">
  <docid>456135</docid>
  <title>Raunchy Porno Picture Show</title>
  <year>1992</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adult</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>sex</keyword>
    <keyword>hardcore</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">X</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">85</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Benini, Sid</producer>
    <producer>Jizzney, Walt</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Rainwhite, Rod Wrathbone</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Coldwater, Jeff</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jeremy, Ron</actor>
      <role>Special Guest Star 1991 Porn Hall Of Fame Inductee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nasty, Dick</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A 90s nostalgic video lust ode to a lighthearted breed of adult camp which died out with the onset of the assembly line compilation age, this zany sex show represents the end of fun old school style porn shot before the onset of E fast food's household worded cyber era. The shoot is set against the local nightlife and neon nights of the exteriors of Hollywood itself, comedically grandstanding the one shot wonder debut of one Woodie Piper, the announcer host and porn's uber neurotic answer to mainstream cinema's Mr. Allen of the same name. His running instructional commentary for would-be studs is not for the hardcore at heart, since much of it is shot with a carefree amateurish attitude. Which is to say this was made when fans still cared about Xer drama, no matter how plot flimsy, ad libbed or makeshift. Girls, girls, girls, from an early Dominique Simone to Viper at the tail end of her career, fill ten sex scenes in all. So there is enough turn on potential in this 80 plus minute stroker provided that new age fans can put up with sex made lukewarm with tongue in cheek humor. Oldtimer consumers who long for the innocence of historic pop culture and porn when sex trade horniness was still funny and sleazy will gush over this raunch time machine trip back into retro titilation. As far as smut scope, it played in NYC's infamous Time Square before Mayor Giuliani cleaned it up. Back when X-raters took themselves less seriously and the erotic milieu was more exclusive and less saturated via the world wide web, stars actually had fun living out their dirty dreams on videotape. Younger fans spoiled by the explosion of the Internet revolution may scoff at the datedness, but for those of us who've been there and done that, father time tells and swells a different glory or story.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?456135</url></doc>
