<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="456227">
  <docid>456227</docid>
  <title>Raven Tales: The Games</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Hystad, Caleb</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">15 August 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">24</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Smith, Vincent (III)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Curwen, Colin</producer>
    <producer>Kientz, Chris</producer>
    <producer>James, Simon (XII)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>James, Simon (XII)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Lee, Mitch (II)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Adams, Evan</actor>
      <role>Raven</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kientz, Chris</actor>
      <role>Wina</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moore, Carmen</actor>
      <role>Frog</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Reid, Ian (IV)</actor>
      <role>Eagle</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Raven, Eagle, Wina and Qos are out fishing when they become ensnared by a storm and blown far out to sea , finally coming to rest on a strange island. They notice footprints that lead them to a village of people much like themselves, complete with their own Raven and Eagle. They are surprised to see Frog, who explains that there are many other people in the world, and many other Ravens and Eagles. She introduced everyone and and evening of dancing, storytelling and gift giving ensues. The following morning, they head back to their canoe to return home, only to find the rest of the first people, led by Gwai, arriving in canoes of their own. The two villages decide to visit together a little longer. The children soon become bored, so Frog suggests that they organize some games to pass the time. Soon, both villages are competing in a variety of activities, which culminate in a huge feast and the exchanging of prizes. They soon realize that in the process of competing, they have come to know and respect each other's culture all the more, and come together in friendship. The people decide to get together on regular basis, and to join together in friendly competition once each year.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?456227</url></doc>
