<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="456658">
  <docid>456658</docid>
  <title>Re bina mmogo</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Tswana</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Botswana</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="South Africa">7 January 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="South Africa">26</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Eustice, George</producer>
    <producer>Engels, Ernst</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Basuhi, Gaolope</actor>
      <role>Boitumelo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bikitshane, Saone</actor>
      <role>Koketso</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dikgomo, Joseph</actor>
      <role>Blocks</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dikgomo, Ontlametse</actor>
      <role>Abel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kebaitsang, Masego</actor>
      <role>Tebogo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moilwa, Kgalalelo</actor>
      <role>Mpho</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mokandla, John Mazabathi</actor>
      <role>Obed</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Otukile, Vuyisele</actor>
      <role>Onkemetse</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Towards the end of a hot Botswana summer, members of a traditional dance group, "Tsosolosa!" are grappling with emotionally-charged dilemmas. Six dancers - three young women and three young men - come from very different backgrounds but are drawn together by their love for traditional Setswana dance. For some their love for the dance will be tested. For all, the test is in their relationships with family, friends, lovers, and fellow dancers. This is a story of the lives and loves, and hopes and dreams, of young Batswana in the context of the changing cultural norms and values of modern times. Each of the dancers are shaped and challenged by the forces upon them: love, power, money, lust, and authority. They must choose their destiny by making difficult choices and search for what they truly believe in. In the interlinking story strands we are introduced to the characters who affect the lives of the dancers. These are parents, relatives, employers, work colleagues, friends, and lovers. Throughout these layers of storylines, the dancers are united by a common goal. They must work hard to perform well in an upcoming competition. The pressure increases when news arrives that a Hollywood talent scout will be present at the competition to hunt for a group that will be featured in the first Hollywood movie ever filmed in Botswana. The series is a co-production between the Camel Thorn Media for Development Trust, a new not-for-profit organization that specializes in producing programming about development, and Red Stone (Pty) Ltd, one of Botswana's leading production companies. The co-producers have identified a well-known local dance group, Mogwana, who have willingly contributed to the research and development of the storylines. "Re Bina Mmogo" is as much an exploration of the relationships in our daily lives, as it is a celebration of traditional dance. This is fun and intelligent entertainment that challenges norms and values, and has authentic educational content appealing to a broad audience.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?456658</url></doc>
