<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="456892">
  <docid>456892</docid>
  <title>Real Access</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bergacs, Chad</editor>
    <editor>Grizzle, Mark</editor>
    <editor>Huber, Summer</editor>
    <editor>Jones, Juan (II)</editor>
    <editor>Plotkin, Richard</editor>
    <editor>Storesund, Thomas</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">19 March 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Plotkin, Richard</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Fessak, Daniel</producer>
    <producer>Silverstein, Rob</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Baxt, Mathew</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Collins, Lauren (I)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Duff, Hilary</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Epstein, Jake</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mayhew, Lauren C.</actor>
      <role>Host</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Murray, Chad Michael</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>West, Shane (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Real Access is produced by the makers of the popular television tabloid Access Hollywood. The show is basically the 'tween/teen version of its parent program, airing on the young adult network "The N" within the United States, and focusing on young actors, singers and entertainers that appeal to the aforementioned age group, (e.g., Britney Spears, Hilary Duff, Orlando Bloom, etc.). In addition, the show also is a promotional vehicle for its own network's programming, occasionally profiling actors from its own shows, (e.g., Degrassi, Radio Free Roscoe, etc.). Mostly relying on archived interviews and newsclips, former aspiring pop star and host, Lauren C. Mayhew, occasionally has the opportunity to interview the show's subjects. Overall, Real Access is a well-done entertainment show, and while it may not get overly-explicit due to the age of its primary viewership, it manages to be unique, informative and entertaining, and is very responsive to comments made and polls taken by its viewers at The N's website.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?456892</url></doc>
