<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="458556">
  <docid>458556</docid>
  <title>Redemption Falls</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Vitt, Austin</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>summer-camp</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Leonard, Brendan M.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bersani, Julie</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Leonard, Brendan M.</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Abeles, Daniel</actor>
      <role>Dan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bersani, Julie</actor>
      <role>Jude</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brant, Nathan Scott</actor>
      <role>Wolfman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Drago, Jason A.</actor>
      <role>CB</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gupta, Arjun</actor>
      <role>Tom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hadley, Matthew</actor>
      <role>Fenn</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hunter, Laura (III)</actor>
      <role>Fiona Donne</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>James, Michael (XIX)</actor>
      <role>Coach</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Klaum, Cierra</actor>
      <role>Gabby</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Medville, Lillian</actor>
      <role>Sera</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Redemption Falls is a workplace drama that goes inside the cabins and offices at Dovetail Falls, a struggling summer camp in Northeastern Ohio. Featuring a diverse cast of characters, the series explores the challenge faced by all camping professionals: How do you separate your personal and professional lives when you live where you work? Can Lauren, a tough climbing/adventure specialist, overcome her grief and self-destructive nature to help kids who really need saving? Does arts director Dan choose between Irish spitfire Fiona, who represents the safety of his past, and aggressive businesswoman Jude, who keeps pushing him to realize his true potential? Will Ellie, the camp "lifer" moving up the ranks, reconcile her sexuality with a board of directors determined to impose a certain set of values on Dovetail Falls - and will her relationship with fellow counselor Bethany be affected by it? How does equestrian director Sera face her boss and ex-lover "Wolfman" now that she's dating the director of a rival camp? Just when will somebody realize that junior counselor Hope and the brooding South African C.B. are more than "just friends?" And let's not forget about the mission imparted on the staff by ex-ballplayer and camp director Coach Franklin: "We're here to give kids the best time of their lives." From the ranch at day to the waterfront after hours, the soccer field to the smoking patio, these characters -and more- face their fears and realize the healing power of summer camp each week on Redemption Falls.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?458556</url></doc>
