<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="459636">
  <docid>459636</docid>
  <title>Release</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Hagerty, Silas</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">5</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Hagerty, C. Josephine</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hagerty, C. Josephine</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Hagerty, C. Josephine</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>McKay, Jason (II)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Beers, Mason</actor>
      <role>Tom Perkinson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cimmet, Alison</actor>
      <role>Jane</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Goodridge, Chad</actor>
      <role>Wes</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Izquierdo, Michael (I)</actor>
      <role>Robert</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Levenson, Jon</actor>
      <role>Stephen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McClain, Amelia</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Perkinson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Miller, Scott Andrew</actor>
      <role>Victor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Williams, Victor (I)</actor>
      <role>Reggie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>York, Marshall</actor>
      <role>Ted</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Based on a true story and starring 'King of Queens' star Victor Williams, in the aftermath of 9-11, what began as a bad day for Reggie, has suddenly gotten irrevocably worse and he just can't take it anymore. Desperate to unleash the anger exploding inside him, he focuses on an unnamed man on the other end of the fateful cell phone call that pushed him past his breaking point as Reggie now marches his way through the streets of New York City with the intention of killing him. However, Reggie isn't the only one visiting this unnamed man - his wife and baby boy are on their way there as well, to meet him at his office for lunch. And like a perfect storm, Reggie and this unnamed man's family end up in the same cramped elevator on the way up his office. While Reggie doesn't know who the woman and child are, it's clear that Reggie is going to explode and it doesn't look like he's going to wait until the doors open. And then with the innocence and charm only children have, the child offers Reggie a goldfish cracker by throwing it at him. Reggie is faced with these critical questions: What is required to remind ourselves of our own human connectivity? What does it take to tear down the walls between us that keep us separated?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?459636</url></doc>
