<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="460478">
  <docid>460478</docid>
  <title>Repentance</title>
  <year>1995</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Brunkhardt, Ben</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">25 February 1995</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">8</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Brunkhardt, Ben</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Brunkhardt, Ben</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Venable, James L.</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Allen, Kristy</actor>
      <role>Dark-Haired woman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Baker, Dee Bradley</actor>
      <role>Matthew</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Caprita, David</actor>
      <role>Father</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>It's hard to tell what's real and what's a demented fantasy in this dark and atmospheric homage to early Twilight Zone, shot in B&amp;W and featuring an orchestrated score. Matt is a single middle-aged businessman who wakes up with a start one morning after having a nasty dream about some kind of domestic dispute in which a man violently slaps a woman. But was it a dream? Matt looks shaken, a voice in his head telling him he may have a second chance. A second chance to do what? On his way to work, while passing a bank, he hears gunshots. Ducking into the protection of the bank's doorway, we notice a guard standing there, a curious look on his face. Did Matt imagine this too? Is he insane? The guard clearly thinks so. Then Matt sees the woman from his dream, a young Latina who runs when she sees Matt looking at her. He gives chase. A mysterious homeless man becomes an unlikely witness, and may have more to do with the situation than we first think. The voices in his head continue, and we soon learn that it's his father, speaking to him as if he were still a child. "Don't ever point a loaded gun at someone" his father yells. "You're just like your mother."</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?460478</url></doc>
