<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="461656">
  <docid>461656</docid>
  <title>Return of the Starpeople</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bech Christensen, Pernille</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>interview</keyword>
    <keyword>superstition</keyword>
    <keyword>alien-species</keyword>
    <keyword>dogumentary</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Danish</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Denmark</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Denmark">27 November 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">57</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Milton, Bente</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Savel, Jordan</producer>
    <producer>Birket-Smith, Signe</producer>
    <producer>Holst, Carsten</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>Is it possible that civilization on Earth began with the help of visiting Aliens - and that these visitors will one-day return to see how we are progressing? It will be hard to dismiss the theme as pure fantasy and science fiction after having followed Nabil Shabans gripping investigation. Nabil Shaban is an extraordinary man, who would qualify for an honorary membership of the X-files Team. Not only does he look a bit like E.T., but he has been studying the subject of UFO's and extraterrestrials for thirty years, searching widely and deeply - collecting a dizzying patchwork of evidence. In this "dogumentary" we follow Nabil Shaban on a fascinating journey through space and time, Meeting with Native Americans, scientists and authors he investigates a number of extraordinary strange things. Some of them so strange that our entire worldview could be shaken if the collected data should turn out to be correct! Nabil has his very own - decidedly cranky, humorous and entertaining approach to the subject. Nevertheless he delves into astronomy and ancient history with a dazzling display of scholarship. The evidence he presents is convincing and the implications are quite shattering.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?461656</url></doc>
