<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="462168">
  <docid>462168</docid>
  <title>Revisited</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Gutteridge, Mark</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>docu-drama</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">5 August 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">7</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Gutteridge, Mark</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Gutteridge, Mark</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Gutteridge, Mark</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Is our protagonist about to commit a terrible crime or revisiting the scene? Does a film location have a life of its own? A scene from a film by Michelangelo Antonioni is reinterpreted and chosen because of its reliance on physical surroundings. The original location Maryon Park in Woolwich, London, England, UK is very small and completely enclosed by large trees to the city surrounding it, making a kind of visual claustrophobia. It was made at a time, decades before digital color correction, when the Director was having elements of nature literally painted to enhance colors prior to filming. Trees, grass, fences and paths all received this treatment, using gallons of paint. During scouting it was found that some of the paths and steps still have large patches of black paint on them from production dressing 37 years ago by Production Designer Assheton Gorton, keeping the park a fading movie set. The original film contains themes about reality (the photographer protagonist's interpretation and therefore our interpretation of what is seen down a lens). In this reinterpretation, members of the public are employed to highlight this theme. Is the audience to expect fiction or reality?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?462168</url></doc>
