<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="464175">
  <docid>464175</docid>
  <title>Ripple</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Elizabeth, Morgan</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Elizabeth, Morgan</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Elizabeth, Morgan</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bellamo, Jo</actor>
      <role>Angie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Elizabeth, Morgan</actor>
      <role>Girl</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Garland, Queen</actor>
      <role>Susie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Liberati, Lauren</actor>
      <role>Carrie</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This is a story about four disenfranchised women living in New York who are searching for meaning after having lost someone they experienced a true life altering connection with. Meet Carrie the Fighter. Carrie is a 33-year-old Caucasian woman who used to be a domestic violence advocate in a small town in Pennsylvania. After trying to help a young rape victim and losing, Carrie's torch has been extinguished. Meet Angie the Thespian. Decades ago the craft of acting was at its height, and now this Italian New Yorker in her late fifties spends all her time pushing actors to rediscover that level where the work matters not the fame. She thought she found someone who shared her passions and beliefs, but she was wrong. Meet Susie the Loner. Her mother never showed her any compassion and she never had a true friend until Lydia entered her life and illuminated her soul. However, Lydia was deported from the country, and now this 40-year-old black woman once again has nobody. And then there's Girl. Girl is on a search to connect with others and give hope. Hope that there is a chance to reconnect with another human being. Girl listens to Carrie, Angie, and Susie. The climax occurs when these three women all admit to wishing to get hit by a cab to end their suffering. Hearing this, Girl shares her own story about witnessing a loved one die by being hit by a cab and losing her voice as a result. She tells her story through sign language.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?464175</url></doc>
