<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="464319">
  <docid>464319</docid>
  <title>Rising Up</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Letamendi, Eduardo A.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">17</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Letamendi, Eduardo A.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Letamendi, Eduardo A.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Letamendi, Eduardo A.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Wahlback, Petter</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Alvarez, Ana María</actor>
      <role>Mother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Camacho, Felipe</actor>
      <role>Miguel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Camacho, Phil</actor>
      <role>Miguel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>De Leon, Christina</actor>
      <role>Arecelli</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jimenez, Ramses</actor>
      <role>Tee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Letamendi, E.A.A.</actor>
      <role>Baby</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Letamendi, Luz M.</actor>
      <role>Wife</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vazquez, Luis (III)</actor>
      <role>Man</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A tough gang member, Tee, must come to terms with the reality that his life will never be the same after he is shot. Tee is struggling to cope with his paralysis. His constant failures to complete the most mundane task on his own cause him to descend into a depression discouraging him to rehabilitate. All wants to do now is sleep all day, but he can't even do that because his neighbor Miguel keeps him awake with the loud salsa music he plays while he works on his car just outside Tee's apartment building. His girlfriend Arecelli tries everything she can to bring some normality back to Tee's life by trying to get him out of his house, but all she gets is resistance from him. Tired of seeing her son self destructing, Tee's mother confronts him and tells him to stop feeling sorry for himself or he'll never get better. Tee feels that everyone is treating him differently now that he is paralyzed and the respect he once commanded when he entered a room will never be regained. His insecurities are finally revealed when he becomes angry at Arecelli for flirtatiously waving at Miguel while dancing to the salsa he is playing. After a face to face confrontation with Miguel concerning the music and his girl, Tee is awakened again by the music and erupts with anger finally having enough. What he decides next could potentially affect which road to recovery he will take one that is dark, full of self pity and violence, or a path with a changed perspective on life. Will Tee fall back into his violent ways or will he take the steps necessary to get his life back together?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?464319</url></doc>
