<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="464621">
  <docid>464621</docid>
  <title>Rivaaj</title>
  <year>1972</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Prakash Rao, T.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bokadia, K.C.</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Pankal, Jaikishan Dayabhai</composer>
    <composer>Raghuwanshi, Shankarsinh</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jalal, Farida</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Sanjeev (I)</actor>
      <role>Shekhar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sinha, Shatrughan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Shekhar has fallen in love with the new priest's daughter, Lakshmi. Lakshmi's father divulges a secret...she was married and widowed as a teenager. Shekhar's mother objects to them getting married, and Lakshmi takes up the traditional role of a widow (white saris, no bangles, etc.) Shekhar instead marries Kamla, a woman of his mother's choice, and they have a daughter, Raji. Several years later, Kamla dies from cancer, while Raji is at a party. Unaware of her death, Raji gets a shock at her cremation (which she stumble upon by chance) when her father sets her on fire. Since then she becomes afraid of her father, thinking he'll burn her too. Even worse, she longs for a mother figure. Having gotten a quick spiel about reincarnation from her grandmother, Raji pictures her late mother in a rose. Lakshmi stumbles upon there by chance, and provides a voice, pretending to be her motehr. Will Shekhar find out about Lakshmi? Will the Grandmother? Will Raji believe Shekhar won't hurt her? Will Shekhar and Lakshmi get together? Watch the film and find out.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?464621</url></doc>
