<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="465079">
  <docid>465079</docid>
  <title>Road to the Big House</title>
  <year>1947</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bernie, Jason H.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>embezzlement</keyword>
    <keyword>prison</keyword>
    <keyword>gangster</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">13 December 1947</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">74</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Colmes, Walter</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Levinson, Selwyn</producer>
    <producer>Colmes, Walter</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Wisberg, Aubrey</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Allen, Joseph (I)</actor>
      <role>George Bates</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bailey, Richard (I)</actor>
      <role>Clyde Sutter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Boyle, Walden</actor>
      <role>Prosecutor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Conrad, Jack (I)</actor>
      <role>Collins</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Doran, Ann</actor>
      <role>Agnes Clark</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Doucette, John (I)</actor>
      <role>Danny</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fields, Eddie</actor>
      <role>Kelvin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jordan, Charles (I)</actor>
      <role>Benson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mallinson, Rory</actor>
      <role>Fred</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Richards, Keith (I)</actor>
      <role>Harvey</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shaw, C. Montague</actor>
      <role>Judge</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shelton, John (I)</actor>
      <role>Eddie Clark</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Simpson, Mickey</actor>
      <role>Case</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Williams, Guinn 'Big Boy'</actor>
      <role>Butch McQuinn</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In 1929, middle-class bank clerk Eddie Clark (John Sheldon), unhappy with his lot in life and jealous of prosperous George Bates (Joe Allen, Jr.),an ex-suitor of his loyal wife Agnes (Ann Doran), steals $200,000 from his bank, with intentions of he and Agnes being in Mexico before the theft is discovered. Agnes trys to persuade him to return the money to no avail. He is caught and sent to prison without revealing the hidden location of the loot, figuring to get it and live in luxury when his ten-year term is over. His case has received much publicity and nearly every inmate in the prison attempts to wrest the information from him. Gangsters on the outside arrange with convicts Clyde Sutter (Dick Bailey) and Butch McQuinn (Guinn Williams) to get the secret from him. Agnes, who has taken a waitress job in a nearby city, is also trying to find the money with the intention of returning it and getting Eddie a reduced sentence. Sutter's plan is to involve Eddie in a prison break and turn him over to the gangsters on the outside. Butch is shot during the break, and Eddie is the only one to escape. He meets Agnes in an old warehouse but she has been trailed by gangsters Kelvin (Eddy Fields) and Benson (Charles Jordan). They beat him up but his life is saved by the arrival of the state police. He is returned to prison with an additional five years added to his sentence. He is released in 1947 and makes his way to the money's hiding place - a cemetary plot he had bought in 1929.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?465079</url></doc>
