<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="465999">
  <docid>465999</docid>
  <title>Rock 'n Tokyo</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>di Fonzo, Erasmo</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>cult</keyword>
    <keyword>rock</keyword>
    <keyword>japan</keyword>
    <keyword>underground</keyword>
    <keyword>tokyo</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Japanese</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Japan">24 August 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="UK">10 November 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="France">24 January 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">9 February 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="France">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Valente, Pamela</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Valente, Pamela</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>5.6.7.8's, The</actor>
      <role>As themselves</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Boys, Jet</actor>
      <role>As themselves</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nine</actor>
      <role>As themselves</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wolf, Guitar</actor>
      <role>As themselves</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Tokyo proposes several different levels of reality. You can find anything you can imagine there and at the same time get a new surprise at every corner. I chose to portray this amazing city through rock 'n roll music. The Japanese love and understand rock, a kind of music and a way of life they discovered during the American occupation, after World War II. Even if Japanese society still preaches uniformity and order, there is an important underground world, where people live more freely. This is the Tokyo I show in my movie. We follow 4 rock bands : Guitar Wolf, 3 good looking guys wearing black leather and sunglasses, a singer/guitar player with a devilish presence, a garage rock that is among the most intense and loudest ever heard and surprisingly- a contract with a big record company ; The 5678s, rock-a-billy queens with a wild 50s elegance who conquered the world with a memorable scene in Quentin Tarantino's Kill Bill ; the Jet Boys, led by an extreme, crazy, border-less and exhibitionist singer/guitar player ; Nine, young guys who believe in success by music - when I first met them, they played in front of Shinjuku station as if it was the last concert of their lives. The movie shows their music, but also their way of living, their style-totally faithful to rock ,n roll- and their wanderings all around the incredible city that is Tokyo.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?465999</url></doc>
