<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="466074">
  <docid>466074</docid>
  <title>Rock Fresh</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Lee, Danny (VI)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>graffiti</keyword>
    <keyword>art</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Australia">M</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">5 November 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">81</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Lee, Danny (VI)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Lee, Danny (VI)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Lee, Danny (VI)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Okay, Cloak</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Axis</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Clae</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kofie</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Trixter</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tyer</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Official selection AFI FEST 2004. ROCK FRESH is an electrifying documentary on the world of the graffiti artist. A raw snapshot of artists who literally have their back against the wall, the film follows five of the world's most legendary street artists as they make the leap from graffiti art to commercial art. From the street to the gallery. From walls to clothing. From private to worldwide. Our cameras unmask the mystifying process behind graffiti art like never before. Revealing step-by-step how the colors blend, how the angles sharpen, how the shadows emerge. Lifting the veil from a subculture so clandestine, it took 40 years to get this close. The artists take their skills to a variety of surfaces -concrete, canvas, metal, cloth, and brick. And to an array of locations - city rooftops, the desert, downtown lofts, the sewers, even the forest. ROCK FRESH also reveals artists painfully coming of age. From kids drawing in their sketchbooks, to grown men struggling to make a living off of their art. Struggling between the codes of the underground and the lure of the mainstream. Journey through the buzzing underground art world - from live graffiti battles and gallery showcases, to underground parties and late night bombing sessions, Hollywood alleyways to Tokyo skyscrapers. Learn what it takes to ROCK FRESH.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?466074</url></doc>
