<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="466055">
  <docid>466055</docid>
  <title>Rock Bottom</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Baum, Jason (I)</editor>
    <editor>Svatek, Adam</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>neo-noir</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">22</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Baum, Jason (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Baum, Jason (I)</producer>
    <producer>Levine, Ross</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Baum, Jason (I)</writer>
    <writer>Reid, Elwood</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ceponis, Brian</actor>
      <role>Jack Lamarr</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grey, Reatha</actor>
      <role>Waitress</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hartson, Samantha</actor>
      <role>Shirley Thanos</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Howard, Beth (III)</actor>
      <role>Gladys Oates</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hulsey, Dava</actor>
      <role>Jill Olsten</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kramer, Casey (I)</actor>
      <role>Fran Darden</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>de la Diosa, Cristina</actor>
      <role>Tina</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>It's the not-too-distant, yet indefinable future. The world has undergone some catastrophic change that's knocked out satellites, governance and ideas of right &amp; wrong. JAKE VINCENZO and his partner realize they're onto something big and dangerous when they end up in Blake's illegal booze warehouse and gun factory. It's cold and dark and tension's high, they're nervous, strung like a two-dollar fiddle. When a man steps out of the shadows, our hero Jake shoots first, only to find out that he hasn't shot the notorious Blake, but Blake's twin brother, a priest. Hell's fury is unleashed upon them. Five henchmen shower them with bullets. A dramatic gunfight leaves all five dead and Jake's partner hit. Hit bad. Racked with guilt about the priest and fearful of Blake's revenge, Jake switches guns with his dying partner. He hopes Blake will never know it was him. But someone's watching it all and the guilt of framing his partner will be the real killer. The future is here and it's grim. Tonight Blake's put the word out. This is Blake's city and you keep your head down. The enigmatic ALEX sits in Rick's Bar unfazed by the fact that the streets are a time bomb ready to go off. Also ignoring the curfew, Jake Vincenzo strolls in after months of being on the lamb. These two have a lot in common; wry banter, close held secrets and furtive glances at each other. Gunfire rings out in the streets. Through the door plows two thugs, Tom and Tony, a racy dame named Nancy, and Billy, a reedy little gangster who's already been shot. Alex and Jake are caught in a crossfire protecting this bunch of cagey misfits who are as mysterious as our two heroes. As the night wears on and the dramatic shoot-out with the unseen assailants continues, Jake and Alex begin to fall for each other. And...they begin to suspect each other. The mystery is, who is after who and why? Seems no one's who they say they are and everyone's got a secret. Pretty soon, people start dying. First Tom makes a foolish escape attempt, only to die in the trying. And then...a car crashes through the wall of the bar bringing the war to close range and shattering their hideout with lead. Seems the driver/shooter knows some of the gang inside and he doesn't last long either. Later Billy slumps over dead in a huge pool of blood - more blood than his wounds should or could've made. The suspects and body count are growing.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?466055</url></doc>
