<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="466079">
  <docid>466079</docid>
  <title>Rock Hard</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kiely, Rob</editor>
    <editor>Snyder, Karen</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Australia">M</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Australia">13 April 2003</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">2 February 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Australia">3</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="USA">88</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Brooks, Ivy</director>
    <director>Kiely, Rob</director>
    <director>Kiely, Tzaddi</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Brooks, Ivy</producer>
    <producer>Dupont, Kyra</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chloe (I)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dior, Karen</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jeremy, Ron</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Midori (II)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>O'Boy, Marshall</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Toxic, Johnny</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>An outrageous roller coaster ride of sex, rock, and self-fulfillment, ROCK HARD gets up-close and personal with the stars of porn they foray into the music industry. San Fernando Valley. 8:30am: Jim Powers kicks back in a tiny office filled with WALL TO WALL videos. All porn. All produced by him. Eager talent is easy to find, as he recruits up to a dozen new girls each day. In the distinct lingo of the industry, they're paid per scene, per hole and per gender. Fast money. Nina Whett stands in a local liquor store for the fifth of Jack Daniels that enables her to face her day's work as an adult entertainer. Two hours of make-up, an enema, a douche and sex with a complete stranger. She'll probably leave with close to two grand in her pocket, but at what price to her psyche? She dreams of one day making it as a rock star but today she has to pay the bills. Can porn stars be rock stars? Ex-legendary porn star Madison slept with every rock star in the eighties and is now ready to explore life as a rocker herself. Her band tours the L.A. club scene, hitting up the usual suspects as she struggles to find legitimacy on the "other side." Success. Being a part of the mainstream media. Respect. This is what drives the stars of ROCK HARD to pursue their dreams of making music. Rock. Alternative. Punk. Soul. The music industry is a billion dollar industry yet it is financially dwarfed by the money-machine that is porn. From porn to rock; ROCK HARD is an unconventional and rare insight into the underground world of SEX, DRUGS and ROCK N' ROLL.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?466079</url></doc>
