<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="467125">
  <docid>467125</docid>
  <title>Rolling Stones: Under Review - 1967-1969</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>mick-jagger</keyword>
    <keyword>rock</keyword>
    <keyword>rolling-stones</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Australia">M</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">20 November 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Altham, Keith</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Christgau, Robert</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Clayton, Merry</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The Rolling Stones - Under Review 1967 - 1969 is a 90 minute documentary film reviewing the music and career of the band during, arguably, their most creative period. In the second half of the 1960s the sound of the Stones changed dramatically, while concurrently Jagger and Richards' songwriting hit an all time high. These advances didn't just affect The Rolling Stones forever, they changed Rock n' Roll forever too. This DVD includes rare musical performances (many never before available on DVD), and obscure footage, rare interviews and private photographs of and with the band. It also contains contributions from; 1960s NME editor and friend of the band, Keith Altham; Village Voice music editor, Robert Christgau; Stones backing vocalist, Merry Clayton; Stones session musician, Byron Berline; Rolling Stones biographer, Alan Clayson; Keith Richards biographer, Kris Needs; ex-Rolling Stone magazine editor Anthony De Curtis, Mojo magazine's Barney Hoskins, Uncut magazine's Nigel Williamson and many others. In addition, live and studio recordings of Stones classics have been added, as well as footage of and comment on many of their pivotal influences during this period.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?467125</url></doc>
