<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="467133">
  <docid>467133</docid>
  <title>Rolling Thunder</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Utke, Corey</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">8</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Henry, J. Gator</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Henry, J. Gator</producer>
    <producer>Labarowski, Todd J.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Coleman, Peter (III)</writer>
    <writer>Henry, J. Gator</writer>
    <writer>McCrea, Robert J.</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bludsworth, Tonya</actor>
      <role>Lynette Moore</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bovill, Kirk</actor>
      <role>Frank</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>James, Dylan (III)</actor>
      <role>Frankie Moore</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>As a man of faith, loving husband and father of two boys, Florida Department of Law Enforcement Detective John Russell's life seems to have come full circle, the epitome of the American Dream. As the FDLE'S best detective, he's been named to lead an investigation into the disappearance of Dylan Jacobs. Dylan was placed in foster care by the Florida Department of Family Services, and he's missing. Further investigation reveals that he may have been missing for as long as six years - and now the media is on to the story. John and his partners, Tim Porter and Roberta "Robbie" Sanchez, need to find answers - yesterday. While searching for a boy missing from state care, John's peaceful world is rocked by the arrival of a strange visitor, a man from his past. John suddenly finds himself face to face with the man who murdered his mother and stole his childhood. Nightmares buried for over 30 years come back to haunt him, and the spirit of rage that took his mother, now threatens to consume John, and tear him and his family into pieces. With John's past and present colliding, threatening the future of his family and everything he ever cared about, he must choose whether to give into the rage buried deep in his soul, or forgive, as he's been forgiven.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?467133</url></doc>
