<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="469800">
  <docid>469800</docid>
  <title>Rubber Rituals 1</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <editors>
    <editor>Miller, Pete (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <directors>
    <director>Liesegang, Tom</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>English, Steve</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Liesegang, Tom</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Hall, Simon (IV)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cor</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Esmee (II)</actor>
      <role>Woodchick #1 &amp; Gyno Girl #1</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Klaus (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Venture into the world of fetish. This collection of four short films explores realms inhabited by a wonderous collection of rubber clad afficionado's. "Woodchicks" voyeuristically follows the exploits of two female rubber clad lovers to a remote swarth of nature on a glorious wind swept summer day far from prying eyes. Be there yourself, peering through the reeds as these two voluptuous, hooded lovers walk through nature in heavy capes and raincoats, well protected in rubber boots and gasmasks to a remote spot where they make orgasmic rubber love. "Pissboy" is hard core clinical rubber action presided over by rubber nurse Mistress Nadia. Invasive therapy is the order of the day as she straps her patient to a gyno chair. A heavy leather neck brace is firmly buckled on to prevent any head movement with a drip feed-gag. A large enema is given and a catheter is inserted for the removal of urine which she then ruthlessly connects to his mouth feed. The patient is then physically "released". "Gyno Girls" is some of the hottest same-sex rubber play caught on film. Shot entirely with one hand held camera outside the presence of a film crew, Gyno Girls gets intimate, up close and very personal. Tight rubber hoods, protruding lips and restrictive goggles get these rubber nymphs in the mood to reach orgasmic rubber heights. The memorable end scene is not to be missed! "Dickhead" features "corrective pain" therapy by Rubber Nurse Nonna. Watch her strap the victim to a dentist chair and prepare a very large surgical needle. She then inserts a long stiffener into the penis and then proceeds to methodically sew his penis into a bloody stump! The muffled screams are real as the blood flows. Our poor victim will not be using it again for some time.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?469800</url></doc>
