<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="470047">
  <docid>470047</docid>
  <title>Rudranetra</title>
  <year>1989</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>based-on-novel</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Telugu</language>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">U</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">16 June 1989</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Raghavendra Rao, K.</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Yandamoori, Veerendranath</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Ilayaraja</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brahmanandam</actor>
      <role>Hero friend</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chiranjeevi (I)</actor>
      <role>Nethra/Yaadgiri/ISS Agent Trinethra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nutan Prasad</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Raghuvaran</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ranganath</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>When the Indian Secret Service find out that Sarva Bushan Rao, in collusion with international underworld don, Q, are using live human specimens to conduct experiments, they assign Agent Nethra to this case. Nethra is on the verge of apprehending both arch-criminals, but gets killed in the process. Indian authorities then re-assign this case to Agent Pratima, who accepts it, and sets about to seek the duo. She comes across a man named Yaadgiri, who resembles Nethra, she meets him, asks him to act like Amitabh Bachchan did in 'Don', to which he agrees. He gets training and proper etiquette and is shown the profile of the two gangsters. His first job is to woo and seduce Swarnalekha and Hanslekha, Rao's daughters. He starts with Swarnalekha, but she turns out to be Hanslekha. Before Yaadgiri could correct this error, Rao finds out and has Hanslekha killed. The question remains how can anyone combat a person who is ruthless enough to do away with his own daughter, and little do they know that Rao himself is merely a pawn in the hands of Kuala Lumpur-based underworld don, known only as Black Eagle - who is even more ruthless and cunning than Rao and Q put together - and is on the verge of launching a missile that is capable of killing thousands of people.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?470047</url></doc>
