<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="470044">
  <docid>470044</docid>
  <title>Rudraksh</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Shankar, Mani (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>doctor</keyword>
    <keyword>beautiful-woman</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="UK">12A</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">13 February 2004</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="UK">13 February 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Shankar, Mani (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Maklai, Sohail</producer>
    <producer>Manmohan, Nitin</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Shankar, Mani (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Mahadevan, Shankar</composer>
    <composer>Mendonsa, Loy</composer>
    <composer>Noorani, Ehsaan</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bachchan, Amitabh</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Basu, Bipasha</actor>
      <role>Dr. Gayetri</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bedi, Kabir</actor>
      <role>Ved Pujan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Darenius, Agnes</actor>
      <role>Suzy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dutt, Sanjay</actor>
      <role>Varun</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Negar</actor>
      <role>Dancer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Koppikar, Isha</actor>
      <role>Lali</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Saxena, Veerendra</actor>
      <role>Watchman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shetty, Sunil (I)</actor>
      <role>Bhuria</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zutshi, Rajendranath</actor>
      <role>Man in mental institute</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Healing powers that science cannot explain and voodoo practices that defy all logic are just some of the instances of paranormal activity that Dr. Gayatri [Bipasha Basu] is busy investigating. Her experiments bring her with her team of fellow scientists from America to India where they encounter the gifted Varun [Sanjay Dutt].Varun has inexplicable paranormal powers, yet is highly disciplined and evolved. His unusual ability of taking away pain and affliction from his subjects fascinates Gayatri and he becomes a willing subject of her cause. Gayatri's unusual experiments suddenly hurtle Varun towards guessing the existence of a dark power that is hidden and evil. What is the force all about? And why does it wage a battle against Varun? And how is it linked to Ravan's Rudrakash? Hidden away, vanished in the hoary mists of time is the most unusual Rudraksh. Legend has it that it carried in its folds seed sounds that promised to mutate humans into a new species. This was not a normal Rudraksh worn by ordinary people. In the language of science, it was a multi-dimensional hologram in the form of a seed. It beheld the power to mutate its bearer into a power beyond all reckoning.Though he first tries to evade the forces that beckon him, Varun is drawn deeper and deeper into a pact of peril. He is soon hurtled into a heady adventure and chase that takes him to the Himalayas and then into the mysterious ruins of the legendary King Ravan's palaces in Lanka. Varun digs deep to discover the secret of Rudraksh. And suddenly everything starts making sense.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?470044</url></doc>
