<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="471292">
  <docid>471292</docid>
  <title>Rustom-E-Baghdad</title>
  <year>1963</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Shetye, Dinkar</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">1963</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Patel, B.J.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Mirchandani, Kirpal</producer>
    <producer>Talway, Bany</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Dutta, N.</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhagwan, Master</actor>
      <role>Sultan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhopali, Shakeela Bano</actor>
      <role>Najma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chandrashekhar</actor>
      <role>Shehzada Salim</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Choudhury, Vijaya</actor>
      <role>Nasreen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Rajan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumali, Prince</actor>
      <role>Habaloh (Wrestler)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Polson</actor>
      <role>Badru</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Singh, Dara (I)</actor>
      <role>Dara/Rustom-E-Baghdad</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Circa the Mughal rule in the Persian Gulf in Baghdad, the Badshah is killed by his very own brother, his wife put to death, and their new-born child is to be captured and killed by none other than his uncle. But Rustom-E-Baghdad, who has sworn to protect the Badshah and his family, abducts the child, and flees from the kingdom with the new Badshah's soldiers hot on his trail. Mortally wounded on his death-bed, the Rustom asks his son, Dara, to take care of the young prince and ensure that he comes to no harm. Dara promises and watches sadly as his father passes away. Now it is Dara's turn to be on the run along with the young prince in his arms. The Badshah announces a hefty reward of 5000 ashrafis to the one who brings in Dara and the young prince dead or alive. The question remains, how long will Dara continue to elude the Badshah, his soldiers, as well as greedy bounty hunters, who will not rest until they have Dara and the young prince killed, and their lifeless bodies brought before the Badshah.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?471292</url></doc>
