<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="472806">
  <docid>472806</docid>
  <title>Saaz</title>
  <year>1997</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Musical</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">29</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Paranjape, Sai</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Khanna, Amit (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Deo, Yashwant</composer>
    <composer>Hazarika, Bhupen</composer>
    <composer>Hussain, Zakir (I)</composer>
    <composer>Kamal, Raj (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Azmi, Shabana</actor>
      <role>Bansidhar (Bansi) Vrundavan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dharker, Ayesha</actor>
      <role>Kuhu Vrundavan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hussain, Zakir (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Irani, Aruna</actor>
      <role>Mansi Vrundavan (Maan Didi)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sahni, Parikshat</actor>
      <role>Dr. Ranjit Samant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Yadav, Raghuvir</actor>
      <role>Vrundavan</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Mansi and Bansi come to Mumbai after the death of their parents. All they have as a legacy is a love for music instilled in them by their father Vrindavan, and their divine voices. After their initial struggle, Mansi finds her way into the film industry with music director Indraneel as her mentor. Mansi keeps Bansi's talent under wraps and gets her married to an unsuitable man. Her argument is that both should cherish their father's memory - Bansi by bearing children to carry on the family name and Mansi by keeping his music alive. When Indraneel picks Bansi as his new protégé, Mansi breaks off with him. The sisters become bitter rivals. After her divorce, Bansi fights to keep her place in the sun against crippling odds. A dynamic young music director Himen Desai, is obsessed with Bansi and she finally succumbs to his charm and persuasion. The film tells the story of a brave woman's battle to come to terms with her life, she does not give up even when she loses her voice. A renowned psychiatrist Dr Samarth comes into her life. Does she find fulfillment this time? Does she find her voice?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?472806</url></doc>
