<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="472812">
  <docid>472812</docid>
  <title>Sab Golmaal Hai</title>
  <year>1997</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <editors>
    <editor>D'Souza, Sheldon</editor>
  </editors>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Chitraarth</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Khanna, Amit (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Kalsi, Sukhwant</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Berry, Pankaj</actor>
      <role>Satpal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gupta, Neena</actor>
      <role>Shanta</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pahwa, Manoj</actor>
      <role>Balwant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vachani, Ajit</actor>
      <role>Gillu</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Sab Golmaal Hai is a situational comedy that revolves around Gillu, a simple small town man and his family. The characters are quaint and unique and yet represent attributes present in all of us. Witty lines and slice-of life humour make this sitcom very appealing. The comedy revolves around Gillu, a lovable, naïve but exasperating character - a man plagued by suspicion all his life. He is suspicious of everyone and everything. The simplest of actions and the most innocent gestures are questioned by him. The doubts include his wife having an affair with his closest friend, about his son's affection for him, his in-law's behaviour etc. Situations and events of everyday life are reason enough for Gillu to be suspicious of people and their motives. Gillu's wife, Shanta is the typical Indian housewife, devoted to her husband. Very often, she is amused and tolerant of her husband's idiosyncrasies. Unfortunately, she is also frequently the victim of his irrational suspicions. Gillu's friend and neighbour, Satpal, is a very colourful character. Boisterous, charming and intensely lazy, Satpal keeps busy enjoying life and narrating jokes to people. Satpal's wife, Vimla, dotes on him, however, at times hates him for his inactivity. Vimla is a capable, working woman who supports Satpal most of the time. In addition to these quirky and unique people, is Gillu's friend who is a psychiatrist. This friend is brought in by Shanta to help cure her husband, but, in fact, the friend manages to exacerbate the situation every time. For he too is afflicted with the same problem.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?472812</url></doc>
