<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="473891">
  <docid>473891</docid>
  <title>Sahra</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>tv-mini-series</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Turkish</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Turkey">6 October 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Kocatürk, Volkan</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Öyken, Asli</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Devres, Nuran</writer>
    <writer>Yüce, Oya</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Evgin, Murat</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arasil, Aylin</actor>
      <role>Pelin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arsever, Tugrul</actor>
      <role>Engin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Berberoglu, Günes</actor>
      <role>Melek</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Demirer, Ruken</actor>
      <role>Feyza</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Garibagaoglu, Murat</actor>
      <role>Yemin Tezer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kiper, Mazlum</actor>
      <role>Ilhan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Oya, Berkun</actor>
      <role>Hüseyin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Savasçi, Ali</actor>
      <role>Hüseyin-2</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Senozan, Okan</actor>
      <role>Sinan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sergen, Semih</actor>
      <role>Fahri</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sözmen, Bogaçhan</actor>
      <role>Metin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Taylan, Ahmet Mumtaz</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tutumluer, Serhat</actor>
      <role>Mithat Demircan</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Fahri was one of the richest and respected man in the country. He got married to Kerime. Her 5 year old girl spoiled in this glory until Sahra's birth, then Nil envied her so much and after their mother death, Nil's jealousy turned into hate.Years have passed and Nil couldn't manage to get a job in her step-father's company. She got married to Cemal, who was working in the same company. When Sahra turned back to the company after completing her education. Cemal admired Sahra so much. With the jealousy and hate, after an argument, Nil killed her husband and sentenced. Sahra falls in love with this charismatic man, Sinan and they get married. Nil loses everyhing in the jail while Sahra gains everything. After their marriage, Fahri is dead and with the born of Sahra's child, Nil is acquitted and have a chance to turn back to home. And starts to apply her plans to take a revenge. She manages to seperate Sahra and Sinan. After Sahra leaves her home and goes to Morocco, Sinan follows her to be reconciled. Nil makes her friend from the jail, Melek kill Sahra in Morocco. Melek plans a terrible accident and tries to kill Sahra. Everybody believes her death but actually she is injured seriously. A doctor called Hossein cures her. After a couple of succesful surgical operations, Sahra becomes totally a different woman and turns back to Turkey. Now it's time for her revenge</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?473891</url></doc>
