<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="474444">
  <docid>474444</docid>
  <title>Sal Mosca: Un-Sung</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Lester, James (III)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>interview</keyword>
    <keyword>jazz</keyword>
    <keyword>dark</keyword>
    <keyword>live-music</keyword>
    <keyword>pianist</keyword>
    <keyword>performance</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">7 June 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">11</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Lester, James (III)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Mundy, Lisa M.</producer>
    <producer>Lester, James (III)</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arthurs, Bob</actor>
      <role>Himself - Trumpet</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chattin, Bill</actor>
      <role>Himself - Drums</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Halperin, Jimmy</actor>
      <role>Himself - Saxophone</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Messina, Don</actor>
      <role>Himself - Bass</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mosca, Sal</actor>
      <role>Himself - Interviewee</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>If a piano plays in a room and no one hears it, did it really make music? Legendary jazz pianist, Sal Mosca would say it did. In this intimate look into a master's life, we are presented the portrait of a man who chose to sacrifice fame and glory for the purity of his art. In doing so, Mosca lived a hermetic life in a dark studio where musical magic was made daily. Mosca, who studied with piano guru, Lennie Tristano, played and recorded with greats such as Lee Konitz, Warne Marsh, Miles Davis, Charlie Parker, Max Roach, and Sarah Vaughn. But after the 1950's he chose a sedentary life in which his art would never be compromised, settling to teach his craft while wowing audiences when he would emerge for infrequent performances. This is the first and only film of Mosca. Even at age eighty, Mosca's fingers glide effortlessly over the keys, displaying a freedom in music which is rare. Unfettered by big record labels, he achieved an unbridled method of jazz improvisation. His ambition to "get into himself" rather than go after capitalistic gains is startlingly bold in an era where dollars seem the main measure of success.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?474444</url></doc>
