<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="475333">
  <docid>475333</docid>
  <title>Samantha</title>
  <year>1998</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Venezuela</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <writers>
    <writer>Nouel, Vivel</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Alvarado, Daniel (II)</actor>
      <role>Arcadio 'Maute' Guanipa</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Aravena, Jorge</actor>
      <role>Rodolfo Villalobos</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arreaza, Carlos</actor>
      <role>Samuel Casanova</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arteaga, Nohely</actor>
      <role>Raiza Rincón Luzardo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Balza, Haydée</actor>
      <role>Lavinia Luzardo de Rincón</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barboza, Janín</actor>
      <role>Cristina</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bascope, Daniela</actor>
      <role>Anabela</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Blanco, Eva</actor>
      <role>Alba Luján de Aranguren</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Capote, Julio</actor>
      <role>Rosendo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carbillo, Martha</actor>
      <role>Alexandrina</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Castro, Katerine</actor>
      <role>Rina</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ferrari, Francisco</actor>
      <role>Dr. Arturo Hidalgo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gaviria, Aitor</actor>
      <role>Pascual Martínez</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gil, Elaiza</actor>
      <role>Chicharra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>González, Mauricio (II)</actor>
      <role>Padre Lino</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Groppuso, Carolina</actor>
      <role>Yusmeri</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Henríquez, Olga</actor>
      <role>Vestalia Luzardo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hoffman, Karl (I)</actor>
      <role>Ramón Demetrio Calzadilla</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lantigua, Martín</actor>
      <role>Lorenzo del Llano</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Machado, Alicia</actor>
      <role>Samantha del Llano</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Machuca, Antonio</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Martínez, Alejandro (III)</actor>
      <role>Luis Alberto Aranguren Luján</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Martínez, Ana (IV)</actor>
      <role>Querubina</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Massimo, Ana</actor>
      <role>Laura del Llano</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Montenegro, Jonathan</actor>
      <role>Alexánder Hernández</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Morales, Elizabeth</actor>
      <role>Elena de Aranguren</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Omaña, Carlos</actor>
      <role>Pantoja</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rentería, Mauricio</actor>
      <role>Tirzo Guevara</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rodríguez, Gustavo (I)</actor>
      <role>Don Valdemar Rincón</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tepedino, Vicente</actor>
      <role>Salvador Hidalgo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zapata, Johnny</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zuleta, José Luis</actor>
      <role>Jorge</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Love literally falls from the sky for Samantha del Llano, a beautiful and free-spirited young peasant, who lives and works at landowner Valdemar Rincon's lavish hacienda. One day, while wandering around the far reaches of the ranch in search of her horse, Samantha sees a small private plane crash nearby, and she immediately runs to the scene of the accident. Inside the plane, she finds Luis Alberto Aranguren, badly hurt but semi-conscious. Although she does not realize it yet, this handsome millionaire from the city will be her one true love. Because the impact from the crash has caused Luis Alberto to lose his memory, he is unable to tell Samantha and the Rincon family his real identity. They believe him to be merely the pilot, an employee of the powerful Aranguren Corporation instead of its owner. Samantha does not really care who he is - she is a sweet, unpretentious country girl with few ambitions - and her main concern is nursing this stranger back to health. During the following weeks, a magical romance develops between Samantha and Luis Alberto, two persons who know practically nothing about each other, but are simply following their hearts. However, once Luis Alberto is taken back to the capital, he recovers his memory and unconsciously blacks out everything that happened after the accident, including the loving Samantha. He returns home to discover that his wife, gravely ill for five years, has died. Everyone thinks she succumbed to her illness, but in reality Betzaida, who is secretly in love with Luis Alberto and is now determined to conquer him, murdered her. Another woman will try to do the same: Raiza, Valdemar Rincon's daughter, a spoiled and selfish college student who set her sights on Luis Alberto after discovering his wealth and social position. One day, while on a date with Raiza, Luis Alberto suddenly remembers Samantha, her soft touch, her radiant smile, her overpowering sweetness. Realizing what he left behind, he goes back to find her. They marry immediately, in a quiet village ceremony. Upon their return to the city, Samantha must face three formidable enemies: Betzaida, Raiza and Luis Alberto's teenage daughter, Anabela, who feels betrayed by her father's wedding, so soon after her mother's death.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?475333</url></doc>
