<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="475829">
  <docid>475829</docid>
  <title>Samuel the Boy Prophet</title>
  <year>1993</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Koford, James</editor>
    <editor>Paton, Randy</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>bible</keyword>
    <keyword>cartoon</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>old-testament</keyword>
    <keyword>kids-and-family</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 June 1993</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Rich, Richard</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Noss, Terry L.</producer>
    <producer>Griffin, Stephen W.</producer>
    <producer>Brown, Jared F.</producer>
    <producer>Rich, Richard</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Nissen, Brian (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>de Azevedo, Lex</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arrington, James</actor>
      <role>Eli</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Basco, Cindy</actor>
      <role>Woman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hale, Ruth (II)</actor>
      <role>Old Hannah</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jackson, Pat (VII)</actor>
      <role>Young Hannah</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Keeler, Daniel A.</actor>
      <role>The Lord</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lynch, Joe (VIII)</actor>
      <role>Old Man</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Porter, Ray (I)</actor>
      <role>Phineas</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Richards, Wayne (IV)</actor>
      <role>Prophet</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Toppo, Johnathon</actor>
      <role>Samuel</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Eli, the high priest of Israel, knowingly disobeys the Lord, and he and his sons are punished. Hannah fulfills her promise to God, and gives up her son to His service. In return, God blesses Hannah by making her son, Samuel, the chosen Prophet of the people of Israel. At the tabernacle of Ark of the Covenant, Hannah prays for a son. She promises God that she will offer the boy up to His service. Eli, the high priest, overhears her prayer and sends her off with vague promises. Eli's sons abuse their position and steal from those who come to offer sacrifice. One night, a man of God appeared to Eli. He informs him that because Eli has allowed his sons to make a mockery of holy things," condemnation is upon this house. I shall raise up a faithful priest. He shall reign over Israel." In answer to her prayers, Hannah has a son, whom she names Samuel. She brings her young son to the tabernacle. She tells Eli that his promise has been fulfilled, and so she will fulfill her vow, giving up Samuel to the servant of God. Hannah promises to visit once each year and Samuel tells his mother that he will serve God all the days of his life. At night, Samuel hears a voice calling t o him. He thinks it is Eli, but the high priest, a good man for all his faults, knows that it is God calling to Samuel. Eli tells him that if he hears the voice again, to say, " Speak Lord, thy servant hears you." God tells Samuel that He has warned Eli and his sons to purify themselves. God says, " A day of judgment will come against them." Word comes that Eli's sons have been defeated and killed, and the Philistines have taken the Ark. In shock, Eli falls to his death. Elijah's prophecy has come to pass, and the young Samuel is now the high priest and the true prophet of Israel. Great blessings are on him and his faithful mother, Hannah.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?475829</url></doc>
