<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="476231">
  <docid>476231</docid>
  <title>Sanam Bewafa</title>
  <year>1991</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Razdan, Jawahar</editor>
  </editors>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">11 January 1991</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Tak, Saawan Kumar</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Tak, Saawan Kumar</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bhalla, Bharat B.</writer>
    <writer>Khan, Anwar (I)</writer>
    <writer>Tak, Saawan Kumar</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Sharma, Kishore (II)</composer>
    <composer>Sharma, Mahesh (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Alok, Master</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bakshi, Rashim</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chandni (I)</actor>
      <role>Ruksar Khan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Denzongpa, Danny</actor>
      <role>Sher Khan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dhanoa, Dan</actor>
      <role>Shaukat Khan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dheer, Pankaj</actor>
      <role>Zuber Khan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ghatge, Vijayendra</actor>
      <role>Sajjan Thakur</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Issar, Puneet</actor>
      <role>Afzal Khan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jagdeep</actor>
      <role>Daroga</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jugnu (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kanchan (I)</actor>
      <role>Kanchan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Salman (I)</actor>
      <role>Salman Khan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Tahira</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mahajan, Chander</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pran (I)</actor>
      <role>Fateh Khan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Singh, Gurbachchan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Traditional rivals arise between two Pathan families who were at daggers drawn for many generations. Brought up with immense love and affection Rukhsar, a beautiful damsel is Fatehkhan's daughter. Rukhsar with a dear friend Kanchan and other friends go to a hill for an outing. As the luck would have it, Rukhsar gets attracted to Salman, the rider is Sherkhan's son. Sherkhan.....the eternal enemy of Fatehkhan. Love blossomed admist all adversities. On knowing the truth, Fatehkhan finds his wrath too much to control. On the other hand, Sherkhan is extremely happy to know that his son is in love with his worst enemy's daughter and promises Salman that he will get him married to Rukhsar. The marriage is settled after great difficulties. On the marriage occasion Fatehkhan places an incredible demand in Haque-Meher. Sherkhan is dumbfounded and shocked but gives in for his sons happiness. Hurt by the insult, Sherkhan retaliates by throwing Rukhsar out of the house next morning after paying the agreed Haque-Meher. On seeing Rukhsar back, her people are numbed with shock. Fatehkhan goes to Sherkhan's house but he refuses to relent unless Fateh khan begs for his pardon before the whole community. Not to be intimidated, Fatehkhan challenges Sherkhan that a day would come when he would come begging him for Rukhsar and only then he would send her. The two innocent continued to suffer at the hands of their fathers but Sherkhan and Fatehkhan remained adament. Blood flowed killings continued.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?476231</url></doc>
