<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="476796">
  <docid>476796</docid>
  <title>Sanjh Aur Savera</title>
  <year>1964</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Dhaimade, Das</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Mukherjee, Hrishikesh</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Shah, Sevantilal</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Chatterjee, Dhruva</writer>
    <writer>Ghosh, Anil (II)</writer>
    <writer>Kanwal, Jagdish</writer>
    <writer>Mukherjee, D.N.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Pankal, Jaikishan Dayabhai</composer>
    <composer>Raghuwanshi, Shankarsinh</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bala, Preeti</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhardwaj, Brahm</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chattopadhyay, Harindranath</actor>
      <role>Mama, Radha's uncle</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dutt, Guru</actor>
      <role>Dr. Shankar Chaudhry</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jagdev</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Rashid (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khote, Shubha</actor>
      <role>Radha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Krishna, Manmohan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumari, Meena (I)</actor>
      <role>Gauri</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mehmood (I)</actor>
      <role>Prakash</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Roy, Kanu</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Dr. Shankar Chaudhry lives a wealthy lifestyle in Bombay with his widowed mom, Rukmini, and younger sister, Manju. His mom would like him to get married to Ambala-based Advocate Madhusudan's daughter, Maya, even though neither of them have seen her. Shankar does agree to this marriage; the marriage takes place, the bride faints after the formalities; she is looked after by her cousin, Prakash, and Madhusudan; she recovers, and the next day she accompanies Shankar to his home. On the very first night she informs him that since she is undergoing a Holy Fast, she must refrain from any sexual activity. A few days later, Prakash arrives to take her to Banaras where her dad has re-located. Shankar accompanies them and get re-married to her at Bhagwan Vishwanath's Temple. Thereafter, both get intimate and soon Maya becomes pregnant. One day Shankar comes home to find both Prakash and Maya missing. He searches for them, but is unable to locate them. It is then he finds out that the woman claiming to be his wife is not the daughter of Madhusudan, and may well have eloped with Prakash - who is not her brother. Watch as events unfold and the impact this discovery has on Shankar and the rest of his family.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?476796</url></doc>
