<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="478841">
  <docid>478841</docid>
  <title>Sautela Bhai</title>
  <year>1996</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">1996</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Ishara, B.R.</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Burman, Rahul Dev</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Babbar, Raj</actor>
      <role>Advocate Rajaram</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bundela, Raja</actor>
      <role>Gopal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gaurav, Kumar</actor>
      <role>Shankar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hangal, A.K.</actor>
      <role>Bindiya's maternal grandfather</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Satyendra</actor>
      <role>Advocate Surendranath</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Amjad (I)</actor>
      <role>Thakur Narayandas</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khanna, Rajesh</actor>
      <role>Master Tulsiram</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Qazir, Deepak</actor>
      <role>Harkishan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ranjeet</actor>
      <role>Rehman</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Tulsiram teaches village children how to read and write. He is married to Saraswati and has an step-brother, Advocate Rajaram, who practices in Bombay, as well as an uneducated younger step-brother named Shankar. When Rajaram returns, Tulsiram wants him to get married to Bindiya, the daughter of Thakur Narayandas. But Rajaram has already married Sheena, who is the only daughter of wealthy Advocate Surendranath. When Tulsiram finds this out, he is upset with Rajaram, but subsequently relents and agrees to get Shankar married to Bindiya. This angers Thakur Narayandas, who does not want his daughter to get married to an uneducated man like Shankar and he decides to give Tulsiram an ultimatum - to either get Rajaram to change his mind and marry his daughter - or he will forcibly take over their land and house, which have been mortgaged with him to pay for Rajaram's education. Then, Tulsiram gets arrested on charges of Fraud, Theft and Cheating and is held in a cell. When Shankar attempts to get help, the police arrest him for kidnapping Bindiya and holding her hostage. Rajaram returns home to defend his brothers and finds out that the Public Prosecutor is none other than his very own father-in-law. The question remains, will a step-brother help other step-brothers overcome their problems and end up complicating his life?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?478841</url></doc>
