<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="479150">
  <docid>479150</docid>
  <title>Saving Face</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kendall, Mark (III)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">12</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Kendall, Mark (III)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kendall, Mark (III)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Kendall, Mark (III)</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>This experimental film follows three dogs on their hospital beds, which are the subjects of medical experimentation and brought back to life by means of mechanical manipulation. Each of the dogs' journeys from death to life is partnered with an appropriate song in the soundtrack. The combination of the three songs and three dogs provides the structure for the music video trilogy. Reincarnation, literally "to be made flesh again", is a belief that some essential part of a living being survives death to be reborn in a new body. This essential part is often referred to as the spirit or soul, the "higher" or "true" self, or the "divine spark." According to such beliefs, a new personality is developed during each life in the physical world, but some part of the self remains constant throughout the successive lives. Belief in reincarnation has ancient roots, but during recent decades a significant minority of people in the West have developed a belief in reincarnation. But, in an age filled with tools and machines, what causes a heart to reestablish its appropriate rhythm? During this film, the soundtrack makes the viewer question whether it is, in fact, the machines used by the doctors on the screen or if it is the beckoning, soulful vocals in the soundtrack that calls and brings the souls of the three dogs back to life.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?479150</url></doc>
