<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="479956">
  <docid>479956</docid>
  <title>Scene Not Heard</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Holmes, Maori Karmael</editor>
    <editor>Rozier, Christian</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>philadelphia</keyword>
    <keyword>women</keyword>
    <keyword>b-girl</keyword>
    <keyword>hip-hop</keyword>
    <keyword>feminism</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="South Africa">16 June 2006</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="UK">8 September 2006</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">14 June 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">45</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Holmes, Maori Karmael</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Robinson, Araeia</producer>
    <producer>May, Deirdre</producer>
    <producer>Holmes, Maori Karmael</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Peterson, James Statik</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>B, Lady</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bahamadia</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jade, Ms.</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lester, Sheena</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Love, Monie (I)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Martínez, Mercedes (I)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moore, Tracey (V)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Schooly-D</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Philadelphia is often referred to as the mecca for American soul music, however its contributions to hip-hop have been overlooked despite its mass proliferation of artists, many of whom have made landmark contributions as emcees, graffiti artists, dancers, and most notably as deejays. Native talents such as Will Smith, The Roots, and Eve have become international pop stars and made great strides domestically and internationally, but somehow "the Illadelph" still doesn't get the kind of props of a city like Los Angeles or even Atlanta. Despite all of this, the City of Brotherly Love has continued to churn out some of the most innovative hip-hop artists of the current generation. Perhaps one of the most unique aspects to the scene is the abundance of powerful female voices that it has produced as artists, promoters and writers. In this debut featurette, director and producer Maori Karmael Holmes seeks to tell the story of these women-the legends, the famed, and the ingénues-as they struggle to succeed in a male-dominated industry in a city that has been left behind in the national consciousness. Scene Not Heard features interviews with some of the originators of hip-hop such as Lady B, Schoolly D, Monie Love and Rennie Harris, with vanguards chiming in including Bahamadia and Ursula Rucker, and presents current talents such as the Jazzyfatnastees, Ms. Jade, and Lady Alma, and emerging talents such as Versus, Keen of Subliminal Orphans and Michele Byrd-McPhee of Montäzh, as well as scholars, critics and local promoters.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?479956</url></doc>
