<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="480045">
  <docid>480045</docid>
  <title>Scenes from a Parking Lot</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Carss, Mike</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">1 October 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">3</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="default">50</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Pappas, Alexander</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Gladstone, Judy</producer>
    <producer>Pappas, Alexander</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Pappas, Alexander</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Khurana, Rob</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>True love can happen in unexpected places, even in an old abandoned parking lot. At least that's what Radik thinks. Radik, a softhearted day dreaming flower, is a world-class ballet dancer. Only problem is, nobody else knows that. His whole life, his persistently shy mannerisms have made him an outsider in most of the cities floral social circles. What's more, Radik shares his parking lot home with Anya, a beautiful and well-manicured purple tipped tulip and coincidently the love of Radiks life. Though Radik has made several attempts to court the alluring Anya, he's found himself alone year after year. Only able to gaze at her from afar. In an act of sheer impulse, Radik has mustered up the courage and devised a plan impress the blossoming beauty. He's going to ask her to dance. But his well-meaning actions may lead Radik in over his head. Then what will he do? With a combination of cutting edge high definition animation and untraditional storytelling, Scenes from a Parking lot is a film you'll want to keep next to your heart. Beautiful, inspiring and poignant, Scenes from a Parking lot is a true testimony to what courage, determination and a little bit of flower power can do.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?480045</url></doc>
