<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="480765">
  <docid>480765</docid>
  <title>School Dayze</title>
  <year>1987</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adult</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>sex</keyword>
    <keyword>bondage</keyword>
    <keyword>hardcore</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Annie, Little Oral</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Benji (IV)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Majors, Bill</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Little Oral Annie, BONDAGE, Tiffany Jordan, DISCIPLINE, Viper! Do these words and names mean anything to you They should! Once again B&amp;D Pleasures brings you more than you bargained for. While making "Class of '86," we found that we had more material than we could use and that there were stories that had to be told. Viper with Bill Marigold (playing Teddy the retarded school gardener) has been left in the sun in tight bondage as punishment for having not done all of her work. Being totally wanton she tries to convince Teddy to untie her and when that fails she urges him to punish her. Be prepared to witness the harsh use of a riding crop with real marks and lots of passion on the part of Viper. Viper finally convinces Teddy to untie her and turns the tables on Teddy. She binds him and uses him for her own pleasure. But not for long! Bill comes along and finds the two of them and is he ever mad. Viper is ordered to think up her own punishment and have Teddy do it to her. At the end she convinces him to free her and walks off. While this has been going on Debbie is confused about why she is in training in her own school. In a flashback we see her as a teacher training Little Oral Annie. This sequence features a really blistering spanking as well as physical discipline of the student. Of course having been Bill's slave, Debbie makes sure that nipple clamps are used on Annie's ample breasts and a spanking bench makes its appearance in the gym. Tiffany Jordan is trained by her boyfriend with several different bondage positions including an unusual adhesive tape scene, saw horse bondage and spanking! Of course at the end of the film we are treated to the fascinating graduation scene along with an interesting surprise from Teddy.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?480765</url></doc>
