<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="481731">
  <docid>481731</docid>
  <title>Scott VanPala: Heavy Metal</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>VanPala, Scott</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>automotive-technology</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">13 November 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">106</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>VanPala, Scott</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>VanPala, Scott</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>VanPala, Scott</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Instantly up to speed and powered by that rarest of cinematic fuels -- intelligent action - "Scott VanPala - HEAVY METAL" is a manly, irreverent, automotive satire for all ages. VanPala is back with his second inflammatory DVD to take us on a hunt for the best and worst SUVs by piloting 16 different ones much too quickly up mountains, over rocks, and into lakes. With a creative flair and without ever being pedantic, VanPala wades through all the media and marketing hype to show us that it is just that, hype. Who knew that over 80% of all SUVs are just pickup trucks with camper bodies welded on? Even the biggest names in the business, Lexus, Cadillac, Infiniti, and Mercedes-Benz are not immune from delivering us the charlatans, the dross, and the quacks. Then we get to the real, honest-to-god, garbage. The real disasters, the SUVs that sell in there millions solely based on preconceptions and image. Here is where VanPala takes a hard and all too often violent look at these abominations. Most are mocked, some are chastised, but a select few are less lucky as a death sentence is handed down in some of the most creative ways to destroy a car you have ever seen. Finally, we get to the real purpose of SUVs. Voicing the cries of enthusiastic motorists who are tired of the constant social attacks on 4x4s and who just want to drive their gas-guzzlers fast and free and with Rush Limbaugh on the radio, VanPala takes us on a high speed, no-holds barred, freedom ride through 11 states in the best SUV in the entire world, ever!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?481731</url></doc>
