<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="481887">
  <docid>481887</docid>
  <title>Scratched</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Australia">85</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Bain, Travis</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arakelian, Francesca</actor>
      <role>Mother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dean, Emma (I)</actor>
      <role>Tamsin Burnett</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Finden, Mark</actor>
      <role>Patrick</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>O'Donnell, Steven (III)</actor>
      <role>Donald</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Seager, Andre</actor>
      <role>Lorenzo</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Townsville. Tropical North Queensland. Australia. Present day. University student Patrick has just won a million dollars on a "scratchie" ticket given to him for his birthday. The problem is, it's Saturday, and he can't collect his winning cheque until Monday, so he decides to hide it somewhere inside the house he shares with five other university students: anal retentive "house mother" Jones, obnoxious security guard Lorenzo, laid-back surfer Blake, computer nerd Donald, and meek nursing student Tamsin. Patrick goes out on the town to celebrate his big win, but he drinks far too much alcohol and inadvertently insults a violent thug. Patrick cops a severe thrashing which lands him in Townsville General Hospital in a vegetative state. Back at the share house, Patrick's five housemates discuss Patrick's predicament and his hidden million-dollar scratchie. Figuring that Patrick probably won't live long enough to enjoy the spoils of his newfound fortune, the housemates decide to find his hidden ticket and split the prize five ways. And so it begins, as the five disparate students spend one insane summer night tearing their share house apart in search of instant wealth. But there's no such thing as easy money. A ferocious tropical cyclone-"Julie"-is brewing off the coast, growing in intensity, moving relentlessly closer to Townsville, threatening to wipe out everything in its path. As the night wears on and the cyclone draws nearer, the housemates doggedly continue their treasure hunt in the face of increasing danger-from Cyclone Julie and from each other.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?481887</url></doc>
