<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="481933">
  <docid>481933</docid>
  <title>Scream at the Sound of the Beep</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Giannelli, Rick</editor>
  </editors>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Fontanes, Lori</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Rosenburgh, Andrew</producer>
    <producer>Fontanes, Lori</producer>
    <producer>Rivard, Jesse H.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Fontanes, Lori</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Biribin Jr., Renato</actor>
      <role>Detective</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Boecher, Katherine</actor>
      <role>Amber</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Borden, Rainbow</actor>
      <role>Stu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bridges, Todd</actor>
      <role>Lamar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Buckley, A.J. (I)</actor>
      <role>Peter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dungey, Merrin</actor>
      <role>Jill</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jonathan, Wesley</actor>
      <role>Arsenio</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mello, Tamara</actor>
      <role>Tori</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Powell, Esteban</actor>
      <role>Josh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stashwick, Todd</actor>
      <role>Romero</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Strouse, Gregg</actor>
      <role>Homeless Guy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Todhunter, Chad</actor>
      <role>Jesse James</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wise, Ray (I)</actor>
      <role>Brother Jake</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zarif, Moe</actor>
      <role>Nerd 1</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>You have nightmares. You write them down. You make a lot of money from them. Your night horrors start to bleed into your day job. Then you remember where the bad dreams came from. Real life. This is the story of Samantha Martin AKA the hottest scariest sexiest writer in the SF/fantasy biz. One night, a stranger leaves a savage death threat on Sam's phone machine. But it's the wrong number! The guy really wants this girl named Christina who has a similar number so Samantha decides she'd better track this chick down before the guy does. Problem is, 18-year-old Christina Lombardo doesn't want her help. Yeah, she's been hanging with some pretty freaky people and she's tired of their crazy scene and wants out. But now that she knows all about their whack rituals of sex and magic, these freaks and their leader, Jesse James Brown, don't want to let her go. Still, she doesn't want anyone, not Samantha, not the cops and, most importantly, not her beloved dad, to come down on her. So Sam should just drop it, right? Not likely. As persistent and dangerously handsome Det. Henry Romero discovers, Samantha already knows (firsthand) of the evils young men do. She doesn't want Christina to suffer as she has, so Sam goes to the edge to try to save the life of this lost girl - whether she wants to be saved or not.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?481933</url></doc>
