<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="482001">
  <docid>482001</docid>
  <title>Screen Addicts</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Engeran, Dave</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>technology</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 March 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">22</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>DeWitt, Stacey</producer>
    <producer>Siedor, Collin</producer>
    <producer>Seith, Robert</producer>
    <producer>Wilkenfeld, Adam</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Wilkenfeld, Adam</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Experts have called it "the world's greatest social science experiment." Never before has a generation of children grown up staring at so many electronic screens. According to a survey from the non-profit Kaiser Family Foundation, each week, kids eight to 18 spend five hours online, six hours on their phone, eight hours playing videogames, 12 hours listening to music and 30 hours watching TV and movies. Teenagers swear that the technology they won't turn off is just harmless fun. What if they're wrong? Larry Rosen is a psychologist, professor, and author of the parenting book "Me Myspace and I." He says "Being in the virtual world, being in front of a screen all day is not sufficient for good teenage socialization. You need to have a combination of screen life, and a real life." He teaches parents, and Connect With Kids viewers, how to become "Authoritative Parents." These true stories are profiled in the TV special, Screen Addicts. Sabrina, Ruben, Daniel and Alinna are siblings ranging in age from six to 16. Together they send thousands of text messages, instant messages and emails each month, and spend countless hours on Myspace, playing video games and watching TV. Their parents say they're addicted, and want to get this technology use under control. Joshua, 19 was addicted to online pornography. It started when he was 12 years old. And at age 18, Daniel discovered online gambling. Within a few weeks he was thousands of dollars in debt. Connect with Kids programs feature real kids, true stories, experts and educators ... a way to help parents and kids start a conversation about the tough topics kids face every day.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?482001</url></doc>
