<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="482514">
  <docid>482514</docid>
  <title>Sderot: Rock in the Red Zone</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>israel</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hebrew</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Bialis, Laura</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Krapf, Caitlin</producer>
    <producer>Bialis, Laura</producer>
    <producer>Horwich, Elana</producer>
    <producer>Markus, Ravit</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>Told through the eyes of Sderot's talented and diverse young musicians, this documentary explores daily life in Sderot and the effects of living under the long-term stress of constant bombings. From those who have already 'made it big' - Teapacks, Knessiat Hasechel, Sfatayim, now among Israel's cultural elite - to the up-and-coming teenagers who play in SDEROCK, a bomb shelter turned into an underground rock club to be a safe and fun haven when Qassams hit. The artists and their music represent a culturally and ethnically diverse representation of Israel. Musical sounds and instruments from all over the world meld together in this place at the crossroads of East and West. As they try to live normal lives, and realize their careers, the musicians write about their daily struggles and the harsh realities of living in Israel and especially, Sderot. Their music captures their fears and challenges, the feeling that the world has abandoned them, the uncertainty of this place. Through Hip-Hop, Folk, Middle-Eastern, and Rock'n'Roll, they express their desperation and determination. To many, the questions about Israel and the Middle East are abstract. However, the people of Sderot are at the tip of the spear - they live the battle on a daily basis. To them, peace in the Middle East is not a question of road maps or diplomatic initiatives, it's just a day that goes by when they don't have to run for cover.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?482514</url></doc>
