<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="483268">
  <docid>483268</docid>
  <title>Second Chance</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Parker, Derrik</editor>
    <editor>Romberger, Ron</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>transplant</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">28</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Robertson, Todd J.</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Klug, Chris</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nabors, Jim</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Walker, Paul (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Second Chance is a documentary that tells the compelling stories of people who now have a Second Chance at life by receiving organ and tissue transplants. This program tells the inspirational stories of organ recipients and the heroism of organ donors that saved their lives. Paul Walker, host of the program, is known by his roles in The Fast and the Furious, The Skulls, Joy Ride, Into the Blue and more. Stories of real people in the program include: Taylor (Tee) Burton, a young girl with life-long heart trouble is on the waiting list to receive her third heart transplant. Even though she is very sick and in need of a new heart, Tee is vibrant and lives her life to the fullest. Ryan Kitamura, a young boy suffering from leukemia, has waited months for a bone marrow donor. Ryan and his family share their experiences and hopes for him to have a normal life. Brett Henderson, an altruistic kidney donor, chose to give life to a person he didn't know. We come to understand his motives to perform such an extraordinary and see that the capacity to help others is within all of us. Steven Ginoza, a young man who, through his passing, was able to save several lives by donating his organs. We'll see a meeting between some of the recipients and the donor's parents. Yolanda Domingo is a mother and grandparent who was on the brink of death before she received a heart transplant on Mother's Day. She shows us the value of living a new life that was received from Steven Ginoza. Chris Klug, professional snowboarder and 2000 Winter Olympic Bronze medalist, received a liver transplant prior to the Olympic games and continues to snowboard at the highest levels today. Jim Nabors, known for his music and his role as Gomer Pyle, has continued to perform for many years as a liver recipient.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?483268</url></doc>
