<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="489443">
  <docid>489443</docid>
  <title>Shaadi Ke Baad</title>
  <year>1972</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Prasad, L.V.</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kudalkar, Laxmikant Shantaram</composer>
    <composer>Sharma, Pyarelal Ramprasad</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Asrani</actor>
      <role>Ramu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dubey, C.S.</actor>
      <role>Advocate Govind</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gopal, V.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gulzar, Rakhee</actor>
      <role>Shobha S. Ram</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jain, Jugnu</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jeetendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Advocate Shyam B. Ram</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khote, Viju</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mishra, Leela</actor>
      <role>Parvati</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Paintal</actor>
      <role>Raju 'Masterji'</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, Satyajit</actor>
      <role>Chabiley</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Purohit, Shekhar</actor>
      <role>Bhagat Ram</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Randhawa</actor>
      <role>Balam</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sinha, Shatrughan</actor>
      <role>Choudhury Bishan Swaroop Singh</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Widower Bhagat Ram lives a wealthy lifestyle in a small village in India, along with his son, Shyam, who is an Advocate in Bombay, and makes a living as a Hindu Priest. He receives a marriage proposal from Choudhury Bishan Swaroop Singh for Shyam, the girl in question is Bishan's son-in-law, Raju's sister, Shobha. Hoping to get a dowry of Fifty thousand Rupees, he agrees and the marriage takes place. After the ceremony he is handed a Promissory Note, and angered he and Shyam return home, leaving a devastated Shobha and the Singh family to deal with this crisis. Raju takes some cash and jewelry, hoping to placate Bhagat, but this only angers him all the more. Shyam decides to leave for Bombay. Shortly thereafter Bhagat is informed by Advocate Govind that Shobha has eloped with an unknown lover, and her mom, Parvati, has initiated legal proceedings against him. A panic-stricken Bhagat rushes to Bombay, and is shocked to find that Shyam has lost his mental balance and is in the care of a doctor and a nurse. The question that comes to mind is why did Shyam lose his mental balance? And what actually became of Shobha and who did she actually elope with?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?489443</url></doc>
