<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="490565">
  <docid>490565</docid>
  <title>Shanghai Exodus</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Andermann, Greg</editor>
    <editor>Li, Xin (III)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>shanghai-china</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">128</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Andermann, Greg</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Andermann, Fawn</writer>
    <writer>Andermann, Greg</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>A small, sleepy fishing village known as Shanghai was destined to become the world's largest city. Shanghai began to evolve into a completely Westernized city. European businessmen brought their families to Shanghai, built large European-style homes, and led extravagant lifestyles. "Shanghai Exodus" features the Caucasians who grew up in China, migrated there for safety and fled Shanghai after the Communist revolution. These are the personal stories of struggle, survival, and success over a nation. What it was like to grow up in China, experience the blending of cultures as East and West collided. Old Shanghai became the most unique cross-cultural international settlement that's ever existed. These European Settlements formed the world's first and largest international community. Children growing up in Shanghai were imprinted with a unique world-view that literally made them the first "global citizens." Shanghai was a safe haven, an open port - tens of thousands fled there to escape the Russian Revolution and the rise of Hitler's Nazi Germany. The sudden impact of communism was both felt and feared by the remaining foreigners living in China. Giving up everything they had, they fled in masses, but left their hearts back in China. To them, the Old China Hands, it's Shanghai and China that formed their world-view, and made them into who they are today. They share something special - these people still reserve Shanghai and China as home in their hearts. Many keep coming home to find their past... that special place in time; in Shanghai.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?490565</url></doc>
