<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="490909">
  <docid>490909</docid>
  <title>Shareef Budmaash</title>
  <year>1973</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Khosla, Raj</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kartik, Kalpana</producer>
    <producer>Khanna, Amit (I)</producer>
    <producer>Anand, Dev</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Burman, Rahul Dev</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ajit (I)</actor>
      <role>Ranjit</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anand, Dev</actor>
      <role>Rocky/Inspector Ramesh/Sustram</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Asrani</actor>
      <role>Govind/Gomes</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhagwan, Master</actor>
      <role>Ranjit's henchman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Birbal</actor>
      <role>Prisoner</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Helen (I)</actor>
      <role>Carmen/Rita</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hercules (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jankidas</actor>
      <role>Prisoner</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jeevan (I)</actor>
      <role>Diwan Saheb</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Trilok (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khote, Viju</actor>
      <role>Prisoner</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Malini, Hema</actor>
      <role>Seema</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Manmohan (I)</actor>
      <role>Gulab Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mohan, Mac</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sapru, D.K.</actor>
      <role>Lawyer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Singh, Gurbachchan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sinha, Shatrughan</actor>
      <role>Kanhaiyalal/Rocky (Guest appearance)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sudhir (I)</actor>
      <role>Ajit</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The Government of India has devised plans for a new kind of super aircraft. A gangster, Diwan, manages to procure this plan from corrupt military officials, and hides it in his safe along with other valuables. The police find out that the plans have been stolen by a "Diwan", and start a manhunt for all Diwans in Bombay. When they come across the Diwan, they ask him to show them his valuables, which he agrees to do so. To his shock, he finds that he has been burgled. The police conclude that the thief is none other than Diwan's trusted man, Ajit. They have him arrested, but he refuses to divulge any information. Diwan recruits a man called Rocky to spring Ajit from prison, as well as find out where he has stashed the valuables. Rocky, who keeps on denying that he is indeed Rocky, agrees to do so for a large sum of money as his fee, to which Diwan agrees. Rocky's plan is to seduce cabaret dancer, Seema, who is the lover of the Jailer, and hence gain entry to the jail. When this fails, Rocky gets himself arrested and jailed in the same prison as Ajit. Upon his entry in the prison, is where the truth surfaces that the man they call Rocky is not Rocky at all but an impostor, who has agreed to be Rocky just to get the large fee. The real Rocky, who calls himself Kanhaiyalal, agrees to help the false Rocky escape from prison, along with Ajit, so that they can find the plans and hand them in to Diwan, and collect their fee. But fate has other plans for the false Rocky, as he is caught by another master criminal and gangster, Ranjeet, and held until he tells him about the whereabouts of the plans as well as the valuables.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?490909</url></doc>
