<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="491406">
  <docid>491406</docid>
  <title>She Kills</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>detroit-michigan</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Lawrence, Brian (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Frapasella, Tamara</producer>
    <producer>Lawrence, Brian (II)</producer>
    <producer>Munoz, Aida</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Balzerini, Brian</actor>
      <role>Wyatt Wexler</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cochran, Don (II)</actor>
      <role>Detective Rodicker</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Frapasella, Tamara</actor>
      <role>Scarlett Miner</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gall, Hugh</actor>
      <role>Joe Miner</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gibbs, Cordell</actor>
      <role>Marcus Rivers</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Litzner, Elton</actor>
      <role>Tim Monroe</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McDaniel, Willie 'Mac'</actor>
      <role>Chief Kane</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mitchell, Donna</actor>
      <role>Detective Mars</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wrenn, Duane</actor>
      <role>Detective Stryker</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Man framed for murders committed by his serial killer sister escapes prison to stop her. Convicted murderer Joe Miner resides in a Federal prison on death row. All the while maintaining his innocence, he begins to have disturbing dreams about his sister Scarlet. Having had a lifelong psychic connection to her, he begins to gets visions of her impending suicide. Determined to save her - and to stop her from killing - he devises a plan with fellow inmate Tim and boldly succeeds in escaping prison. Although immediately the subject of a nationwide manhunt, Miner and Tim evade capture and are picked up by Miner's loyal girlfriend Lucinda who takes them to a remote hideaway, not far from Miner's haunts on Hell Street. Hell Street, a den of the most heinous and dreadful iniquity, is where Miner heads first to find Scarlet. Tragedy soon follows as Lucinda becomes the victim of a horrible murder. With a renewed sense of urgency, Miner recruits his prison mate Tim to help him find his sister Scarlet before she can kill again. Meanwhile, the massive manhunt intensifies as Miner becomes the number one suspect in Lucinda's murder.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?491406</url></doc>
