<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="491922">
  <docid>491922</docid>
  <title>Sheetla Mata</title>
  <year>1981</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Rao, Bhaskar (III)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">1981</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Gupta, Ramgopal</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Rajpati</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Jagmohan, Sapan</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Birbal</actor>
      <role>Jaggu Jivanpuria</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dalvi, Sudhir</actor>
      <role>Bhiku</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dhumal</actor>
      <role>Munim Ram Bharose</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dubey, C.S.</actor>
      <role>Teja Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Pinchoo</actor>
      <role>Zamindar Rana</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kaul, Satish</actor>
      <role>Sarju</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kausalya, Jaya</actor>
      <role>Devi Maa Sheetla</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Raj, Jagdish</actor>
      <role>Sardar Phoolan</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Widowed Kunti lives a poor lifestyle in rural India along with two sons, Bhiku, and Sarju, who are married to Bhagyawanti and Dayawanti respectively. Bhiku has a daughter named Kamli while Dayawanti is expecting. Bhiku's first wife had killed herself by setting her afire. One night Kunti gets instructions from Devi Maa Sheetla to dig up a plot of land belonging to Zamindar Rana where an idol is buried, and after doing so, construct a temple. The next morning Kunti asks her sons to carry out this task and they go to the Zamindar to ask his permission, but he refuses leading to Bhiku backing away, but Sarju eventually digging the ground at night, finding the idol much to the chagrin of Zamindar who blacklists Sarju, Kunti and Dayavanti. Arguments ensue at home forcing the trio to re-locate and live with Teja Singh. Sarju then decides to leave and find donors in order to construct a temple. Zamindar and his Munim, Ram Bharose, steal the idol and drop it in a well. A visibly pregnant Dayawanti is forced to work as a servant for Bhagyawanti, while Sarju faces many challenges in his quest for donations, but accumulate some, only to have it stolen but later recovered by a bandit named Sardar Phoolan. Sarju returns home, a baby boy is born to him, and a temple is constructed. An enraged Zamindar has the temple blown to bits by an explosive little knowing that this will enrage Sheetla Mata who will turn her wrath on the entire region.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?491922</url></doc>
