<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="491915">
  <docid>491915</docid>
  <title>Sheesh Mahal</title>
  <year>1950</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">144</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Modi, Sohrab</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Modi, Sohrab</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Banu, Naseem (I)</actor>
      <role>Ranjana Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hans, Pushpa</actor>
      <role>Nalini</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kaul, Jawahar</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mishra, Leela</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Durgaprasad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Modi, Sohrab</actor>
      <role>Thakur Jaspal Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mubarak</actor>
      <role>Durgaprasad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pran (I)</actor>
      <role>Sundermukh</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Thakur Jaspal Singh lives in the prestigious and palatial house called the Sheesh Mahal. He is badly in debt, yet continues to live a lifestyle far over and above his means. His son and two daughters are concerned, and try to stop him from over-spending, but he disregards them. Then one day the inevitable happens, and Jaspal Singh has to leave Sheesh Mahal, which must now be sold by auction to pay off his debts. Jaspal and his children move into a small room in the nearby slums, where they hope to spend the rest of their lives. Jaspal's son finds employment in a mill, but unfortunately meets with an accident, and in order to save his life, the doctors amputate his leg, leaving his unemployed and dependent. Jaspal's daughter, Ranjana, attempts to secure employment, but proud Jaspal will not hear of this. Ranjana gets employment, but she does not tell her father about it. Ranjana meets with a young man and both fall in love with each other. When this young man's father, Durgaprasad, comes to ask Jaspal for Ranjana's hand, Jaspal finds out that he is the new owner of Sheesh Mahal, and that Ranjana has been working as a maid there. Jaspal is furious, and taking his sword, he rushes over to the Sheesh Mahal with a clear intend of killing Ranjana, and anyone else who dares to stop him.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?491915</url></doc>
