<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="493441">
  <docid>493441</docid>
  <title>Shirdi Ke Sai Baba</title>
  <year>1977</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Bhushan, Ashok V.</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Dikshit, Pandurang</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Birbal</actor>
      <role>Kulkarni</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chavan, Usha</actor>
      <role>Laxmi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dalvi, Sudhir</actor>
      <role>Sai Baba</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dubey, C.S.</actor>
      <role>Groom's dad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Krishna, Manmohan</actor>
      <role>Ganpat Rao</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Dheeraj (I)</actor>
      <role>Tatya (Baijamma's son)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Manoj (I)</actor>
      <role>Devotee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Rajendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Doctor (Pooja's husband)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Malini, Hema</actor>
      <role>Pooja</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mehra, Raj</actor>
      <role>Murthy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nath, Prem (I)</actor>
      <role>Som Dev</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Paintal</actor>
      <role>Karim</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, Madan (I)</actor>
      <role>Ranbir Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sachin (I)</actor>
      <role>Sarju</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sinha, Shatrughan</actor>
      <role>Heera</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tito, Master</actor>
      <role>Beta</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Pooja lives with her doctor husband and a young son. Her son becomes seriously ill and does not respond to any medication, her husband wants him to be moved to a hospital for further treatment, but Pooja has heard of Sai Baba and wants her son to be treated there. Her son regains consciousness for a short while and demands that he be taken to Shirdi, the town of Sai Baba. So they travel there, and that is where they meet with an ardent devotee of Sai Baba who recounts the tale behind the Baba. A young boy who traveled with a marriage procession to Shirdi, he stayed there, grew up, looked after by the kind townspeople, who subsequently named him Sai Baba. He showed Ganpat Rao that he is one with Vithoba and Bhagwan Shri Kishan; he demonstrated to Som Dev that he is one with Bhagwan Shri Shiv; former jailbird Heera regained his eyesight with Sai's blessing; During all of these miracles, the Sai always went door to door begging for alms and food. The legend grew, people flocked all over to witness this new Messiah, one whom the Muslims called "Allah Sai", Christians "Jesus Sai", Sikhs "Nanak Sai", and Hindus "Bhola Sai". Sai could recite scriptures from all the Holy books, whether it was the Holy Quran, the Holy Bible, the Holy Granth Sahib, or the Holy Geeta, and always blessed Hindus with "Allah bless you", and Muslims with "Krishna bless you". After his passing, a temple was built in his memory. It is here that a doubting doctor has to decide whether his ailing son can be treated by Sai Baba, and it is here where we will witness whether faith or scientific reality and logic will prevail.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?493441</url></doc>
