<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="495028">
  <docid>495028</docid>
  <title>Shri Siddhivinayak Mahima</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kokate, Sunil</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>History</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>DTS</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">U</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Nalawade, Arun</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Lad, Neeta Prasad</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Patki, Ashok</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhave, Subodh</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dalvi, Tushar</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khalatkar, Manoj</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pradhan, Gaurav</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ranade, Aditya</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vaid, Tejasri</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Madhav lives a middle-class lifestyle along with his wife, Madhavi. Both had a son named Pintu, who passed away, but Madhavi is unable to accept his death. Madhav works for a Film Producer, Sunil, who wants him to make a commercial success of a documentary on Bhagwan Shri Siddhivinayak. Sunil lives a wealthy lifestyle with his wife, Rohini, a devotee of Siddhivinayak, and a son, Ashu, who has been vocally-challenged since his birth. Sunil faces a crisis when he is threatened by a gangster named Jaffarbhai to come up with a huge amount or else he and his family will face certain death. Then there is Prasad Buddhisagar, another devotee of Siddhivinayak, whose parents were killed in an automobile accident, and he has since been adopted by Sandy and his wife, who treat him more as a servant than a child, and are in debt with another gangster named Hakim Hatela. Finally there is Rama, yet another devotee of Siddhivinayak, who runs a tea-stall near Siddhivinayak Temple near Prabhadevi, lives with an abusive husband and two daughters. Watch how Ganeshji in the guise of Gajanan and Dr. Vinayak comes to the aid of his devotees in this movie which is based on two true events.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?495028</url></doc>
