<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="495075">
  <docid>495075</docid>
  <title>Shrink Me</title>
  <year>2010</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Jaymes, Christopher</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Klinghor, Niki</producer>
    <producer>Horton, Shae</producer>
    <producer>Jaymes, Christopher</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Jaymes, Christopher</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jaymes, Christopher</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stroumboulopoulos, George</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Award-winning filmmaker Christopher Jaymes places himself in the hands of the medical field to properly 'handle' his so-called mental ailments. Shrink Me is a comedic investigation into why we have become a society in such need of pharmaceutical drugs for mental stability. His initial assessment by a trusty psychiatrist stated... "You do not fall into one simple, clean cut category as you have irregular symptoms. My initial assessment on your case would be as follows. You suffer from an irregular bipolar disorder, A.D.D., O.C.D. and possess a Paranoid Personality Disorder. There will not be one single medication, as we will have to fish through a number of them and for all we know it may take three of four different medications to find a solution." We will follow his journey beginning with a non-chemical body into a prescription-filled world led by psychiatrists moving through psychiatric institutions and mental wards across the country. He will be monitored constantly by a nutritionist from the beginning to assess the evolution of his physical health, while searching for answers to the universal questions we all strive to answer... "what's wrong with me?"... While looking into the mindset of a society that thinks solace comes in the form of a pill.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?495075</url></doc>
