<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="495895">
  <docid>495895</docid>
  <title>Sibelius - Finlandia</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Anttonen, Jari</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>nature</keyword>
    <keyword>classical-music</keyword>
    <keyword>finland</keyword>
    <keyword>lapland</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Finnish</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Finland</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Finland">K-3</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Finland">17 October 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">56</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Anttonen, Jari</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Anttonen, Jari</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Anttonen, Jari</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Sibelius, Jean</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Finland is a country of contrasts. The enthralling white nights of summer, the mystery of the darkness of the winter months and differences in temperatures of up to 80 degrees Celsius, are often hard for people from elsewhere to comprehend. The fertile fields, dense forests, thousands of lakes, wilderness expanses of Lapland, majestic fells and the surrounding natural environment are all part of nature's wonder, and they create our unique four seasons. We experience fields abloom with flowers, the glorious russet palette of autumn and then the stark white and blue hues of winter. The greatness of Sibelius lies in his ability to have inhaled the drama of nature and to have reproduced this in his compositions so that strength and reservation strike a joint chord. The magic of the aurora borealis and the infinite charisma of nature would be impossible to describe without this music. Thanks to the latest digital technology, we are able to experience the sources of these incredible compositions through images and sounds, and we feel we are part of the creative process.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?495895</url></doc>
