<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="496596">
  <docid>496596</docid>
  <title>Significant Others</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">23 November 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Milberg, Marc</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Franco, John (X)</actor>
      <role>Enzo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harnish, Cody</actor>
      <role>Anton</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Soderbergh, Erik</actor>
      <role>Dorian</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This gangster short film tells a story about a mafia boss, Dorian, his right hand man, Enzo, and his hit man, Anton. Anton has been under suspicion by the mafia for some time now, and with the help of Rita, they are finally going to put him to justice for his actions. Anton has been sleeping with Rita, which is forbidden. He has fallen in love with RIta and has realized that he does not like working as a hitman anymore. Furthermore, Rita does not love Anton and he is completely oblivious to this. She is loyal to her boss brother Dorian and helps the mafia by pretending to be in love with Anton so he has no idea what is coming for him. The structure of the film is what makes this more than just an average gangster short. The film starts off at night in an interrogation room, Anton being tied up to a chair with his mouth duck-taped. Dorian and Enzo come in to confront Anton for his misbehavior; Enzo is eager to kill their hitman, who he never liked, but Dorian actually shoots him because of this being such a personal matter. Next, the film goes back in time to the morning before Anton's death and opens up with Anton looking as if he had a horrible nightmare. This surrealistic dream actually becomes a reality for Anton with the help of Rita, and emphasizing the concept of family values and loyalty.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?496596</url></doc>
