<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="496653">
  <docid>496653</docid>
  <title>Signs of Undoing</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Taddeo, Tom</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Taddeo, Tom</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Damico, David</producer>
    <producer>Taddeo, Tom</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Taddeo, Tom</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Damico, David</composer>
    <composer>Larson, Neil (II)</composer>
    <composer>Paul, Gregory (I)</composer>
    <composer>Reeg, Chris</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Caisley, Nyle</actor>
      <role>Luna</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Damico, David</actor>
      <role>Dev</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Poston Jr., Larry</actor>
      <role>Andino</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The story centers on Luna, Dev, and Andino.... three eccentric characters that meet at a Christmas party and set off on a journey of lust, deceit, adventure, betrayal, and spiritual messages. Andino will do or say anything to get a reaction out of people. Yet, when he lays eyes on Luna, he can't seem to stay focused on his former mission of chaos and his little group of followers don't like it. Luna is a trouble artist. She's more than a bit delusional and not sure who to trust as both Andino and Dev make a play for her attendion. It's all a bit too much when she learns that Andino and his crazy friends might try to destroy her upcoming gallery show. Dev consoles her with a plan to set Andino up for a fall, right in the middle of his biggest triumph. Dev lives and breathes music. In the middle of their crazy night out together, Dev disappears and leaves Luna in Andino's arms. Three days after they all meet, everything in their own individual world is changed! Everybody lives their own unique dream inside their own head. Your memories are your own.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?496653</url></doc>
