<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="496740">
  <docid>496740</docid>
  <title>Sikka</title>
  <year>1989</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>D., Venkataratnam</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">22 September 1989</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Bapaiah, K.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Nahata, Shrikant</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Khan, Kader (I)</writer>
    <writer>Sunder, M.D.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Lahiri, Bappi</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anand, Mahesh</actor>
      <role>George (Pranlal's Henchman)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Asrani</actor>
      <role>Pyarelal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brahmachari</actor>
      <role>Daruka's Creditor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chatterjee, Moushumi</actor>
      <role>Laxmi (Vijay's Wife)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chopra, Prem</actor>
      <role>Pranlal Sinha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dharmendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Vijay</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Irani, Aruna</actor>
      <role>Dulari</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapadia, Dimple</actor>
      <role>Shobha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Bharat</actor>
      <role>Gupta (Pranlal's Agent)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Kader (I)</actor>
      <role>Daruka</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pal, Amrit</actor>
      <role>Ship's Captain</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Parvez, Yunus</actor>
      <role>Jackie's Landlord</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Saigal, Sumeet</actor>
      <role>Amarlal Sinha 'Amar'</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shroff, Jackie</actor>
      <role>Jai Kishan 'Jackie'</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Two close and very wealthy friends, Vijay and Pranlal, decide to cement their friendship to a relationship when Vijay proposes marriage on behalf of his sister, Shobha, with Pranlal's son, Amar. Pranlal agrees, and preparations are on for the marriage to take place. Vijay finds out that Pranlal and his men are using their business as a front for drugs and smuggling, and he decides to cancel the wedding. Pranlal is angry with Vijay, but refuses to give up his criminal career. When Amar finds out about his dad's spurious activities, he kills himself. Pranlal, humiliated and angered, vows to avenge Amar's death, and wants Shobha to be Amar's widow for the rest of her life, which is not acceptable to Vijay. Then Shobha meets with a handsome stranger named Jackie, who rescues her. She offers him employment with her brother's firm, and they fall in love with each other. When Vijay finds out he is upset that his sister has chosen a mere employee for a life-partner, and decides to oppose this marriage at all costs. But both Shobha and Jackie are adamant, and refuse to budge, and finally Vijay gives in, and soon both are married. After the marriage, Jackie starts to show his true colors, and becomes very abusive. Shobha then finds out the terrible truth behind Jackie's hatred, a truth that will change her and Vijay's lives forever.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?496740</url></doc>
