<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="496933">
  <docid>496933</docid>
  <title>Silent Glide</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Cavusoglu, Ergin</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Turkish</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby SR</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">28</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Cavusoglu, Ergin</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Altan, Ali</producer>
    <producer>Cavusoglu, Ergin</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Cavusoglu, Ergin</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Sesler, Bulent</composer>
    <composer>Sesler, Selim</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Halici, Taylan</actor>
      <role>Halil</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harvey, Esin</actor>
      <role>Tulya</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Silent Glide portrays the dynamics, inner complexities and strains of a couple's relationship, and the growing incompatibilities of their moral values. Halil, a talented novelist and a poet, goes to Hereke, a small town on the Izmit Bay near Istanbul, to research materials for his forthcoming book on collection of short stories around oriental carpets. Tulya is his publisher back in Istanbul, and Halil is her lover. In the opening scene we see Halil standing at the Pier in Hereke at night, and murmuring to himself passages from a book. After the usual tense late night conversation on the telephone, the following morning Tulya pays an undesired visit to Hereke. Eager to win his heart back, and to patch up their relationship, she discovers some of the reasons, behind the drift between them. In parallel with the scenes revealing their incompatibilities as characters, we see Halil's inner voyage and esteem for understanding himself, his moral conscience and his role in the society. Halil's character is loosely based on Leo Tolstoy himself in his memoir 'A Confession', which explains his inner struggles and search for the philosophical meaning of life and its moral values. The scenes showing the downward spiral of Tulya and Halil's relationship are set against the dim industrial landscape of Hereke. Once renowned for the production of the finest silk carpets in the world, a destination for the noble and wealthy, nowadays the landscape is dominated by the malaise of the cement factory and the freighter's port. This setting contains all the poetic ingredients for Halil to enable him to create, and ultimately becomes his point of departure.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?496933</url></doc>
