<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="497229">
  <docid>497229</docid>
  <title>Silna voda</title>
  <year>1975</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>based-on-novel</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Bulgarian</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Bulgaria</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Bulgaria">19 September 1975</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">85</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Terziev, Ivan (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Papasov, Boyan</writer>
    <writer>Stoyev, Gencho</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Tsibulka, Kiril</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dimitrova, Mariana</actor>
      <role>Michona</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grigorov, Ivan</actor>
      <role>Chiko</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kavadarkov, Kirill</actor>
      <role>Miro</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kynev, Velko</actor>
      <role>Dimeto</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Trifonov, Filip</actor>
      <role>Flori</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Yordanov, Yordan (I)</actor>
      <role>Kmetat Gachevski</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This is a problem-oriented social film. The action takes place in a small town on the Danube, which is suffering from a shortage of drinking water. Drilling has begun in the hope of discovering 'strong water'. However, water has not and will not be found. Both the drillers and the citizens are aware of this and the chairman of the city council, who refuses to undertake the purifying of the river water, will not accept it. However, his sweeping fatherly gestures conceal a mere patriarchal willfulness. In fact, his actions encourage the drilling crew to cheat. With pretending to work, they are idling their time away. This lasts until one fine day the drill operator Chiko gets fed up and lets the cat out of the bag. Now he is pitted against his calculating foreman Miro and shifty Flory. Chiko not only stops playing the unfair game, but also requires his fellow workers to do the same. He succeeds because of his unflinching belief in honestly. Along with 'Men Without Work', the film is director Ivan Terziev's contribution to the advancement of the contemporary theme during the 1970th in Bulgarian cinema.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?497229</url></doc>
