<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="498473">
  <docid>498473</docid>
  <title>Single-Handed Sanders</title>
  <year>1932</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>O'Brien, Pat (V)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Western</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Passed</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">10 February 1932</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">61</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Nosler, Lloyd</director>
    <director>Post, Charles A.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Carr, Trem</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Buffington, Adele S.</writer>
    <writer>Post, Charles A.</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Beasley, Barney</actor>
      <role>Henchman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bell, Hank</actor>
      <role>Hank Perkins</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bridge, Loie</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Perkins</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>De Main, Gordon</actor>
      <role>Judge Parker</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Elliott, John (I)</actor>
      <role>Senator Graham</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ellis, Frank (I)</actor>
      <role>Judd</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gibson, Helen (I)</actor>
      <role>Judd's wife</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Haskell, Al</actor>
      <role>Cyrus Noble - Saloon owner</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lorch, Theodore</actor>
      <role>Sheriff Murray</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McKee, Lafe</actor>
      <role>Dr. Walker</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Seiter, Robert</actor>
      <role>Phillip Sanders</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Simon, S.S.</actor>
      <role>Murdered homesteader</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Smith, F.R.</actor>
      <role>Henchman Jim</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Strange, Glenn (I)</actor>
      <role>Gang leader</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Toones, Fred 'Snowflake'</actor>
      <role>Snowflake</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tyler, Tom (I)</actor>
      <role>Matt Sanders</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The cattlemen send a note to Judge Jim Parker warning him to quit giving credit to the homesteaders, whom they assert, are ruining the range. Parker declares that his store will continue to give credit to the homesteaders and, incensed at his defiance, the cattlemen kill him. As he is dying, he tells his daughter Alice and Matt Sanders, honest blacksmith, to carry on the fight to protect the homesteaders. Matt declares that he will, with the assistance of his brother, Phillip, who is expected back from law school after an absence of many years. Phillip returns and is elected Judge by mostly the homesteaders vote. He is pleased with his new position, and also pleased with the friendship of Senator Graham who holds out the bait of election to the Governor's chair if he will betray the homesteaders. He persuades Alice to mortgage her water rights to Senator Graham in order to have the money to extend further credit to the homesteaders. Despite several machinations by Graham and the cattlemen, mostly blocked by Matt, the homesteaders make a bumper crop and pay Alice back. Taking the money to the bank so she will have it in time to meet Graham's note, a galloping rider takes it from her. Snowflake, who works for Matt, tells him of a conversation he overheard between Phillip and Graham when he was delivering a newly-shod horse to the Senator that reveals the Senator and Phillip connived to have the money stolen, so the mortgage can be foreclosed, and drive out the homesteaders. Matt refuses to believe the story, but finds proof in Phillip's desk. Matt and Phillip fight, with Matt winning and then going to rally the homesteaders to prevent the cattlemen from taking over.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?498473</url></doc>
