<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="499673">
  <docid>499673</docid>
  <title>Siyama</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Sermsuwittayawong, Thawat</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>History</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Thai</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Thailand</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Thailand">31 January 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Russia">4 September 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">107</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Songsakul, Preecha</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Asavaprapha, Dr. Soraj</producer>
    <producer>Bodharamik, Pete</producer>
    <producer>Ratthanaviriyachai, Jirun</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Benjathikul, Sompob (I)</actor>
      <role>Khruu Jom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chanreuang, Bawriboon</actor>
      <role>Boat</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jantarawetch, Nattanun</actor>
      <role>Gift</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Juramakorn, Viriya</actor>
      <role>Lung-Tup</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ketkaew, Montri</actor>
      <role>Luang Putone</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kongsib, Hassapon</actor>
      <role>Yuntra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maliwan, Thitima</actor>
      <role>Ana</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Thanakorn, Than</actor>
      <role>Pray</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Three young lives from the present are mysteriously destined to travel back in time through a portal to an old forgotten city. It is an era of civil war among the people of Siam where the fight is to protect the capital city of Ayuthaya from being conquered and overthrown. Bloodshed is about to unfold among the small group of villagers loyal to their land and prepared to battle to the death with the opposing military troops of Ong Mien, known for their cut throat, piercing swords. Siyama led by, Kru Jom, uses religious sorcery to protect his small village located amidst a ravine populated by only a mere one thousand villagers and two hundred rooftops. By being the choice of passage towards the capital city of Ayuthaya, Siyama becomes a targeted obstacle for the gruesome military brigade of Ong Mien. Anna, Gif, and Bote from present day Bangkok are thrown into a gateway through time after coincidentally conversing about the history of warfare that took place in the ancient days of what was then called Siam. They suddenly appear out of no where right at the onset of battle causing utter confusion and havoc among the soldiers. These girls are forced to put their book-learned history knowledge to the test to see if they can save Siyama from being trampled through.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?499673</url></doc>
