<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="500520">
  <docid>500520</docid>
  <title>Skorpion, Panna i Lucznik</title>
  <year>1973</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <editors>
    <editor>Niedzwiecka, Janina</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>bus</keyword>
    <keyword>thief</keyword>
    <keyword>camera</keyword>
    <keyword>road-movie</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Polish</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Poland</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Kondratiuk, Andrzej</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bonarski, Andrzej</writer>
    <writer>Kondratiuk, Andrzej</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Konieczny, Zygmunt</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Berth, Henrik</actor>
      <role>Rudy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bittnerówna-Olszewska, Hanna</actor>
      <role>Hanka</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cembrzynska, Iga</actor>
      <role>Magda</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Himilsbach, Jan</actor>
      <role>Mistrz</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nowicki, Jan</actor>
      <role>Jakub</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Piaskowski, Czeslaw</actor>
      <role>Man at Fair</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Radulski, Edward</actor>
      <role>Man at Fair</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zelnik, Jerzy</actor>
      <role>Jan 'Kapucyn'</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Poetically shown story of love, passion, loyalty, betrayal of trust, and death. A strange group of three people travels throughout the country in a jalopy bus. There is Magda, a young woman, and two men; the group's leader Jakob (always wearing sun glasses) and a friar. The bus serves them also as home, costume store and photographic lab. They're doing an odd performances for a living; they create scenes from Holy Family life, act in the scenes, photograph them and later, sell the self-made photographic prints as "holy" images. The photos are distributed among peasants at small village fairs or church fetes. Some day a mysterious and silent man joins the group. He is received as a guest, with food and wine. Next day the man leaves, stealing their camera. During pursuit after the thief the camera is destroyed. Having lost their main tool of labor, the group faces serious surviving problem; there comes autumn with winds, rains and chillness. The two men got an idea. It consists in kind of trading on Magda.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?500520</url></doc>
