<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="501009">
  <docid>501009</docid>
  <title>Slash</title>
  <year>2010</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>death</keyword>
    <keyword>killer</keyword>
    <keyword>murder</keyword>
    <keyword>slasher</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">R</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">17 August 2010</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">100</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Foreman, Rycke</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Anglin, Chriss</producer>
    <producer>Fallaize, Gene</producer>
    <producer>Wilson, Dempsey</producer>
    <producer>Foreman, Rycke</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Foreman, Rycke</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Joy, Megan (II)</actor>
      <role>Lillith</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Snyder-Kloos, Joseph</actor>
      <role>Cade</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Walters-Foreman, Darbey</actor>
      <role>Constable West</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Walter Sickert beats on the door in a drunken rage as his son Trench and step-son, Cade, cower inside the house. But Trench has a shotgun. He antagonizes his dad, who breaks down the door, coming in shooting. Trench blows him away, cracking a wicked grin. Trench, Rachel's boyfriend, shows up with dinner, though he's not supposed to be there. Inside, they continue to plot and prank as they eat, Trench going deadly with his idea, and Liz Stride, the stage manager, busts them, kicking Trench out. Onstage, they rehearse the Coffee/Dwyer murder scene with Kareem Cream and Annie Chapman, directed by Monte Druitt, in which Cade is The Ripper. Polly digs on Lillith about Kenny, and Lillith bolts for the door. Cade and Rachel follow her out, but she is gone. Jack Barnett offers them a ride. Cade declines, to go look for Lillith. Trench is upset Jack took Rachel home alone. Arriving home, where a party is raging, Trench fantasizes with a reluctant Cade about killing Jack and Paul onstage, during the Koontz murder scene. In the theater, they run through the Coffee/Dwyer murder, and Cade runs offstage to find his cloak and knife. Kenny is missing.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?501009</url></doc>
