<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="501077">
  <docid>501077</docid>
  <title>Slave Farm</title>
  <year>1991</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Tarsis, Brian</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adult</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>sex</keyword>
    <keyword>beautiful-woman</keyword>
    <keyword>hardcore</keyword>
    <keyword>female-nudity</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">X</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>D'Artagnet, Francois</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Candi (I)</actor>
      <role>Bobbie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cassidy (I)</actor>
      <role>Emily</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Comshaw, Lisa (I)</actor>
      <role>Prisoner #1</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>D'Angelo, Desi</actor>
      <role>Amanda</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Haze, Darian</actor>
      <role>Prisoner #2</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kunowa, Maya</actor>
      <role>Mae</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McCullough, Shanna</actor>
      <role>Mistress</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Shanna McCollough is the Mistress of Slave Farm, where captured women toil before being shipped off into slavery. She also has an operation in the city, where fresh victims are held before being shipped off to the farm. Fawna and Darian Haze are two such victims brought to the farm by Candy, Shanna's right-hand woman. Fawna and Darian work alongside Rebecca, but when their weeding job shows no signs of finishing soon, Shanna decides to punish the two recruits. The pair are chained and whipped before they take turns being pony girls, pulling Shanna around the farm in a cart. Meanwhile, Emily escapes but is caught. Shanna blames Candy for the escape and spanks her before punishing Emily. Shanna leaves for her city operation, where Maya has brought in Marilyn to the cell occupied by Desi and Maya's sweetie Stephanie, who expects Marilyn to kiss her feet. When Marilyn tells her to kiss something else, she is hauled away for punishment, first a whipping, then suspension from the ceiling. Desi picks a fight with Stephanie and winds up getting punished by Shanna before Stephanie joins her. When word reaches the city that the inmates have overrun Slave Farm, Shanna loses control of the city operation as well, and she winds up pulling weeds, in chains, on her own farm.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?501077</url></doc>
