<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="502247">
  <docid>502247</docid>
  <title>Small Town Girl</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Daniels, Jill (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>small-town</keyword>
    <keyword>observational-documentary</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">27 September 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">82</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Daniels, Jill (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Daniels, Jill (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Daniels, Jill (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Binns, Joanne</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bithell, Charlotte</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Shot over 5 years from the start of 2001, Small Town Girl is a unique and moving portrait of three British girls growing from childhood into adolescence. Joanne and Charlotte live in a small racially divided town, Nelson, in the north of England and face the daily harsh reality of the high tension between the Muslim Asian and white population. Joanne has an Iranian father she has never met; a mother imprisoned in a high risk mental hospital for burning a house down, and she is fostered into a very poor, born-again white Christian family. The church seems to provide her with the family she never had. When her foster mother dies suddenly, Joanne turns back inside herself and increasingly to the safety of the church. For Charlotte the answer to the problem of growing up is to grasp on to the superficiality of appearance, clothes, make up and style. She takes the easy way out, including dropping her Asian friends when the going gets tough. For Sian living in Frome, a town in the south west of England where there are no places to go, the only attraction seem to be boys and their cars, and alcohol and drugs are hard to resist. The filmmaker's presence provides the entry to a growing intimate relationship between herself and the girls. As the film unfolds, and the girls face relationships and sex, their behaviour changes in surprising, humorous and sometimes tragic ways.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?502247</url></doc>
