<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="502390">
  <docid>502390</docid>
  <title>Smashing Pumpkins: If All Goes Wrong</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Andrew, Felix</editor>
    <editor>Coloma, Justin</editor>
    <editor>Salkind, James A.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>tour-documentary</keyword>
    <keyword>pete-townshend</keyword>
    <keyword>live-concert</keyword>
    <keyword>orange-peel</keyword>
    <keyword>fillmore-auditorium</keyword>
    <keyword>smashing-pumpkins</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
    <soundmix>DTS</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">1 December 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Belgium">17 October 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">11 November 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">271</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Gulick, Jack</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Cupit, Sandi</producer>
    <producer>Catullo, Daniel E.</producer>
    <producer>Gulick, Jack</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Corgan, Billy (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chamberlin, Jimmy</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Corgan, Billy (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harriton, Lisa</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Perez, Darren</actor>
      <role>Audience Member</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Schroeder, Jeff</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A full concert filmed in late July and early August of 2007 over five of the 11 sold-out nights at the famed Fillmore Auditorium in San Francisco, CA. Features seven all new tracks not available anywhere else, along with new versions of fan favorites and a selection of Pumpkins rarities. From the opening note to the final chord, the documentary If All Goes Wrong showcases a band returning with an "enveloping epic force" (Los Angeles Times) as it traces The Smashing Pumpkins during their 19-show residency, which began with eight shows at Asheville, NC's Orange Peel in late June and continued through 11 sold-out nights at San Francisco's famed Fillmore Auditorium. Interviews with band members, fans, journalists and fellow musicians reveal the fears, excitement, determination, exhaustion and tension inherent in main singer-songwriter and lead guitarist Billy Corgan and his newly revitalized musical unit. The documentary also includes Voices Of The Ghost Children, a featurette about the band's fans, and an interview with The Who's legendary guitarist and songwriter Pete Townshend as bonus material. The band explore the freedom afforded to them in a live setting, including the 30+ minute opus "Gossamer". The Fillmore Residency also includes five songs recorded live from the floor of The Fillmore that gives fans an intimate glimpse of the band as a performing entity.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?502390</url></doc>
