<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="503230">
  <docid>503230</docid>
  <title>Sneham Kosam</title>
  <year>1999</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Telugu</language>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">U</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">1 January 1999</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Ravikumar, K.S.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Rathnam, A.M.</producer>
    <producer>Selvam, A.</producer>
    <producer>Stephan, C.P.</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>S.A., Raj Kumar</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Babu Mohan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brahmanandam</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chiranjeevi (I)</actor>
      <role>Simhadri/Chinnayya</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kota, Srinivasa Rao</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mallikharjunarao</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Meena (I)</actor>
      <role>Prabhavati 'Prabha' 'Guddiya'</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Narayana, M.S.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Raj, Prakash</actor>
      <role>Peddabbayi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ravikumar, K.S.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vijayakumar (I)</actor>
      <role>Prabhavati's dad</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Prabhavati lives a wealthy lifestyle in India with her dad, mom, and elder sister, Rani. Rani is of marriageable age and her marriage is arranged with her mom's half-brother, but just after the marriage one of their servants, Sheroo, a close friend of her dad's, kills her mother, is arrested by the Police, tried in Court, and sentenced to 15 years in jail. Since that day relations have been strained between her dad, Rani, and her husband. She re-locates to U.S.A. to study, and when she returns she finds that Sheroo's has been replaced by his son, Veeru, and runs their household, while there has been no improvement in the relationship between her dad and Rani and her family, which also includes, Veena, Rani's daughter. Prabhavati attempts to bridge the misunderstandings between her dad and sister, but to no avail, and when she proposes to get married to Rani's nephew, Ranjeet, her father opposes this tooth and nail. Then Sheroo is discharged from prison and returns home to find that Rani, Prabhavati, and even Veeru hate him. Watch what happens when Sheroo finds out that Prabhavati has accused Veeru of molesting her, and the impact this has on everyone concerned.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?503230</url></doc>
