<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="505431">
  <docid>505431</docid>
  <title>Solomon Enev</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Goldberg, Jeffrey (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Russia">23 June 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="France">89</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Goldberg, Jeffrey (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Goldberg, Jeffrey (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Goldberg, Jeffrey (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Galarneau, Francois</composer>
    <composer>Henon, Vincent</composer>
    <composer>Katsarski, Plamen</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Campbell, Alexander (II)</actor>
      <role>Petr Pastin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dean, Patrick (I)</actor>
      <role>Agent 2</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dossin, Estelle</actor>
      <role>Nadia</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gontcharova, Tatiana</actor>
      <role>Millla Pastin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Haggerty, John D.</actor>
      <role>Agent 1</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Henry, Paula Jo</actor>
      <role>Rachel Williams</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hollidge, Nigel</actor>
      <role>Agent 5.11 - Narrator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Koumpan, Alexander</actor>
      <role>Joshua Enev</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Koumpan, Igor</actor>
      <role>Solomon Enev</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mercadal, Franck</actor>
      <role>Christophe Dubois</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Morris, Michael (II)</actor>
      <role>Charles</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vincent, Jacques</actor>
      <role>Vassilli Zhuckov</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Walsh, Jesse Joe</actor>
      <role>Gregorii Trepolov</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In the summer of 2000, what communism had failed to accomplish a half-century ago capitalism had achieved. The leaders of Russia and China signed an exclusive free trade and military agreement. The Chinese-Russo trade pact promised Russia's infant market economy access to Chinese consumers behind the Great Wall in return for which Beijing would see it's thirst for oil and for military technology and training quenched by Russia. Throughout the West the pact signaled a very alarming new political and economic reality that was unacceptable. NATO and its allies were left with only three choices to prevent the pact from being put into action; diplomacy, confrontation or the CIA. Left with no choice the CIA used a paid informant, Petr Pastin, a member of a tiny communist organization in Paris, the SCR, to plan a robbery that would stop the first investment between China and Russia from ever happening. The heist was organized for five assailants, but at the last minute the leader of the operation, Ivan Enev, asked a sixth person to drive the getaway car, his brother Solomon Enev. Solomon had no political convictions and was an artist comfortably living far away from his family, a choice he made long ago following his father's assassination. His father Joshua was a famous political theorist who was mysteriously killed in a Berlin Hotel in 1998. At that moment Solomon cut all links to his family, while his brother Ivan followed in their father's political footsteps. On the summer day of the operation, five suspects were killed at the scene of the crime as the Geneva police authorities received an anonymous tip that the armed car carrying the first transfer of money between China and Russia was endangered. They later found an abandoned car with French license plates near the scene of the robbery, which prompted them to launch a European-wide manhunt for the unexpected sixth suspect. Solomon, after receiving a message from his now dead brother flees to Paris in search of what has happened and a way to free himself from a mess he never planned to get into. In the process he finds a bag that his brother left in an abandoned school locker, which is of great value to the CIA, the SCR and the answer to who killed his father. Five years later, following the events of the summer of 2000 the Chinese-Russo Trade Pact ceased to exist for reasons that neither nation publicly disclosed. The SCR has vanished and the story of Solomon Enev is only known to those who lived it.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?505431</url></doc>
