<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="505953">
  <docid>505953</docid>
  <title>Someplace in Between</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Alvarado, Daniel (VII)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">11 December 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">10</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Leoni, Michael</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Boutte Brothers, The</producer>
    <producer>Exler, Ross</producer>
    <producer>Goldberg, Eden</producer>
    <producer>Kaufer, Michelle</producer>
    <producer>Regitko, George W.</producer>
    <producer>Richmond, Nina</producer>
    <producer>Katzin, Erica</producer>
    <producer>Wade, April (I)</producer>
    <producer>Wish, Corey</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Leoni, Michael</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Montoya, Michael</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Boutte, Banks</actor>
      <role>Delivery Guy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>DiMiceli, Deborah</actor>
      <role>CEO Woman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gourdin, Joel</actor>
      <role>Business Man</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>James, James</actor>
      <role>Maintenance Man</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Katzin, Erica</actor>
      <role>Assistant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moraes, Luisa</actor>
      <role>Hot Girl</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Have you ever been stuck in an elevator? These 7 people have. A prissy CEO woman, a self-conscious assistant, a distant hot girl, an obnoxious businessman, a disgruntled maintenance man, a dorky pizza delivery boy and a morose Gothic chick enter the elevator at 1111 Langhall Blvd. at 5pm on Friday. No sooner do they begin moving toward the lobby than they come to an abrupt and frightening stop. As we get a sneak peak into their thoughts and insecurities, the voice from above exclaims 'It will just be a few minutes!' Hours later, nerves are wearing thin and the elevator comes to life with the sounds of fidgeting and restlessness. 4 hours pass. It's hot. It's uncomfortable. It's getting ridiculous. With a little help from some marijuana that the delivery boy has had tucked away, the group begins to open up to one another, shedding their previous facades and sharing deeply personal secrets. When the elevator drops dramatically once more, they cling to each other, no longer strangers, but new allies in this fight for life. Will they return again to be the stereotypes that they have worked so diligently to hide themselves in - or are they forever changed by being stuck Someplace In Between?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?505953</url></doc>
