<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="506518">
  <docid>506518</docid>
  <title>Son of India</title>
  <year>1962</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">U</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <directors>
    <director>Khan, Mehboob (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Naushad (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Garewal, Simi</actor>
      <role>Lalita</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jayant (I)</actor>
      <role>Jung 'J.B.' Bahadur</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kamaljit</actor>
      <role>Kishore</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kanhaiyalal (I)</actor>
      <role>Paro's dad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Sajid (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khote, Durga</actor>
      <role>Head Nun</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumkum</actor>
      <role>Kamla</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lilian (III)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mayer, Ruby</actor>
      <role>Paro</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mukri</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Murad</actor>
      <role>Judge</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Singh, Bakhtawar</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Kamla comes from a wealthy family and is the only child. She meets with and falls in love with Kishore, both get married, without approval of Kamla's dad, and are subsequently parents to Gopal. Shortly thereafter, Kamla finds out that Kishore has never loved her, and had married her only for her wealth. When confronted, Kishore does admit but only after being pressured by J.B. alias Jung Bahadur, who wants Two Lakh Rupees or he will abduct and kill Gopal. She leaves, becomes a nun, but ends up getting separated from her son. She goes home to live with her father, while Kishore becomes a homeless bum, &amp; Gopal ends up with a foster mom. Years later both father and son are unknowingly re-united when both are arrested for stealing someone's wallet. Kishore accepts the blame and is sentenced to 2 months in Jail, while Gopal falls in the clutches of none other than J.B. himself, who is now standing for elections. In the meantime, Kamla, who still lives with her parents, meets and befriends a woman named Lalita. One day Lalita introduces her to fiancé - much to the shock of Kamla she finds herself being introduced to her very own husband. The question remains, will Kishore and Kamla ever get back together again, and what will be the fate of young Gopal?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?506518</url></doc>
