<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="508052">
  <docid>508052</docid>
  <title>Souled Out</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Adelman, Charles (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Paul, David (IV)</producer>
    <producer>Paul, Peter (I)</producer>
    <producer>Adelman, Charles (I)</producer>
    <producer>Kelly, Jacqueline A.</producer>
    <producer>Walley, Keith (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Adelman, Charles (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Busey, Gary</actor>
      <role>Gabriel (The Angel)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kelly, Jacqueline A.</actor>
      <role>Kara</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Longo, Tony</actor>
      <role>Soul Broker</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Paul, David (I)</actor>
      <role>Ace Stevens</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Paul, Peter (I)</actor>
      <role>Dorian (The Devil)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Smith, J.W. (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sontag, Frank (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Ace Stevens (David Paul) is a struggling musician dealing with his midlife woes, and balancing his life out as an illegitimate father to a young boy. Once the opportunity arises from an encounter with a Soul Broker (Tony Longo) Ace sells his soul to the Devil (Peter Paul). Soon after, three beautiful vixens, Agents for the Reapers, come to take his body away. He cannot live on Earth without a Soul. In an effort to get his soul back he calls on the Devil. Unfortunately, the Devil has already sold his soul to someone else. Breaking his contract, the Devil must help Ace find his soul. A journey which goes from soul owner to soul owner. Each person tries on the soul and sells it to someone else for various reasons. Along the way they pick up a wild-eyed Angel (Gary Busey), who joins in the misadventures of a man searching for his soul, his identity and his heart. A movie that is as heartfelt as it is funny, combining the human search for identity with the struggle between good and evil, life and death and the ultimate question of who we are.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?508052</url></doc>
