<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="508193">
  <docid>508193</docid>
  <title>Soundproof</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Wildash, Matt</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>hitchcockian</keyword>
    <keyword>suspicious-neighbor</keyword>
    <keyword>nosy-neighbor</keyword>
    <keyword>sound-effect</keyword>
    <keyword>suburban</keyword>
    <keyword>mysterious-behavior</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">6 March 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">14</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="default">14</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Wildash, Matt</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Harwood, Paula</producer>
    <producer>Wildash, Matt</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Wildash, Matt</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Evans, Jayne</actor>
      <role>Diane</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Keighley, Anna</actor>
      <role>Victim</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lyth, Sadie</actor>
      <role>Alice</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McDonald, Andrew (IV)</actor>
      <role>Ben</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pizzey, Christopher</actor>
      <role>Ray</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>--- CAUTION! SPOILERS! --- Ray wakes from the best dream he's had in years to the sound of screaming. After failing to get confirmation from his slumbering wife Alice that it was a scream he heard, he turns over and goes back to sleep, only to be immediately woken again by another LOUDER scream. He leaps out of bed and rushes to the window but all he sees is the dark cul-de-sac in which they live, and a single light on in the opposite neighbour's window. Fighting fatigue, Ray keeps watching and listening. Then suddenly another scream, this one loud enough to wake Alice who becomes as intrigued as her husband with just what's going on over there. Some time later, both Alice and Ray are still watching but just as Ray has to nudge his sleepy wife awake, they spot their neighbour driving off. Alice leaps upon the chance to send her husband across the street to investigate. A reluctant Ray discovers the back door has been left open and after much indecision (and walkie-talkied persuasion from Alice) steps inside. He finds nothing downstairs but somehow accidentally manages to switch his walkie-talkie off after a sudden shout from Alice scares him out of his skin. Suddenly hears a pained whimper from upstairs and heads towards it! Meanwhile Alice, who has temporarily nodded off again, suddenly wakes to see their neighbours car returning! Ray creeps up the stairs but again finds nothing. As he's about to leave he suddenly hears that same scream again! He turns, steps towards the room it's coming from and bursts inside to find their neighbour Ben sat at a computer playing with the sound mix and putting the finishing touches to a particularly bad-looking horror film! Terrified, Ben turns to see a rather sheepish-looking Ray trying his best to back away unnoticed. Ben ejects his neighbour furiously. Ray runs from the back door leaving Ben cursing his nosy neighbours. Then Ben switches on the light in the kitchen to reveal a young woman strung up; beaten, bloodied, unconscious. Without even a flicker, Ben places a large microphone in front of the woman and wakes her just as his wife enters struggling with a large black bin liner full of something heavy.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?508193</url></doc>
