<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="508997">
  <docid>508997</docid>
  <title>SpaceCraft #008</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Jung, Min Woo</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">9 July 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Jung, Min Woo</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Jun-Heon, Oh</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>A spacecraft that runs out of fuel makes an emergency landing on a small planet in the peaceful and quiet universe. The pilot of the spacecraft, a duck, wanders around the hot and dry planet feeling thirsty. The duck finds a free soda vending machine. The duck presses the button to get a soda, but it doesn't work. The duck gets angry because the vending machine doesn't work even with the repetitive presses and he bangs on the machine. When the angry duck bangs on and shakes the machine, the pig appears from the back of the machine. The pig appeases the duck and hits the vending machine and soda cans come out The duck drinks it deliciously. As time goes by and the night comes, the big moon appears in the sky. The duck easy his thirst and becomes comfortable and falls asleep under the moonlight. Suddenly, a big black shadow carefully passes by the duck. The black shadow under the moonlight appears to be the pig with big soda cans. The pig carefully approaches to the duck's spacecraft. The pig fiercely shakes those soda cans. And the pig puts the cans into the jet nozzles of the spacecraft. The pig opens the soda can in the jet nozzle and the spacecraft rises up into the sky with the impetus of the soda cans. The duck wakes up because of big noise that the spacecraft rises up and the duck sees the sky. But the spacecraft is disappeared to the sky. An empty can hits the head of the duck as he gazes vacantly and the pig takes the space trip as it dreams.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?508997</url></doc>
