<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="509724">
  <docid>509724</docid>
  <title>Specter's Rock</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Eisenstadt, Josh</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Mystery</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Eisenstadt, Josh</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ritter, Robin</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Eisenstadt, Josh</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Burns, Greg (II)</composer>
    <composer>Burns, Jeff (I)</composer>
    <composer>Kirk, Brian (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Aarons, Bonnie</actor>
      <role>Verna Frenz</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Clemons, Michael (II)</actor>
      <role>Harris Frenz</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Eisenstadt, Josh</actor>
      <role>Minks</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grace, Dorrie</actor>
      <role>Wendy Molanko</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Haight, Brad</actor>
      <role>Leon Giton</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harrison, Jonathan (I)</actor>
      <role>The Lurker</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kane, Jamielyn</actor>
      <role>Clara</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kaplan, Quentin</actor>
      <role>Detective Goodbar</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Plunge Into the bizarre happenings of Lamplight County. Geneva Brading, a frightened young woman awakens in terror at 4:00 AM as she discovers her boyfriend, Halbert Olshan, standing in the corner of her bedroom. The following morning she learns Halbert was murdered at the same time of his nightmarish appearance. After receiving a threatening note from Halbert's killer, Geneva is sent to a safe house. Travis Martin, a philosophical seeker, becomes obsessed with finding and helping the now sequestered Geneva after seeing her on a news broadcast. Is Geneva his one true love and the key to his future? Are Travis' metaphysical theories craziness or an altered awareness of true reality? What is the secret of the mysterious Specter's Rock? Leon Giton, an impulsive hitman, receives an enigmatic and anonymous contract to kill a girl who sells lotion on a street corner. This "lotion girl" appears to have befriended Geneva Brading. Detective O'Malley, the Interrogator and their various flunkies are on the case to discover the identity of Halbert's killer before he (or she) strikes again. Travis Martin becomes a prime suspect as police become aware of his obsession to find Geneva and his philosophies regarding perception, dreams and reality. The various plots and subplots all lead to one shocking conclusion with more than a few laughs in between. These are the players of Specter's Rock, the surreal independent thriller. A story of murder and fear. A story of self discovery. A story of a girl in the midst of forces she does not understand. A story of the lengths a man will go to find true love. This is the world of Specter's Rock.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?509724</url></doc>
