<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="509717">
  <docid>509717</docid>
  <title>Spectator 3-D</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">25 June 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">53</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="USA">23</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Potter, Christopher (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Potter, Robin Hall</producer>
    <producer>Potter, Christopher (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Potter, Christopher (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Weber, Kevin (III)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bruff, Clyde J.</actor>
      <role>Detective Frett</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Burgess, Cynthia</actor>
      <role>Interviewer #2</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Caspillo, Glen</actor>
      <role>Manuel Samson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ellis, Keith (I)</actor>
      <role>Defense Attorney</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>MacKellan, Patrick</actor>
      <role>TV Anchor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Marrone, Dominick</actor>
      <role>Joe</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shah, Rajiv (II)</actor>
      <role>Detective Ray</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Soderburg, Jim</actor>
      <role>District Attorney</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Thom, David (II)</actor>
      <role>Date</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Cynthia Mash, avoiding a pestering phone call from Mom, steps out onto her first floor balcony. She sees a woman enter her building and then a man exit. She hardly notices them. Cynthia's best friend Joe walks up and they converse about a party they are to attend. While she's recovering from a hangover the next day, the police come to her door. Detectives Ray and Frett are asking questions about a death in her building the day before. The victim is Manuel Samson, a retired baseball player and gambler. Cynthia knows little but remembers the man and woman she saw outside the building. Cynthia is asked to come to the police station, where she views secret recordings that the victim made. Cynthia is shocked to see herself on the recordings and is fascinated by seeing herself from someone else's perspective. She identifies the man and woman from a photo lineup. Meanwhile, the murder has received minor national attention because of the illicit fame of the victim and his secret recordings. Cynthia is asked to testify about who she saw, and she watches the trial on her TiVo and pauses the TV on a man's face. Cynthia looks strangely at the man. She tries to remember the day she testified about. Spectator is a stereoscopic (3D) film about memory, perception, and perspective. A realistic use of stereoscopy drives the audience to experience Cynthia's reality, and decide what it is to remember.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?509717</url></doc>
