<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="510353">
  <docid>510353</docid>
  <title>Spielberg on Spielberg</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>McKenzie, Bryan (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Biography</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>filmmaker</keyword>
    <keyword>film-director</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Germany">20 December 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="France">19 September 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Hungary">6 April 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Hong Kong">31 March 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Australia">10 May 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">9 July 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Denmark">24 September 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">86</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Schickel, Richard</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Freeman, Douglas (II)</producer>
    <producer>Brown, Tom (VII)</producer>
    <producer>Schickel, Richard</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Schickel, Richard</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Cohen, Casey (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Spielberg, Steven</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Considered to be one of the most respected film critics in the country, as evidenced by his work with Time magazine, Richard Schickel is widely known for writing, producing and directing a number of documentaries about Hollywood and its most important figures. As the producer of works such as "Woody Allen: A Life in Film" and "Scorsese on Scorsese", Schickel allows legendary filmmakers to explain their work. This time, Schickel has reunited with producer and director Steven Spielberg (welcome back from Mars if you haven't heard of him) for his most recent effort, "Spielberg on Spielberg", which premiered on Turner Classic Movies. The pair also collaborated on 2000's "Shooting War", a profile of World War II photographers. Already a living legend, the Oscar-winning director has chosen to share one of the most impressive American success stories: that of a young filmmaker who was brave enough to dare to dream and who would eventually give the world some of the most entertaining and successful movies, including "Jaws", "Close Encounters of the Third Kind", "Raiders of the Lost Ark", "E.T. The Extra-Terrestrial", "Schindler's List", "Jurassic Park", and "Saving Private Ryan". In the past, Spielberg has chosen not to record audio commentary tracks for DVDs of his movies. This is the first time he talks about his films in any kind of detail. He speaks for 90 minutes about other directors and friends and about his well-known (and not so well-known) movies throughout his amazing career as one of the world's most celebrated and influential directors.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?510353</url></doc>
