<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="510838">
  <docid>510838</docid>
  <title>Splendid Splinters: The Armand LaMontagne Story</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Piermarini, Carl</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">G</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">6 February 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">58</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Piermarini, Carl</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Celli, Jack</producer>
    <producer>D'Entremont, Jeremy</producer>
    <producer>Piermarini, Carl</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>Splendid Splinters: The Armand LaMontagne Story "Splendid Splinters: is an hour long documentary focusing on the life and works of world-renowned master sculptor and artist Armand LaMontagne. The film showcases the dynamic talents and inspirational works of the artist starting with his early work as an illustrator, furniture maker, painter and wood carver, right through to his most recent commissioned sculptures. Five years in the making, and selected for national broadcast distribution on PBS, the production also spotlights the creation of the artist's most recent masterpiece "On Deck" from its inception to its unveiling. Armand LaMontagne ranks as one of America's pre-eminent sculptors of celebrated personalities. He has created works depicting the images of Ted Williams, General George S. Patton, Babe Ruth and many others. He is a self-taught artist who has refined his skills through practicing his profession. He is best recognized for his life-size wood and bronze sculptures of sports figures. His significant sculptures are housed at The Baseball Hall of Fame, Cooperstown, NY; The New England Sports Museum, Boston; The Patton Museum, Fort Knox, Kentucky; and the The Basketball Hall of Fame, Springfield,Massachusets.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?510838</url></doc>
