<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="510827">
  <docid>510827</docid>
  <title>Splatterhouse 3</title>
  <year>1993</year>
  <type>VideoGame</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>h.p.-lovecraft</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">M</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">18 March 1993</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Shimotsuma, Sammy</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Shimotsuma, Sammy</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Lovecraft, H.P.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Eiko, Milky</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Time has passed since the escape in Splatterhouse 2 and Rick is slowly regaining his sanity. But at night, he is still haunted by nightmares from the place. Rick has married Jennifer and they have a son, David. Now, in the final Splatterhouse installment, Rick finds out that an entity called The Evil One has kidnapped his beloved family members. He has no choice but to wear the demon mask with the supernatural powers to save Jennifer and David from the demon-infested Splatterhouse. The third title in the series builds upon the game-play of its predecessors. The game consists of six consecutive levels in a huge mansion. In a race against time, you have to wipe the demons from each room and find the quickest path to the boss area. After clearing a room, you can use an in-game map to decide upon the quickest route. Improvements over the second title include moving between rooms in multiple directions, multiple endings based on your performance, special moves for Rick and better graphics. It still has a horror theme and maintains the same level of gore and violence. You can collect weapons such as a skull-smashing baseball bat, an ax and cinder blocks. If you get knocked down, a ghost will try to snatch your weapon and drop it in another room of the house. Other collectible items include extra lives, health meat or orbs. These orbs build up a power meter. Upon completion, you have the ability to transform into a berserk mutant for a short time. The cut-scenes feature real actors who act out the characters.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?510827</url></doc>
