<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="511034">
  <docid>511034</docid>
  <title>SpongeBob SquarePants: Lights, Camera, Pants!</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>VideoGame</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">18 November 2005</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">21 October 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Baker, Dee Bradley</actor>
      <role>Bubble Bass/Squilliam/Kevin C. Cucumber/Don the Whale</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brown, Clancy (I)</actor>
      <role>Mr. Krabs</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fagerbakke, Bill</actor>
      <role>Patrick</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Joles, Bob</actor>
      <role>Man Ray</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kenny, Tom (I)</actor>
      <role>SpongeBob SquarePants</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lawrence, Carolyn</actor>
      <role>Sandy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lawrence, Mr.</actor>
      <role>Plankton</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>North, Nolan</actor>
      <role>Gill Hammerstein</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>When 3 episodes of the popular series "The New Adventures of Mermaid Man and Barnacle Boy", is supposed to be filmed in Bikini Bottom, nobody shows up to audition except for one yellow sponge. With the show in danger of being canceled, the show's producer, Gill Hammerstein makes it SpongeBob's job to collect props and find actors in order for the show to go on. After SpongeBob finds them and filmed the 1st episode, Mermaidman and Barnacleboy fail to show up for the 2nd episode. It is SpongeBob's job to find Mermaidman and Barnacleboy and gain roles for him and his friends in order for the show to go on. After SpongeBob finds Mermaidman and Barnacleboy and the 2nd episode was filmed, the producers uses the locals as actors for the 3rd episode. All your favorites are desperate to impress the talent scouts who have created a game party that has series of action-packed challenges to test the wannabe stars. Join SpongeBob, Patrick, Sandy, Squidward, Mr. Krabs and Plankton as they compete for 10 different roles, including the coveted super villain role.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?511034</url></doc>
