<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="511869">
  <docid>511869</docid>
  <title>Spy Fox: Dry Cereal</title>
  <year>1997</year>
  <type>VideoGame</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>video-game</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <producers>
    <producer>Barrett, Bret (I)</producer>
    <producer>Carlton, Brad (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Barrett, Bret (I)</writer>
    <writer>Hill, Julia (II)</writer>
    <writer>Rinehart, Barry</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kirk, Geoff</composer>
    <composer>Soule, Julian</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Boynton, Ken</actor>
      <role>Professor Quack, Weasel Doorman, Sal The Sailor, Narrator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Burns, Scott (I)</actor>
      <role>Howard Hugh Heifer Udderly III, Walter Wireless</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Levin, Kathy</actor>
      <role>Bea Bear, Mata Hairy, Goon #3 (Guard at Kid's Office), Stewardess</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lowery, J.</actor>
      <role>William The Kid</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Manley, Dex</actor>
      <role>Artimice J. Bigpig, Hong Kong Doodle, President Bull Clinton</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Scully, David</actor>
      <role>Captain Drydock, Gilbert, Mr. Waltz, Tattooed Sailor, Radio Room Rabbit</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shapiro, Michael (I)</actor>
      <role>Johnny Gecko</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zenk, Robert</actor>
      <role>Spy Fox</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>William The Kid has stolen all the dairy cows in an effort to take over the dairy industry. SPY Corp has sent their top agent, Spy Fox to stop William's plan of dairy destruction. Monkey Penny (who gives Spy Fox important clues), Professor Quack (gives Spy Fox his inventions) Walter Wireless (who helps Spy Fox track down William The Kid's hidden fortress) and Mata Hairy (who gives Spy Fox the passwords) help out Spy Fox on his mission. Along the way he meets villians Artemis J. Bigpig (villainous "go fish" player), Russian Blue (seductive owner of the SS Deadweight), and Hong Kong Doodle (NOG's top martial arts master) and of course, William The Kid himself. Set in the Greek island of Asodopolos, Spy Fox gets clues from the inhabitants of the island, and aboard the suspicious SS Deadweight. It's up to Spy Fox to stop William's plans to make dairy milk go bad.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?511869</url></doc>
