<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="512102">
  <docid>512102</docid>
  <title>Squatterpunk</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Ang, Lawrence</editor>
    <editor>Carlos, Caloy</editor>
    <editor>Matutina, Anna Isabelle</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Tagalog</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Philippines</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Netherlands">31 January 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Germany">21 January 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Denmark">11 November 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Philippines">79</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Khavn (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Khavn (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Khavn (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Brockas, The</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hapon</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Filmed in just one day, Squatterpunk follows an eight year old Slum King named Hapon, a cocky would-be gangster with a Travis Bickle haircut, and his rat-bag minions through one of the thousands of shanty towns that spring up between the cracks in the Manila pavements. The manic collage of stunning hand-held black and white images capture kids being kids as they frolic amidst the cardboard and corrugated walls of home-sweet-home and the surrounding debris, human and otherwise. Like watching infants at play at a car crash, it's a mesmerizing, almost seamless collision of social realism and visual poetry. It's a rush to the heart, too, fueled by the mostly improvised punk score by Khavn's outfit The Brockas. The relentless clang-bang drowns the need for dialog or most background noise, leaving a stark impression without comment and, more significantly, without judgment. A vivid and jarring collection of postcards of innocence at the brink of a short and possibly non-existent adolescence, of simple pleasures amidst appalling squalor, of human junk that society ignores in a country the rest of the world prefers to forget.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?512102</url></doc>
