<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="512353">
  <docid>512353</docid>
  <title>Sreeram</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Venkatesh, Martand K.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Telugu</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">21 June 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="India">162</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Aditya, V.N.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Krishna, Burugapally Siva Rama</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Brothers, Paruchuri</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>R.P., Patnaik</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anitha (III)</actor>
      <role>Madhu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deepa (III)</actor>
      <role>Sister</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kiran, Uday</actor>
      <role>Sreeram</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Krishna, Siva</actor>
      <role>Sreeram's father</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Narayana, M.S.</actor>
      <role>Neighbour</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Paruchuri, Venkateswara Rao</actor>
      <role>Sreeram's uncle</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vidyarthi, Ashish</actor>
      <role>Encounter shankar</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Sreeram (Uday Kiran) is an unemployed youth who tries for the police selections to become a Sub Inspector of Police. There is a righteous police officer Narayana (Siva Krishna) who encourages Sreeram to become a police officer. He has a steady girl friend Madhu (Anitha). One evening, Sreeram beats a guy black and blue as that guy misbehaves with Madhu. Later on, Sreeram realizes that the person whom he has beaten is a deadly CI (Circle Inspector) of Police whose name is 'Encounter Shankar' (Asish Vidyardhi). Sreeram's sister marriage is settled with the brother of Madhu. When the marriage of Sreeram's sister is about to happen, Encounter Shankar traces Sreeram and beats him up badly in police station and leaves him on a railway track and expects the train to run over Sreeram. But luckily, the will-powered Sreeram jumps form the train track and escapes from the death. The parents of Sreeram find out the beaten up Sreeram with the help of Narayana and they join him in a hospital. The doctor inspects the injuries, dresses him up and tells them that Sreeram won't be able to move his body for 3 months and he needs complete rest. But his interview for SI post is scheduled in the next month, which requires him to be physically fit. He motivates himself and attends interview as with 100% fitness. In the meantime, Encounter Shankar is under impression that Sreeram is dead. But Sreeram is selected for the post of SI and Encounter Shankar is asked to enquire and give the conduct certificate of Sreeram. After confirming that Sreeram is alive, Encounter Shankar gives a bad conduct certificate. And he also teases Sreeram into a street fight and takes clandestine photographs and produces them to the higher authorities as evidence. The hide and seek game between Sreeram and Encounter Shankar comes to an end when Encounter Shankar comes to Sreeram's place to humiliate him. How Sreeram win over Encounter Shankar is that point that is covered in the climax.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?512353</url></doc>
