<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="512316">
  <docid>512316</docid>
  <title>Srecno Kekec</title>
  <year>1963</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Persin, Darinka</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>based-on-novel</keyword>
    <keyword>sequel</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Slovenian</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
    <country>Yugoslavia</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="West Germany">20 November 1963</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">58</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Gale, Joze</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Ribic, Ivan</writer>
    <writer>Vandot, Josip</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Vodopivec, Marjan</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bojc, Rusa</actor>
      <role>Pehta</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Florjanc, Blanka</actor>
      <role>Mojca</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gjurin, Velimir</actor>
      <role>Kekec</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gorsic, Marija</actor>
      <role>Mother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mele, Martin</actor>
      <role>Rozle</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sever, Stane</actor>
      <role>Beggar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sotlar, Bert</actor>
      <role>Father</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Two boys, Kekec and Rozle, come to serve a farmer, with a blind daughter Mojca, as shepherds. As the night falls, the two boys start talking about a woman who lives in the mountains and is supposed to steal children. Her name is Pehta. In the morning, Kekec, Rozle and Mojca go to an Alpine cottage and Kekec promises Mojca that he will find her a remedy for her eyes. As the girl is picking flowers, Pehta arrives and takes Mojca into her cottage. She wants to keep Mojca because of her singing. Pehta is a woman herbalist and she finds a rare flower in the mountain, from which she makes a remedy for Mojca's eyes. Kekec and Rozle start looking for Mojca and they find Pehta's cottage. Rozle is so frightened that he runs away, but brave Kekec climbs trough the thatched roof of Pehta's cottage and runs away with Mojca. Pehta sends her dog - Volk (Wolf) to hunt them down, but they manage to escape it. The timid Rozle tells at home that Pehta's dog probably ate Kekec and Mojca. Mojca's father and villagers start looking for them. Pehta's sees them coming, burns her cottage down and hides. Meanwhile, Kekec brings Mojca home and as she is telling her mother that Pehta has a cure for her blindness, Kekec runs out of the house and lets himself be caught by Pehta. She takes him into her cave and tells him that she would have cured Mojca if he didn't took her away. She keeps Kekec as a servant and tells Volk to watch him as she leaves to collect flowers. Kekec makes friends with Volk and starts searching the cave for the remedy. Pehta catches him in the act, beats her dog for not obeying her and shows to Kekec that she's carrying the bottle with the remedy around her neck. The villagers are looking for Kekec, Pehta hears them and Kekec tries to get the bottle, but she throws it in the abyss in anger. Kekec escapes from the cave and finds the bottle undamaged. Pehta sets her dog on him but Volk starts barking on her. Kekec returns to the cave, shows the bottle to Pehta and she tells him, how to use the remedy - just three drops in each eye. Kekec returns home with Volk, find Mojca sleeping and pours the remedy in her eyes. She wakes up and finds out that she can see. Kekec leaves the farm with his dog.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?512316</url></doc>
