<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="513011">
  <docid>513011</docid>
  <title>Stalker</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Harding, Lisa (II)</editor>
    <editor>Yenovkian, David</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">16 November 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Borrison, Vinit</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Borrison, Vinit</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bradley, Jean (II)</actor>
      <role>Grandma McCann</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brejak, Anton</actor>
      <role>Dennis McCann</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Henley, John</actor>
      <role>Grandpa McCann</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kellerman, Sandy</actor>
      <role>Karen McCann</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mushahbash, Amer</actor>
      <role>Dominic</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Spevack, Jason</actor>
      <role>Josh McCann</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"Stalker" is a filmic prequel to a life that everyone fears; an existence where you are always being watched. The story is about a stalker; the focus is on Karen, a single mother running away from everything she loves to protect what she loves most. The film opens with Karen quickly packing her bags. She drags her son Josh out of the house and along with her; he is hesitant and doesn't want to leave. Karen ends up at her parent's house where we realize she is running away from her hometown and is terribly afraid. She leaves Josh and some belongings with her parents and runs out of the house in tears. The audience soon learns there is someone stalking Karen. Wherever Karen goes Dominic follows, she tries to lead her normal life but can't because she is constantly looking over her shoulder. Throughout the film a "voice of god" narrative explains things one should not do if being stalked. This only adds to the tension as we watch Karen continually doing the "wrong" thing which makes it easier for Dominic to follow close behind. "Stalker" is a powerful film, both to itself and as a supportive document to defenseless women who wouldn't know what to do if they were ever being 'stalked'. The film itself is simple; it doesn't try to explode with the newest and greatest special effects or Hollywood actors. The story might be seem hard to follow, but if you pay close attention to the voice over from beginning to end you will realize there is actually a linear story. This film marked Vinit Borrison's directorial debut. It was a piece that represented the work of a writer/director/cinematographer combo and couldn't have been accomplished without the hard work and dedication of the entire cast and crew. The film was entirely funded out of pocket with countless evenings without sleep, sex, and friends for a film that is truly from the heart. For filmmakers it's a world of high-stakes and compromise but in the end it always pays off?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?513011</url></doc>
