<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="513324">
  <docid>513324</docid>
  <title>Stanley Jordan Trio: The Paris Concert</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>guitar</keyword>
    <keyword>jazz</keyword>
    <keyword>paris</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">13 May 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">130</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Haynes, David (VI)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jordan, Stanley (III)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moffett, Charnett</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This DVD features a performance by one of the most gifted guitarists of his generation, Stanley Jordan. Here at the New Morning in Paris (July 2007), he is backed up by Charnett Muffett and David Haynes. Jordan could easily content himself with the title of "uncontested master of the two-handed tap technique" which allows him to play rhythm and melody simultaneously, like a pianist or like two guitarists. This spectacular ability gained him fame and respect all over the world. Stanley Jordan is, however, much more than a top-class virtuoso. His interpretations of the grand repertoire - from Bird and 'Trane to John and Paul - are true masterpieces which boldly straddle tradition and new age. But the strength &amp; depth of his multi-faceted diamond-like music stem from his early - and unshakeable - belief in the power of his art. For Stanley, making music has always been more than just entertainment; it is - in a world that needs it sorely - a genuine healing journey which will inspire &amp; at the same time cure the soul, in the immediate and utterly therapeutic sense of the word...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?513324</url></doc>
