<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="514535">
  <docid>514535</docid>
  <title>Static</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">13</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Trounce, Kerri</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Golding, Dominic</actor>
      <role>Peter Fisher</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lamoral-Roberts, Julian</actor>
      <role>Old Tom Fisher</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Tom Fisher is a 10 year old scientist in the making. He is an only child and has few friends, but that's just fine with him as it gives him more time to devote to his one passion in life: Radios. Tom can't get enough of them and is amazed by the idea that we are constantly surrounded by radio waves our entire lives, wherever we are. In fact Tom is so obsessed with tuning in, that he often skips school just to listen to another obscure broadcast from some distant corner of the earth. Tom lives with his father Peter, who always seems to be working, whether he be at the office or at home. We quickly see a pattern forming of their everyday lives and it's clear that father and son don't spend a great deal of time together. So whether Tom is at home or out on his bike, he seems to be alone and it is easy to understand why he likes having the radio on for company. When Tom should be at school he can always be found, a few miles from his house, sat beneath a large collection of radio masts and antenna. On one such day, he receives a message through his radio that is so intriguing and important that it may change his life forever.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?514535</url></doc>
