<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="514796">
  <docid>514796</docid>
  <title>Stealing Home</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Coffman, Aaron</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">23 July 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">42</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="USA">15</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Coffman, Aaron</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Parmentier, Bill</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Coffman, Aaron</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Godsil, Daniel</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Asser, Mark</actor>
      <role>Grady</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bibb, Libby</actor>
      <role>Sara</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harting, Brian</actor>
      <role>Peter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McCarter, Aidan</actor>
      <role>Dylan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moore, Dale D.</actor>
      <role>Dan</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Stealing Home is the story of a single mother who must recapture the relationship she once had with her son over the course of a single weekend and come to terms with the role she now plays in his life. Sara has thought out every detail of what the weekend will be like with her son, Grady, and though the house of cards can be destroyed at any moment, a steady and delicate care is needed to sustain the structure for any length of time. Her plan, which consists of introducing Grady to the man she loves and who has helped her in her new life, goes wrong at every turn and she struggles to hold onto Grady and what they could have while at the same time battling to not destroy this new life she's created for herself. Grady, feeling as though the weekend would be about only he and his mother, fights all advances she makes to incorporate him into her new life. As he resists their fragile bond slowly grows weaker until the final confrontation that has been building in him for over a year comes bursting out. They realize that what they can have is something much stronger, based on love that only comes through shared pain. The life they create will not be built on stolen memories but on new experiences and a deep understanding that together they can create a new version of home.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?514796</url></doc>
