<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="514807">
  <docid>514807</docid>
  <title>Stealing Rich</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Goodlad, Stephen</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">120</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Goodlad, Stephen</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Lehl, Rich</producer>
    <producer>Goodlad, Stephen</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Goodlad, Stephen</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arm, Mark</actor>
      <role>The P.I.</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barr, Jaye D.</actor>
      <role>Ma Lehl</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Black, Katelyn</actor>
      <role>Tereza</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cimino, Michael (III)</actor>
      <role>Gary Gitney</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Clayton, Vanessa Lynn</actor>
      <role>Mourner #1</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cloud, Zia</actor>
      <role>Mourner #2</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Colburn, Scott (II)</actor>
      <role>Pa Lehl</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dunkerley, Jed</actor>
      <role>The Bartender</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hackleman, Jaime</actor>
      <role>Mourner #3</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Itman, Jodi</actor>
      <role>Mourner #4</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lehl, Rich</actor>
      <role>Rich</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lehl, Sarah</actor>
      <role>Sarah</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rizzi, David</actor>
      <role>Conga Drummer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stone, Edwin</actor>
      <role>Jiminy Pringle</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wainwright, Matt (II)</actor>
      <role>Usher</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Things are looking up for Seattle surrealist artist Rich Lehl when a film crew arrives to make a documentary about his life and work. But Rich soon finds that the life of a celebrity artist is anything but peaceful. Badgered and belittled by a beautiful sexy interviewer named Tereza, Rich struggles valiantly to hang onto his artistic integrity in a world increasingly governed by crass commercialism and money-hungry wheeler-dealers. As Rich sinks ever deeper into the surreal nightmare world of the celebrity artist, he seeks solace (and wealth) in a strange New Age religion. A cross between Buddhism and voodoo, Buddhivoodoo seems initially to offer salvation, but an elaborate prosperity ritual soon backfires with appalling results. And the weirdness keeps getting deeper: summoned to the Office of Artistic Governance, Rich falls victim to a sadistic government agent who may not even be of this earth; a mysterious stranger arrives in the dead of the night to perform a bizarre medical procedure; meanwhile, his nutty drug-addled wife pursues a dark agenda of her own with the help of a sister she may not even have. When he finds himself trapped in a sinister international art scheme, Rich desperately turns to the only friend he has: his trusted agent, Gary Gitney. Gitney has just sold six of Rich's paintings through a gallery in Berlin. Trouble is, Rich only gave him three paintings to sell. When Rich finally decides to confront Gitney, everything hits the fan.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?514807</url></doc>
