<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="517596">
  <docid>517596</docid>
  <title>Strani amori</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Mete, Marzia</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Italian</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby SR</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Italy">21 July 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">17</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Scarpetti, Roberto</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Gambacorta, Roberto</producer>
    <producer>Scarpetti, Roberto</producer>
    <producer>Viro, Marina</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Sajot, Nordine</writer>
    <writer>Savino, Alessandro Nico</writer>
    <writer>Scarpetti, Roberto</writer>
    <writer>Viro, Marina</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Giangrande, Massimo</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grazioli, Irene</actor>
      <role>Barbara</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Barbara, a stewardess, met a man on the airplane during her flight from Milan to Bombay. For a fantastic week they become lovers in the multicolored Indian city, spending their time between the sites and long sex sessions in their hotel room. Sara works in a call center. She met a man on the phone while at work. She doesn't exactly know why, but she gave in and accepted a date with him. She was disappointed when they met for the first time because he was much older than she was. However, she was won by his playful sense of humor. Miranda used to be an upper-class housewife, totally fulfilled by her status. Everything changed when she met a man at a school play. The strong physical attraction pushed them beyond every limit. She let herself go, to the point where her lifestyle changed dramatically. Gloria runs a night bar. She has met a lot of men in her life, but she will never forget a particular one, even though nothing happened between them but a simple kiss. Nevertheless, she often yearns for him. He was to her a kind of strange brother.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?517596</url></doc>
