<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="517922">
  <docid>517922</docid>
  <title>Streaks in the Mirror</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kouroumalis, Toly</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Canada">13+</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">15 October 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">17</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Kouroumalis, Toly</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kouroumalis, Toly</producer>
    <producer>Tzoutis, Helen</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Kouroumalis, Toly</writer>
    <writer>Tzoutis, Helen</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kouroumalis, Toly</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Finnan, Sean</actor>
      <role>Matt</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Huljak, Irena</actor>
      <role>Susie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tiderington, Greg Russell</actor>
      <role>Edwin</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>There's an ideal husband by the name of Matt who has a good job, is very compassionate, sensitive man and loves his new wife Jess whom he always protects her and they move into a wonderful apartment. What could be better?! What Jess doesn't know is that Matt's ex-wife Susie has gone through a manic depression ever since Matt has left her. Is Susie depressed enough to go insane to the point of killing Jess? Jess suddenly sees images of her husband as a corpse and is getting obscene phone calls. Are they just pranks and the images are just streaks in the mirror? Jess doesn't think so as her dream of marrying the ideal husband and living in a lovely suite becomes a terrifying nightmare! But, Susie's brother Edwin is best friends with Jess and while Matt is at work from an emergency call he tries to comfort her and convinces her that his sister is not out to get her. However, one of these people are crazy enough to kill Jess. Can she trust even Edwin with all the deadly surroundings going on that's been even advertised in their local paper? Slowly Jess is getting more paranoid to the point where she feels that she'll have to kill or be killed!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?517922</url></doc>
