<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="518009">
  <docid>518009</docid>
  <title>Street Fighter II: The World Warrior</title>
  <year>1991</year>
  <type>VideoGame</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>fight</keyword>
    <keyword>brazil</keyword>
    <keyword>china</keyword>
    <keyword>number-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>cult-favorite</keyword>
    <keyword>world-tour</keyword>
    <keyword>second-part</keyword>
    <keyword>chun-li</keyword>
    <keyword>roman-numeral-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>video-game</keyword>
    <keyword>street-fight</keyword>
    <keyword>boxer</keyword>
    <keyword>las-vegas-nevada</keyword>
    <keyword>martial-arts</keyword>
    <keyword>karate</keyword>
    <keyword>contest</keyword>
    <keyword>sequel</keyword>
    <keyword>street-fighter</keyword>
    <keyword>sumo-wrestler</keyword>
    <keyword>nevada</keyword>
    <keyword>fighting-game</keyword>
    <keyword>street</keyword>
    <keyword>show-girl</keyword>
    <keyword>japan</keyword>
    <keyword>streetfighting</keyword>
    <keyword>fireball</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Japanese</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Japan</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Germany">12</certificate>
    <certificate country="USA">T</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Japan">6 February 1991</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Okamoto, Yoshiki</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Abe, Isao (I)</composer>
    <composer>Shimomura, Yôko</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>The second Street Fighter tournament is here with General M.Bison. Ryu and Ken are no strangers to the tournament. Ryu enters for a true fight, while Ken enters for competition and are some new faces. Edmond Honda (E.Honda) is fighting because he heard that sumo is nothing and now he's out to prove a point. Blanka's in the tournament for to find out about his past. Guile is out for M.Bison's blood for killing Guile's best friend Charlie and will stop at nothing to get revenge. Chun-Li is a woman with fire in her eyes and with educated feet to avenge her father's death by defeating Bison and winning the tournament. Zangief is out to prove that Mother Russia is the most powerful country in the world. Dhalsim is a Yoga master who is on a quest to defeat Bison for peace in Dhalsim's homeland. Balrog the first boss is a Mike Tyson gone extremely wrong. He was barred from the boxing ring for his violent temper. Vega is a metal claw wearing "Spanish ninja" who loves to wear a mask to protect his face from facial injuries. Sagat,the former SF Muai-Thai champion who will not stop to get back at Ryu for beating and humiliating him,and leaving a scar on his chest. Finally,Bison,the leader of Shadaloo and the main boss in the tournament who funded the tournament and is the master of the base is Thailand.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?518009</url></doc>
