<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="518394">
  <docid>518394</docid>
  <title>Strictly Global</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>music-video</keyword>
    <keyword>international-music</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-television</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">19 November 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Averett, Terrance S.</producer>
    <producer>Leyva, Mike</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Averett, Terrance S.</actor>
      <role>Host</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Leyva, Mike</actor>
      <role>Host</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>An hour long international music video show catering to the world scene, Strictly Global showcases music videos spanning every genre of music from around the world. Independent and underground, Strictly Global defies the mainstream music market, sharing an appreciation for music that ignores borders. Strictly Global highlights international artists that might otherwise be overlooked by mainstream media, taking its audience on a trek around the world every week. Strictly Global is not just about world music, it's about music from the world. Strictly Global introduces viewers to music videos they won't find anywhere else. Musicians from Chile, Japan, Thailand, Mali, Russia, England, Australia, the Philippines, Venezuela, Germany and nations all over the globe are represented. Independent American artists from Folk, Zydeco, Jazz, Blues and Bluegrass replace the mainstream American Pop, Rock and Hip-hop music which dominates the nation's airwaves. Strictly Global furthers independent media pioneer MHz Networks mission to promote inter-cultural understanding through intelligent programming and outreach-- celebrating both the diversity and universality of music. Strictly Global presents the viewer with as much diversity as possible. Hosted by producers Mike Leyva and Terrance Averett , Strictly Global provides a fresh approach to music. Mike and Terrance do not follow the traditional role of VJs you'd find on other music video programs. The music videos above all take precedence. Mike and Terrance function like radio station program directors. They appear in the beginning, introducing the show and previewing some show tidbits, and the end, closing out the show and prompting viewers to make requests through the website.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?518394</url></doc>
