<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="518959">
  <docid>518959</docid>
  <title>Stuck in the Closet</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">23</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Vlassopoulos, Nick</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Sylvester, Joey</producer>
    <producer>Vlassopoulos, Nick</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Vlassopoulos, Nick</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Armani, Hadi</actor>
      <role>Franky</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Belle, Tiana</actor>
      <role>Veronica</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Evans, James (I)</actor>
      <role>Bouncer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Manzella, Giuseppe</actor>
      <role>Bartender</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sylvester, Joey</actor>
      <role>Joey</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tasso, Val</actor>
      <role>Ifrael</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vlassopoulos, Nick</actor>
      <role>Nick</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Nick is hairstylist from Detroit who has just moved to Los Angeles with his friend Joey. It has always been Nick's dream to work in an upscale Beverly Hills salon that supermodels and actresses frequent. He quickly finds out that a certain "type" is only accepted. Joey comes up with the idea that the only way to be respected as a hairstylist in Beverly Hills is to pretend to be gay. Nick, however, is reluctant, until he decides that the idea will work if he dons a "disguise." He attempts to get a job in this disguise and it works perfectly. Nick then lives the life of the gay hairstylist at work and the straight guy outside of work. Things become more difficult when at the salon he is stationed between the flamboyantly gay Ifrael, who apparently has a crush on Nick, and the beautiful Veronica. Nick now must hide the fact that he is attracted to her. Joey joins the group as the assistant in the salon to Nick, but finds out quickly he is in for more than he asked when each day becomes an adventure at hiding Nick's real identity.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?518959</url></doc>
