<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="519004">
  <docid>519004</docid>
  <title>Student No. 1</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kotagiri, Venkateswara Rao</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Telugu</language>
    <language>Hindi</language>
    <language>Tamil</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">27 September 2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Raghavendra Rao, K.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Dutt, C. Ashwini</producer>
    <producer>Raghavendra Rao, K.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Raghavendra Rao, K.</writer>
    <writer>Raj, Pruthvi</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Keeravani, M.M.</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brahmanandam</actor>
      <role>Dr. Brahmanandam</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gajala</actor>
      <role>Anjali</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Junior, N.T.R. Rao</actor>
      <role>R. Aditya</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kanakala, Rajeev</actor>
      <role>Satya/Satish (Hindi version)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kota, Srinivasa Rao</actor>
      <role>Sampat Verma</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Aditya lives a middle-classed lifestyle in Aurangabad along with dad - Raghav, mom - Laxmi, and sister, Swati. His dad wants him to be a lawyer, but Aditya wants to be an Engineer. Arguments ensue at home and get complicated when Aditya confesses that he has killed a man named Shekhar who had abducted and was molesting a woman named Lalita. Raghav asks him to leave, Aditya surrenders to the Police, who arrest him after Lalita refuses to recognize him, and he is sentenced to life in prison initially in Aurangabad and then transferred to Vishakhapatnam. He decides to study law, and gets permission to get admitted in R.N.R. College where he finds out that unruly elements, led by Satish, rule the roost and prevent students from studying. He decides to confront Satish, makes him mend his way, while he becomes a hero and gets undivided attention from attractive Anjali. Then things gets complicated when Satish decides to forcibly woo Anjali and even threatens to throw acid on her body, the students find out about Aditya's criminal background, and Raghav himself gets arrested for leaking examination papers and accepting a bribe, is arrested and housed in the same jail as his son.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?519004</url></doc>
