<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="520118">
  <docid>520118</docid>
  <title>Sucker Punch</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Hovmand, Brian</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="UK">18</certificate>
    <certificate country="USA">R</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">26 April 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="France">6 May 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Martin, Malcolm (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Jacko, Ali</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Martin, Malcolm (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Warne, Baz</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Alexander, Gordon (III)</actor>
      <role>Buchinsky</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fargas, Antonio</actor>
      <role>Baz</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Freeman, Ian (II)</actor>
      <role>Maitland</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gunn, Tommy (III)</actor>
      <role>Villain</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hardy, Tom (I)</actor>
      <role>Rodders</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hassan, Tamer</actor>
      <role>Del</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>House, Janet</actor>
      <role>Isabelle</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>John-Jules, Danny</actor>
      <role>Harley</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kent, Jimmy</actor>
      <role>Weed</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Long, Joe (I)</actor>
      <role>News</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pyle, John</actor>
      <role>Mr. Harriman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Walters, Leon</actor>
      <role>Creel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Warne, Baz</actor>
      <role>Coburn</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Ray 'Harley' Davidson is a hustler. With flash clothes and a fast mouth, Harley lives life in the fast lane. With his passion for all things gambling, money runs like water through Harley's hands and as quickly as he makes a killing he takes a beating, normally at the poker table. Nominally an illegal prize-fight manager, Harley hasn't produced a live one in months, until Charles Buchinsky literally wanders into his life. Charles Buchinsky, street fighter extraordinaire. He's from out of town looking for a fight and the chance to tie up a few loose ends. Keeps himself to himself, lets his fists do the talking and his word is his bond. Victor Maitland, top illegal fight promoter and porn baron. Hates losing and loves the prestige of managing the best hitter in town. Harley dreams of bringing Maitland down and after seeing Buchinsky at work, engineers a fragile partnership. The duo soon becomes a hot ticket, Charles knocking out all-comers, Harley cleaning up the side-bets. Old habits die hard, however, and Harley squanders the money as quickly as Charles earns it. This alerts Maitland, who offers to buy out Buchinsky's contract. Harley refuses, and to make matters worse, Buchinsky defeats Maitland's best fighter in a brutal contest. A second offer is rebuked, but after another disastrous gambling spree, Harley finds himself heavily in debt to a local loan shark. Seeing his opportunity, Maitland buys the debt and now Harley owes him. Unless Buchinsky agrees to fight a top professional, brought in from the North, using all his winnings as the stake, Harley will never walk again. It begs the question, just who is this enigmatic fighter and is he setting Maitland up for a sucker punch or will he simply walk away with his winnings?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?520118</url></doc>
