<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="520569">
  <docid>520569</docid>
  <title>Suhag Sindoor</title>
  <year>1961</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Krishnan, R.</director>
    <director>Panju, S.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Desai, Chandrakant</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Gupta, Chitra</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chavan, Padma</actor>
      <role>Nalini</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kanhaiyalal (I)</actor>
      <role>Dayashankar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kashmiri, Sheila</actor>
      <role>Rasili</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khote, Shubha</actor>
      <role>Gulabi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Manoj (I)</actor>
      <role>Ratan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mehra, Raj</actor>
      <role>Sadhu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mishra, Leela</actor>
      <role>Rukmini</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sahni, Balraj</actor>
      <role>Ramu</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ulhas (I)</actor>
      <role>Advocate Ramprasad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Walker, Johnny (III)</actor>
      <role>Professor Rasik Rasiya</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Ratan is an Air Force Pilot and lives a wealthy lifestyle with his money-lender father, Dayashankar. While journeying home for a holiday with his father, he is approached by an Army Officer, Ramu, who asks him to deliver a attaché case to his sister, Rukmini, who lives in the same town as Dayashankar, to which he agrees to do so. Ramu returns to the front, is seriously wounded and hospitalized. When he recovers he returns home to find out that his sister has passed away, and his niece, Ratna, who he had last seen as a 10-year old is missing. He is upset with the Pilot and hopes to extract his vengeance whenever he comes face to face with him. He meets with the daughter of a rickshaw driver, Gulabi, who permits him to draw the rickshaw. One day they come across a pregnant woman, Chanda, lying on the street, they assist her, she gives birth to a baby boy, and comes to live with them. Months later, Ramu finds out that Chanda's husband is none other than the pilot who had taken his attaché case, thrown Chanda out of the house, and is getting married for a second time to a woman named Nalini, the only daughter of a lawyer named Ramprasad. An enraged Ramu is now on a mission - to kill the pilot - and in his hands is a loaded shotgun to help him achieve this purpose. The question remains will Ramu succeed in his vengeance?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?520569</url></doc>
