<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="521347">
  <docid>521347</docid>
  <title>Sun Meri Laila</title>
  <year>1983</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">22 April 1983</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Bahl, Chander H.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Barjatya, Tarachand</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Patil, Vijay (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Birbal</actor>
      <role>Cook</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deepika (I)</actor>
      <role>Annie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Iftekhar</actor>
      <role>Abid Khan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jain, T.P.</actor>
      <role>Anwar Khatib</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Goga</actor>
      <role>Jay Dee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kiran, Raj</actor>
      <role>Vikram "Vicky" Rai</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Malhotra, Madhu</actor>
      <role>Laxmi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Malini, Madhu</actor>
      <role>Salma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mangu, Shrikant</actor>
      <role>Aslam</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Manmauji</actor>
      <role>College student</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mishra, Leela</actor>
      <role>Nani</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mohan, Ram (I)</actor>
      <role>Manglu Dada</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mukri</actor>
      <role>Ad Film Director</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nath, Rajendra</actor>
      <role>Waiter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shivdasani, Hari</actor>
      <role>Mr. Shivdasani (Ad Film Producer)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shivpuri, Om</actor>
      <role>Amrish Rai</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Subbiraj</actor>
      <role>David</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Yadav, Babbanlal</actor>
      <role>Babban</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Wealthy industrialist Amrish Rai and his wife welcome their U.S. returned son, Vikram alias Vicky back to India. They would like him to get married to a beautiful young woman named Nisha, but Vicky is interested in another young woman, whose name is Annie, and is the daughter of an employee of Rai Industries named David. Then the youngsters go on an overnight picnic with several other college friends, miss their transportation, and end up in the clutches of two truck-drivers - from whom they escape and fall in a pit meant to trap large animals. They are rescued by an elderly woman, only to find themselves abducted by a group of female bandits. The leader of this band, feels sorry for the young lovers, and let's them go - and they try to make their way home - only to find that Amrish has appealed in the newspapers that he will reward anyone with information on Vicky with one lakh rupees. This creates a furore in the community, and the young lovers are on the run from several mobs. The youngsters do make it home in one piece. When Amrish finds out about Vicky's love for Annie, he is enraged and dismisses David from work, only to re-hire him back after the workers, together with Vicky, go on an indefinite strike, until Amrish relents and re-hires David. But Amrish makes it quite clear that this does not mean that he will let his only son marry the daughter of a mere employee - under any circumstance. On the other hand David, who is intimidated by the Rai family, instructs his daughter never to see Vicky again. Looks like this is the end of the line for the young heartbroken lovers.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?521347</url></doc>
