<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="521433">
  <docid>521433</docid>
  <title>Sunayana</title>
  <year>1979</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Nag, Hiren</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Barjatya, Tarachand</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Jain, Ravindra</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gayatri (I)</actor>
      <role>Sushma (Indrajeet's sister)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ghatge, Vijayendra</actor>
      <role>Dr. Indrajeet</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jagdeep</actor>
      <role>Jaggoo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Pinchoo</actor>
      <role>Heeramohan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khote, Viju</actor>
      <role>Prisoner #204</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Latkar, Sulochana</actor>
      <role>Dr. Indrajit Sharma's Mother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mishra, Leela</actor>
      <role>Maushiji</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mukri</actor>
      <role>Circus owner</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Murad</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nath, Rajendra</actor>
      <role>Lion-tamer: Shamsher</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shah, Naseeruddin</actor>
      <role>Rajoo</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Rajoo (Naseeruddin Shah) is an honest, naive, villager with a heart of gold. When he comes to the big city, he comes across a beautiful young girl, Sunayana (Rameshwari), who almost gets runover by a car. He assists her to her feet, and she tells him that she is blind, lives in a small tenement with a neighbourly woman everyone calls Maushi (Leela Mishra), and sell flowers for a living. Rajoo takes it upon himself to make arrangements to ensure that Sunayana can see again. He meets with all kinds of people in this process, namely a wealthy suicidal drunk, Heeramohan (Pinchoo Kapoor); Circus owner (Mukri); Lion-tamer, Shamsher (Rajendra Nath); Prisoner Jaggoo (Jagdeep); Prisoner #204 (Viju Khote). He also meets with Dr. Indrajeet (Vijayendra Ghatge) and arranges to pay him a sum of Rs.2000/- for Sunayana's cure. Dr. Indrajeet lives with his mom (Sulochana), and sister, beautiful Sushma (Gayetri). When Sunayana is cured, she has nowhere to go to, for Rajoo has ended up in prison, Dr. Indrajeet takes her home and introduces her to his family. After Rajoo is released to comes to see Sunayana, only to find out she and Dr. Indrajeet are about to be married that very same day.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?521433</url></doc>
