<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="521749">
  <docid>521749</docid>
  <title>Sunny's Time Now</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Thiesmeier, Theo</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>jazz</keyword>
    <keyword>musician</keyword>
    <keyword>drum</keyword>
    <keyword>drummer</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>French</language>
    <language>German</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>France</country>
    <country>Luxembourg</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Denmark">14 November 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">108</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Prum, Antoine</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Thiltges, Paul</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>Retracing the longstanding career of avant-garde drummer Sunny Murray, one of the most influential figures of the Free jazz revolution. Through a series of interviews with key time witnesses as well as historic and contemporary concert footage, it reassesses the relationship between the libertarian music movement and the political events of the 1960s, whose social claims it so intimately reflected. By doing so, it also recounts how the most radical forms of musical expression were excluded from the major production and distribution networks as the libertarian ideal went out of fashion. Beyond its historical approach, the film follows Sunny Murray on current gigs, showing his daily struggle to perpetuate a musical genre which is still widely ignored by the general public. In doing so, Sunny's time now also dwells on the near-clandestine community of aficionados who continue to worship the gods of their musical coming of age, and whose unfaltering support has permitted free improvisational music - of which Sunny Murray is one of the last Mohicans - to live on.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?521749</url></doc>
