<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="522247">
  <docid>522247</docid>
  <title>Super Mario Bros. 2</title>
  <year>1986</year>
  <type>VideoGame</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>sequel-to-cult-favorite</keyword>
    <keyword>super-mario</keyword>
    <keyword>second-part</keyword>
    <keyword>side-scrolling</keyword>
    <keyword>video-game</keyword>
    <keyword>princess</keyword>
    <keyword>plumber</keyword>
    <keyword>jump-and-run</keyword>
    <keyword>nintendo</keyword>
    <keyword>pipes</keyword>
    <keyword>sequel</keyword>
    <keyword>luigi</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>third-person-view</keyword>
    <keyword>mario</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Japan</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="South Korea">All</certificate>
    <certificate country="USA">K-A</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Japan">3 June 1986</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
<plot>Just when Mario rescues Princess Toadstool, King Koopa returns and takes her once again and Mario must go after them. Only now, in this part 2 of the first game, Mario must brave eight of the most perplexed, difficult, and steep levels ever! With new surprises: Luigi can jump very high, much high than Mario, and now there's also a green trampoline that shoots you high into the sky and you can move from place to place before you land, pipes with Pirhana Plants in the ground and in the water, heavy winds that try to push you off cliffs, mind boggling pipe codes jumping codes, and many more! It's gonna take every ounce of power Mario and Luigi have to brave this game. Originally released in Japan only because Japanese players enjoy hard games, and the Super Mario 2 released in America was a remake of a Japanese game called 'Doki Doki World' reworked to fit Mario, Luigi, Toad and Princess. In 1992 when Super Mario All Stars was released, this game was recolored and redone and added with the package. One Players have the choice of being either Mario or Luigi. Hint: Luigi is the best one to be because the huge cliffs and things were specially designed for Luigi's high jumping capability. So if Mario and Luigi can brave this task, they will reach Koopa's castle, send him swimming in the lava and rescue Princess Toadstool.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?522247</url></doc>
