<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="522913">
  <docid>522913</docid>
  <title>Support? System Down</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Jones, Mathew (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">74</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Lobo, Angelo</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Lobo, Angelo</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>SUPPORT? is a film that covers the everyday issues of stress, family, struggle, and suffering that families experience when put through the detrimental, winding maneuvers of the Family Court systems, which are flooded with more cases than the labor force can handle or chooses NOT to handle. Finally, a shocking documentary that exposes the truth! Hear what experts say about how some have figured out how to make money by emphasizing on divorce and child support issues between men and women through court orders. Parents are made to pay exorbitant amounts of money in exchange for their CREDIT, HOMES, BANK ACCOUNTS, and even their FREEDOM! Exposed...SUPPORT? brings you deep into the MILITARY angle! Go face-to-face with the attorneys that handle the cases of the men and women who give their lives to protect our homeland. Shockingly, when soldiers return home after fighting, they are met with incarceration when they arrive on American soil for child support payments that they were unable to make while abroad. Is this justice? You be the judge! SUPPORT? was made to be educational and provocative in order to spark a call to action to bring about much-needed reform in the family courts. American children should not have to suffer due to an ineffectual and corrupt legal system!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?522913</url></doc>
