<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="523512">
  <docid>523512</docid>
  <title>Surviving the Treatment: The Return of Myles McLellan</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Mintz, Billie</editor>
    <editor>Tiernay, Jamie</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Greece">June 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Mintz, Billie</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Mintz, Billie</producer>
    <producer>Bras, Jamie</producer>
    <producer>Mintz, Billie</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Vrabac, Igor</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>When Myles McLellan was diagnosed with a malignant brain tumor he was forced to take a journey from which he might never return. He was nine years old. Through twenty hours of surgery and weeks of chemo and radiation therapy, Myles' resolve never wavered. He was a determined hero. A tiny warrior. But when the time came to return home, Myles found his childhood gone. So great were the changes in him, both physically and mentally, that nobody knew how to deal with his return. And he found himself alone. Surviving the Treatment: The Return of Myles McLellan is a documentary that drives into the core of the aftermath of childhood cancer. It is an intimate glimpse into one family's battle to regain their lives. And it is a brutal portrait of the social isolation experienced by children with cancer. This film is Myles' story. Myles told his story because he wanted people to be educated about their fear of cancer. And in doing so, ensure that no other child would have to go through what he did. On February 16, 2006, the world lost a great storyteller. Myles' cancer returned. This time he lost. Surviving the Treatment tells the tale of last year of his heroic mission to change one thing in this world.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?523512</url></doc>
