<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="523629">
  <docid>523629</docid>
  <title>Susan for Now</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Connors, Ian J.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>alternative-reality</keyword>
    <keyword>bdsm</keyword>
    <keyword>dominatrix</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Australia">20 September 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Canada">16 June 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">28 August 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">54</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Franzi, Robin</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Franzi, Robin</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>The documentary Susan for Now takes the viewer on a journey of discovery through what most people know only vaguely as a mysterious and taboo subculture: the world of sadomasochism. The film is a first person account of a woman reclaiming her sexual freedom after a ten-year period of self-imposed celibacy and follows the filmmaker's personal quest through the underground world of the sex positive community in Seattle. While Susan for Now is a memorably vivid and unflinching exploration of this widely practiced and yet little known genre of alternative sexuality, the film is equally notable for its revealing insights into the minds and hearts of articulate and sincere individuals from every walk of life, from lawyers, IT professionals, graphic artists, musicians and real estate agents to name a few. The individuals portrayed convey how BDSM is practiced in a consensual and responsible manner. What emerges is an informative depiction of a diverse and growing community and its uneasy relationship with society's shifting mainstream culture. This film dispels the myth that all forms of BDSM and its practitioners are inherently deviant.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?523629</url></doc>
