<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="524463">
  <docid>524463</docid>
  <title>Swab the Duck</title>
  <year>1956</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>noveltoon</keyword>
    <keyword>frying-pan</keyword>
    <keyword>disguise</keyword>
    <keyword>buried-treasure</keyword>
    <keyword>booby-trap</keyword>
    <keyword>baby-huey</keyword>
    <keyword>pirate</keyword>
    <keyword>blindfold</keyword>
    <keyword>pirate-ship</keyword>
    <keyword>walking-the-plank</keyword>
    <keyword>treasure-map</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">11 May 1956</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">7</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Tendlar, Dave</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kneitel, Seymour</producer>
    <producer>Sparber, Izzy</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Meyer, Carl (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Sharples, Winston</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Beck, Jackson (I)</actor>
      <role>The Fox</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mercer, Jack</actor>
      <role>Ducklings</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Raymond, Sid</actor>
      <role>Baby Huey</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Baby Huey sees some little ducks playing pirate and wants to join in, but when he jumps on their raft, he sends them flying into the hungry fox's frying pan. Huey accidentally frees them when he jumps onto the fox in his enthusiasm to join them. The fox decides he'd rather pursue the gigantic Huey than the tiny ducklings, and when he overhears Huey wishing he could play pirate, the fox dresses as a pirate aboard a convenient nearby replica pirate ship. The fox tries a kettle in the crow's nest, rigged to drop onto a stove, but Huey inadvertently gets the fox into the kettle instead. Next, fox blindfolds Huey and has him walk the plank into a kettle dangling off the end, but Huey sends the kettle flying onto the fox and into a barrel of tar; thinking the trapped fox is an octopus, Huey bashes him. Finally, fox sends Huey after buried treasure, consisting of a booby-trapped treasure chest; Huey sends the knives in the chest flying toward fox, where they remove his minimal disguise, allowing even Baby Huey to recognize the fox. Huey sends the fox on a small boat crashing into the pirate ship, where the ducklings use him as a mop to swab the deck.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?524463</url></doc>
