<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="526178">
  <docid>526178</docid>
  <title>Synergy</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Johnson, Jessica 'Midge'</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>mosaic</keyword>
    <keyword>buckminster-fuller</keyword>
    <keyword>children</keyword>
    <keyword>art</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>12-Track Digital Sound</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">28 July 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">13</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Saleman, Buddy</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kardatzky, David</producer>
    <producer>Kavanaugh, Katy</producer>
    <producer>Saleman, Buddy</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Budz</composer>
    <composer>Lemon JuJu</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dorrance, Sarah</actor>
      <role>Mosaic Artist</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Then you will conceive your own way of doing that which needs to be done -- that no one else has told you to do or how to do it. --- R. Buckminster Fuller The Synergy Project reveals the best defense for art in early education: children's startlingly articulate responses to building a mosaic in San Francisco guided by artist Sarah Dorrance and inspired by Buckminster Fuller. In 2005, Mosaic Artist Sarah Dorrance engaged seven to nine year-old students from the Synergy School of San Francisco in a public art project. Their task was to come up with a subject and construct a mosaic for an exterior corner of their school. With very few rules, Dorrance challenged them to work together, think universally and consider the ideas of Buckminster Fuller through the model of his Dymaxion map their work would surround. Their responses to the artistic process Dorrance provided are the focus of this film. The film employs interviews with the artist, the children, teachers and parents that reveal indelible moments of discovery and change while photo montage, interviews and original music expose the gradually developing piece of art. Together, they produce an elegant experience that extends the excitement and value of making art to the film's viewers. Our intention had been to discover children at a crucial awakening point of recognizing the larger world for the first time; but what we found instead, were children who had well surpassed that point.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?526178</url></doc>
