<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="526283">
  <docid>526283</docid>
  <title>Systematic Collapse</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Isaacs, Hayley</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>experimental-film</keyword>
    <keyword>art</keyword>
    <keyword>technology</keyword>
    <keyword>postmodernism</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">27 January 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">10</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Isaacs, Hayley</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Isaacs, Hayley</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ho, Hai (II)</actor>
      <role>Control</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Our relationship to the land is expressed as a constant and unwavering cut through the passive soil. Tolerant of our intimate exploitation, the land absorbs our manipulation willingly. Tragically, it is through our resolute abuse, disguised as seemingly dutiful and beautiful human intervention, that an irreparable scar is at last exposed. SYSTEMATIC COLLAPSE is a ten minute film shot with three cameras positioned above, beside and beneath a vessel filled with seeds. The seeds are continuously and consistently divided with a blade. As this act is performed the cuts are simultaneously traced on the underside of the skin which holds them suspended above the lower camera. The film documents the systematic cuts as they inevitably become scars left in the surface of the skin. The skin, weakened by this relentless manipulation inevitably succumbs to the load imposed upon it. As the audience anticipates the release, they begin to crave the devastation. It is the suspension of the penetration of the skin which implicates the viewer in the act. The bystander can not be disconnected from what he/she witnesses, they become inextricably linked to the act and its repercussions.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?526283</url></doc>
