<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="526278">
  <docid>526278</docid>
  <title>System Shock</title>
  <year>1994</year>
  <type>VideoGame</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>laser</keyword>
    <keyword>spacecraft</keyword>
    <keyword>survival-horror</keyword>
    <keyword>artificial-intelligence</keyword>
    <keyword>space</keyword>
    <keyword>corporation</keyword>
    <keyword>hacker</keyword>
    <keyword>cyberspace</keyword>
    <keyword>video-game</keyword>
    <keyword>shoot</keyword>
    <keyword>cyborg</keyword>
    <keyword>stealth</keyword>
    <keyword>mutant</keyword>
    <keyword>villain</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="South Korea">18</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">26 March 1994</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <producers>
    <producer>Spector, Warren (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>LoPiccolo, Greg</composer>
    <composer>Ries, Tim</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brosius, Terri</actor>
      <role>Shodan</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Aroused by rumours of questionable experiments being conducted by the Troptimum corporation aboard their "Citadel" space station, you hack into their corporate mainframe. But it seems you're not the hotshot you thought you were; Trioptimum security personnel apprehend you and drag you off for detention and interrogation on Citadel. However, your actions have piqued the curiousity of Triop Executive Edward Diego. He offers to overlook your earlier transgressions if you help him disable some troublesome security features on Citadel's controlling Artificial Intelligence: the Sentient Hyper-Optimized Data Access Network, or SHODAN. In addition to clearing your name, he'll kit you out with a Military Grade Neural Interface, a classically cyberpunk device that allows you to plug your brain directly into cyberspace, as well as equip yourself with a variety of cybernetic devices. How could you say no? You easily remove the ethical constraints that have prevented SHODAN from allowing Diego to proceed with research into a particularly destructive virus and settle down for a 6-month sleep as you recover from the surgery. Little do you know what you have unleashed upon the inhabitants of Citadel, and potentially the entire human race. The game begins upon your awakening, on the second day of November, 2072. Dead bodies litter the hallways, the robotic inhabitants of the station react to you with hostility and there are signs of a great struggle. Not to mention the deformed creatures lurking in the shadows. With time running out and limited outside of support, it's up to you to find out what's happened and put things right.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?526278</url></doc>
