<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="528628">
  <docid>528628</docid>
  <title>Tahran macerasi</title>
  <year>1968</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Turkish</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Inanoglu, Türker</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Inanoglu, Türker</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Oran, Bülent</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Akin, Filiz</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Colgecen, Feridun</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gaffari, Cihangir</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Seyhan, Ali</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tekce, Necip</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Terziyan, Nubar</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tibet, Kartal</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Ali and Cafer, the truck drivers, continue their way in the mountains of Iran. They take the bandits to their boss and deliver the carpets. The boss just thanks them. At the bar Ali feels attracted to Ayse, the dancer. Cafer's sister Zeynep needs a surgery to regain her eyesight. They ask the boss for money, but get a refusal. So, the two partners rob the office. The police pursues them. They question Ayse. The two hide in a hut. Cafer leaves Ali to find a passport and accepts Ayse's plot to get the money and denounce Ali. Ali is jailed. He escapes from prison and finds out Cafer's place. He meets Zeynep, Cafer's sister by accident, they fall in love. He encounters Cafer who is scared of him. He offers Ali money to leave Zeynep though Ali rejects. Zeynep and Ali ask Cafer for half of the money he gets from the robbery. Cafer finds his sister and Ali in bed. They have a fight, Ali makes him confess everything. As Cafer takes the gun to shoot both of them, a gun shot is heard, Cafer falls on the ground, Ayse is at the door. Zeynep and Ali embrace each other, never to leave..</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?528628</url></doc>
