<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="530691">
  <docid>530691</docid>
  <title>Tangewala</title>
  <year>1972</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Kumar, Naresh (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kumar, Naresh (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Naushad (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhagwan, Master</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Choti, Mohan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chuggani, Kumud</actor>
      <role>Gauri</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Johar, I.S.</actor>
      <role>Nagina</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kanhaiyalal (I)</actor>
      <role>Munimji/Panditji</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kaushal, Kamini</actor>
      <role>Laxmi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Rajendra (I)</actor>
      <role>Rai Bahadur Kishandas/Raju/Dilbahadur Khan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Sujit (I)</actor>
      <role>Zamindar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mehmood Jr.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mishra, Leela</actor>
      <role>Mausi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Paintal</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Raj, Jagdish</actor>
      <role>Police Inspector</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Rai Bahadur Kishandas, due to his weakness for alcohol and women drives his wife and children out of the house. Suddenly, his fortune takes a turn and he is reduced to the state of a beggar. While his wife Laxmi raises their two kids against all odds, the two children being Gauri and Rajoo. Rajoo, who later becomes a tangewala. Oneday, Laxmi feels a sudden urge to see her husband, so the of a pretext of a pilgrimage goes to meet him. But, to her despair, she doesn't find him there. On the other hand Rajoo and Gauri gives an old beggar refuge in their house, not knowing that he is their father in real life. By the time Laxmi returns, the old man has left the house. Paro is in love with Rajoo and refuses the marriage proposal of a Zamindar. He wants to take revenge on her and so tries to woo Gauri, but Rajoo has already arranged for Gauri's marriage with someone else. Rajoo, is disappointed to know that Gauri is pregnant with the Zamindar' baby. Rajoo goes to the Zamindar and demands justice, but the cruel Zamindar does not listen to him. Rajoo decides to leave the village with his family. In the meanwhile Rai Bahadur comes to know that Rajoo and Gauri are his kids. But unfortunately by the time he reaches their house they have all left for their new destination. Rajoo rearranges Gauri's marriage, but on the eve of marriage Gauri leaves with her child, leaving Rajoo to face humiliation once again. Does Rai Bahadur find his family again? Does Gauri return back to her house? Watch the family drama in Tangewala!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?530691</url></doc>
