<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="531427">
  <docid>531427</docid>
  <title>Taraj</title>
  <year>1985</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Motalebi, Saeed</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Persian</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Iran</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Ghaderi, Iraj</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Tobekhah, Mohammad</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Davoudnejad, Alireza</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Cheshmazar, Naser</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Delshakib, Hamid</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hashempur, Jamshid</actor>
      <role>Zeinal Bandari</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Javanbakhsh, Behzad</actor>
      <role>Lieutenant Ahmad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khorvash, Fakhri</actor>
      <role>Zeinal's wife</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maleki, Hossein</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nivandi, Said</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tavakolli, Rasoul</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Zeinal Bandari (Jamshid Hashempur) is an opium dealer with a past criminal record. He is nabbed in a series of arrests on drug traffickers by Iranian DEA. He then In court is convicted of drug trafficking but by giving money to the corrupt judge gets lighter prison sentence and therefore after one year in prison and because of his so called "good behavior behind bars", gets a Parole and sets out free but soon he is caught again in another drug deal and once again Zeinal finds himself behind bars. This time he feels regret and realizes that his life is ruined so he accepts the offer of lieutenant Ahmad, who is the head of Iranian DEA to become an undercover agent for DEA. With the help of Zeinal they decompose the local Opium network. But the triumph is no longer sweet for Zeinal after he finds out that during the time he was serving his time in prison, his only son became a Heroin addict. Lieutenant Ahmad and Zeinal help Zeinal's son together to quit his habit. After Zeinal's son recovers, the two decide to demolish the Heroin Network which they later found out is belong to a strong heroin cartel with ties to high position officials so they realize that they can not demolish the network with the help of government and DEA. So Zeinal and Lieutenant Ahmad set out to strike down the Heroin Network even though by sacrificing their own lives by assassinating the leaders of Heroin Cartel and so in the path they choose they both give their lives for the sake of their people.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?531427</url></doc>
