<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="533567">
  <docid>533567</docid>
  <title>Teenage Angst</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Thomas, Philipp</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>German</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Germany">29 January 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Germany">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Stuber, Thomas</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bahar, M. Reza</producer>
    <producer>Gebauer, Sinje</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Jäckle, Holger</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Klein, Matthias (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>De Ahna, Kerstin</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Severin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dinda, Franz</actor>
      <role>Konstantin Stürmer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ginsburg, Michael (III)</actor>
      <role>Bogatsch</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kocaj, Janusz</actor>
      <role>Leibnitz</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kohrt, Niklas</actor>
      <role>Dyrbusch</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Schweighöfer, Michael</actor>
      <role>Mentor</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>At an elite private Border School four students form a clique to sneak out of school after hours to meet, drink and play. By trying to escape the golden cage which their wealthy parents have stuck them in, they search for the Extreme. In the course of time their excessive games grow more and more violent and soon they turn against the weakest of the group: Leibnitz. Dyrbusch (Leader of the pack) and Bogatsch (the executive power) continue to torture him, he voluntarily puts up with it because he can't manage to dispose of his tormentors, on one hand being afraid to loose their "Friendship" and on the other hand due to the consequences that might arise with his parents. Konstantin, the opportunist is the only one who sees through the moral magnitude of their games, but he hesitates too long not wanting to endanger the alleged common destiny that these boys in this school appear to have: their clique. They get caught deeper and deeper in this downward spiral of violence and peer pressure till the unavoidable happens...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?533567</url></doc>
