<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="534030">
  <docid>534030</docid>
  <title>Teesra Kaun?</title>
  <year>1994</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">23 December 1994</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="India">160</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Ghosh, Partho</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Pillai, Prem</producer>
    <producer>Sippy, N.N.</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Chitragupth, Anand</composer>
    <composer>Chitragupth, Milind</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ali, Somy</actor>
      <role>Priyanka</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Amrapurkar, Sadashiv</actor>
      <role>Insp. Aditya Talwar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anand, Tinnu</actor>
      <role>P. K. Rasiya</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Banerjee, Beena</actor>
      <role>Manjula's mother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bedi, Rakesh</actor>
      <role>Khoka Ganguli</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chakraborty, Mithun</actor>
      <role>Himself (the actor)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chandran, K.D.</actor>
      <role>Mr. Verma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dhawan, Anil (I)</actor>
      <role>Anil Saxena (special appearance)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gautami (I)</actor>
      <role>Herself (special appearance)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gill, Avtar</actor>
      <role>Advocate Saxena</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jaffrey, Javed</actor>
      <role>Pankaj Nigam/Sanjay Chopra</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Palekar, Amol</actor>
      <role>C. K. Kadam</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pandey, Chunky</actor>
      <role>Vijay Verma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shah, Satish</actor>
      <role>Bingo Nagpurkar</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Three Bollywood-striken, Calcutta-based slackers, Vijay Verma, Bingo Nagpurkar, and Khoka Ganguli, board the Howrah-Bombay Mail, to head to Bombay to watch a cricket match, and to meet Bollywood megastar Mithun Chakraborty. During this trip, they drink a lot of alcohol. Vijay notices that the people in the next room in his train coach, are a couple with an attractive young woman. He goes over to introduce himself, and finds that the man calls himself Mr. C.K. Kadam, and the young woman's name is Manjula. Vijay wants to change his seat, so that he can near Manjula, but unfortunately that seat is taken up by a young man, Pankaj Nigam. Vijay attempts to forcibly take the seat from Pankay, and a fight ensues, and Vijay is asked to leave them alone. During a stopover, Pankaj leaves the train, and when the train starts, Mr. Kadam finds that Manjula has been killed. The police begin their investigation, and they have two suspects namely, Pankaj Nigam, and Vijay Verma. They also find out that Pankaj is not who he claims to be, and that his real name is Sanjay Chopra. Further investigations prove that neither Vijay nor Pankaj could have possibly murdered Manjula, leaving the police, Vijay and his friends on one hand, and Sanjay Chopra, to hunt for the third suspect, the one who actually killed Manjula, and the one who may also kill anyone who stands in his/her way.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?534030</url></doc>
