<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="534576">
  <docid>534576</docid>
  <title>Teller</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">25 October 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">20</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Himes, Dave</director>
    <director>Himes, David (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Covington, Brenton</producer>
    <producer>Himes, Dave</producer>
    <producer>Nordell, Austin</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Himes, Dave</writer>
    <writer>Himes, David (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Himes, Dave</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Adam, Patrick</actor>
      <role>Stewart</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Alsadi, Sam</actor>
      <role>SWAT team member</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rosete, Jose</actor>
      <role>SWAT team member</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tye, Kevin (I)</actor>
      <role>Swat Team Member</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Director David Aaron Himes presents an American psychological thriller about a bank teller named Stewart, who becomes dangerously obsessed over a customer named Michelle and turns his feelings of love into an aurora of despair. Violating the trust of his position, Michelle's account provides Stewart with personal information about her work, address, birthday, and activities. Stewart confides with his close friend, and female roommate Megan, about the new girl he has become overly infatuated with through work. Megan suggests Stewart, should visit Michelle at her job. Following her advice, Stewart goes to Michelle's restaurant to impress her, but he appears to be more of a creep than socially inclined. After Michelle comes home one night, and while preparing to shower, she believes that someone is in her house. She investigates and finds nothing unusual. But, well hidden, Stewart later emerges from the dark, lurking and watching Michelle as she sleeps. Michelle is awakened by her phone ringing with Stewart on the line; calling about issues with her bank account. He suggests to Michelle, she should come into his bank and sign up for overdraft protection. Upset, Michelle tells Stewart to stop bothering her. Confiding in Megan again, he shares his deep emotions for Michelle; Megan suggests women love flowers. When Stewart delivers the flowers, he encounters Michelle's real love interest, which Stewart was not aware. Obsessed with jealousy, Stewart becomes distraught and his mysterious love life begins to unravel, taking new twists and turns.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?534576</url></doc>
