<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="534785">
  <docid>534785</docid>
  <title>Templar: Honor Among Thieves</title>
  <year>2010</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>mercenary</keyword>
    <keyword>bounty-hunter</keyword>
    <keyword>outer-space</keyword>
    <keyword>thief</keyword>
    <keyword>martial-arts</keyword>
    <keyword>femme-fatale</keyword>
    <keyword>space-western</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2010</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Hinojosa, Rene</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Amani, Paris</producer>
    <producer>Bloodgood, Anne Marie</producer>
    <producer>Bloodgood, Paul Michael</producer>
    <producer>Smith, Janell</producer>
    <producer>Yi, Grandmaster Wonik</producer>
    <producer>Hinojosa, Rene</producer>
    <producer>Warren, Tommy G.</producer>
    <producer>No, David (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Hinojosa, Rene</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Krench, Mark</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bloodgood, Paul Michael</actor>
      <role>The Bounty Hunter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carley, Jeff</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fanucchi, Bob</actor>
      <role>Devlin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Garcia, Yesenia</actor>
      <role>Gwinn</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hagood, Lee</actor>
      <role>Cain</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hartman, Chance</actor>
      <role>Brine</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nguyen, Anh Huu</actor>
      <role>Tiv</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>No, David (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sato, Garret</actor>
      <role>Azrael</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Dust kicks up along a nearly deserted street. Three bounty hunters stage an ambush on a known criminal. But as they rush into the stone building where the suspect is known to be hiding, they each meet their end at the hands of their prey. For some, this scene would seem to describe a time when law and order were decided by how fast a man could draw a gun. The old west. But imagine this scene playing out on another planet in a distant galaxy. Award-Winning Writer, Producer &amp; Director Rene Hinojosa presents Templar: Honor Among Thieves, an epic story that pays tribute to the classic genre of the "spaghetti western" but sets the action against the canvas of a galaxy on the brink of chaos. At its heart, the story pays respect to the classic tales of western mythology and its character archetypes. There is the lone gunman, the anti-hero, who finds himself always on the edge of darkness. Bound to a life of greed, he sets off on a quest to attain the unattainable. Joining him on his journey is the thief. A man who is much more than what he appears to be and who holds a secret so valuable that many have pursued him across the galaxy just to discover it. And finally, the mercenary. A man with a reputation for always seeing the job through once he has been paid. Together, these three fortune hunters will seek to best each other in their quest to claim the ultimate prize.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?534785</url></doc>
