<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="534867">
  <docid>534867</docid>
  <title>Temporary Loss of Power</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Cooper, Chad (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>power-struggle</keyword>
    <keyword>race</keyword>
    <keyword>class</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">20 October 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">6</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Dixon, Nia Malika</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Grafton, Ameenah</producer>
    <producer>Dixon, Nia Malika</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Dixon, Nia Malika</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bianchi, Julianne</actor>
      <role>Lila Smith</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dixon, Natasha M.</actor>
      <role>Sheryl Logan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grafton, Ameenah</actor>
      <role>Sara</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Sheryl has an agenda. She's out to prove that a black woman can be just as effective in her top-ranking corporate position as her white male counterparts. It hasn't been easy; working long hours, for-going social engagements, taking on high-risk assignments, and giving one hundred and ten percent to her career. She's on top and in control. Lila's a working mother. Her goal is to live comfortably and send her kids to college. She's content being one of the boss' assistants at the firm. Lila is soft-spoken and inconspicuous, but she gets her job done and does it well. She prides herself for being the world's greatest mom, more so than anything else. She doesn't argue or fret about her job; she takes things as they come. These two very different women share an elevator at the end of a long day at work, when the power suddenly goes out. Sheryl is suddenly thrust into a situation where she is no longer in control, and she panics. Lila has experience being in a position where she's powerless, so she remains calm in the situation. Lila manages to calm down Sheryl, and then calls to find out what's going on with the elevator. The power has shifted, and now Lila is the one on top. She takes control of the situation, and demonstrates that human power is illusory. After interacting with Lila, Sheryl reluctantly realizes that this is a fact that she must face. Soon, the power is restored. Inside the elevator things are returned to normal. As the women leave the elevator, what will they take with them from this brief moment, this temporary loss of power?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?534867</url></doc>
