<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="536040">
  <docid>536040</docid>
  <title>Terraformers</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>VideoGame</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Sweden</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Sweden">2003</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Pettersson, Marcus</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Gustavsson, Paulina</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Helldin, Henrietta</actor>
      <role>Voice of the instructor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Magdu, Christian</actor>
      <role>Narrator &amp; The Professor</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The game takes place in the future. Mankind has started colonisation of other planets and uses intelligent robots to create an atmosphere suitable to human life. But on the distant planet Tellus 2 something went wrong. Some of the robots evolved and became too intelligent and revolted against their creators. The revolting robots imprisoned professor van Lange in his lab. The professor is the only one with enough knowledge to regain control over the revolting robots. The robots also disassembled the main computer and scattered the parts in the area around the professor's lab. Your mission is to defeat the revolting robots, find the parts to the computer and free professor van Lange. To solve the quest you will use fire arms, ammunition, secret keys, audio puzzles, communication devices and other things. In order to stop you, the robots have locked doors, hidden the computer parts and will attack you on sight. Your Powersuit use power to protect you from the planet's hostile environment and other physical injury, and you need to find Power-up stations on a regular basis.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?536040</url></doc>
