<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="536611">
  <docid>536611</docid>
  <title>Testing Taklo</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Sandford, Melanie</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Amharic</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Australia">6 August 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Australia">26</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Melville, Troy</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Jager, Claire (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Melville, Troy</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Edwards, Helen (IV)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mekonnen, Taklo</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Molla, Gebianesh</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Taklo is an Ethiopian refugee who wants his driving licence. But Taklo's not a good driver. He's gone for a license test three times - and failed three times. Helen, his Hobart neighbor, offers to help. Reverse parking seems to be the main hurdle. As they gear up for the fourth test Helen and Taklo are feeling confident. Taklo's reverse parking has vastly improved, but to Helen's dismay, Taklo and the driving assessor return early. The assessor was forced to pull on the handbrake to avoid a head-on crash. Taklo fails again - four out of four! Helen and Taklo are devastated but resolve to keep at it. Helen is now resigned to hundreds of hours of driving. Taklo makes use of the driving time to do various errands. He's responsible for the grocery shopping and Helen helps him decipher the local fruit and vegetables. A friendship blossoms that is about far more than learning to drive. The day of the fifth test finally arrives. Taklo is terribly nervous. After half an hour, Taklo and the tester are still not back and Helen fears the worst again. But Taklo passes! With his newfound independence and "P" plates, Taklo is about to spread his wings. He decides he has a better chance of finding work in Melbourne and - somewhat impulsively in Helen's view - he plans to uproot once more and move the family to Melbourne. Helen is worried about Taklo driving in a big city. She offers to go with him and he gladly accepts. The driving lesson isn't over yet.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?536611</url></doc>
