<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="540368">
  <docid>540368</docid>
  <title>The Animated Alias: Tribunal</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Gargani, Dave</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">7 September 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">7</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Lipson, David (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Abrams, J.J.</producer>
    <producer>Alexander, Jesse (II)</producer>
    <producer>Bernstein, John (II)</producer>
    <producer>Frazier, Breen</producer>
    <producer>Lipson, David (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Frazier, Breen</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Aumueller, Brian</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Garner, Jennifer (I)</actor>
      <role>Sydney Bristow</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kramer, Steve (I)</actor>
      <role>Rudolph Gaborno</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>O'Quinn, Terry</actor>
      <role>F.B.I. Asst. Director Kendall</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Tribunal opens with F.B.I. Assistant Director Kendall telling a home-sick Sydney that returning home would jeopardize the lives of the people she loves, including Michael Vaughn. He reminds her that The Covenant could be more deadly than The Alliance, which is why it is imperative that Sydney continues as Julian Thorne since The Covenant think they have Sydney programmed. Reluctantly, Sydney acquiesces. The action then jumps into animation, where we see Rudolph Gaborno being interrogated by Lucian Cezar about Julia Thorne. He tells how he was stationed in Ibiza to guard an artifact. We see Sydney as Julia, sitting at a bar in a disco. She disappears from the bar and approaches the club's floor manager. Feigning a misstep, she falls on him and steals his access pass. In a nearby restroom, she takes a previously-hidden gun and jumpsuit. Under the guise of an explosion caused by a plastique explosive that she had laced on her glass at the bar, Julia runs to the back of the club and overpowers three guards in hand-to-hand combat. She then descends the elevator shaft and meets Rudolph in the basement. She steals a strange-looking key in Rudolph's bag and tries to escape but Rudolph manages to lock-down the elevator. We then learn that the building is set to self-destruct in a few seconds. Fortunately, Julia has a plan -- she escapes upwards via the elevator shaft, taking Rudolph along for the ride. They land on a nearby rooftop and Julia warns him not to say anything about her, or she would track him down. Unbeknownst to Julia, her actions were being monitored by a security camera. After she escapes, Rudolph realizes that Julia had stolen a fake key. The action switches back to the interrogation and Rudolph offers this key to his captors in return for his safety. While Rudolph's captors leave the room to consider the offer, Julia breaks into the interrogation room and steals the real key from around Rudolph's neck. "I told you I'd find you" are Julia's parting words to a desperate Rudolph. She then destroys the video camera that was taping the interrogation session, thereby destroying Rudolph's chance of explaining himself and being set free.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?540368</url></doc>
