<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="540855">
  <docid>540855</docid>
  <title>The Art of Living Your Dream</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Foster, Leslie (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">5</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Garza, Adriana</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Garza, Adriana</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Cayer, Laura</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Baine, Greg</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Boston, Evan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cole, Barbara (V)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Garza, Adriana</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gilbert, James Thomas</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Griffin, Jency</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Haldane, Kris Pustina</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hortis, Effie</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jensen, Jesse (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>La, Tammy</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Light, Maggie</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mullen, Michael (V)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sanhueza, Jonathan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The Art of Living Your Dream is a behind the scenes look at The Art of Being, a play created to bridge the gap of loneliness within humanity through art by showcasing actors expressing themselves through monologues that range from embracing of their sexuality, ethnicity, and age to acceptance of their body as is, allowing them to celebrate their individuality. Adriana Garza, creator of the play The Art of Being, takes you on the journey of making the play come to life and the challenges she faced while doing so. The tour was done solely to spread the message of the play, that individuality is a gift we all possess and can choose to honor, while supporting the arts by donating the proceeds to a different art related non-profit organization in each city. The short like the play was created to inspire people to embrace their individuality and create a more loving environment for differences by showcasing all it entails to be human. Through their monologues actors express how they perceive themselves all in hopes that not only will the audience identify with them but that through the identification they can find compassion for themselves and others and not judge each other or themselves so harshly. The Art of Being is about creating another option in this media driven world where we are sold the idea that the more you have the more valuable you are. A world where you can accept yourself, your choices and the journey they lead you on all while realizing that being human binds us all and that humanity is equality.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?540855</url></doc>
