<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="541007">
  <docid>541007</docid>
  <title>The Arubian Nostalgic</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Campbell, Peter (XII)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">100</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Campbell, Peter (XII)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Campbell, Peter (XII)</producer>
    <producer>Stewart, Gavin (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Campbell, Peter (XII)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Beaton, Kirsty</actor>
      <role>Friend</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Byrne, Jennifer (V)</actor>
      <role>Woman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Donnachie, Becky</actor>
      <role>Best Friend of male lead</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Irwin, Tony</actor>
      <role>Friend</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McCaig, Catriona</actor>
      <role>Sister</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Roberts, Pab</actor>
      <role>Boyfriend</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stewart, Gavin (II)</actor>
      <role>Man</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The Arubian Nostalgic begins with a man harshly demanding his girlfriend has an abortion. She is hounded into agreeing to this. They part ways and meet later, when she is with someone else. The attraction between the pair remains and a tentative, combative romance begins. The new boyfriend becomes a problem, leading to violence between the men. As this situation progresses, we begin, through voice-overs within visual mood pieces and fantastical areas, to get a sense of the characters, what drives and limits their actions, as well view their friends and family, who inform their decisions. The relationship continues despite threat within the combative relationships, the woman becoming pregnant again, the ex-boyfriend the father. He panics and causes further confrontation with her new boyfriend. As their lives devolve, the former couple have to both examine their previous actions so as to decide how to deal with the pregnancy. They begin to think on what drives them, what they think of themselves. This is not always dealt with directed in mature actions, as they work on how to hurt the other to get at emotional reactions, to see what the other thinks, beyond the self they use as protection and to show the world. Following a miscarriage, they have to examine their decisions, how they interact with one another, how they live individually. It is a situation that leads them into unique outcomes regarding their problems in life. The situation becomes tragic.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?541007</url></doc>
