<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="542564">
  <docid>542564</docid>
  <title>The Beautiful Letdown</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>spiritual</keyword>
    <keyword>social-justice</keyword>
    <keyword>magical-realism</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Travis, Jeffrey</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Petrik, Erik</producer>
    <producer>Gonzales, David (VI)</producer>
    <producer>Caplan, Seth</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Egerton, Owen</writer>
    <writer>Travis, Jeffrey</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>McNairy, Scoot</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Based on a novel by Owen Egerton, THE BEAUTIFUL LETDOWN is a multi-layered spiritual drama that weaves together three gripping and contemporary stories of love, courage, loneliness and faith. The first story centers around Walter Trampt, a slacker with religion who goes on increasingly dangerous midnight missions to help the homeless until a reckless act kills a woman and lands him in jail. The second story follows Marshall Hollenzer, a middle-aged accountant, who after getting fired, abandons his wife and daughter hoping to start a new life with a younger woman he meets online. But, on his journey to meet this woman, Marshall discovers he's cursed with a mysterious and astonishing power to greatly affect the behavior of people around him. The third story involves Gladis Stert, a beautiful history student, who has discovered a secret heir to a European king. This prince-in-disguise, turns out to be a jet-setting billionaire named Branson Bulyowsky; a relationship begins to form. All of these people will end up in the same room in an emotional finale. Dealing with issues of loneliness, broken relationships, faith and love in the context of social justice, THE BEAUTIFUL LETDOWN takes us on a journey through the best and worst of human nature, concluding in a thought-provoking climax that will leave viewers filled with as much hope as questions about the meaning of their own lives. In the vein of films like Magnolia, Crash, About Schmidt, and The Grand Canyon, these three diverse stories will collide and converge to a shocking and moving conclusion.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?542564</url></doc>
