<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="542827">
  <docid>542827</docid>
  <title>The Bench</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Nehs, Laura</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">9 June 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">21</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Augustine, Greg</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Augustine, Greg</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chamberlin, Scott (I)</actor>
      <role>Chris</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Goad, Melissa</actor>
      <role>Melissa</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lee, Jameson</actor>
      <role>College Student</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McClenney, Josh</actor>
      <role>Lewis</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McKinnon, Tekay</actor>
      <role>Runner</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Thomas, Christian (VIII)</actor>
      <role>Mr. Thomas</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zakhariants, Vartan</actor>
      <role>Gerald</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Gerald is teaching Lewis, his trainee, the art of begging. He takes Lewis to the middle of a busy park in order to stop pedestrians as they walk by the bench in which they are sitting. Lewis messes up at every turn and Gerald is there to guide him towards more effective methods of begging. They use a device called a Sheep Tracker to scan the area for potential customers. Gerald places Lewis in different types of situations in order to teach him how to increase revenue for the company. Lewis tries his best to impress Greald, but fails on every account. Chris, the 3-11 shift, shows up and takes over for Lewis. It is then revealed that the beggars are really rich men pretending to be homeless just for the sake of the company. Mr. Thomas asks his girlfriend, Melissa, to meet him at the bench. He attempts to break up with her. She flies into a rage and attempts to kill him. During the struggle, they stumble upon the Sheep Tracker. Melissa sees that it has her personal information in its database and accuses Mr. Thomas of stalking her and other women. She threatens to take the device to the police when another beggar, Chris, takes it upon himself to chase her down before the begging industry is unveiled.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?542827</url></doc>
