<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="544791">
  <docid>544791</docid>
  <title>The Blue Horse</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>van der Laan, Roald</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Netherlands">6 November 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Netherlands">98</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>van der Laan, Roald</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>van der Laan, Sandor</producer>
    <producer>Scheffers, Coen</producer>
    <producer>van Heeren, Jan</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>van der Laan, Roald</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Deliberate Jeopardization</composer>
    <composer>van der Laan, Roald</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Geerdink, Sten</actor>
      <role>Drifter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kamerling, Antonie</actor>
      <role>Trevor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moerland, Nicole</actor>
      <role>Linda</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sinclair, Terrence</actor>
      <role>Joseph Bilger</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tonnon, Jasper</actor>
      <role>Jerome 'Mr. Coco' Woods</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wiebers, John Derek</actor>
      <role>Gary</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In the small town of Morden Falls, Joseph Bilger lives a secret life. While his family believes he is working as a local carpenter, in reality Joseph hunts down and kills men who hurt and threaten children. Joseph is unable to bond with his youngest daughter Natalie. His family - consisting of Natalie, his wife Kristen and oldest daughter Alison - is in a constant emotional crisis. After a tragic accident, Natalie is paralyzed from below the waist and spends most of the time in her bedroom. As both Joseph and Kristen are unable to give Natalie the needed attention, they hire the mysterious clown Mr. Coco. Quickly, Natalie befriends Mr. Coco, who starts visiting her on a daily basis. Things change when Mr. Coco tells Natalie a big secret: that he killed someone. After hearing this Natalie asks Mr. Coco: "Would you kill a bad person if I asked you to?" Despite being reluctant at first, Mr. Coco promises Natalie to do so, although he's not fully aware of the consequences this promise will have. At the same time Joseph is trying to find and kill Jerome Woods, a man who seems to have gone into hiding. Joseph has been informed that Jerome has been terrorizing his ex-wife Linda and son Deenan. What Joseph doesn't know is that Jerome Woods is actually the same man who visits his house every day: Mr. Coco.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?544791</url></doc>
