<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="548266">
  <docid>548266</docid>
  <title>The Cheeseburger Manifesto</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Harrison, Michelle (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>food-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">115</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Nicolaou, Ted</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Patel, Kamal (II)</producer>
    <producer>Hall, Martyn</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Nicolaou, Ted</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>An arrogant executive for an American auto company, Jake, smuggles a million dollars in bribe money to Romania weeks after the revolution to grease the wheels of the post-Communist bureaucracy. Jake unwittingly gets swept up in his Romanian chauffeur's dream: the first American style hamburger joint in Eastern Europe. He falls in love with his chauffeur's sister, a firebrand of the opposition party and minor hero of the revolution, who's attracted to him, but offended by everything he stands for. The secret police, suspicious of his fraternizing with dissidents, mistakenly conclude that the burger joint is a front for an American-funded anti-government party, and brand him an enemy of the people. Back home, the SEC investigates the undeclared million, and his American cohorts let him take the fall. In a comedy of errors, he goes on the run, loses the million, and ends up disguised as a peasant, fleeing for his life across the wilds of Transylvania. From Armani suits to peasant rags, from Malibu to the post-Communist Twilight Zone - he journeys light years from home to rediscover the American Dream.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?548266</url></doc>
