<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="548632">
  <docid>548632</docid>
  <title>The Chosen Few</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Gupta, Sudhakar</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">96</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Podder, Robin</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Lasser, Richard</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brannan, Matthew</actor>
      <role>Peter Greenberg</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cohen, Frank</actor>
      <role>Landlord</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Coltress, Oliver</actor>
      <role>Doug</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dallery, Jennie</actor>
      <role>Melinda Firebaugh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>James, Wil</actor>
      <role>Chuck Kaplan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Knollenberg, Lisa</actor>
      <role>Star</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mathews, Bruce</actor>
      <role>Master John Roper</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McClure, Tane</actor>
      <role>Sienna Barr</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Miller, Gerry (II)</actor>
      <role>Agent Tom Flaherty</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Neville, Chris</actor>
      <role>Chris</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sauber, Jeff</actor>
      <role>Blake Driver</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sturm, Gary (I)</actor>
      <role>Dr. Milton Klein</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>John Roper, a disillusioned Vietnam Vet and ex-drug dealer travels through the Orient to get spiritual. He comes back, calling himself The Master, and becomes a charismatic spiritual leader, running a teen shelter in Hollywood. The Master rescues Melinda, a gang-banger on the run; Blake, a failed young artist; and Ariel, teen hooker; and brings them to his shelter along with other social rejects. The Master preaches his self proclaimed spiritual wisdom and eventually selects the most dependable (i.e. desperate) ones who undergo sexually-charged secret rituals and become the 'The Chosen Few'. When Blake is initiated, he agrees to abide by the three cardinal rules: share your spirit, body and soul with others; devote your life to saving homeless kids; and never leave unless the Master casts you out. As the story unfolds, Blake realizes that the Master seduces young devotees including Melinda and Ariel into ritualistic acts of sex. Blake falls in love with Melinda but the Master compels Blake to marry Ariel against his will to keep him away from Melinda his kept woman. Blake now starts to sink into the scary, twisted world of the Master where sharing, sacrifice and loyalty take on bizarre and dangerous new meanings.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?548632</url></doc>
