<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="549168">
  <docid>549168</docid>
  <title>The Closet Tales of Australian Fashion</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Murphy, Bill (III)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>lover</keyword>
    <keyword>new-york-fashion-week</keyword>
    <keyword>paris-fashion-week</keyword>
    <keyword>australian-fashion-week</keyword>
    <keyword>fashion</keyword>
    <keyword>art</keyword>
    <keyword>australian</keyword>
    <keyword>tv-mini-series</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Australia">6 December 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">26</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Tarasin, Jasmin</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Lock, Simon</producer>
    <producer>Marlow, Julie</producer>
    <producer>Rose, Nicole (I)</producer>
    <producer>Tarasin, Jasmin</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bergman, Yael</writer>
    <writer>Hexter, Sophie</writer>
    <writer>Tarasin, Jasmin</writer>
    <writer>Watkins, Polly</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Luscombe, Dan</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chong, Susien</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Isogawa, Akira</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Morrisey, Peter</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nic, Briand</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Willow, Kit</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Tendrils of creativity creep into everyday life. Those who embrace their ingenuity and explore its marketability often end up walking a perilous path: one that struggles to find balance between the creative and the commercial. The Closet Tales of Australian Fashion explores the lives of four prominent Australian fashion designers. Each share a similar passion for fashion, but the working realities of their creative pursuits could not be more varied. Explored through four half-hour episodes, Closet Tales features Australias seminal sartorial stars: Akira Isogowa ,Peter Morrissey, Willow and Lover, offering a rare insight into what it takes to succeed and survive in the highly competitive and ever changing fashion industry. From inception of ideas through to the execution of a complete collection, we follow the designers through the creative highs and the commercial lows of putting a range together. From sketching dreams and sourcing fabrics to showcasing the range at an international fashion week (either locally or abroad) and ensuring that the back-end of their business can fill an order and deliver there product on time. Nurturing the concept of fashion as art, the series looks at the innovative and imaginative ways the designers explore their medium. Whether the art of fashion design is steeped in history as with Akira Isogowa, or achieved through the pop culture driven label Lover, Closet Tales reveals the distinctive and very personal visions of each of these fashion designers.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?549168</url></doc>
