<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="549364">
  <docid>549364</docid>
  <title>The Coffee Thief</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Dickinson, Lance</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">29 September 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">18</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Dickinson, Lance</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Callaway, Ken (I)</producer>
    <producer>Holt, Arnie</producer>
    <producer>Dickinson, Lance</producer>
    <producer>Persico, Evelina</producer>
    <producer>Schlotter, Wally</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Callaway, Ken (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bollinger, Adam</actor>
      <role>Daniel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brunetti, Mark</actor>
      <role>Festival Host</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Castro, Arnoldo</actor>
      <role>Purepecha Storyteller</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Castro, Luis (IX)</actor>
      <role>Medicine man</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chandler, Cristyn</actor>
      <role>Laura</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Coulter, Bridget</actor>
      <role>Pam</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Daniello, Ashley</actor>
      <role>Theater Employee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Denny, Wyatt</actor>
      <role>Kyle</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dickinson, Elizabeth (II)</actor>
      <role>Bonnie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hall, Ryan (II)</actor>
      <role>Quetzemoc</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Richter, Joseph</actor>
      <role>Theater Manager</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In the story Kyle Callaghan falls heir to his grandfathers life-long quest and travels to central Mexico to find the Aztec's most prized possession, Caferi. The fabled coffee-like drink was said to allow "visions of truth to the living and sight through the eyes of the dead." While in a zombie-like state the ancient storytellers were able to see the imaginations of the people they spoke to. Caferi was a secret window to another world used only by the high priests of the day. That is until it was stolen and consumed by Quetzemoc, a covetous Aztec warrior who was not prepared for the visions to come nor the consequence of his act. The legend of the coffee thief was told to Kyle many times by his grandfather, a man known for tall tales. His grandfather bequeathed Kyle just two things - the family coffee business and the means necessary to find the fabled elixir. But the Caferi found him first, turning Kyle into Shipajkula Caferi... The Coffee Thief. Upon his return to civilization an unsuspecting Kyle begins a twisted journey of self-discovery. The same tonic that allows him to see "something amazing" in the people around him may very well show him something very dark in himself. His girlfriend Laura watches Kyle fall apart as he begins an ill-fated attempt to make the world a better and more loving place by using Caferi as a means of pure communication. Is pure communication possible? How thin is the blade of reality? Maybe Kyle is actually seeing mass imagination or maybe its the creeping specter of Victus Mortis Phobia. But zombies don't really exist... do they? Better consider switching back to decaf Kyle.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?549364</url></doc>
