<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="549830">
  <docid>549830</docid>
  <title>The Con Test</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Arriens, Julian</editor>
    <editor>Beauman, Allan</editor>
    <editor>Lord, Andrew</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Game-Show</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>cash-prize</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Australia">PG</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Australia">4 April 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Australia">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Zubairy, Asif</producer>
    <producer>Tate, Stephen (II)</producer>
    <producer>Corrigan, Kalita</producer>
    <producer>Tanner, Geoff (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Hall, Stephen (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Duclos, Brigitte</actor>
      <role>Herself - Host</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>G, Andrew</actor>
      <role>Himself - Host</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Goldman, Grant</actor>
      <role>Announcer</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The Australian version of the elimination quiz. Six contestants are each given $1000 to start with, and then they answer eight multiple-choice questions, adding $500 for each answer that they get right. As they play, each contestant will only know their own score. At the end of the questions, the scores of all of the contestants are revealed to the viewers, then host Andrew G asks the contestants to share their thoughts about the round and how they performed in it. It is up to the contestants to decide if they want to answer truthfully or try to bluff the other contestants into thinking that they did better than they actually did. The contestants then step forward towards their own "fold buttons" to take the "con test", and after some more discussion, they are given a ten-second countdown. If any contestant thinks, rightly or wrongly, that they have the least amount of money, they can choose to hit their button and fold, taking the money that they have earned to that point. If no one has folded by the time the countdown hits 0, then the contestant with the lowest amount of money is eliminated, and leaves the game with nothing. If there is a tie for the lowest score, then the speed with which the contestants selected their answers is used as a tie-breaker, with the slowest contestant being eliminated if they don't choose to fold. In the subsequent rounds, five questions are asked and the amount of money for a correct answer increases by $250 each round, and each round is followed by another "con test". After the last two remaining contestants have answered the final five questions (with every correct answer worth another $1500), they take one final "con test", where if one of them chooses to fold, they will take home the money they have accumulated over the five rounds, but will hand the major prize of $50,000 to their opponent. If neither of them fold, then the person with the higher amount of money wins the $50,000, and the person with the lower amount of money leaves with nothing.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?549830</url></doc>
