<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="551981">
  <docid>551981</docid>
  <title>The Darndest Things</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Wood, Kris (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>student</keyword>
    <keyword>wood</keyword>
    <keyword>kris</keyword>
    <keyword>miami</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">29 August 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">17</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Wood, Kris (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Wood, Kris (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Wood, Kris (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Goldman, Evan (II)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Beach, Matt</actor>
      <role>Judd</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Key, Calvin</actor>
      <role>Marcus</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pursell, Sean</actor>
      <role>Jackson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Roller, Brad</actor>
      <role>Webster</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Marcus Pearl is nearly brought to tears when his young son Jackson begins to repeat a curiously obscene new phrase. Not wanting to burden his wife Deb with the news that their six-year-old son has the mouth of an accident prone mid-shipmen, Marcus makes it his personal mission to pinpoint the origin of such dirty words and wipe them out in order to keep his family together. His search first leads him to suspect those closest to him, that of course being his loud mouthed neighbor, Judd. While he may not be the culprit Marcus is looking for, Judd is happy to suggest alternate leads for Marcus to follow. As Marcus' search becomes more expansive, he soon finds himself in over his head. Mainly with his wife, his community leaders, and even the law. Marcus then soon realizes that perhaps the problem he is looking for may not come from outside sources. Perhaps the problem he has been searching for the whole time lay right in front of him. Will Marcus be able to save his perfect little son before it's too late?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?551981</url></doc>
