<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="553070">
  <docid>553070</docid>
  <title>The Devil in the Detail</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Dominique, Carlos</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">June 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">54</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Greensmith, Heidi</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Wood, Tilly</producer>
    <producer>Greensmith, Heidi</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Greensmith, Heidi</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Greensmith, Dominic</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Tracey Emin calls him an artisan and Christina Aguilera says she is having a love affair with his work and she'll always be a fan. Meet Stephen Webster, the bad boy of jewelery design and subject of Devil In The Detail. With his tattoos, wild hair and leather jacket this charismatic cockney rebel bears no resemblance to your traditional, conservative jeweler. His unique collections, many featuring daggers, skulls and thorns, gained him global notoriety in the 1990s when they were first seen on Hollywood and music A-Listers and led to him being labeled the Rock 'n' Roll Jeweler. Since then his highly desirable and distinctive designs have adorned the bodies of some of the world's most glamorous individuals including Madonna, Elizabeth Taylor, Jennifer Lopez, Brad Pitt, Charlize Theron and Cameron Diaz. A home-grown talent Stephen was a normal kid living in a three bed semi at the edge of the motorway in Gravesend. It was his dreams that made him into a British success story to be proud of. 2006 was his 30th year in business as a fine jeweler and this year he became the creative director at Garrard the oldest jewelers in Britain. Not bad for an art school punk who made his first ring at the tender age of sixteen. Devil In The Detail celebrates Stephen's 30th anniversary in the business, with Kiken Films' director Heidi Greensmith following the 'enfant terrible' on a world tour of four continents. This road movie shows him inspecting a $1/2m 98-carot pariba stone in Las Vegas, struggling with the language barrier with a tattoo artist in Tokyo and mining for gems, the ethical way, in Tanzania and later visiting the hospital and schools funded by the money made from those gems.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?553070</url></doc>
