<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="555697">
  <docid>555697</docid>
  <title>The Essence of a Fighter</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Lords, Antonio</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>fighter</keyword>
    <keyword>mixed-martial-arts</keyword>
    <keyword>live-action</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">20 January 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <producers>
    <producer>Alexander, Julie (VII)</producer>
    <producer>Lords, Antonio</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Alexander, Julie (VII)</writer>
    <writer>Lords, Antonio</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Lords, Antonio</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Alexander, Julie (VII)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fabian (X)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jacobsen, Corey Nels</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lords, Antonio</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Revolution, Aldo</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Antonio Lords becomes a true mixed martial artist and documents his fights while letting the camera tell the truth. As the film maker, he weaves his way through the world of mixed martial arts to help you understand the attraction of the sport. Antonio takes the hard hits and pays the price for the knowledge, but comes out with a new found respect for what a low paid MMA fighter must go through to make it to the top. Antonio interviews with regular people to uncover the true feelings of this vastly popular sport and the true potential without the cooperate involvement, /the real fights and the aftermath are surreal and give a numbing reminder that not everyone can just decide to fight in the world of MMA. Antonio provides a first hand look at what a body goes through and how long it takes to recover and what to avoid in a fight to maintain your name. The interviews with different instructors and seminars are fascinating which encourages the beginning fighter to seek out the best instructors to enhance the mind, body and soul. This documentary is inspiring an one for the ages.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?555697</url></doc>
