<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="555743">
  <docid>555743</docid>
  <title>The Eternal Pitfall of Prokofiev</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>avant-garde</keyword>
    <keyword>period-drama</keyword>
    <keyword>cinémathèque</keyword>
    <keyword>silent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>satire</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>christian</keyword>
    <keyword>surrealism</keyword>
    <keyword>student-film</keyword>
    <keyword>supernatural-power</keyword>
    <keyword>spoof</keyword>
    <keyword>experimental-film</keyword>
    <keyword>magical-realism</keyword>
    <keyword>evil</keyword>
    <keyword>caligari</keyword>
    <keyword>neo-noir</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">13</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Clement, Patrick (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Parker, Dennis (VI)</producer>
    <producer>Clement, Patrick (II)</producer>
    <producer>Goodman, Alanna</producer>
    <producer>Harwell, David Michael</producer>
    <producer>Small, Jeremiah (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Clement, Patrick (II)</writer>
    <writer>Harwell, David Michael</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>MacLeod, Kevin (I)</composer>
    <composer>Maria Dwyer, Anna</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gilliam, Matthew</actor>
      <role>Prokofiev</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mendel, Oron</actor>
      <role>The Devil</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Our "Joe Everybody" hero, Prokofiev, finds himself immersed inside of a strange, but familiar world. Things are not as he remembers them. Yet, he finds his thirst an overwhelming and unquenchable desire. As familiarity turns to elliptical surrealism, soon arrives a character with all of the answers. Somewhat dated in appearance, but unmistakably The Devil, the ominous figure offers a simple answer to Prokofiev's beverage bedevilment. He will gladly exchange a "pitch tinted drink" for his virgin soul. Still unawares of the world in which he now inhabits, Prokofiev thinks nothing of this silly trade and promptly accepts it. Now, having drunk his recently acquired beverage, Prokofiev soon realizes the gravity of the situation. The Devil demands the payment of which he is owed, one Virgin Prokofiev Soul. Panicked, Prokofiev offers a duel, double or nothing. The Devil accepts and they are whisked away to the dueling table. Of course Prokofiev looses, and makes a mad dash in a feeble attempt to escape. Now caught, Prokofiev, pulls one last rabbit out of his hat, and out foxes the Devil with a simple technicality - he had his fingers crossed. Defeated, The Devil promises to return and capture the soul which he still believes is owed to him. As Prokofiev celebrates his victory, he awakes. Laying in his bed. Descending into his kitchen, he finds a full refrigerator of cold refreshing beverages. Sipping from his bottle he turns to leave - sitting confidently behind him is a smiling, laughing Devil. Smugly, he offers a "cheers" in celebration of his now paid-in-full debt. Prokofiev sits up in bed - awake.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?555743</url></doc>
