<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="556794">
  <docid>556794</docid>
  <title>The Family Trees</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>French</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">20 April 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">13</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>McMahon, Bryan</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>McMahon, Bryan</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>McMahon, Bryan</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Charbonnier, Pierre (III)</actor>
      <role>Pierre</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fouquet, Raymond</actor>
      <role>Raymond</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Innocenti, Claude</actor>
      <role>Claude</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nicot, Henri</actor>
      <role>Francois</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sackrider, David</actor>
      <role>The Farmer</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The American owner of a French country home (David Sackrider) continues his annual effort to create a forest behind his property north of Paris. Instead of his usual trip to Belgium to purchase the trees, he visits a local nursery where he selects this year's plantings - Claude, Henri, Raymond and Pierre (all voiced by veterans of the French Foreign Legion). It's a long day for the American; his transportation is garaged a walk, a Metro ride and another walk away from his Paris apartment. Then it's on and off the autoroute before finding the nursery. He then has to squeeze the trees into a too-small minivan, find his way back to the autoroute, reach his destination and, finally, get them into the ground. The trees, meanwhile, are not pleased: It's cold, they're nervous, he's lost. But they're also young, and opinionated, and ready to give the American (and each other) a piece of their French minds. Claude and Pierre are more youthful in spirit while Henri and Raymond aren't quite sure what they've gotten themselves into. The trees provide hilarious running commentary on the misadventures and misdirection of their new caretaker. And argue amongst themselves? Of course - they're family!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?556794</url></doc>
