<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="557371">
  <docid>557371</docid>
  <title>The Fifteenth</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Grey, Ian (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Sport</genre>
    <genre>Biography</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">28 February 2006</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="France">16 May 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">15</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Jones, Neil (IX)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Brennan, Stuart</producer>
    <producer>Jones, Neil (IX)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Jones, Neil (IX)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Deacon, Alan</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Aucott, Phil</actor>
      <role>Vicente Saldivar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bond, Richard (VIII)</actor>
      <role>Terry Spinks</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brennan, Stuart</actor>
      <role>Howard Winstone</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>James, Don (V)</actor>
      <role>Billy Evans</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>White, Edward E.</actor>
      <role>Alberto Serti</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Howard Winstone is a legendary Welsh boxing figure that has been largely forgotten by the public of today. In the film 'The Fifteenth', his skills as a fighter are once more brought to the forefront of our imaginations, and the changing face of Wales, subtly displayed. A young boy overhears three lads remarking on an old man in the corner, that he used to be a figurehead of the boxing world. The boy inquisitively approaches and is about to question the man, when he notices the lack of fingers on the supposed boxers right hand. The boy loudly dismisses the lads claims, much to the amusement of the old man, who invites the boy to take a seat and listen to his tale. Back to the fifties we go and the training of one of the fastest and most powerful boxers of the time; Howard Winstone. The boxer working hard in one of the local factories in Merthyr suffers the agony of the loss of the tips of his fingers in a freak accident, just as he is being tipped for great things in the boxing world. The boy listens with excitement as one man's determination spans a decade of classic boxing, seeing the fighter evolve in to one of the most feared fighters in Europe and eventually the world. The poignancy in the script is drawn through the young lad, who by trying to get served alcohol at an age too young, has seen the errors of his ways by looking in to the past - a thing that we as a society seem to be doing too little these days - remembering our roots and the mistakes of our elders. The films weaves through Welsh culture and sporting achievements with passion and enthusiasm, with strong imagery and both intimate and lavish scenes; highlighting the rise and fall of one of Wales' greatest boxers.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?557371</url></doc>
