<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="557855">
  <docid>557855</docid>
  <title>The Firebird</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Langcake, Andrew</editor>
    <editor>Mannion, Scott</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Russian</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Australia">30 October 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Mannion, Scott</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Andriano, Vincent</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Mannion, Scott</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Cashman, David (II)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bishop, Mark (XII)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Iredell, Maude</actor>
      <role>The Firebird</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Langcake, Andrew</actor>
      <role>Vassili</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Love, Ian (III)</actor>
      <role>Vyslav</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Smith, Don (XXX)</actor>
      <role>The Firefirebird's Father</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Smoliakov, Roman</actor>
      <role>Ivan</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Long ago, in a distant kingdom, in a distant land, lived Tsar Vyslav Andronovich. A Firebird began to visit his garden; her wings were golden and her eyes were like Oriental crystals. Every night she flew down and alighted on Tsar Vyslav's favourite apple tree, plucked some golden apples and then flew away... He summoned his three sons and said to them: "My beloved children, which one of you can catch the Firebird in my garden? To him who catches her alive I will give half of my kingdom during my life, and all of it upon my death. The Firebird, is a modern adaptation of the Russian fairytale. The fable tells the story of a Tsar who promises his kingdom as a reward to the son who can capture the wild and precious Firebird. In our adaption Ivan, struggles between honoring his father, the head of a criminal family, and saving whats left of his soul. It takes a mystical event and a chance meeting for him to realize that gaining that honor would destroy him forever. He can see the darkness in his family, he must now tread his own path.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?557855</url></doc>
