<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="559693">
  <docid>559693</docid>
  <title>The Game</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Nguyen, Vu (VIII)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>based-on-novel</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">4 April 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">4</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Nguyen, Vu (VIII)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Diep, Vinh</producer>
    <producer>Granado, Derek</producer>
    <producer>Weitz, Paul</producer>
    <producer>Miano, Andrew</producer>
    <producer>Nguyen, Vu (VIII)</producer>
    <producer>Weitz, Chris</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Diep, Vinh</writer>
    <writer>Strauss, Neil</writer>
    <writer>Weiss, D.B. (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kraft, Jared</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Diep, Vinh</actor>
      <role>Vincent Li</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hooks, Herb</actor>
      <role>Jackhammer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jagannathan, Poorna</actor>
      <role>Dr. Diamond</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Malenke, Jennifer</actor>
      <role>Traci Glassman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pearl, David (III)</actor>
      <role>Agent</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Snow, Billy</actor>
      <role>Willy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tapia, Joe</actor>
      <role>Rhino</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"The Game" is the All-American story. It is a story of patriotism, survival and redemption. America's beloved underdog football team is finally on its way to their first Superbowl when they are kidnapped and taken to a remote area of the Canada and brutally held by mercenary soldiers of unknown origin. Two unlikely partners are thrown together to rescue the team. The story centers around their efforts, involvement and eventual success. The lead character is JIM REEVES, who until 2 years ago was the NFL's greatest running back until he was thrown out of the league after betting against his own team in the sports biggest scandal. Since that day, Reeves has lived in self-imposed exile as a swamp guide in the Florida Everglades. The antagonist is DOUG BARRETT, today's reigning running back. He is dedicated to breaking Reeve's rushing record and erasing his memory from today's youth by restoring football's positive image. In the course of the story, the two men are forced together to play a real game of life and death in a valiant attempt to save their teammate's lives and reveal the mystery surrounding the kidnapping as well as the truth about each other. "The Game" is the story about when the going gets tough, the tough get going and kick ass - the American way. It is also the story about the spirit of the American public and their ability to "bounce back" and turn a major defeat into a major victory.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?559693</url></doc>
