<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="560295">
  <docid>560295</docid>
  <title>The Ghouligans! Super Show!</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>cult-movie</keyword>
    <keyword>halloween</keyword>
    <keyword>stage-show</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>zombie</keyword>
    <keyword>vampire</keyword>
    <keyword>werewolf</keyword>
    <keyword>vintage</keyword>
    <keyword>classic</keyword>
    <keyword>monster</keyword>
    <keyword>b-movie</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">20 July 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">41</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>King, Sean (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Koscik, Michael</producer>
    <producer>Bune, Pete</producer>
    <producer>King, Sean (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Koscik, Michael</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Laino, Paul T.</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bune, Pete</actor>
      <role>Wolfgang</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Castelli, Dino</actor>
      <role>Vampire Lifeguard Fairling</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Curcio, Erica</actor>
      <role>Ginger</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Frevele, Jamie</actor>
      <role>Gi-Gi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hertz, Justin</actor>
      <role>Count Farnham</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>King, Sean (I)</actor>
      <role>Void</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Koscik, Michael</actor>
      <role>Boris</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Koscik, Theresa</actor>
      <role>Gia</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maggio, Rick</actor>
      <role>Krill Gill</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McGowin, Shane</actor>
      <role>Makeup Artist</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Taffurelli, James</actor>
      <role>Pvt. Taffy/ The Fist</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The Ghouligans are a collection of nostalgic monster dead beats that live for classic comedy and chaos. These retro horror characters deliver an electric mix of fun and excitement. Count Farnham, the most royal of all vampires! Once a proud vampire socialite, now just an old washed out blood sucking embarrassment, he often gives a warped self -righteous view of the underworld. Count Farnham bites! Void, Void, return from the dead, with or without your rotted head! The depressed slow moving hippie zombie, named after the worm infested hole in his heart. Void is always looking for love in all the wrong graveyards. Wolfgang puts the "G "in Groovy! This rock n roll werewolf is the crazy cool ghastly ghoul, who likes to surf, and howl at the moon. Ghouls, girls and good times, Wolfgang is the original party animal! Boris is your typical modern day man-made horror. Created by science to be a domesticated ghoul tool, Boris is the essential square, in a world of cool cats. It is not easy fitting in, when you have two metal bolts in your neck. The Ghouligans! concept combines a deep cast of horror monsters, with a variety of traditional styles. Creative themes and story lines tend to reflect a more simple time in entertainment. The current project " The Ghouligans Super Show! " is a sketch variety television show , that includes spooky skits , creepy talk shows, and haunting original content . It features the Ghouligans as wacky horror television hosts, with a supporting cast of misfit monster performers. The free form of the scenes lends itself to the viewer as a warm blanket of smiles and laughs, perfect for sleeping in on a Saturday morning. There is a current promotions tour scheduled for the release of the DVD. The Ghouligans will be touring the top horror conventions on the east coast of the USA and Canada in 2008.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?560295</url></doc>
