<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="560570">
  <docid>560570</docid>
  <title>The Girl Who Lost</title>
  <year>1917</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">12 March 1917</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Cochrane, George</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Johnstone, Calder</writer>
    <writer>Meredyth, Bess</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Leighton, Daniel (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Madison, Cleo (I)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Malone, Molly (I)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nelson, Jack (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Star Cleo Madison plays a chorus girl and is supporting her younger sister Frances who wants to be an actress. Cleo gets work and has to go on the road, and leaves her sister in care of the landlady. The landlady looks the other way and, ere long, the sister has sacrificed her honor and ends up more than a little bit pregnant. Cleo returns, finds out her sister is well along the path of motherhood and Cleo is more than a little bit peeved about it. She becomes acquainted with the son of the man who despoiled her little sister. The son, Hayden, is engaged to Millicent, a nice girl in no danger of allowing herself to become despoiled. But Cleo the Vamp wins the affectation of the fickle Hayden to the point he is willing to throw the pure Millicent aside. Then Cleo calls on the father, who is all for his son marrying the un-despoiled Millicent and tells the old rake he will either marry her despoiled sister...or she will marry Hayden. The father, hopefully a widower or at least divorced, says he will do the right thing. Thusly, Cleo, who has fallen in love with Hayden,has to give him up to ensure her sister's happiness.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?560570</url></doc>
