<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="562574">
  <docid>562574</docid>
  <title>The Greatest Lesson: Robin's Story</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Chaignat, Frédéric</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>death</keyword>
    <keyword>forgiveness</keyword>
    <keyword>hope</keyword>
    <keyword>faith</keyword>
    <keyword>struggle</keyword>
    <keyword>breast-cancer</keyword>
    <keyword>cancer</keyword>
    <keyword>monologue</keyword>
    <keyword>love</keyword>
    <keyword>document</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Unrated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">7 December 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">62</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Westberg, Robert</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Westberg, Diana</producer>
    <producer>Westberg, Robert</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Westberg, Robert</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Westberg, Robert</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The Greatest Lesson - Robin's Story is the true and gripping story of Robin Westberg's 5 year battle with stage 4 metastatic breast cancer. Her story is told by her surviving husband, Robert Westberg, in a moving testament to love, hope, forgiveness and faith. This docudrama weaves gripping emotion with life events starting from her initial diagnosis, to the multiple procedures and surgeries, and culminates with her final courageous stand against cancer. The Greatest Lesson is one of courage, deep faith, and boundless love. Robin Westberg characterized her life with effusive strength, determination, grace, and hope. Her spirit and light affected all who knew her. Her struggle was a triumph, showing us all that the most effective medicine doesn't come from a pharmacy; it is in our hearts from the moment we are created. Robin's Story isn't just the story of one brave woman's fight against a terminal illness. Within is a shining example of who we can all become, if we take the courage to see and know the One that shapes our lives and our tomorrows. She is your sister, your cousin, your mother, your father, your daughter, your son, your uncle, your best friend. In her story, we are all one. We are all in this world together, our lives touching when we least expect it. Take a moment and look deep inside yourself... do you let yourself become defined by your situation or rise above it to define your character? How will you face your destiny?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?562574</url></doc>
