<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="564575">
  <docid>564575</docid>
  <title>The History of University of Kentucky Basketball</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Pickart, Ed</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Sport</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">4 December 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Carlson, D.P.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Rudman, Peter</producer>
    <producer>Carlson, D.P.</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>Since its inception in 1902, the University of Kentucky Basketball program has amassed 1,948 wins against only 608 losses for a staggering 76.2% winning percentage. No other school has as many wins or a greater all-time winning percentage, not UCLA, not UNC, Indiana or Duke. Kentucky's accomplishments don't end there however. 7 National Championships, 13 Final Four Appearances, 46 NCAA Tournament appearances, 139 NCAA Tournament Games, 43 SEC Championships and 25 SEC Tournament Championships have clearly established Kentucky basketball as one of the greatest programs in all of sports in the U.S., college or professional. These impressive numbers are very much part of the tradition and glory that surround University of Kentucky Basketball. However, just as much a part of this tradition is the players and coaches who have guided the program over the years. Legendary coaches like Adolph Rupp, Joe B. Hall, Rick Pitino and Tubby Smith. Players such as Louie Dampier, Dan Issell, Pat Riley, Jack "Goose" Givens, Kyle Macy, Sam Bowie, Kenny Walker, John Pelphrey, Rex Chapman, Jamal Mashburn, Ron Mercer, Tony Delk, Tayshaun Prince, Keith Bogans and many more. Own this extraordinary piece of University of Kentucky Basketball history and relive some of the greatest moments of one of college basketball's more storied programs.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?564575</url></doc>
