<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="565336">
  <docid>565336</docid>
  <title>The House of Adam</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Ballon, Paul</editor>
    <editor>Lavin, John (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Mystery</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Panama">1 January 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Mexico">28 May 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">31 October 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">83</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Ameer, Jorge</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ameer, Jorge</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Ameer, Jorge</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Dickey, Brent J.</composer>
    <composer>Jossifov, Ilia Eshkenazy</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ameer, Jorge</actor>
      <role>Real Estate Agent</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brown, Joella</actor>
      <role>Monica</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cadwell, Jared</actor>
      <role>Adam</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Davison, Rex</actor>
      <role>Brett</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Howard, Reeve (I)</actor>
      <role>Mark</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Howard, Reeve (II)</actor>
      <role>Mark</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kappler, Thomas Michael</actor>
      <role>Albert Ross</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Karriker, Lexi</actor>
      <role>Nina</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lee, Marcelle</actor>
      <role>Joanne</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McFarland, Tiffany</actor>
      <role>Helen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ryan, Ted (V)</actor>
      <role>David</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shaw, John (XIII)</actor>
      <role>Anthony Ross</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stepp, Scott</actor>
      <role>Roger</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This is the newest, most dramatic and most thought-provoking cinematic thriller from Jorge Ameer, director of The Singing Forest. This intensely emotional supernatural tale revolves around Adam, a congenial recluse living quietly in a small town, who is brutally murdered by a trio of religious fanatics. His lover, a closeted police detective, is forced to live with the guilt and sorrow of having kept his now-deceased lover isolated and hidden from view within their cozy but isolated cabin.  Concerned about the reaction of his colleagues within the police force, he keeps his lifestyle a secret, suppressing any real insights into his inner core. One day, ironically, he becomes the victim of his own double-sided values. The results evolve into a tragic and traumatic ordeal for Anthony as he's forced, as part of a murder that he's charged with unraveling, to unearth the bodily remains of the victim (his former lover) as the first step in solving the mystery.  Things turn scary when Adam's spirit remains within the cabin as a vital and sometimes visible force.  Unfulfilled and unsatisfied, the spirit lingers uncomfortably between the living and the dead, making appearances to a newlywed couple that now lives where Adam did. The now-traumatized Anthony attempts to solve the mystery of who committed the murder.   Only a proper burial can give closure to Adam's spirit as it haunts the cabin. Complicating matters is the fact that shortly after the murder, the cabin is sold to an innocent and now-terrified newlywed couple. Watch the trailer of this film at the distributor's website www.hollywoodindependents.com</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?565336</url></doc>
