<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="565914">
  <docid>565914</docid>
  <title>The Ice House</title>
  <year>2010</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>betrayal</keyword>
    <keyword>fbi</keyword>
    <keyword>house</keyword>
    <keyword>mole</keyword>
    <keyword>ice-hook</keyword>
    <keyword>killer</keyword>
    <keyword>drug-lord</keyword>
    <keyword>murder</keyword>
    <keyword>mexican</keyword>
    <keyword>survival</keyword>
    <keyword>mexico</keyword>
    <keyword>suspense</keyword>
    <keyword>sociopath</keyword>
    <keyword>terror</keyword>
    <keyword>ice</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2010</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Giannantonio, Michael</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Romley, Jamie</producer>
    <producer>Hugo, Stephen Lee</producer>
    <producer>Luyet, Frank</producer>
    <producer>McCoy, Joshua (II)</producer>
    <producer>Giannantonio, Michael</producer>
    <producer>Walker, Rob (I)</producer>
    <producer>Walters, Rik</producer>
    <producer>Giannantonio, Michael</producer>
    <producer>Voight, John (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Giannantonio, Michael</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Castro, Mary</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Janzen, Jesse</actor>
      <role>Greg</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lowell, Andrea</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Palmieri, Louie</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Reeve, Devin</actor>
      <role>Attached</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rosete, Jose</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In 1987, a series of unimaginable murders occurred in a rundown Ice House just inside the Mexican border. Now, some thirteen years later, the legacy of terror continues when Mexican drug lord Pablo Costa claims the now abandoned Ice House for his own. The setting, a small Mexican border town of Ojinaga, is a place where corruption runs deep and the law exists only to the highest bidder. Pablo, using the Ice House to cleverly disguise drugs inside blocks of ice, seems to have the perfect organization, that is until it's discovered a ruthless killer lurks within the Ice House. When a government task force is assembled to stop Pablo, now nicknamed "the Iceman", they seize a shipment of drugs at the border and recover an invitation to a party Pablo is planning. The task force is quick to assemble an action packed raid on the Ice House, little do they know they're about to embark upon a gruesome adventure that will leave them chilled to the bone. When the teenage daughter of the agent in charge steals the invitation and is coaxed by her friends into going, it is quickly discovered that there is something to fear other than Pablo himself. The gang of teenage friends is about to make their way to Mexico for an onslaught of action packed horror so cold it'll keep you frozen stiff. THE ICE HOUSE is an exciting tale of strength and survival against impossible odds, filled with terror, suspense and action!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?565914</url></doc>
