<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="566417">
  <docid>566417</docid>
  <title>The Inheritance</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Li, Man Chong</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">21 April 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">62</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="default">62</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Belleville, Charles Henri</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Barrow, John &amp; Jo</producer>
    <producer>Boaretto, David</producer>
    <producer>Barrow, Tim</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Barrow, Tim</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Freemoore</composer>
    <composer>Rutherford, Fiona</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barrow, Tim</actor>
      <role>David</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hardy, Tom (I)</actor>
      <role>Dad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sivewright, Fraser</actor>
      <role>Fraser</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A man makes a phone call to his dying father. Two brothers meet at their father's funeral. DAVID has come up from London. FRASER lives in the village in Scotland he grew up in. On a journey to discover their father's inheritance, which they are told in his will is located somewhere on the Isle of Skye, they set off in their father's old VW van and head north. This brings arguments, comedy, conflict and bitter memories as they are forced to confront their past and each other. When they pick up a hitchhiker TARA, she fascinates them both, and brings them to breaking point. She leaves them, taking the van, and DAVID heads off through the land of Skye to find their destination. They discover there is nothing there. The church is a ruin. DAVID breaks and flees. He reaches the sea, and with nowhere else to go, there he and FRASER finally confront each other. FRASER demands to know DAVID'S secret. DAVID refuses and tries to leave, and in a fit of anger FRASER kills his brother. He's left holding DAVID'S body in his arms. The sun sets over the sea.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?566417</url></doc>
