<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="567262">
  <docid>567262</docid>
  <title>The Jazzspel with Eric J</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bagdasarian, Prince</editor>
    <editor>Chambers, Eric J.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>News</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">14 June 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Chambers, Eric J.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Chambers, Eric J.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Chambers, Eric J.</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>The Jazzspel with Eric J. Chambers, a reality music and entertainment show, airs every Saturday at 4:30 pm EST/1:30 pm PST and repeats on Mondays at 3pm EST/12Noon PST on The Word Network, an urban inspirational station. The network is available in over 32 million homes in the United States via DirecTV (Channel 373) and cable. It also reaches over 75 million homes in Africa, The Bahamas and Jamaica, and is picked up in over 185 different countries via the Armed Forces Network. "So far, the response has been great-from viewers and entertainers alike," says Chambers, the host and executive producer of the Hollywood-based show that debuted on June 14, 2003. The Jazzspel counts among its viewers The Gap Band and Arsenio Hall, both of whom have appeared on the show. The Jazzspel is not limited to just religious-based artists. R&amp;B artists such as Beyonce', Howard Hewett, Jill Scott and Rachelle Ferrell; smooth jazz artists such as Kirk Whalum, Michael Lington, Jonathan Butler, George Duke, and Mindi Abair; and entertainers such as Vivica A. Fox, Arsenio Hall, Holly Robinson-Peete, Queen Latifah, Kimberly Elise, and Mo'Nique; and sports figures Serena Williams, Barry Bonds, Emmitt Smith, LaDainian Tomlinson, Julius "Dr. J." Erving, George Gervin, Joe Morgan, Jermaine O'Neal, James Toney, Chris Berman, Derrick Brooks, Lisa Leslie and Magic Johnson have appeared on the show.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?567262</url></doc>
