<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="567613">
  <docid>567613</docid>
  <title>The Journal of Edwin Carp</title>
  <year>2000</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bengston, Ray</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 February 2000</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">7</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Bazley, Richard</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bengston, Ray</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bazley, Richard</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Laurie, Hugh</actor>
      <role>Edwin Carp</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The Journal of Edwin Carp Set to the strains of an early Beethoven quartet, this droll shaggy dog story relates the unfortunate series of misadventures that befalls the title character when he attempts to rectify a small plumbing problem. Based on the book of the same name by Richard Haydn, with illustrations by the renowned British illustrator, Ronald Searle -- whose style inspired the film's design, The Journal of Edwin Carp was created using Flash and After Effects, which is somewhat remarkable considering its hand-drawn look. The loose drawing style and purposefully understated narration is punctuated by a small number of judicious camera moves and oddly shifting perspectives, all of which serves to convey the story's dry humor and whimsical outlook in a most efficacious manner. Director Richard Bazley has worked for the past decade as a supervising animator for three of the major animation studios, Sullivan Bluth, Walt Disney and Warner Bros. Best known for his supervisory work on The Iron Giant, he was a lead animator on Disney's Hercules and has contributed to Pocahontas, Osmosis Jones and many other animated features. Most recently he was an Animation Supervisor on Steve Oedekerk's Barnyard the Movie and currently at Aardman Storyboarding on series called Chop Socky Chooks. The Journal of Edwin Carp, which is Bazley's directorial debut, received some financial support from Macromedia and Wacom, but was largely self-funded. It has been shown at Laemmle's Theatre on Sunset LA,the Teeside Animation Festival in the U.K. and a number of other venues.The film was Prouduced by Ray Bengston.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?567613</url></doc>
