<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="568365">
  <docid>568365</docid>
  <title>The King and Queen Arriving at Westminster Abbey</title>
  <year>1902</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>News</genre>
  </genres>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">30 August 1902</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>King Edward VII</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Motion picture films of the coronation of King Edward VII, which took place on August 9th, 1902, were ready for delivery from our factory at Orange, N. J., on the 18th the Monday, next following. A cablegram from our special photographers in London on August 9th, 1902, advised us that they had secured the complete pictures on that day, that the pictures were sent to Queenstown, and placed on board the fast steamship "Umbria" of the Cunard Line, sailing Sunday, August 10th, 1902. Thus we were enabled to receive the coronation films in America at least three days in advance of mail matter which was posted in London on the day of the coronation. Remember we had the exclusive right of kinetographing the ceremonies at Westminister Abbey, and our pictures were not only the first to arrive in America, but they were the only authentic views. A wonderful film, showing the crowds that stayed upwards of eight hours waiting for the arrival of their majesties, King Edward VII, and Queen Alexandra. Our camera commanded a most perfect view of this occasion, taking in the double line of military men, who stand at attention as the King and Queen pass. In front of Westminster Abbey was probably the best decorated portion of the route over which the King and Queen passed. The lines drawn up were composed of the following soldiers: The Lief Guards, with their white plumes and white sheepskin saddles. The resplendent Royal Horse Guards. A line of strawhatted bluejackets, with fixed bayonets, from H. M. S. "Cambridge." The Yeomen of the Guards, carrying their halberds. Before the arrival of the royal carriages accompanying the King our camera was set in motion, and the procession passed in the following order. The carriage drawn by the six black horses, containing the King's daughters, accompanied by little Lady Alexandra Duff. Next came the Prince and Princess of Wales and their suite, accompanied by the Headquarters' Staff. Lord Kitchener was loudly cheered. He was followed by Lord Roberts, who was escorted by Colonial and Indian Cavalry. Just then there is a great commotion as the arrival of the King and Queen is proclaimed. Directly, the splendid coach containing their Majesties appears, and passes close to the camera, the walking guards keeping close by the heads of the eight cream colored horses. A grand and imposing spectacle from start to finish.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?568365</url></doc>
