<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="568842">
  <docid>568842</docid>
  <title>The Lady Thief and the Baffled Bobbies</title>
  <year>1903</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">1903</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">September 1903</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Stow, Percy</director>
  </directors>
<plot>This film is remarkable in many ways. The idea is a daring one and is carried out in an exceedingly clever fashion. An expert diamond thief, who has made a large haul, is being followed by the police and makes his escape by disguising himself as a handsomely attired young woman. The opening scene shows the detectives searching for the thief in the railroad station. They unwittingly allow the supposed young woman to pass into the train with her satchel full of booty. Just as the train pulls out, word comes to the detectives telling them the character of the disguise adopted by the thief. They try to catch the train but are too late. The next scene shows the interior of an English coach, where the thief is seen laying aside his feminine apparel and assuming his natural appearance of a young clerk. The next scene shows the train arriving at its destination and the force of detectives pacing up and down the platform, carefully scrutinizing the occupant of each compartment. The young man walks out with his satchel, but inasmuch as the police have been instructed to look for a woman, they do not notice him and only discover their mistake when they find the feminine wearing apparel discarded in the car. Their chagrin at being so easily baffled makes a very amusing finish to a very thrilling and interesting film. The picture is very sharp and clear throughout.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?568842</url></doc>
