<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="569416">
  <docid>569416</docid>
  <title>The Last Frontier</title>
  <year>1999</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Belhumeur, Alain</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2 February 1999</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">55</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Lemire, Jean (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Couët, Gilles</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lemire, Jean (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Smutylo, Allen</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Three men and a passion... Through an extraordinary adventure that unfolds in Labrador, Hawaii, and Alaska, they share the excitement, beauty and unknown mystery of a new world... a world still scarcely unchanged, where creatures live as they lived thousands of years ago, a world so close to our own, yet so different. The line between these two worlds is drawn only by the surface of the oceans that cover the planet. Beneath this line is another world, an underwater world that is home to the last giants on earth... The passionate people, with three distinct backgrounds, share an adventure that was the fulfillment of a dream: to explore the mysterious world of the humpback whale. The first member of the trio is renowned Canadian painter Allen Smutylo. The second, Gilles Couët, is an adventurer. The third, Jean Lemire, is a scientist. Each brings his own training, experience, and vision. They came together, inspired by art, adventure and nature. The challenge then was to give expression to the resulting experience. Through this remarkable journey with whales, we follow the entire process of inspiration and creation. Beneath each line drawn by the artist is a real experience helps us to understand the emotions within. The Last Frontier is an impassioned look at nature, with breathtaking footage, where art, science and adventure blend together to express the full range of emotions generated by an adventure in another world, a world beneath the line.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?569416</url></doc>
