<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="570462">
  <docid>570462</docid>
  <title>The Legend of Bruce Lee</title>
  <year>1976</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>fighting</keyword>
    <keyword>martial-arts</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Cantonese</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Hong Kong</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Hong Kong">1976</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Lau, Daniel</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Lau, Daniel</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Le, Bruce</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In this tale of vengeance, Bruce is a young teenager who is the leader of the Liu City gang, who gets into trouble and street fights every now and again. Bruce is a student in the style of Chinese boxing, but when his skills are not enough to fend off a rival kung fu gang, his father has him go to a man named Master Yen, who teaches him Wing Chun fist. While continuing his training, Bruce and his team confront a bunch of street youths in a rumble and beat them all to a pulp. Apparently, the Master of the youths isn't too happy about some street punk beating his star pupils, so he sends his younger brother and a couple of other students to prepare a trap for Bruce and the Liu City Gang. Bruce is badly beaten and hung upside down outside of a tall building, while his friends On Yu and Ah Choi are also badly beaten. For Ah Choi, the beating is so bad that he dies, but An Yu survives. Bruce goes back to Macau where he asks the She Quan (Snake Style) Fist master that he meets earlier in the film to teach him style of combat. This master teaches Bruce the deadly art of the 3 Cobras and after utilizing and combining the technique with that of Drunken Styles, Bruce is ready to even the score, which he does with deadly kung fu accuracy. The rival kung fu clan is starting to see Bruce as a problem, so they enlist the aid of Mr. Kim, one of the top kung fu fighters in the movie and the father of one of the students Bruce beats into a coma. Mr. Kim learns who attacked his son and sends his top students after Bruce and On Yu, who Bruce is teaching the Snake Fist Style to. An all out battle ensues as Bruce and On Yu utilize their skills to get past the students and straight after Mr. Kim and the people responsible for killing Ah Choi.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?570462</url></doc>
