<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="570764">
  <docid>570764</docid>
  <title>The Libertines</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Wolding, Jonathan</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>libertine</keyword>
    <keyword>psycho-thriller</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">15 October 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">9</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Sherard, Nicholas A.J.</director>
    <director>Wolding, Jonathan</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Wolding, Jonathan</producer>
    <producer>Bruce, Alec</producer>
    <producer>Persons, Jennifer K.</producer>
    <producer>Windish, Brandon</producer>
    <producer>Wolding, Jonathan</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bruce, Alec</writer>
    <writer>Windish, Brandon</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Ramirez, Michael Xavier</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Badger, Jereme</actor>
      <role>Mark</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bishop, Ben (II)</actor>
      <role>Joel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Capaz, Justin</actor>
      <role>Michael</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Leigh, Stephanie</actor>
      <role>Dawn</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moore, Lynn (IV)</actor>
      <role>Mary</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>THE LIBERTINES is an ensemble thriller set within the speed dating circuit. Two undercover detectives, Jenna and Tom fail to trap a serial killer preying on single women via the personal ads. Meanwhile Joel, a sacked sales executive drowns his sorrows in a bar. He still craves the satisfaction of a "kill". He decides to apply his selling skills to improve his empty love life. He quickly finds success by applying his sales management techniques to his dating strategy. Joel befriends Declan, an investment banker impressed by Joel's science. Declan introduces Joel to the speed dating circuit, which he describes as the "the ultimate numbers game". Jenna and Tom also switch their focus to speed dating as they follow the serial killer's tracks. Tom indicates to Jenna that her stoic and reserved manner may affect their success in catching the killer in the speed dating circuit. Jenna rises to the challenge and transforms herself with a fictional identity of a sultry air-stewardess. Joel isn't one to be bluffed, sensing there is more to her than she says. As a romance blossoms between this unlike pair, Tom identifies a pattern than confirms Joel as the chief suspect in the serial killer case. Is Joel the killer who relishes both the hunt and the kill? The resulting investigation reveals sex, tragedy and loneliness in the city. THE LIBERTINES is a disturbing psychological masterpiece.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?570764</url></doc>
