<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="571217">
  <docid>571217</docid>
  <title>The Lingerie Salesman's Worst Nightmare</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Arguilo</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>feminization</keyword>
    <keyword>erotica</keyword>
    <keyword>femdom</keyword>
    <keyword>bdsm</keyword>
    <keyword>spanking</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Arguilo</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Floyd, Michele</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Arguilo</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brixton</actor>
      <role>Brixton Jones</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The Lingerie Salesman Worst Nightmare - Brixton Jones is the most successful Lingerie Salesman in North America and the Boss from hell. He demands perfection from his female employees. He won't hesitate to put them over his knee (or his desk) and teach them a lesson...the old fashioned way. Unfortunately, at a fashion show held by the company's largest buyer, Sky Taylor, the models don't show up. Brixton and his secretary, Ally Ann, have to deal with the wrath of Sky. Brixton finds himself on the receiving end of the same punishment he gave his secretary: over the knee of the sexy, unrelenting, Sky Taylor. Sky beats, spanks, and pummels Brixton forcing him and Ally to model bondage gear and lingerie in front of the large audience. Brixton is humiliated as he models the panties, bras, baby dolls and evening gown of his own lingerie line. Sky begins to fancy the submissive Ally Ann and beds her right in front of the horrified and sissified Brixton. As a reward for her sexual prowess Sky begins to train Ally how to deal with pansies like Brixton. Soon Brixton is over the knee of his secretary as she spanks him like she owns him. He is then violated by both women while the crowd cheers them on. Our best forced cross-dressing, over the knee spanking, quality fetish erotica movie yet.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?571217</url></doc>
