<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="571315">
  <docid>571315</docid>
  <title>The Lisa Jackson Documentary</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Carver, Colly</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>interview</keyword>
    <keyword>transgender</keyword>
    <keyword>rock-'n'-roll</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Goldstein, Becca</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Carver, Colly</producer>
    <producer>Goldstein, Becca</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Jackson, Lisa (XIV)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cahoon, Kevin</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cohen, Todd (IV)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>County, Jayne</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Doroshow, Jack</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hammond, Darrell</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jackson, Lisa (XIV)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Johnson, Dean (V)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lambe, Annique</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tut, Corey</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A young boy in Fayetteville, Georgia, dreams of rock 'n' roll stardom as he fishes with his father in the river behind his rural home. He races his big brother on their motorbikes and attends church with his family. As a teen, he joins a Christian rock band and fantasizes about being a race-car driver when he is grown up. After high school graduation, he moves to New York City to pursue an acting career and plays in several rock bands. Then his life is forever altered by the awakening realization that he is, in fact, a she. With courage, humor and determination she confronts her reality head on and finds not only a new identity, but the hidden depths of her talent as a songwriter and a musician. She becomes Lisa Jackson, creates the Lisa Jackson and Girl Friday band and writes rock 'n' roll music that will inspire and thrill many in the coming years. The Lisa Jackson Documentary is the raw story of the emergence of Lisa Jackson as a human being and as a rock 'n' roll star. In interviews, she elicits praise from such fans as the Academy Award nominated actress Rosie Perez, punk rock legend Jayne County and Saturday Night Live's Darrell Hammond. In addition, home movies, backstage footage, footage of Lisa hanging out with friends, and at home with her female partner are used to paint a portrait of a powerful human force. Concert footage from clubs like the world famous CBGBs show us a talent capable of moving straight, gay, lesbian and trans-gendered audiences alike. Through Lisa's story, we also explore the history of trans rock 'n' roll and the changing face of trans-gendered people in contemporary America. Audiences will be inspired by Lisa Jackson's determination to live her life with integrity and to keep her feet on the ground. They will be thrilled to see her develop into a performer who many believe will, once and for all time, break through the curtain that has kept trans-gendered artists from the mainstream.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?571315</url></doc>
