<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="572325">
  <docid>572325</docid>
  <title>The Lord's Prayer</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>kids-and-family</keyword>
    <keyword>answer-to-prayer</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 June 2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Rich, Richard</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Young, Seldon</producer>
    <producer>Brown, Jared F.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Nissen, Brian (II)</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>On many occasions Jesus taught His disciples the power of prayer through parables and example. After Jesus' resurrection and ascension into Heaven, His disciples find their faith tested when Peter is arrested and cast into a Roman prison. As Herod plots Peter's death, the believers gather together and follow the example that Jesus taught. Through faith and persistent prayer, Peter's chains are broken and the Angel of the Lord opens the prison gates. The united prayers of the righteous save Peter and is still a power on Earth without equal. Peter and Mark return to Jerusalem following a mission converting hundreds. The Romans despise the Christians and want to make an example of Peter. Roman soldiers arrest Peter. The disciples gather at Mark's house and discuss Peter's arrest. They recall when the Romans arrested James and killed him. Peter is charged with treason and informed, if convicted, the penalty is death. The disciples discuss how best to free Peter. The disciples feel anger toward the Romans but also feel hopelessness with the situation. Mark's mother, Mary, challenges the disciples and recalls Jesus' Sermon on the Mount. Joash believes it is weak to sit idly by and rushes off to free Peter. Following Jesus' example, the others gather in prayer. The disciples go door to door throughout the city of Jerusalem to ask fellow Christians to pray for Peter's release. Christians recall Jesus' parable about the friend in the night who continues to ask and finally receives his request for bread. They also remember Jesus' parable about the widow and the unrighteous judge. The widow's persistence enables her to win over the heart of the judge to get her house back. The Romans plan to secretly judge Peter in the middle of the night and the disciples' faith waivers again. However, Mary recalls how in the Garden of Gethsemane Jesus prayed to the Lord about His mission and man's salvation. Christians throughout Jerusalem continue to pray for Peter's release. Meanwhile Joash attempts to pay off the Roman guards to release Peter. The Roman guards trick Joash and take his money but do not free Peter. In the middle of the night, an angel rescues Peter and leads him out of prison. Peter beckons Rhoda to tell the others. The others see that Peter is freed. Peter shares with the disciples how their prayers have been answered and he was set free by an angel sent from God. Joash is humbled and falls to his knees in prayer. Peter leaves Jerusalem and instructs the remaining disciples to feed His sheep and teach them about the power of prayer.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?572325</url></doc>
