<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="572566">
  <docid>572566</docid>
  <title>The Lost Toy</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Ji, Hyungjoon Peter</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">24</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Ji, Hyungjoon Peter</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Galarza, Isaiah</producer>
    <producer>Ji, Hyungjoon Peter</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Ji, Hyungjoon Peter</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Klimaszewski, Bartosz</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carlton, Thomas</actor>
      <role>Jack Duncan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dowd, Jim (I)</actor>
      <role>Gregg Fisher</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Peirce, Jason</actor>
      <role>Johnny</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puliafico, Sam</actor>
      <role>Scott Fisher</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Reneaud, John (I)</actor>
      <role>Spencer</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Jack, black bike patrol officer, reminds the police chief Gregg Fisher of the dinner party at his place. On his shift when Jack catches a white young boy and a black young boy tagging a graffiti wall, he growls only at the first, unleashing his anger at him for being white and disobedient, and takes his super cop toy away for punishment. Later when Gregg and his wife Tiffany show up at the door, Jack is shocked to learn that the white boy turns out to be Gregg's son Scott. Scott reveals his bitter encounter with Jack to everyone. Jack responsively shoots it down by disclosing the fact of the kids tagging the wall, of which Gregg and Tiffany naturally strongly disapprove. However, Scott's uproarious revelation about his terrifying engagement with Jack forces Jack to concede of what he did. Jack then confides the event that took place earlier pushed him to the edge. When Spencer's sunglasses disappeared in the locker room, Spencer and Johnny accused Jack of stealing them. They hounded him and haggled him to empty his backpack to prove his innocence. The sunglasses were uncovered out of his backpack when Spencer threw it. Gregg expresses regret about unintended trouble for Jack because he put the sunglasses in his. In humiliation and futility, Jack turns to Scott and asks for forgiveness. In awakening Gregg promises Jack of making the problem go away. After the Fishers leave, Jack produces the toy out of his backpack and chucks it away.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?572566</url></doc>
