<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="572618">
  <docid>572618</docid>
  <title>The Lottery</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>von Scheele, Andreas</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>vietnam-era</keyword>
    <keyword>draft-dodger</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">9 December 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">13</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>von Scheele, Andreas</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>von Scheele, Andreas</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Pettitt, Jeff</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Conway, Kevin (I)</actor>
      <role>Father</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kehoe, Matthew</actor>
      <role>Alex</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rinaldi, Joe (III)</actor>
      <role>Jim</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>1969, Upstate New York. Alex, 18, and Jim, 18, are picked with high numbers in the Vietnam Selective Service Lottery and they have three days left to report to active duty. Despite Alex's father's advice, they decide to take matters into their own hands. In order to fake a hunting accident, they plan to shoot a bullet through both their legs, rendering them 4f or unfit for military service. Believing that, though dishonorable, the plan might save his son's life, Alex's father lets them go through with their plan even though he has an opportunity to stop them. The plan fails. The bullet only hits Jim in the leg and misses Alex. In an expression of anger and protection, Alex's father locks them in the barn, while he runs to call an ambulance, but, Jim, trying to escape, slips and falls down a flight of stairs to his death. In a panic, Alex tries to shoot open the latch on the barn door. Having heard the crash of Jim falling down the stairs, Alex's father runs to help them, but through the barn doors he is inadvertently shot and killed by Alex. Alex runs to his side, but it's too late. Alex turns the gun on himself. He is left with three choices, suicide, a murder rap, or Vietnam.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?572618</url></doc>
