<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="575624">
  <docid>575624</docid>
  <title>The Master of Farnow</title>
  <year>2010</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
    <country>Hungary</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Germany">2010</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Germany">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Cirkó, József</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Mayersberg, Paul</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Koch, Sebastian</actor>
      <role>Klaus</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>1910 Pommerania - Germany Thomas von Farnow wakes from a menacing, erotic dream. It will stay with him through the summer holiday at his ancestral home and eventually unlock the true nature of his domineering father, Klaus. Thomas has failed his exams and left his boarding school in disgrace. At 18 he's come of age and now finds everything at home is subtly altered. His childhood friend, a country boy, has been made his personal valet. From now on they're master and servant. And his father is distant, Thomas' growing isolation is only lifted by his cousin Ellita. At twenty-five she's fascinating, glamorous and unpredictable. From seeing her as some kind of older sister destined to marry well, Thomas now feels her erotic charge. Ellita shows him her mother's sensual journal of years ago, when she had a passionate affair with an unnamed lover. Fascinated, Ellita &amp; Thomas are drawn together as they try to discover his identity from the clues in the journal. Unknown to them, Klaus was that lover. And the journal reveals the layers of the lover's past. As Thomas gets closer to Ellita, he unwittingly steps into the last ripples of his father's youth. Suddenly Ellita reveals that she has had an affair with her uncle Klaus and though it's now over, Thomas' innocence is shattered. Klaus, having lost Ellita, now wants his son to marry her. But Klaus is as vulnerable as he is manipulative, and Thomas discovers a final and most shocking secret. This threatens to wreck his own love for Ellita, and destroys his father. Thomas finds himself the new Master of Farnow, burdened with a secret he has to keep to protect his future and his family's name. His strange summer dream has become a reality - and he knows he is becoming his father.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?575624</url></doc>
