<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="576836">
  <docid>576836</docid>
  <title>The Mirrors of Longreach Mansion</title>
  <year>2011</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Mystery</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>house-of-mirrors</keyword>
    <keyword>castle</keyword>
    <keyword>kids-and-family</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">June 2011</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Coonce, Michael</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Coonce, Michael</producer>
    <producer>Farster, Bob</producer>
    <producer>Pucello, Jody</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Coonce, Michael</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Longreach Mansion is one of the oldest castles in the United States. It was built by the first priests to come to the New World. Unlike Protestants and other religions; Catholicism has a rigid hierarchy. Coming to the New World created challenges for the priest's on the ground. One of the challenges was the lose of the rite to exorcism's. Without a hierarchy, the priest's were no longer allowed to authority to perform the ritual. Year after year, the priest's watched as populations were killed off by disease, famine, and the harsh winters of the Northeast. These conditions made the area ripe for lost souls, whom still haunt the area to this day. Unable to exorcise the spirits, the priest came up with a new ritual. They would capture the spirits in mirrors until a time in the future when the church is established, then they would exorcise them. Though, the centuries, Longreach Mansion was lost to French, then back to the Americans, back and forth as wars and new borders where drawn. Ultimately leaving Longreach Mansion sit uninhabited between the US and Canada. In time, New York State would take possession of the mansion; keeping it intact as a historical site. A thousand mirrors still hang on the walls to this day. Untouched and forgotten. In 2005, looking to save money, New York State sold the property to a private owner. Unknown to the new family, if one of the mirrors should be broken, the soul of that mirror will be released and free to roam the mansion.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?576836</url></doc>
