<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="577571">
  <docid>577571</docid>
  <title>The Motel</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bellucci, Jarrett</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">20 April 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">12</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Bellucci, Jarrett</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bellucci, Jarrett</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Basedow, John</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Clarke, Peter (XII)</actor>
      <role>Suicidal Man</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cross, Eric (VI)</actor>
      <role>Husband/Employee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dunatov, Lara Jane</actor>
      <role>Wife</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McIntyre, Ross A.</actor>
      <role>Andy</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A seedy dump in Long Island, the Albatross Motel is your last resort. It is the favored site for infidelity, murder and suicide. So it's business as usual to have a broken man in one room, slumped forward and preparing for suicide, while in another, a man waits for his married lover. The suicidal man answers the door and Andy brushes into the room followed by a wild-eyed associate, bristling with violence. Andy discusses the process and legal issues involved with helping to facilitate the recording of a video will prior to the forthcoming suicide. Andy sets up the camera and the man pours out his heart. And in Room 4, the man is forced to hide in the bathroom when his lover's husband unexpectedly arrives at the hotel. The wife arrives moments later, stunned to find her husband. She turns to leave and is pulled into a tight embrace. In Room 18, the suicidal man completes his emotional video confessional, only to be savagely attacked by the associate and brutally stabbed. Andy, impassively, continues filming. The wife tries to pull away from her husband and is thrown down upon the dirty mattress. Her cowering lover peers out in horror as the husband forces himself upon his wife despite her cries of protest. As the violence builds to a crescendo two men look on - the lover with terror and Andy with cold, clinical detachment. Yet nothing here is quite what it seems.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?577571</url></doc>
