<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="578711">
  <docid>578711</docid>
  <title>The Neon Man and Me</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Roberts, Paul Tait</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">17 November 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">54</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Coleman, Slash</producer>
    <producer>Felton, John H.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Coleman, Slash</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Coleman, Slash</actor>
      <role>Himself/Comedian/30 characters</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>It's 1989 and the deep south is buzzing with the hint of the Persian Gulf War. Two eccentric jazz musicians meet - one a Jewish piano player named Slash Coleman and the other a Pentecostal saxophonist named Mark Jamison. Fueled by a series of mysterious prophesies, a stash of dehydrated diet food and bonding over the unique rituals of music and their perspective religions, the two young musicians take a musical tour of the south and become fast friends. Slowly overwhelmed by the limitations of the south and haunted by his mother's tales of the Holocaust , Coleman embarks on a lone artistic journey. From a fisherman in Alaska to a massage therapist in Oregon to an artist in Maine, his globe trotting will take him through 134 day jobs, 117 apartments and 68 failed relationships in 8 different states in 2 different countries. All the while, Jamison, turning his creative energies toward neon, will remain his best friend in Virginia - his North Star back home. Nearly twenty years later, with their marriages turned toward divorce, the friends turn toward a collaboration that will bring Coleman back home when the unthinkable happens. Jamison is electrocuted in a freak accident, leaving Coleman more lost than ever. Looking for a sense of direction, Coleman returns home and learns the girl Jamison loved is pregnant with his child. In his effort to create a care package for Jamison's son, Coleman creates, "The Neon Man and Me" - eight monologues about friendship told by 25 characters, and an original score that Coleman plays on his guitar.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?578711</url></doc>
