<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="578991">
  <docid>578991</docid>
  <title>The New Newlywed Game</title>
  <year>1984</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bowen, John (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Game-Show</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>non-fiction</keyword>
    <keyword>the-newlywed-game</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">TV-PG</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">13 February 1984</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Dorsey, John (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Barris, Chuck</producer>
    <producer>Case, Walt</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Delugg, Milton</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Eubanks, Bob</actor>
      <role>Host (1985-December 1988)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hilton, Bob</actor>
      <role>Announcer (1985-1987)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lange, Jim</actor>
      <role>Host (February 13-17, 1984)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>O'Donnell, Charlie (I)</actor>
      <role>Announcer (1987-1988)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Roddy, Rod</actor>
      <role>Announcer (1984)</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"The Newlywed Game" is among the most enduring game shows of the genre. This 1985 five-day-a-week syndicated revival of the classic game show, again hosted by Eubanks, sported a new set, but with no other notable changes. The rules remained the same as in previous versions four couples, each married less than two years, answered a series of questions designed to expose how well the spouses knew (or didn't know) each other. The husbands were asked a series of questions while their wives were secluded offstage. The wives returned and answered the same questions; matches were worth 5 points each. As before, incorrect answers usually led to full-scale fights and verbal assaults (with Eubanks and the audience not making things any easier). The process was repeated with the wives answering the questions and the husbands herded offstage; questions were now worth 10 points. A final bonus question (usually general, first posed to the wives) was worth 25 points. The couple with the highest point total at the end of the game won a bonus prize "chosen especially for" them usually a trip, furniture or mode of transportation (other than a car or truck). Reruns of the 1985 version of "The Newlywed Game," as do the show's other versions, continue to air on Game Show Network.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?578991</url></doc>
