<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="579270">
  <docid>579270</docid>
  <title>The Nexus</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Leoncini, Laura</editor>
    <editor>Staiti, Massimo</editor>
    <editor>Taylor, Will (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">1 August 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">83</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Taylor, Will (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Leoncini, Laura</producer>
    <producer>Taylor, Will (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Taylor, Will (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kennedy, Matthew (VI)</actor>
      <role>Alec Morgan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kollmuss, Stefan</actor>
      <role>Jason Dean</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Le Roux, Ariane</actor>
      <role>Secretary</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lim, Louis (I)</actor>
      <role>Shamal Rinpoche</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Perez, Angel (II)</actor>
      <role>Damian Dollero</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Damian Dollero is a young man whose ambitions have seemingly come true: at 26 he is an accomplished actor, having starred in 3 blockbuster films and ranking 17th on Star Magazine's power list. The fame and money are all there, and for everyone concerned he is living the ultimate dream. For he himself, however, his life is not all that it appears. Awash in confusion about his identity and the point of his celebrity, Damian seeks a higher truth and a deeper understanding of his inner self. A fateful meeting with his sister eventually leads him to seek counsel with Shamal Rinpoche, a Buddhist monk and former apprentice of the Dalai Lama. The encounter opens a door for him, and very quickly he loses interest in all that he has accomplished theatrically. In the end Damian absorbs a tremendous wealth of knowledge from his mentor, fulfilling his desire for clarity and realizing the destiny that he must fulfill. But it is not only his life that becomes completely transformed, for his personal awakening and surprising enlightenment serve also to lift his teacher to new heights.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?579270</url></doc>
