<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="579565">
  <docid>579565</docid>
  <title>The No Game</title>
  <year>2010</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Germany">20 May 2010</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Horman, Sherry</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Schenck, Sabine</producer>
    <producer>Kirch, Doris</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Abramowitz, David (I)</writer>
    <writer>Fein, Elizabeth</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Aghdashloo, Shohreh</actor>
      <role>Aunt Laila</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harden, Marcia Gay</actor>
      <role>Barbara</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Synopsis: The No Game is a 21st century romance using the Middle East politics of our time as the dramatic backdrop for this very timely story. Sara Cohen is an 18 year old New York Jewish girl, who on a trip to Israel learns more than she bargained for. When she arrives back in New York, Sara is a changed girl who can uniquely see both sides of the Israeli/Palestinian issue. Her first big love to a Jewish boy is put to the test as is her relationship to her parents Barbara and Elliot. She enlists the aid of a charming young man named Khalil who is a senior at Brooklyn College and who guides her on this next part of her journey. Khalil seems to know everyone and soon after he leads Sara to Leila, who immediately accepts her as a miracle from Allah. Back in NYC, Barbara is not about to give up her only child, the daughter she would gladly die for. She and Leila fight over Sara in a metaphoric climatic scene for the ages. Their anger at each other flows from a well of pain and resentment that reflects the current political situation. Sara, caught between the two, feels like she is being torn apart, and lost in the search for her own hybrid identity. We travel on Sara's journey with her, from innocence to first love to revelation to crisis to tragic violence to a beautiful new hope for Sara...and for what she represents.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?579565</url></doc>
