<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="580732">
  <docid>580732</docid>
  <title>The Ostrich Tapes</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Barton, Neil (II)</editor>
    <editor>Gilmour, Gavin</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>scottish</keyword>
    <keyword>absurd-humor</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">41</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Gilmour, Gavin</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Gilmour, Gavin</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Donald, Alex</actor>
      <role>Sean McLetchie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mcgrath, Shaun Paul</actor>
      <role>Roddy Baxter</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>How far can a friendship be tested? With a marriage hanging in the balance and a weight of evidence against your spouse who do you call upon to help you through the tough times? And can you call it help when your trust in everyone fails? The Ostrich Tapes is the story of two men trying to come to terms with their own inadequacies. Roddy is convinced his wife is cheating on him, tapping his own house to try and catch her out and spying on her when he should be at work. Sean is the friend who cannot say no and finds himself getting dragged into Roddy's paranoid escapades eventually becoming a target for wild accusations himself. It is a battle between the weak and the strong, the feeble minded and the bully , reality and disillusion. A character study of two flawed men and their tolerance of each other, The Ostrich Tapes is funny, shocking, sad and strangely uplifting in turn and takes you into the bizarre and often absurd world of Roddy and Sean where the unspeakable is spoken and the unthinkable is thought. A friendship is only truly tested when it is the one thing keeping you from losing your mind.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?580732</url></doc>
