<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="582528">
  <docid>582528</docid>
  <title>The Physical Culture Girl</title>
  <year>1903</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Sport</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>girl</keyword>
    <keyword>fitness</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">October 1903</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">2</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
<plot>The scene is a bedroom with classic flower patterned wallpaper, half a dozen small frames and a single bed to the left and a fireplace with a porcelain clock to the right. To the far right of the scene there is a chair and (not seen in the video transcript, probably) a table. The floor is covered by a large Persian rug and, in the middle of the room, conspicuously suspended from the ceiling, is a large punching ball and a couple of wire pulleys. A brunette is sleeping on the bed, wakes and stands up, dressed in a past the knee skirt and a sleeveless shirt. The girl should be a Physical Culture maniac, as without caring for her long hair, she starts the morning exercises. First, the Girl makes a biceps pose, then punches the ball in a fast, powerful frenzy, until the ball is caught up (off camera, either pulled by its string or accidentally caught on the pulleys' wires). Then, she picks up two clubs (the sort used in circus by hand dexterity artists) and plays with them in arm extension movements, whirling the clubs about. After putting the clubs down, she pulls at the springy wires, only to stop that and do a couple of flexing poses, arms and legs, and bending at the waist, first facing the camera, than with her back to it. The morning exercises end with a couple of push-ups on the right arm, facing the camera, followed by a couple of leg extensions.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?582528</url></doc>
