<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="585442">
  <docid>585442</docid>
  <title>The Rat Show</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Payne, Jason (IV)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">20 April 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Payne, Jason (IV)</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Davis, Ken (XVI)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barlow, Gregory</actor>
      <role>Twitching hand</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Glisson, Rhayna</actor>
      <role>Pool girl</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Payne, Jason (IV)</actor>
      <role>Guy on bike</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Warthol, Andy</actor>
      <role>Guy on tv #2</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>he Rat Show is a postmodern comedy about the daily lives of a pair of rat sisters, Ruby and Sonny, sharing a house together. The Rat Show's storyline is an intricate mix of implied plot and psychological themes, starting out with the sisters resting comfortably in their home until a baby doll invades their personal lives. Soon, as night falls, a tv set is placed in their home by a backwards walking hamster. And as the viewer comes to learn that the Baby and the Hamster are in cahoots, the motives are never truly revealed until the startling climax: THE RAT PAGEANT. Filmed entirely on miniature sets, complete with green-screening, stop motion animation, as well as still photos, and starring, of course, a pair of rats and a hamster, the rat show is a marvel of mixed media digital recording. In addition to the visual eye candy, it is accompanied by classic jazz tracks which give the short film its noirish feel, and complete with tracks to the nervous twitching and stillness of the rats which simultaneously add to the quirky unease of the atmosphere as it forces the viewer to question whether they are watching a horror film or a sitcom. In either case, the Rat Show is sure to please with its classic mix of the absurd and the surreal.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?585442</url></doc>
