<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="586377">
  <docid>586377</docid>
  <title>The Resolution</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Smelík, Petr</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>power</keyword>
    <keyword>control</keyword>
    <keyword>resolution</keyword>
    <keyword>dominance</keyword>
    <keyword>decision</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Czech Republic</country>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">PG-13</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Czech Republic">25 September 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <composers>
    <composer>Cervi, Enrico</composer>
    <composer>Hautamäki, Marko</composer>
    <composer>Portelance, Leon</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hastík, Svatopluk</actor>
      <role>Edward Harrows</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sentl, Martin</actor>
      <role>James Blanc</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Trávnícek, Dusan</actor>
      <role>Derek McBright</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Imagine a world dominated by vast secret societies. Originally formed to protect the people, over the years they have become dysfunctional and corrupt. The Resolution Company, one of the largest and most ambitious of these organizations, has started taking over their rivals, growing in dominance and power. Edward Harrows is the head of the Resolution Company. He is merciless in his thirst for absolute control. More and more, the entire world has become reliant on his power, power which is growing by the day and hour. One of Edward's oldest and most trusted secret agents has become a pawn in this insidious quest for world domination. Now this agent must choose between his loyalty to the Company and his very life itself. One of the rival societies, the Royal Corporation, still stands by the principles upon which it was founded: the welfare and protection of the people. Its leader, James Blanc, with the assistance of his employees, does everything he can to do stop the Resolution Company. However, the Resolution Company is larger and Edward Harrows will not hesitate to use any means at his disposal: friendship, treachery or even death, to achieve his evil ends. He is a vicious adversary with many twisted and unexpected tricks up his sleeve. A period of dominance is coming. Who will prevail? The Resolution is coming soon!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?586377</url></doc>
