<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="586685">
  <docid>586685</docid>
  <title>The Reverend: Vigilante Vampire</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>number-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>second-part</keyword>
    <keyword>vampire</keyword>
    <keyword>priest</keyword>
    <keyword>sequel</keyword>
    <keyword>reverend</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 December 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Jones, Neil (IX)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Brennan, Stuart</producer>
    <producer>Jones, Neil (IX)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Jones, Neil (IX)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Booth, Emily (I)</actor>
      <role>Tracy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bradley, Doug (I)</actor>
      <role>Reverend Andrews</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brennan, Stuart</actor>
      <role>The Reverend</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Daniels, Joe (I)</actor>
      <role>Prince</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Savini, Tom</actor>
      <role>Machine</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Fresh from seminary school a new Reverend embarks on his first parish. A small, low maintenance Chapel based in the quiet idyllic setting of a quiet country village. While on the surface the village seems to be a peaceful parish, with perfect residents, soon it becomes apparent that something more sinister lurks beneath the façade of a local businessman. On a wet, cold night a mysterious girl visits The Reverend at the chapel. Cold and upset she is welcomed in warmly, soon it becomes apparent that her visit is not for sanctuary but to deliver a message, a message in the form of a deep, bloody bite... Awoken with an unknown, uncontrollable thirst a confused Reverend can find no evidence of the girl from the night before, with nothing but the thirst and memory of the bite, The Reverend embarks on his mandate, to clean up the village and the neighbouring estate, by preaching or feasting. With striking visuals from one of Britain's rising directors, a stellar cast of horror legends and a soundtrack from some of the world's biggest Artists. Packed with action sequences, gore, Vampires and naked chicks The Reverend promises to leave you thirsty for more.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?586685</url></doc>
