<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="586828">
  <docid>586828</docid>
  <title>The Ride</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Coppenbarger, Josh</editor>
    <editor>Kim, Thomas Hyungkyun</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Mystery</genre>
    <genre>Sport</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Western</genre>
    <genre>Music</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>nature</keyword>
    <keyword>road-trip</keyword>
    <keyword>paul-revere</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>student-film</keyword>
    <keyword>experimental</keyword>
    <keyword>post-modern</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">PG-13</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">May 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">6</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="USA">10</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Coppenbarger, Josh</director>
    <director>Ide, Brian</director>
    <director>Kim, Thomas Hyungkyun</director>
    <director>Lowe, Justin</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Stark, Nathan</producer>
    <producer>Sullivan, Mikaela</producer>
    <producer>Coppenbarger, Joshua</producer>
    <producer>Flaherty, Elizabeth</producer>
    <producer>Asher, Mollye</producer>
    <producer>Breen, Kyle</producer>
    <producer>Coppenbarger, Josh</producer>
    <producer>Coppenbarger, Joshua</producer>
    <producer>Dawson, Robin (I)</producer>
    <producer>Silva, Elisa (I)</producer>
    <producer>Silva, Elisa (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bononcini, Briana</writer>
    <writer>Coppenbarger, Joshua</writer>
    <writer>Ide, Brian</writer>
    <writer>Kasserman, Kate</writer>
    <writer>Kim, Thomas Hyungkyun</writer>
    <writer>Lowe, Justin</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Weight, The</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Doikos, Cristina</actor>
      <role>Ticket Officer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gordon, Ray (III)</actor>
      <role>Ray</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gutto, Anna</actor>
      <role>Jenny</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Haufrecht, Marcia</actor>
      <role>Nancy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Haufrecht, Robert</actor>
      <role>Driver</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kerson, Chris</actor>
      <role>Donald</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kim, Jun (III)</actor>
      <role>Heesun</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Luka, Angelo</actor>
      <role>Peter</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Radelet, Ruth</actor>
      <role>Ruth</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stark, Nathan</actor>
      <role>The Man</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sullivan, Mikaela</actor>
      <role>The Woman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Turner, Charles (VI)</actor>
      <role>Nathan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wang, Garrett</actor>
      <role>Henry</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The Ride is a feature-length documentary that uses the Professional Bull Riders' circuit as an entry point into the life of the modern cowboy. The idea of the cowboy and the American West is set firmly in the American psyche. Countless films have portrayed the West as a place of freedom and danger, but, above all, a place of boundless possibility. Though we may think they are a thing of the past, cowboys still exist and the professional bull riding circuit is the one place you're guaranteed to find them. The cowboys' earnest reflections on personal liberty, family struggle and the country's changing identity paint a vivid portrait of an America both at odds and in love with itself. Through the film's epic cinematography we come to understand that The Cowboy continues to embody the mythology of the American hero. The Professional Bull Riders' circuit is a tour of the top 45 bull riders in the world, consisting of roughly 32 stops a year around the US. The winner of the world title in Vegas also wins a million dollars, so it's safe to say this is not some little backyard rodeo. Bull riding has entered the mainstream. Droves of fans flock to the sold out arenas toting signs and banners in frenzied support of their favorite riders, making this the fastest growing sport in America. All the while the cowboys are hustling, trying to stay on their bulls, trying to make ends meet and raising hell... good 'ol boy style! Beginning and ending with explosive event footage and packed with daredevil bull riding, pyrotechnics and big arena fanfare, The Ride goes full circle as it takes through the complex lives of one compelling character to the next. We meet champion bull rider and face of the PBR, Justin McBride, as he transitions out of bull riding and into a career in country music. Young Amish bull riding hopeful Willy Ropp is not as lucky as McBride with his earnest attempts to make the elite top 45. The characters surprise with their gritty cowboy personae and genuine wit. The Ride features professional bull riders JB Mauney, Willy Ropp, Justin McBride, PBR entertainer Flint Rassmussen, bull fighter Shorty Gorham and millionaire bucking bull breeder Tom Teague.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?586828</url></doc>
