<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="587337">
  <docid>587337</docid>
  <title>The Road to Independence</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">4 July 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">132</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Church, Mike (IV)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Mosher, Jimm</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Church, Madison</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Church, Mike (IV)</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Church, Reagan</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>D'Aleo, Sal</actor>
      <role>Thomas Paine</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Knight, Jerrod</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McCann, Mike (V)</actor>
      <role>'Timeline' Announcer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Parker, James (XI)</actor>
      <role>Thomas Jefferson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Thomas, Jay (I)</actor>
      <role>John Adams</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Walker, Bo (I)</actor>
      <role>George Washington</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>When Thomas Jefferson, rode on his white horse to Independence Hall on 4 July 1776. Declaration of Independence in hand, people lined the streets of Philadelphia and cheered. Then, once inside the chamber, Jefferson and the Founders posed for pictures while each stood in line behind John Hancock to sign the Declaration. America was born. It's a nice story but it's not true. "The Road To Independence" corrects myths, dispels the P.C. revisions and through the Founders Own, Written Words tells their immortal story of sacrifice, revolution and love of a country that didn't even have a name yet. The creation of the United States of America and the writing of the Declaration of Independence. Listeners will hear the voices of the men who made 1776 the greatest year in American History. From meetings at George Washington's Mount Vernon home and the Apollo Room at Williamsburg's Raleigh Tavern, the Road to Independence takes you to historic places where the Fire of America's Independence was kindled yet are mostly unknown. In Addition to the familiar names of Jefferson, Adams, Jefferson and Washington. Listeners, for the first time, will hear the voices of our Unsung Heroes of Independence. Patrick Henry, Richard Henry Lee, John Dickinson, George Mason, Dabney Carr and Edward Rutledge all played crucial roles in America's Independence and their stories of Patriotism are now told. Listeners will find themselves immersed in the roar of Bunker Hill's cannonade, the ringing of the Market Street Bells of Philadelphia and the soaring oratory of Patriots in Independence Hall, the House of Burgesses and even St. John's Church in Richmond VA. Written and narrated by Mike Church, who puts his infamous wit and Patriotic Devotion to the Founders to this little known, All-Important story of America's Founding.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?587337</url></doc>
