<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="587375">
  <docid>587375</docid>
  <title>The Road to Sanity</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">16 May 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">8</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Warnock, Donald</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Warnock, Rebecca</producer>
    <producer>Warnock, Donald</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Warnock, Donald</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Eknoian, Linda</actor>
      <role>Miss Johnson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Warnock, Donald</actor>
      <role>Dr. Zorken</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Warnock, Jon</actor>
      <role>Tom Quimby</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>At open, we see Miss Johnson, attractive but child-like, skipping to her car, on the way to see her Psychiatrist, Dr Zorken. While this is going on, in an insert, Dr. Zorken talks with a fellow evil genius about his plan to make the winsome Miss Johnson his love slave - how he is MAD about her. He is certainly partly right: he is definitely MAD. Unaware of his intentions, Miss Johnson sings about getting better through therapy (I'm on the Road to Sanity). She arrives and greets Miss Le Moine, the receptionist, who sends her on in to the Doctor's office to wait. Zorken in the meantime, is in his downstairs laboratory sharing the secret of his plan with his cohort. It is actually simple, but quite brilliant. He has developed a machine which emits rays that control the behavior and attitude of the person in the path of said rays. The agency of the ray-delivery is a set of antennae built into the Doctor's couch. All is now ready! The session begins, the rays penetrate poor Miss Johnson, she faints. Then she wakes up. Unfortunately for Dr. Zorken, he miscalculated a bit when adjusting the machine. Instead of a passionate and malleable Miss Johnson, primed to surrender to the Doctor's ministrations, she awakes as a fully-fledged Harpy, sounding suspiciously like Joan Rivers, ready to tear poor Doctor. Zorken to pieces with a double-strength tongue lashing. Sadly, It is a poor ray gun that does not point both ways (after Asimov)</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?587375</url></doc>
