<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="588398">
  <docid>588398</docid>
  <title>The Salmon Fisheries of Vancouver</title>
  <year>1904</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">23 February 1904</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
<plot>A great deal has been written of the great salmon fisheries of Vancouver and many attempts have been made to picture them but up to this time in vain. This season however all of the conditions were unusually favorable. The catch was the largest known in years and the light conditions were all that could be desired and the resulting series of pictures is remarkable from every point of view. At the opening of the scene a view is given of the immense canneries on the bank of the river. This is followed by a most picturesque scene taken at sunrise and shows the departure of the fishing fleet towed for a distance by a tug. As the fishing boats get out into the open sea they drop off from their tow, hoist their sails and start off for the fishing grounds. The next scene shows the nets dropped and the haul in progress. Tons upon tons of magnificent salmon are brought jumping and squirming from the water and are rolled over into an enormous flat boat where they continue their frantic efforts to escape. As the bodies glisten in the sun they present a most magnificent spectacle. The next scene shows the return of the flat boats laden with fish under tow of a powerful tug. Next comes several interior views of the canneries. This is the first time this picturesque scene has ever been photographed. The people who work in the canneries are for the most part Indians, Eskimos and some Chinese coolies, their work being of the most novel and interesting character. The picture must be seen to be appreciated. It has been shown with great success at several of the leading vaudeville theatres and is considered one of the best productions of the winter.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?588398</url></doc>
