<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="588546">
  <docid>588546</docid>
  <title>The Sari Soldiers</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Davis, Mona (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Nepal">15 December 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Argentina">August 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Netherlands">14 February 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Slovenia">24 March 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="India">January 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="UK">14 February 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="France">12 March 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Czech Republic">12 March 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Poland">December 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Canada">5 March 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="New Zealand">27 February 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">14 August 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Bosnia and Herzegovina">14 November 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">92</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Bridgham, Julie</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Limbu, Ramyata</producer>
    <producer>Bridgham, Julie</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Newa, Manose</composer>
    <composer>Thomas, Christopher James</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Filmed over three years during the most historic and pivotal time in Nepal's modern history, The Sari Soldiers is an extraordinary story of six women's courageous efforts to shape Nepal's future in the midst of an escalating civil war against Maoist insurgents, and the King's crackdown on civil liberties. When Devi, mother of a 15-year-old girl, witnesses her niece being tortured and murdered by the Royal Nepal Army, she speaks publicly about the atrocity. The army abducts her daughter in retaliation, and Devi embarks on a three-year struggle to uncover her daughter's fate and see justice done. The Sari Soldiers follows Devi and five other brave women, including Maoist Commander Kranti; Royal Nepal Army Officer Rajani; Krishna, a monarchist from a rural community who leads a rebellion against the Maoists; Mandira, a human rights lawyer; and Ram Kumari, a young student activist organizing the protests to establish democracy. The Sari Soldiers intimately delves into the extraordinary journey of these women on all sides of the conflict, through the democratic revolution that reshapes the country's future.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?588546</url></doc>
