<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="588924">
  <docid>588924</docid>
  <title>The Scottish Parliament: Following the Ghost Road</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Hickey, Jim (IV)</editor>
    <editor>Mitchell, Robin (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">2 January 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">35</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Mitchell, Robin (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hickey, Jim (IV)</producer>
    <producer>Mitchell, Robin (II)</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>The Scottish Parliament - Following the Ghost Road is an accessible and entertaining documentary film that shows a candidate's progress to Election Day. In an era when the electorate grows more apathetic and cynical towards the politics and elections, this 35-minute film shot over 8 years during three Scottish Parliamentary elections is a unique insight into the practicalities of political campaigning. The film's candidate, a pale-faced ghost, Adam Lyal, has stood in three consecutive Scottish Parliamentary Elections in 1999, 2003 &amp; 2007. By following a candidate who is not a member of any major party, the film is able to strip away some of the mystique surrounding parliamentary elections. This documentary goes behind the scenes of the campaign and features unique historic footage of three election-night counts in Edinburgh. It also reveals the unfolding drama of 2007 when an automated count replaced the manual system with far-reaching consequences. The Scottish Parliament - Following the Ghost Road will engage audiences with the issues in a way that is politically empowering.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?588924</url></doc>
