<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="589357">
  <docid>589357</docid>
  <title>The Secret Journal of Francis Hogan</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">98</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Strickland, Ted (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Strickland, Ted (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Strickland, Ted (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Goethe, Bill</composer>
    <composer>Rose, Garren</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Francis Hogan is a famous game designer who hid his secret journal of ideas at his old middle school. Fernando finds out about the journal and decides that he is going to find it. He enlists the help of his friends Baxter and Rusty, but after an altercation at school with a boy named Jake, Fernando has to leave. Baxter and Rusty, with the help of a new girl at school that they will only call New Girl, they decide to find the journal themselves. Jake is a great basketball player who also loves to play guitar. One day a boy named Fernando tries to fight him but ends up getting hurt and leaving schools. He left behind a folder with the plans to find Francis Hogan's secret journal. Jake asks Andy to help him find the journal. Rae is a teacher's pet, who is wants more adventure in her life. When the school office asks her to help clean out a boy's locker, she finds plans to find the secret journal of Francis Hogan. She gets the help of her friend Becky who brings Mallory, and they begin the search. What all three groups don't know is that they are all following Fernando's plans and are destined to run into each other along the way.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?589357</url></doc>
