<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="589477">
  <docid>589477</docid>
  <title>The Secret Sale</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Khoury, Gilbert</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>new-york-city</keyword>
    <keyword>filmmaker</keyword>
    <keyword>director</keyword>
    <keyword>secret</keyword>
    <keyword>sale</keyword>
    <keyword>producer</keyword>
    <keyword>dream</keyword>
    <keyword>auteur-filmmaker</keyword>
    <keyword>ontario</keyword>
    <keyword>toronto</keyword>
    <keyword>canada</keyword>
    <keyword>film-festival</keyword>
    <keyword>new-york</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">1 June 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">4</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Khoury, Gilbert</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Khoury, Gilbert</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Kathuria, Nidhi</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Khoury, Gilbert</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>LaForge, Jennifer</actor>
      <role>Woman</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>'The Secret Sale is a subtle story about a single woman in her early 50's, who looks quite young for her age, but is strongly influenced by the outside world and superficial things. Having a cheerful disposition, the woman is always high on life and smokes relentlessly. Conscious about her weight and looks, she almost desperately cares about how she is perceived by the people. She likes to eat organic veggies, fruit, and drinks organic milk and green tea, also because it's fashionable to do so. She always reads labels first whether they are for food items, face creams or even laundry detergents for that matter. The intoxicating sweet smelling new cream will almost never make her apply it at the spur of the moment. She will not be satisfied unless she separates the delicates from the regular load of clothes while washing them and will put only the precise amount mentioned over the back of the detergent box. She digs fashion magazines, shopping for new gadgets, designer clothes, expensive skin care and cosmetics. This time, as she opens her mail, her life is changed forever.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?589477</url></doc>
