<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="590798">
  <docid>590798</docid>
  <title>The Silent Code</title>
  <year>1935</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Craft, Charles</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Western</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Approved</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">November 1935</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Paton, Stuart</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Weiss, Louis (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Corbett, Ben (I)</actor>
      <role>Henchman Breen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Coxen, Edward</actor>
      <role>Nathan Brent</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Davis, Clarence (I)</actor>
      <role>Redwing</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Furey, Barney</actor>
      <role>Peter Barkley</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Girard, Joseph W.</actor>
      <role>NWMP Inspector Manning</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harmon, Pat</actor>
      <role>Henchman Carney</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Higgins, Rose</actor>
      <role>Indian Servant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mapes, Ted</actor>
      <role>First Mountie Constable</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mathews, Carl</actor>
      <role>Henchman Lobo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McGowan, J.P.</actor>
      <role>Commissioner</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mehaffey, Blanche</actor>
      <role>Helen Brent</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Osborne, Bud (I)</actor>
      <role>Mountie Sergeant</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Richmond, Kane</actor>
      <role>NWMP Cpl. Jerry Hale</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ross, Douglas (I)</actor>
      <role>Second Mountie Constable</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wolfang</actor>
      <role>Rex, King of Dogs</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Nothwest Mounted Police Corporal Jerry Hale is assigned to take over the district of a fellow-officer, and is puzzled as he had worked this district before and had been mysteriously transferred, disrupting his romance with Helen Brent, the niece of Peter Barkley, the Factor at the trading post. An accountant of the company Berkley works for threatens to expose him when his account is found $10,000 short. Barkley pleads for more time to raise the money. His opportunity arises when he learns that Helen's father and his brother-in-law, Nathan Brent, has struck it rich and is on his way to visit Helen. Barkley instructs his henchmen Carney and Breen to lie in wait and rob Brent of his gold. Brent has a premonition of trouble and buries his gold, making a map of the location. Barkley is disturbed by the arrival of Corporal Hale and goes to warn his men, and finds them already engaged in the attack on Brent. Brent's dog Wolfgang (played by a dog named Rex, or maybe the other way around) attacks Barkley who, in trying to shoot Wolfgang (or Rex) shoots Brent instead. Hale rushes toward the sound of the shot and the hidden Barkley watches the dying Brent give him the map. On his way to town, Hale is knocked unconscious off his horse, and Barkley takes the map, studies it and then replaces it. Hale reports the murder to Mountie headquarters, and is amazed to find himself accused by his Commandant of the murder and he produces three affidavits attesting to his guilt. Things look dark for Hale, but Wolfgang (or Rex) is also working on the case.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?590798</url></doc>
