<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="591180">
  <docid>591180</docid>
  <title>The Sisters of Mercy Manchester</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Komline, Kyle</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>convent</keyword>
    <keyword>priest</keyword>
    <keyword>nun</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">21 October 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">19</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Komline, Kyle</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Komline, Kyle</producer>
    <producer>Komline, Patti</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Komline, Kyle</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Nelson, David (XXV)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carmichael, Fred (II)</actor>
      <role>Father Agar</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carmichael, Pat</actor>
      <role>Mother Superior</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Casey, Maureen (II)</actor>
      <role>Nun 1</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Iglinski, Peggy</actor>
      <role>Sister Helen Elizabeth</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Langstaff, Peter (II)</actor>
      <role>Angelo</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Levitz, Norman</actor>
      <role>Jacques</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Angelo is the organist at a small New England convent. When Father Agar decides that the archaic organ hymns need to be replaced with something a little more up to date, he brings in a reggae band of nuns from a neighboring convent, The Sisters of Mercy Manchester. Angelo's jealousy is shaken when he first hears the voice of the band's lead singer, Sister Astrid. At a reception after the service, Angelo asks Sister Astrid out on a date but she declines, explaining that as a nun, she is married to Christ. Angelo stubbornly refuses to accept such a wild claim. He continues to court the nun, which results in a sort of contest with Christ for her love. Angelo has a good run and shares a few tender moments with Astrid so he decides to propose to her before the church service on Christmas Eve. Astrid is deeply disturbed and doesn't have a chance to answer, as Father Agar interrupts to hand Angelo his final paycheck. Angelo is devastated and sits down at the organ, the events of the past few moments racing through his mind. In the middle of a hymn, Angelo tosses the sheet music aside and begins to play a ferocious piece he wrote in honor of Astrid. The organ begins to quake and the crucified Jesus hanging on the wall near the organ begins to shake. Angelo looks back and forth between Astrid and Jesus, the music building to a final climax.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?591180</url></doc>
