<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="591351">
  <docid>591351</docid>
  <title>The Sky Was Angry</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Abdunnur, Sharif</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>War</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>2006</keyword>
    <keyword>children</keyword>
    <keyword>beirut</keyword>
    <keyword>lebanon</keyword>
    <keyword>israel</keyword>
    <keyword>therapy</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Arabic</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Lebanon</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">3 June 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Canada">25 April 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Lebanon">22</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Abdunnur, Sharif</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Abdunnur, Sharif</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Jalgha, Bassam</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>An existential journey through the world of a traumatized child and the lives of everyday citizens turned volunteers - using laughter and hope to survive fear, death and all the compliments of war. "The Sky was Angry" covers scenes from everyday lives of the children that survived the war on Lebanon in the summer of 2006. Taking refugee in Al Madina, a theater in the countries capital, Beirut. The documentary depicts scenes from the drama therapy games the children played to help them cope with the traumas of war. These sketches these children perform are heart-stopping; the shock that a child can deal with such complex thoughts, and such grim realities and severe traumas appear in their innocent acting, frank discussion and drawings. A heart wrenching documentary for the whole family meant to be the ultimate anti-war statement. Violence creates trauma and in return a vicious circle of violence. At the end of the day the true victim of war are the children and if nothing is done this cycle will continue and intensify</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?591351</url></doc>
