<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="591396">
  <docid>591396</docid>
  <title>The Slaughter</title>
  <year>1971</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>cult</keyword>
    <keyword>murder</keyword>
    <keyword>gore</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Argentina</country>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1971</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">91</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Findlay, Michael</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Findlay, Michael</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Amuchástegui, Margarita</actor>
      <role>Angelica</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carro, Ana</actor>
      <role>Ana</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ellis, Xanthe</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fernández Blanco, Liliana</actor>
      <role>Susanna</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Findlay, Michael</actor>
      <role>Detective/Various voices</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Larratelli, Enrique</actor>
      <role>Satan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Massa, Mirtha</actor>
      <role>Terry London</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mayo, Aldo</actor>
      <role>Max Marsh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vilaneuva, George</actor>
      <role>Horst Frank</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Max Marsh, a major film producer, comes to Buenos Aires. He plans his next epic there, with his famous star, Terri London. They arrive to the press, and murder. Terri finds Horst Krein and begins to see him . . . more and more . . . until Angelia cannot stay anymore. Angelia returns to her cult and is told to murder Max Marsh during carnival. She costumes herself as Terri does, and lures Max away, to his death. Terri is distraught, and goes to recover at home with Horst. His father arrives and very much approves the situation. Terri stays on, and Horst is bound to her by her beauty and the baby that is coming. Angelia returns to her cult filled with vengeance. Fresh blood is needed to appease the leader and his cause. The unborn blood of child. Until that time of SLAUGHTER days must be occupied, for all. The girls of Satan must live, and to them life is one of challenges and violence. They live and love, torture and kill. Horst must also play, and his wife heavy with child is no longer appealing. During the company of others Terri becomes withdrawn and finds that Horst's father is willing to offer understanding and companionship. But the time of Satan draws near, and while forces are gathered the prey sleeps. And they sleep forever. For the SLAUGHTER has ended.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?591396</url></doc>
