<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="591670">
  <docid>591670</docid>
  <title>The Smugglers</title>
  <year>1904</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>cornwall</keyword>
    <keyword>coast-guard</keyword>
    <keyword>smuggler</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">1904</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">25 April 1904</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Raymond, Charles (I)</director>
  </directors>
<plot>A thrilling story of a party of rough Smugglers running a contraband cargo on their rocky coast. Scene 1.--Shows the face of the chief of the smuggler's gang. Scene 2.--An old fashioned village inn, in which are seated three old tars studying a chart of the coast and deciding where it would be best to attempt a "run." Scene 3.--A boat coming through the surf laden with kegs, which are lifted on the men's shoulders immediately the boat has grounded, and conveyed across the sands to a cave, where the horses and assistants are waiting to convey them across the country. Scene 4.--A look-out on the Coastguard station is seen sweeping the horizon with his telescope, and suddenly becomes aware that his old enemy the smuggler is actively engaged in trying to get the better of him. Scene 5.--Here the look-out is seen rushing to the Coastguard station to inform his superior officer what he has witnessed through his telescope. All the men are hastily summoned, and rush off to try and prevent the "run" being successful. Scene 6.--Shows the smugglers coming through a galley between two precipitous cliffs, picking their way through the rocks, and urging their horses as fast as possible, so as to get their valuable goods into security. Scene 7.--The Coastguardmen, being unable to get down to the beach quickly, have recourse to a long rope ladder, and are seen coming hand over hand down this ladder to the shore, where they form up and rush in pursuit of the gang. Scene 8.--Shows the smugglers working down amongst the rocks and trees, closely followed by the Coastguards. Scene 9.--Here the smugglers are seen hastily removing the kegs from the backs of the animals, and entering the old smuggling haunt. At this critical moment the Coastguards rush their foes and burst into the house in hot pursuit. Scene 10.--Shows a tremendous struggle between the smugglers and the Coastguards. The smugglers resist violently all attempts to capture, until compelled to throw up their hands and submit to being handcuffed at the muzzle of a revolver. Scene 11.--The final scene shows the smugglers being escorted to the lock-up, handcuffed two and two, and carefully guarded on either side by the Coastguards.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?591670</url></doc>
