<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="591886">
  <docid>591886</docid>
  <title>The Solo Years: Paul McCartney</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Biography</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>lipa</keyword>
    <keyword>the-beatles</keyword>
    <keyword>paul-mccartney</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">6</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Nord, Elisabeth</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Strøm, Vibeke</producer>
    <producer>Nord, Elisabeth</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Beatles, The</actor>
      <role>Themselves</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McCartney, Paul</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Students from LIPA - Liverpool Institute for Performing Arts - have created an entirely new area due to open to the public at The Beatles Story on Saturday 26 July. The Solo Years - Paul McCartney, has been designed by Morgan Large, a graduation student, with lighting by Richard Reardon and Sarah Kamender - both on the Theatre and Performance Technology course - and a video by Elisabeth Nord (ex LIPA student). In response to the demand from the fans, The Beatles Story is to extend the period covered by the exhibition from purely The Beatles as a group to include their individual careers after the break-up - hence The Solo Years. This next stage of the exhibition's development, as well as reflecting on Paul's continuing musical success, focuses on his inspirational achievement in building the future through his support of LIPA. Elisabeth Nord - Director/Producer GriegNord Productions. In the prospectus Paul talks about his involvement with the Institute: "I and others in the industry want to be involved with a place which opens people's eyes and ears, and where we can pass on the skills and experiences that have contributed to our success - lessons which have had to be learnt the hard way. I have always seen LIPA as being that place. It's great that my old school is now back in use helping the next generations. It's exciting that once again my home town will be the world's target for tomorrow's talent."</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?591886</url></doc>
