<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="592022">
  <docid>592022</docid>
  <title>The Sophisticated Misfit</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Chervinsky, Mark</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">26 April 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">59</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Chervinsky, Mark</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Chervinsky, Mark</producer>
    <producer>Garcia, Christo</producer>
    <producer>Wilson, Dave (VII)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Chervinsky, Mark</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Frank, Paul (IV)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Goldberg, Whoopi</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Oswalt, Patton</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shag (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Westland, Holden</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"The Sophisticated Misfit" is a four-year exploration of the world of Shag, the unlikeliest of Los Angeles artistic icons. His work doesn't reflect the multicultural urban milieu of contemporary Los Angeles but rather an entirely different era. Think post-World War II boom years, suburban tracts sprawling across the landscape, Disneyland opening its doors and designers embracing the space-age motifs of the Sputnik and the mission to the moon. Shag's world is one of early 1960s furniture, sprawling ranch houses, built-in wet bars, and jet-set style. He embraces a simpler time. But his artwork is filled with subtle, humorous winks of the eye acknowledging that this period wasn't quite so simple. The smiling women in their mod dresses hold secrets. The festive party scene in the go-go '60s home isn't really what it seems. Shag has become an art-world phenomenon, whose paintings have inspired obsessive fans around the globe, a Las Vegas musical, and collaborations with Disneyland, Paul Frank and Hot Wheels. His once-affordable artwork commands thousands of dollars - that's if you can get it all - and graces the homes of hipsters and celebrities who prefer their worlds filled with clean lines, beautiful people, vibrant colors, and accompanied by a dry martini.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?592022</url></doc>
