<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="594157">
  <docid>594157</docid>
  <title>The Sugar Babies</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Ocasio, Jason</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>dominican-republic</keyword>
    <keyword>human-rights</keyword>
    <keyword>children</keyword>
    <keyword>haiti</keyword>
    <keyword>sugar</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>French</language>
    <language>Spanish</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">19 September 2007</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">18 September 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">95</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Serrano, Amy (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Longoria, Salvador G.</producer>
    <producer>Pujals, Tico</producer>
    <producer>Haqq, Constance</producer>
    <producer>Chiesi, Claudia</producer>
    <producer>Halvorssen, Thor</producer>
    <producer>Serrano, Amy (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Serrano, Amy (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Cruz, Bill (III)</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Until now, the disturbing remnants of colonial slavery were carefully hidden in paradise..... "The Sugar Babies" examines the moral price of sugar --present and past -- from the perspective of the conditions surrounding the children of sugar cane cutters of Haitian ancestry in the Dominican Republic, and the continuing denial of their basic human rights. While exposing those who profit from human trafficking and exploitation, the feature length documentary film "The Sugar Babies: The Plight of the Children of Agricultural Workers in the Sugar Industry of the Dominican Republic" vividly explores the lives of those who live in circumstances that can only be considered modern day slavery. Composed of gripping field testimonies and hidden camera footage obtained during 18 months of documentation, the film also features interviews with Haiti's Ambassador to the United States, Ambassador Raymond Joseph, the U.S. Department of States' Ambassador John Miller from the Office of Human Trafficking, renowned anthropologist and sugar historian Sidney Mintz, Carol Pier from Human Rights Watch, Public Interest Attorneys Bill Quigley as well as Greg Schell, and a number of activists from the field including human rights lawyer Noemi Mendez, Colette Lespinase of G.A.R.R. Haiti [Organization for Refugees and the Repatriated] and missionaries Pierre Ruquoy and Father Christopher Hartley. The film is narrated by award-winning author Edwidge Danticat, and contains original music by the film's composer Bill Cruz including the songs "Branded" and "The Devil's Work." The Sugar Babies" was produced through Siren Studios [Miami] in association with The Hope, Courage and Justice Project [New Orleans] and The Human Rights Foundation [New York].</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?594157</url></doc>
