<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="595063">
  <docid>595063</docid>
  <title>The Technician</title>
  <year>2010</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>hostage</keyword>
    <keyword>hostage-negotiator</keyword>
    <keyword>lunatic</keyword>
    <keyword>police-chief</keyword>
    <keyword>negotiator</keyword>
    <keyword>hostage-taker</keyword>
    <keyword>sniper</keyword>
    <keyword>gunman</keyword>
    <keyword>hospital</keyword>
    <keyword>race-against-time</keyword>
    <keyword>emergency-room</keyword>
    <keyword>hostage-situation</keyword>
    <keyword>san-francisco-police-department</keyword>
    <keyword>san-francisco</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Cassar, Jon</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Begg, Graham</producer>
    <producer>Carmichael, Jamie (I)</producer>
    <producer>Ufland, Chris</producer>
    <producer>Ufland, Harry J.</producer>
    <producer>Ufland, Mary Jane</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>When a crazed gunman takes ten people hostage in the emergency room of a downtown San Francisco hospital, the SFPD are short on options. Kate Doherty, a beautiful young hostage negotiator, is doing the best that she can, but the gunman is a lunatic, and three people are already dead. Chief Maddox is ready to send in a S.W.A.T. team, but he knows that will mean that two-thirds of the hostages won't make it out alive. Time is running out. And that's when he calls Grant Bishop. Bishop is the best in the business, a police sniper with a background in the military, who's only ever needed one bullet to make the necessary kill. But there's a problem, Bishop is suspended from duty. Years of killing have left him a mess, with a thick file in the police psychiatrist's office and enough self-loathing to last a lifetime. Bishop is seemingly a broken man. But when the desperate call from Maddox comes through, somehow Bishop delivers, one shot, one bullet, right where it needs to be. But there's no time for therapy for Bishop. Immediately after the hospital attack, he answers the phone and hears a voice from the dead. It's Parish, a fellow soldier who was supposedly killed while escaping from prison. Yet here he is on the phone, spitting with anger and thirsty for revenge. Parish sets Bishop a series of seemingly impossible tasks that will put his skills as a sniper to the ultimate test, while at the same time shredding what little sanity he had left. Tearing across the city - and forbidden from contacting his colleagues in the police force - Bishop desperately races against the clock to put an end to Parish's crazed revenge mission. But to do so, Bishop knows he must unravel the mystery behind Parish's reappearance - and that ultimately he will have to kill Parish, before Parish kills him.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?595063</url></doc>
