<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="595152">
  <docid>595152</docid>
  <title>The Tell-Tale Heart</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Watford, Lawrence 'Law'</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>avant-garde</keyword>
    <keyword>civil-rights-movement</keyword>
    <keyword>classic-literature</keyword>
    <keyword>black-history</keyword>
    <keyword>based-on-short-story</keyword>
    <keyword>black-film</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">18 October 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">15</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Swertfager, Michael</director>
    <director>Watford, Lawrence 'Law'</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Bagg, Nick</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hobbs, Dave (I)</actor>
      <role>Master</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hobbs, David (IV)</actor>
      <role>Master</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Smallwood, Antwon</actor>
      <role>Slave</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This avant-garde piece, adapted from the Edgar Allen Poe Classic short story centers around an indentured servants plot on the life of his master. The servant has repressed his memories of abuse by his master, but these memories are displaced onto the master's evil "vulture eye". Eventually, this results in a neurosis that fuels the slave to revenge and murder. This film was created with the artistic challenge of taking an established classic and changing its context while using the exact same text of the source material. To that end, we juxtaposed the exact wording of the classic tale against a montage of photographs that capture racial conflicts and atrocities occurring throughout American history to create an entirely new layer to the original story. Quite a challenge to make coherent, the film has gone through a series of re-edits before reaching this final version; not quite horror, not quite comedy, but definitely socio-political. The result is a unique perspective of the cycle of racial violence in America.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?595152</url></doc>
