<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="595261">
  <docid>595261</docid>
  <title>The Ten Dimensions</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Clifford, Nicholas (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Australia">10 December 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Australia">15</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Clifford, Nicholas (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ciccone, Michael (II)</producer>
    <producer>Berrystone, Roz</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Clifford, Nicholas (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Breen, Sarah (I)</actor>
      <role>Kalashnakova</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cooper, Matthew (VII)</actor>
      <role>Gunmen #1</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Croughan, Trevor</actor>
      <role>Gunmen #3</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ellis, Paul (X)</actor>
      <role>Gunmen #2</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gunn, William (IV)</actor>
      <role>Gunmen #4</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hines, Luke</actor>
      <role>The Boyfriend</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mammarella, Enrico</actor>
      <role>Bronson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Orlando, David (II)</actor>
      <role>Montain</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>To get your Tax done, you see an accountant. To get legal advice you see a lawyer. To get revenge on your cheating wife and her secret lover, you see Bronson, the murder consultant. With the help of the good looking, deadly Russian rattlesnake Kalashnakova, Bronson has been helping people who need that little bit of criminal advice get the job done. Bronson lives in his own world and has not left his office for many years. Every client must listen to his stories and theories. This time Mr. Montain gets an insight into the ten dimensions, starting with length, width and depth, and finishing with an explanation for the mass of existence. Mr. Montain is fighting his own internal battle. As Bronson keeps him on his toes with details of how to exact revenge, there is something not quite right about Mr. Montain. His new customer, Mr. Montain, is just another client and all goes well until he leaves. There is no loyalty and no truth in the criminal world, and we learn that no one was who they said they were, the hunters soon become the hunted.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?595261</url></doc>
