<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="595474">
  <docid>595474</docid>
  <title>The Texan</title>
  <year>1932</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Seldeen, Murray</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Western</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>sheriff</keyword>
    <keyword>horse-racing</keyword>
    <keyword>horse</keyword>
    <keyword>actor-shares-first-name-with-character</keyword>
    <keyword>betting-on-horse</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2 February 1932</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">55</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Smith, Clifford (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Browne, Lucile</actor>
      <role>Mary Lou</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Holbrook, Allen (I)</actor>
      <role>Allen</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Keaton, Harry</actor>
      <role>Tony</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lee, Duke R.</actor>
      <role>Sheriff</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McKee, Lafe</actor>
      <role>Jim</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Meehan, Lew</actor>
      <role>Townsman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mix, Art</actor>
      <role>Cowhand Art</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mower, Jack</actor>
      <role>Buck Townsley</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nelson, Bobby (I)</actor>
      <role>Bobby</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pope, Bud</actor>
      <role>Cowhand</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wilsey, Jay</actor>
      <role>Bill Rust</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Bill Rust (Buffalo Bill Jr)., escaping from the sheriff, rides into a town where a cross-country horse race is about to be staged in a few days. A buckboard driven by young Bobby (Bobby Nelson) runs away and Bill overtakes it and rescues the boy. Local tough Buck Townsley (Jack Mower) starts an argument with Bill, and Bill bets all of his money that his horse can beat Buck's in the upcoming race. The townspeople are also willing to bet on Bill's horse after seeing the rescue. Bobby's sister, Mary Lou (Lucile Browne), shows her gratitude by inviting Bill to use their ranch as a training ground. Bill enters a hotel where he runs into old Jim (Lafe McKee), who he used to be in a gang with until Bill decided to reform. Bill is still wanted and Jim threatens to expose him to the sheriff unless Bill agrees to throw the race, so Jim and Buck can clean up betting against him as he is the betting favorite. Bill reluctantly agrees, but then learns that Betty Lou is betting the family fortune, $2,000, on him. He goes back and tells Jim that the deal is off and he will be out to win. But he is spotted by the pursuing sheriff (Duke Lee) and is chased out of town. Jim and Buck also go after him, fearing he will expose them also. Bobby, after throwing the sheriff off of Bill's trail, is tricked by Jim into telling them where Bill is hiding. They capture him and leave him tied up with a man guarding him. And the race is about to begin.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?595474</url></doc>
