<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="595414">
  <docid>595414</docid>
  <title>The Terrorist She Freaks of Texas</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Lewis, Holly M.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
    <genre>Sci-Fi</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>queer</keyword>
    <keyword>gay-interest</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="France">18 November 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">25</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Davidson, Bug</producer>
    <producer>Lewis, Holly M.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Lewis, Holly M.</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pinkerton, Floyd</actor>
      <role>Terrified shopkeeper</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Post-millennial America was supposed to be a futuristic utopia marked by progress and optimism. Who could've known that a group of crazed reactionaries would take over the United States government and turn the nation into a hellish police state? After detaining immigrants, silencing journalists, and demonizing intellectuals, the leaders of the New America decide that they need a New Enemy to distract the restless citizenry... THE QUEERS! When the new leaders discover that most Americans are willing to deny human rights to sexual minorities, the government whips the nation into a frenzy of hatred towards gays and transsexuals -- a frenzy that culminates in the mass extermination of THE GAY MENACE! Yet the new leaders make one fatal mistake: after rounding up the majority of American gay males, they assume that queer females will surrender without a fight. But the New Government quickly comes to realize that even the U.S. Army is no match for the loveably wacky militant dykes and trannies rising up from the depths of the Homosexual Underground. They thought turning America into a theocracy would be easy. But they didn't expect to fight...THE TERRORIST SHE-FREAKS OF TEXAS!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?595414</url></doc>
