<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="595918">
  <docid>595918</docid>
  <title>The Three-Cornered Hat</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Liano, A.D.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>surrealism</keyword>
    <keyword>pirate</keyword>
    <keyword>treasure</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">17 October 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">8</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Liano, A.D.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Liano, A.D.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Liano, A.D.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Powell, Mike (II)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Liner, Al</actor>
      <role>Man</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Saguar, Luis</actor>
      <role>Pirate</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sherif, Nabil</actor>
      <role>Neighbor</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The Three-Cornered Hat is a work with deep roots in literature, music and folklore. The story of 'The Three-Cornered Hat' (or 'The Corregidor') officially dates back to a collection of ballads, Romancero General, published in Spain by Agustin Duran in 1821. Duran took the ballad from a broadsheet that he purchased in the street by a blind man. This bawdy tale of marital confusion between a Corregidor, a Miller and the Miller's wife no doubt had a long history before it was turned into a ballad and in 1874 it became the basis of a novel by the most widely read Spanish author of the day. In 1874, El Sombrero de Tres Picos, or The Three-Cornered Hat, was published by Pedro Antonio de Alarcon. The story had obsessed Alarcon for many years and he claims to have first heard it in the form of a ballad recited by an old shepard. Twenty-two years later, in 1896, Hugo Wolf based an opera on the story and in 1919 Diaghileff put it on stage as a balet, The Three-Cornered Hat, with music by Manuel de Falla and costumes and decor by Picasso. Over 80 years later, The Three-Cornered Hat is brought to the screen in a loose adaptation by A.D. Liano, based on a short story by Greg Boyd.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?595918</url></doc>
