<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="596847">
  <docid>596847</docid>
  <title>The Traveler</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Hernstrom, Ben</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>medicine</keyword>
    <keyword>science</keyword>
    <keyword>politics</keyword>
    <keyword>religion</keyword>
    <keyword>embryo</keyword>
    <keyword>parkinsons-disease</keyword>
    <keyword>ethics</keyword>
    <keyword>morality</keyword>
    <keyword>stem-cell</keyword>
    <keyword>catholic-church</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">10</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Hernstrom, Ben</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Hernstrom, Ben</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ferraro, Frank (III)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>An examination of the debate surrounding embryonic stem cell research and the moral and ethical implications involved in it, which requires destroying fertilized embryos. The film focuses on an artist, Frank Ferraro, who due to Parkinson's disease, has lost his career and the ability to make his art. At 46 years of age, he's scraping to make ends meet and trying to find new ways of expressing himself because the symptoms of his disease have made it impossible to handle the physical demands of being a sculptor. Many believe that a cure for Parkinson's disease will come from embryonic stem cell research, and some argue that it's not far off, meaning that to continue to ban federal funding could result in the loss of many lives and continual suffering, that would have been otherwise preventable. Weighing in on the debate are a theologian, a bioethics professor and lawyer and the Catholic Diocese of Pittsburgh. Each party has fascinating ways of approaching this difficult subject and culled together, their perspectives offer a complex look at the debate.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?596847</url></doc>
