<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="596970">
  <docid>596970</docid>
  <title>The Trial of Fentris Waterloo</title>
  <year>1995</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Joseph, Daniel (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>animate-doll</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">10 June 1996</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">22</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Joseph, Daniel (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Joseph, Daniel (I)</producer>
    <producer>Pappalardo, Maria Luisa</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Joseph, Daniel (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Brick, Andy</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ferrara, Luisa</actor>
      <role>Shirley</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gorenstein, Douglas</actor>
      <role>Simon</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Miranda, Marcos Antonio</actor>
      <role>Herberto</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Swansen, Larry</actor>
      <role>Fentris Waterloo</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Fentris Waterloo wakes up packs his doll Luisa into a doctor bag and takes her on a walk to Simon's lair, where they perform a ritual intended to transform the doll into a human. After Fentris is unable to bestow enough passion into the ritual, Simon becomes irritated and sends Fentris home. Fentris confides in another doll, his best friend Herberto a Mexican mariachi. Fentris plays the flute for Luisa then sets her on her pedestal and goes off to bed. After having a nightmare that Luisa and Herberto are having a secret affair, Fentris wakes up and finds the two dolls together. He strangles Luisa in the bathtub and hangs Herberto from a noose and goes back to bed. When he awakes, a life size Herberto is in bed next to him, so he hits himself over the head to call a consultation with himself. Fentris splits into three images of himself, dressed like doctors. They decide that Herberto is only a doll, and they throw him into a trash can and light him on fire. Then Herberto comes back, burnt to a crisp, so Fentris challenges him to a sword duel. Herberto wins the duel, and Fentris runs outside only to find himself in a courtroom where Simon is the judge. He is forced into participating in a game show called The Wheel of Destiny which will determine his fate. He spins the wheel and is sentenced to eternal life as a doll.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?596970</url></doc>
