<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="597269">
  <docid>597269</docid>
  <title>The True Story of the Mary Celeste</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Joyce, Chris (III)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>non-fiction</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">4 November 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">52</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>MacGregor, Anne</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>MacGregor, Anne</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>MacGregor, Anne</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>On the 5th of December 1872, the American-registered brigantine, the Mary Celeste, was found drifting in the Atlantic. The ship was in good condition. Its cargo was intact. However the 10 people on board were missing without trace. An official inquiry in Gibraltar failed to find the cause of their disappearance and since then, rumour, wild speculation and many theories have been proposed. In the 135 years that have passed, the mystery of this "ghost ship" has never been solved - until now. This is not another re-telling of this famous story or another theory which cannot be proved. A four-year investigation for this programme has turned up new information including a transcript of the ship's lost log. Now, vital new clues have enabled an international team of experts to finally solve what is widely regarded as the greatest mystery of the sea. The first accurate model ever created of the Mary Celeste has been used to create stunning CGI scenarios by RED VISION, the UK-based award-winning graphics studio. Interviews with members of the families of the American captain and the German seamen who were accused of murdering those on the Mary Celeste. Rare archive and the personal possessions of those on board which have never been seen outside the families of those whose lives were touched by this event. Filmed in full HD at the locations where this remarkable story unfolds: The Azores, The US, Germany, Gibraltar and the UK.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?597269</url></doc>
