<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="597335">
  <docid>597335</docid>
  <title>The Truth About Juliet</title>
  <year>1998</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Reed, Tripp</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="UK">15</certificate>
    <certificate country="Germany">12</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Germany">72</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>McGinly, Sean</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ginnane, Antony I.</producer>
    <producer>Lyons, Ann (I)</producer>
    <producer>McGinly, Sean</producer>
    <producer>Reed, Tripp</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>McGinly, Sean</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Lazar, Alan Ari</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Berkeley, Xander</actor>
      <role>George</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chase, Bailey</actor>
      <role>Willie/Dirk</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Einbinder, Chad</actor>
      <role>Todd</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Garrett, Spencer (I)</actor>
      <role>Dominic</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Granath, Tiffany</actor>
      <role>Stacey</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Loftin, Lennie</actor>
      <role>Ralph</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Marich, Michael</actor>
      <role>John</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>May, Ashley (III)</actor>
      <role>Trampy Girl</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Reed, Tripp</actor>
      <role>Reilly</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>St. John, Marco</actor>
      <role>Jack Green</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wiedergott, Karl</actor>
      <role>Chaloots</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The Truth About Juliet is a comedy about the secrets people hide and the truths that they're willing to live with. The story centers around four friends living in Los Angeles. DOMINIC, a pompous agent, has designs on a more satisfying career and lifestyle, which do not necessarily include Juliet, his girlfriend of two years. CHALOOTS, Dominic's best friend since childhood, is a writer who's gotten his first paid writing job, for what turns out to be a glorified porno. JULIET works in development, reading scripts for a studio. She's in love with Dominic but tired of his unwillingness to commit. So, for the last month she's been having an affair with John. JOHN, an acquaintance of Dominic's and a good friend of Chaloots', is the exact opposite of Dominic. He'll occasionally work as a writer to make some money, but mostly he watches television and drinks. When Chaloots discovers the truth about Juliet and John, things start to get complicated. Now he has to decide if he should keep his mouth shut or tell his best friend what he knows. Things get worse when Dominic gets hold of a script that John wrote. He passes it on to Juliet, who passes it on to her boss. Suddenly, the script is making waves in Hollywood and they're all on their way, except Chaloots.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?597335</url></doc>
