<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="597962">
  <docid>597962</docid>
  <title>The Undeniably Untimely Death of Leland Sturgis</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Schwartz, Pete (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">22 October 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">8</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Schwartz, Pete (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>DeGarmo, Chris</producer>
    <producer>Falcinelli, Laura</producer>
    <producer>Bucher Jr., John K.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Schwartz, Pete (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Covell, James</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Booker, Tom</actor>
      <role>Jonathan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Davis, Jon Michael</actor>
      <role>Seth</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Reeves, Lindsey</actor>
      <role>Dawn</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Growing up, Seth and Jonathan were best friends. As children they created Leland Sturgis, an imaginary personality that they could both enjoy. Seth's family moved and he and Jonathan were forced to part ways when they were 9 years old. 25 years later, Jonathan is the creative mastermind behind an immensely successful children's book series, "The Undeniably Unsystematic Adventures of Leland Sturgis". However, albeit good-natured, he is also a shut-in, his day to day exploits a mystery. Back in town for the first time since he was 9, Seth and his wife Dawn set a dinner date with Jonathan in order to catch up and to reminisce. What they discover is that not only has Jonathan based his award winning book series on he and Seth's old imaginary companion, but also that Jonathan still believes Leland is real. Jonathan admits the main reason he's such a shut-in is because Leland monopolizes so much of his time with his "unpredictable antics". Seth, concerned for his old friend's sanity is quick to deem Jonathan's condition unhealthy and to entertain drastic measures to ensure he gets help. Faced with no other options, Seth and Dawn plot The Undeniably Untimely Death of Leland Sturgis.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?597962</url></doc>
