<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="598489">
  <docid>598489</docid>
  <title>The Urn</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Schoenbrun, Lewis</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">29 February 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Usen, Skip</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Jacobs, Messiah</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Usen, Skip</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Burke, Leith M.</actor>
      <role>Policeman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Finkel, Fyvush</actor>
      <role>Sol</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kamel, Stanley</actor>
      <role>Joseph</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Keyes, Irwin</actor>
      <role>Albert</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mayeux, Rosalee</actor>
      <role>Zoe</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shimerman, Armin</actor>
      <role>Fiester</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Zola, Greg</actor>
      <role>Daniel</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Joseph is upset that his mother who just died was cremated, not buried according to Jewish tradition. His blind father, Sol, old and feeble, carries the urn containing Sophie's ashes everywhere, talking to her, listening to her, misplacing her. Sol is certain the "urine doctor" (urologist) planted a listening device up his keister enabling the Feds to spy on the family. Sol also claims to have been abducted by aliens who forced him to have sex and create a half-human, half-alien, "like Leonard Nimoy." Joseph's ex-wife, Zoe, now remarried to Bubba on her farm, has come in for the funeral. Their son, Daniel, an MBA graduate, returns from a two year stay in Israel, walks in the door dressed like a Hassid, with full beard, hat, black coat, the whole works. Joseph, a secular Jew, can't believe his eyes. He had expected Daniel to return to run his business. Sol relays Sophie's telepathic message that Daniel's future is in a hot place surrounded by Jews? Daniel: "Israel?" Sol: "Miami." Meanwhile, Joseph's ex-con cousin, Albert, shows up with his weird friend, Feister, who, from time to time sneak in dead bodies, storing one corpse in a trunk in the living room. Albert, whose liver is shot, is delighted to learn he shares the same blood type with Joseph, while Feister eagerly assembles his "instruments" awaiting the go-ahead from Albert. We answer these important questions: Why are Albert and Feister dragging in dead bodies, and why do they laugh uproariously when they talk about Joseph's "donation?" Will Zoe be able to convince "City Boy" Joseph to come live on the farm with her? And what about Daniel? Is his conversion for real? And Sol? Is a home in his future or could he be abducted again? Permanently?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?598489</url></doc>
