<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="599857">
  <docid>599857</docid>
  <title>The War Zone</title>
  <year>2000</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>War</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">22 December 2000</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="India">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Kumar, Atul (II)</director>
    <director>McDonnell, Brendan</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Mortimer, Thomas (I)</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>In June 1999 during the India - Pakistan War in Kargil every filmmaker around the world wanted a glimpse of the action. The Army Headquarters in Delhi were inundated with requests from television networks that had sent representatives from all over the globe to let them through. Each camera crew was taken on a tour once a week. Permissions were few and far between. The phone rang. They said yes. A certain segment of the Army agreed to depute a single officer who helped to sneak in a lone filmmaker. This was not an official tour. This is not official footage. Surmounting the inherent risks, what was achieved was footage that is concise and clear. Unknown to the Army the objective of this mission was to procure footage of the Bofors Gun in action for a documentary being produced by VPUK, aimed at exposing the scandal involved in the purchase of the gun. It seemed a waste to lose the remaining footage. This film brings never before seen images together with impressions, ideas, and views that rock the very foundations that our society has been built upon. Tracing the development of man, society, politics, military and finally an insight into humans from the aperture that is the war zone.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?599857</url></doc>
