<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="600229">
  <docid>600229</docid>
  <title>The Way of the Vampire</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Ka'aloa, Christine</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">11 November 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">20</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Williams, Canella</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Castillo, Miozoty</producer>
    <producer>Castillo, Sandy</producer>
    <producer>Zalinger, Keith</producer>
    <producer>Castillo, Sandy</producer>
    <producer>Williams, Canella</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Williams, Canella</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Zalinger, Keith</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Castillo, Miozoty</actor>
      <role>Bookstore Clerk</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>De La Mora, Carolina</actor>
      <role>Crystal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hawkins, Jakob</actor>
      <role>Prithivi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McFadyen, Cat</actor>
      <role>Dead Girl</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shrader, Stewart</actor>
      <role>Vayu</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Two brothers have a deep dark family secret. The elder brother Prithivi constantly strives to quench his lust for blood and sadism by performing ritualistic murders of young women, then dressing them like his favorite painting. The younger brother, Vayu, is obsessed with Alexandre Dumas' book 'The Count of Monte Cristo', which allows him to escape from the lurid lifestyle and unpredictably violent outbursts that his brother Prithivi routinely inflicts upon him. Prithivi desperately wishes for Vayu to fully accept his vampiric nature, the blood thirst Vayu consistently denies. When Vayu defies his older brother, Prithivi reacts with his fists and cruel words. One day Vayu meets a beautiful girl named Crystal at a bookstore who happens to share an interest in Dumas. This piques Vayu's curiosity whereby he flirts with the naïve girl and beguiles her into a date. The tension tightens as Prithivi becomes increasingly jealous of this newfound relationship. In defense of his emotions, tries repeatedly to convince his morose and decidedly un-vampiric like brother to dispatch the girl like a real hunter-killer should. Vayu continues to refuse his brother's will, despite being the recipient of Prithivi's malicious passion. Prithivi's last nerve is hanging by a thread as Vayu unknowingly snaps it. Vayu awakens to misfortune and bondage, with Crystal unconscious and defenseless, he pleas for Prithivi to let them go. Prithivi toys with what he sees as an entertaining opportunity, humoring Vayu's bleats of mercy. Eventually he grows tired of mocking his brother and orders Vayu to do what should come naturally, which is to kill her. What happens next is a twisted turn of events from which Vayu cannot escape.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?600229</url></doc>
