<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="602131">
  <docid>602131</docid>
  <title>The World Baking Cup: The Best Bread in the World</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Osghian, Edi</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Reality-TV</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>bread</keyword>
    <keyword>baker</keyword>
    <keyword>wheat-floor</keyword>
    <keyword>paris</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">1 February 2003</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 February 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Versteeg, Nick</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Osghian, Edi</producer>
    <producer>Versteeg, Nick</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bjornson, Michelle</writer>
    <writer>Drewery, Dale</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Bowers, James (IV)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harvie, Ellie</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Every three years the best bakers from around the world meet in Paris, France for the ultimate baking battle - Le Coupe du Monde de la Boulangerie. Twelve teams of devoted men and women will race the clock and each other, testing their skills, creativity, and endurance in this Olympics of baking. Working from secret recipes, the teams prepare scores of traditional baguette and wonderfully shaped specialty breads, containing everything from fruit to nuts. Each team must also create an elaborate showpiece, reflecting their country's national identity and made entirely of edible ingredients. Originality, technique, and attention to detail are the name of the game; the prestigious prize - the glittering World Baking Cup trophy. While the French team struggles with temperamental equipment, the Japanese competitors unveil their green brioche. Their showpiece is a marvel of realism: dough coaxed and twisted into a spectacular Japanese garden, complete with tiny, white cherry blossoms. Will the U.S. team's piece de resistance, including a handsome American flag and intricately detailed Navaho blanket, be enough to win over the judges and allow the United States to hold onto the coveted Cup? n the last competition, USA toppled 11 other countries when it took home the World Cup for the very first time. Watch as the French try to regain the title of makers of "the best bread in the world", see who will take home the Cup this year.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?602131</url></doc>
