<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="602426">
  <docid>602426</docid>
  <title>The Wounded and the Slain</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Begue, Jason</editor>
    <editor>Rowe, Erica (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">8 May 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">29</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Begue, Jason</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Gatti, Steven</producer>
    <producer>Phillips, Becky</producer>
    <producer>Phillips, Becky</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Begue, Jason</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Torres, Liam</actor>
      <role>James Bevan</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>New York. 1951. A man battles with his conscience when he enters an extramarital affair to fulfill desires that are unmet by the woman he loves the most; his wife. James and Cora Bevan have been sleeping in separate beds for the last few years of their marriage. They move from day to day in hushed, polite interaction. The spark, has been out for years because Cora is unable to sexually engage with her husband. This results from deep seeded troubles in Cora's past; something she struggles to define even to herself and doesn't dare to mention to her husband, hiding instead behind an innocent, soft-spoken demeanor. James attempts to be the loving and understanding husband, but after years without unrepressed human contact he eventually finds comfort in another woman, Lita, a beautiful, charismatic prostitute who is everything Cora is not. Soon they develops a very tender relationship with her. It lasts a few months before Cora confronts James admitting that she followed him one night and has learned his secret. Blaming herself she offers to leave him so he can be with Lita, but James - unable to stand the thought of losing Cora- breaks it off with Lita almost immediately over the phone. Cora makes an attempt at pleasing James but he refuses to continue when he realizes he is causing her pain. He resorts to drinking, spending his nights in various taprooms. Deep into his love affair with drinking James returns to visit Lita, but discovers she has died after a night of heavy drinking. One night Cora collapses at James feet begging him to quit drinking and asking that they promise each other they would try and make it work.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?602426</url></doc>
