<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="603991">
  <docid>603991</docid>
  <title>They Never Found Her</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Friedman, Gary (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">23 March 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">23</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Kerven, Claude</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kerven, Claude</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Kerven, Claude</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Tremante, Michael</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stormare, Peter</actor>
      <role>Woods</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Woods, a ruthless professional killer, arrives at a palatial country home with orders to kill the occupants and retrieve a suitcase of stolen money. At the door, the hit man encounters not his intended victims, but only Anna, a young retarded woman. Posing as a police officer, Woods deceives her into letting him in. Once inside, he takes Anna hostage and terrorizes her into leading him through the house on a search for a suitcase of money he says was stolen by her sister, Beth. Following the discovery of a ransacked office, Woods begins to suspect that, although retarded, Anna is hiding the truth. In a strategy to divide and conquer, he taunts Anna that her sister plans to take the money and abandon her, and backs it up by showing her a half-packed suitcase and one airplane ticket in Beth's name. But Anna's loyalty does not waiver. Woods breaks into Beth's closet, where he makes a gruesome discovery. Enraged, he assaults Anna, manhandling her and throwing her to the floor. But despite the intimidation, he is unable to pry the truth from his captive. Having failed to find the money, Woods places a call to his employer, who callously orders him to leave no witnesses, in other words - Woods must kill the mentally challenged young woman. After a lifetime of remorseless violence, the hit man faces the dilemma of executing a defenseless innocent or risking his own life to spare hers.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?603991</url></doc>
