<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="603995">
  <docid>603995</docid>
  <title>They No Longer Sleep Alone</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Woollen, Ben</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>New Zealand</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="New Zealand">42</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Mayall, Jeremy</producer>
    <producer>Granville, Scott</producer>
    <producer>Woollen, Ben</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Granville, Scott</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Granville, Scott</actor>
      <role>Roadie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maha, Adam</actor>
      <role>Band member</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mayall, Brendan</actor>
      <role>White Man</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mayall, Jeremy</actor>
      <role>Band member</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Powell, Matt (III)</actor>
      <role>Howard</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Scheurich, Matt</actor>
      <role>Band member</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>They No Longer Sleep Alone captures the story of one man, Howard, a musician, who has become trapped by the emotional and spiritual confusion of an unexpected break-up from his girlfriend. Choosing to escape from his grief with a combination of alcohol and drugs, Howard slips from reality into the depths of an imagined world populated by the distorted figures of his past and present life. He is forced to return to the real world through an overseas tour with his band, yet Howard continues to mask his internal pain with substance abuse and meaningless physical relationships, constantly battling with subconscious returns to the imagined world. With his soul desperately searching for new meaning, Howard has a chance meeting with Kelsey in an inner-city park. Kelsey's gentle nature captivates Howard and slowly he begins to rediscover the beauty and power of love and life, cherishing his newly found appreciation for the people around him. Ultimately the tour comes to an end and Howard is forced to say goodbye to Kelsey, choosing his music career over love. Once back in his hometown however, Howard begins to regret his decision, falling back into a depression. At rock-bottom and with his life in disarray, Howard finally confronts his inner demons and banishes them from his life. With his mind and body now cleansed, Howard leaves his past life behind and returns to Kelsey, ready to let love decide his destiny.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?603995</url></doc>
