<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="604384">
  <docid>604384</docid>
  <title>Third Date</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Day, Michael (X)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">16 August 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">30</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Craddock, Jeff</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Lucas, Kristen</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Henrickson, Tom</writer>
    <writer>Seamans, Jon</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cleary, John (IV)</actor>
      <role>Mr. Harvey</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Connolly, Shaun</actor>
      <role>Cousin Jim</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gagnon, Sari</actor>
      <role>Suzanne</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harvey, Christopher (IV)</actor>
      <role>Bar Tender</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jules, Tracie</actor>
      <role>Kara Harvey</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kelleher, Molly</actor>
      <role>Ann</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lavelle, Maurice</actor>
      <role>Rudy Tucker</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Martinelli, Linzy</actor>
      <role>Sandy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Miller, Jay (IX)</actor>
      <role>Kevin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Perzanoski, Kyle</actor>
      <role>Craig</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Smith, Billy (XI)</actor>
      <role>Ed Sliwoski</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Ed Sliwoski is not a bad man. He is not an unattractive man. But, he has never made it to a third date. Oh, Ed's no virgin, in fact he's gotten lucky on more than a few occasions. But somehow, something always goes wrong by the time the second date - and his chances for a long-term relationship - comes crashing or whimpering to an end. As he watches from the sidelines at yet another friend's wedding, Ed meets fellow guest Rudy Tucker (Maurice Lavell). Rudy has a positive approach to life, but even he can feel the pain as Ed recounts his sad history of disastrous dates. Embarrassingly enough, the wedding party is also filled with many of the women Ed has loved and lost. There is Kara, his first love. Their second date was going well until things tanked over an illicit cigarette and Ed ended up being chased down the street by her enraged dad and the family dog. Two dates were as far as he made it with Suzanne (Sari Gagnon), a gold digger fond of anything with a designer name and large price tag. Then there's Kelly, a stunner whose unfortunate encounter with a bird at the beach sent Ed packing. Last but not least is Ann, a sure bet if there ever was one. Ed was in her apartment passing third and being waved into home when, in his inimitable style, he managed to botch things up. So what's his problem? Just bad luck? Or, as a drunken cousin blurts out, is he the victim of a family curse? And could Ed have triggered it as a boy on that summer afternoon when he snooped around the family attic knowing full well he shouldn't have been up there? That antique pocket watch he absconded with that summer day so long ago may hold the key...</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?604384</url></doc>
