<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="604561">
  <docid>604561</docid>
  <title>This Body Is a Prison</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>occupation</keyword>
    <keyword>bethlehem</keyword>
    <keyword>palestine</keyword>
    <keyword>israel</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Arabic</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">10 November 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">45</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Bergeson, Dylan</director>
  </directors>
<plot>Go behind the scenes of media coverage about Palestine and enter a world where terror is a daily reality. Against this backdrop, there emerges a deeply layered story of a nation fractured by walls both physical and emotional. This Body is a prison discusses the existential dilemmas faced by Palestinian youth as they attempt to develop a sense of self in a land carved by war. Balata Refugee Camp, where 30,000 refugees are sardine-packed into concrete high-rise housing units, sometimes only inches apart. Emotional developmental problems among young children have skyrocketed in recent years due to increasing violence. These experiences are juxtaposed with those of children growing up in Bethlehem, where attacks have mostly ended since 2003. There, children relate a different method of dealing with their political situation: by ignoring it, seeking escape through books and fantasies. The story climaxes as rare footage takes the viewer into the chaos of a military incursion. The ending analysis is both surprising and thought provoking as interview subjects grapple to maintain a sense of hope for their future.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?604561</url></doc>
