<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="604808">
  <docid>604808</docid>
  <title>This Is Who We Are</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Dehm, Zachary</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">15</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Willis, Stephanie (IV)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Randolph, Brooke</producer>
    <producer>Willis, Stephanie (IV)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Willis, Stephanie (IV)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Vincent, Jay (III)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Culver, Ryan</actor>
      <role>Kevin Jones</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hale, Willow</actor>
      <role>Sally McGuffin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lance, Laura</actor>
      <role>Wendy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McCauley, Thomas (II)</actor>
      <role>Doctor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Negron, John Antony</actor>
      <role>Jaime</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Cheryl, a socially awkward, DMV worker, desperately clings to her oversexed mother for a sense of self-worth. Cheryl has lived her entire life attached to her mother's side, and instead of successfully traversing the world around her, she is fixed on the steamy Spanish telenovela she and her mother watch. She lives a mundane life composed of the DMV, the telenovela and her mother's constant nudging to have a child. When her mother suddenly falls ill and enters the hospital, Cheryl's grasp of reality is rattled and her world is turned upside down. Cheryl is on her own for the first time and cannot bear the idea of being alone. She seeks to fill the void in her life with the company of a man's expired driver's license. Cheryl's mother gets wind of her new "romance," and demands to meet the man and help get a baby pushed out. Cheryl struggles to keep her mother happy, sustain her "relationship" with the license and hang onto the new shred of value she has found in her life. Will she tell the truth or keep living in a make-believe world?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?604808</url></doc>
