<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="605453">
  <docid>605453</docid>
  <title>Though the Heavens Fall</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Andersen, Andrew (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>War</genre>
    <genre>History</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>airplane</keyword>
    <keyword>bomber-aircraft</keyword>
    <keyword>world-war-ii-bomber</keyword>
    <keyword>wwii</keyword>
    <keyword>aircraft</keyword>
    <keyword>bomber</keyword>
    <keyword>b-17-bomber</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">13 July 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">46</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Gerisch, Julie</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Gerisch, Julie</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Gerisch, Julie</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>The 447th Bombardment Group flew 258 combat missions in the skies over Europe during World War II. Their history is representative of the 350,000 men who flew in the 8th Air Force. The film begins with a group of 447th veterans recounting their most memorable missions and life at their base in Rattlesden, England. After their stories are told, first time director Julie Gerisch encourages the men to look deeper into their souls - past the missions - and into the emotions that have remained inside them for over sixty years. The veterans wander back into the fog of war exploring the physical and emotional cost of combat. The relive the joy of V-E Day and reveal the pain of coming home with ghosts that continue to haunt them. The men celebrate their brotherhood and discuss the positive ways in which their military experience impacted them and shaped their lives. Their inspirational stories paint a portrait of courage beyond history, adding a new dimension to our understanding of their wartime experience and insight into the sometimes lonely hearts of heroes.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?605453</url></doc>
