<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="606071">
  <docid>606071</docid>
  <title>Three to Five &amp; Glassy</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Rivera, Colin</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">8 September 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">101</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Rivera, Colin</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Relucio, Angela</producer>
    <producer>Torres, Cindy L.</producer>
    <producer>Rivera, Colin</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Rivera, Colin</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>French, Steve (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cohen, Barnett</actor>
      <role>Chester</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Davey, Dylan</actor>
      <role>Martin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Galante, Michael</actor>
      <role>Frank</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hatfield, Sara Malia</actor>
      <role>Audrey</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Luis, Andrew (II)</actor>
      <role>Tom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Osei, Kwasi</actor>
      <role>Dallas</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rafferty, Bobby</actor>
      <role>Shawn</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Roth, Andrew (I)</actor>
      <role>Ryan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sangalli, David</actor>
      <role>Dave</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vause, Jeffrey</actor>
      <role>Mr. Aikane</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Annie is having a bad day. The morning after a curious first date, she wakes to find herself in a compromising position. Unable to remember anything, her self respect shaken by this apparent lapse in judgment, Annie scrambles to piece together the events of the night. Her mystery date unreachable, and further stressed about her father being in town for her hula performance later that night, Annie inadvertently locks herself out of her apartment. Reaching out to her friends, who seem unusually distracted and aloof from her, Annie embarks on a quest to track down copies of her keys scattered about the city, as well as solve who her mystery date is and what really happened last night, in time to hula for her daddy. During her quest, in which she encounters and confronts her sleazy ex-boyfriend, her estranged older sister and a random, 'smelly jerk', Annie is forced to assess her own sheltered life. Accused by her ex of having no interest in holding a real job or paying for her own rent, taunted by her sister of being daddy's little baby girl and unable to get through life without someone to hold her hand through the hard times, Annie's confidence is further shaken by her inability to get her keys back or find out anything about her mystery date, while her friends seemingly abandon her and her dreaded, unrehearsed hula performance in front of her father draws closer and closer.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?606071</url></doc>
