<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="606023">
  <docid>606023</docid>
  <title>Three for the Road</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">1 March 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">87</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Lucas, Ralph (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Lucas, Ralph (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Minthorn, Timothy</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bacon, Nancy</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>MacEachern, Pat</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Nancy Bacon, Brad Bianchin and Pat MacEachern are three average, ordinary Canadians. Nancy works as a financial consultant, Brad owns a bar and Pat is an actor. They had been close friends for about two years when Nancy came up with an idea to raise money and awareness for a local non-profit organization by riding a bike from Calgary to Vancouver through the Rocky Mountains. Brad didn't think she should make the trip alone and Pat was willing to lend his support to the idea. None of them were trained athletes but all three were willing to risk pain and injury to help Calgary's Society for the Treatment of Autism. This is the story of that unique journey told on a day-by-day basis as the events unfolded along 1000 kilometers of Canada's Highway 1 West and captures the challenges the riders faced. From wind and rain to tractor-trailers rushing past on narrow mountain roads to physical exhaustion and the real risk of personal injury, Three for the Road tells the story of ordinary people under extraordinary circumstances trying to accomplish a nearly impossible task.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?606023</url></doc>
