<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="606350">
  <docid>606350</docid>
  <title>Through These Eyes</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Callies, Kevin</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">12 September 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">11</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Callies, Kevin</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Callies, Kevin</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Callies, Kevin</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Flanagan, Will</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Callies, Kevin</actor>
      <role>Ben</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gifford, Michael</actor>
      <role>Stranger</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hughes, George (VI)</actor>
      <role>Officer Frederick</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ingram, Lance</actor>
      <role>Nick</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Larsen, Matt</actor>
      <role>Travis</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Miller, Warren (V)</actor>
      <role>James</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sawvell, Travis</actor>
      <role>Steven</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ullsmith, Chris</actor>
      <role>Mark</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>It was on a Halloween night after Steven and Mallory had left their friend's party, that the two found themselves in a situation that inevitably threw their lives a curve ball. Steven finds himself standing up for his girlfriend face to face against three guys. What comes out of it is a blind sided sucker punch that shatters his jaw. This was not a meaningless punch thrown by a costumed stranger. It was Mallory's ex-boyfriend James who committed the crime. Now with his jaw wired shut Steven is faced with the decision to press charges, or to take matters in his own hands. Although Mallory tries desperately to help Steven swallow his hunger for vengeance. It's Steven's friends Mark and Ben who eventually persuade him to look for James. The gates open after six weeks when Steven's wires are removed from his jaw. The situation becomes similar, there's one guy who finds himself face to face against three guys. Only this time, the roles between Steven and James are reversed. Steven gets his vengeance, but not without his conscience paying the cost. Guilt settles in, as he steps away from James's body lying limp on the ground. Steven is back in the emergency room for the second time in two months. This time bringing with him, the reason for his first visit.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?606350</url></doc>
