<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="609404">
  <docid>609404</docid>
  <title>TitleRacer</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Yohe-Mellor, Arron</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Reality-TV</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>race</keyword>
    <keyword>drive</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">10 November 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">55</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Tabri, Nick</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Yohe-Mellor, Arron</producer>
    <producer>Falck, Barry</producer>
    <producer>Franklin, Carl (II)</producer>
    <producer>Doro, Emily</producer>
    <producer>Franklin, Carl (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Falck, Barry</writer>
    <writer>Franklin, Carl (II)</writer>
    <writer>Tabri, Nick</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Starr, Fredro</actor>
      <role>Host</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>At speeds of over 100 mph, you can have more than just your life on the line. Because the car you're driving, the car you've spent what seems like a lifetime building and customizing and detailing and injecting, the car you've lived in and on and under every waking hour for as long as you can remember, is only 12.9 seconds away from belonging to someone else. You're a TitleRacer and you live in a world where a tenth of a second can mean the difference between winning and walking; full throttle is the only gear you've got and cut throat is the only game you know. As a TitleRacer, all that you have are your wits and your wheels and you've just wagered both of them against the hellion in the other car. TitleRacer is the record-breaking reality series where 6 of the best amateur street racers in the world are pitted against one another in a winner-take-all-single-elimination tournament. The ticket for admission? Their reputations and their rides - both of which they have spent the better part of their adult lives building. One loss and they surrender their titles to the winning driver who then moves on with one more car and one more week in RacerMansion, a state-of-the-art automotive utopia where every conceivable creature comfort is afforded both car and driver. And to the victors go the spoils. Or the spoiler or the camshaft or the transmission or the engine or anything else the winning drivers see fit to harvest from the cars they win. They can use their race-gotten gain for spare parts to improve their own vehicles, or vice versa, switching rides and salvaging what they want to give their new machines even more muscle than their old ones. The most sadistic of the drivers might just park the cars they've won in the middle of the track... at a monster truck rally. Or maybe they're curious about how long it takes a Makita UC120DWA electric chainsaw to chew through the chassis of a 2005 Dodge Viper. You want drama? Cut to a close-up of a 28 year old man who has spent the last 7 years of his life building a car that's about to be crushed beneath the 66 inch tires of a truck called GRAVE DIGGER. What drives these adrenaline junkies and what do they drive? We go beyond the track and explore street racing's slick underbelly. Hosted by hip-hop impresario and television/ film actor, Fredro Starr (Torque, Light It Up, Moesha), TitleRacer delves deep into the lives of this millennium's Ben-Hurs: people's champions whose chariots represent the single most important relationship in their lives. Each week will feature a different type of race: ranging from drifting to drag racing to a 500-mile endurance race during our captivating two-hour season finale. Although the races are controlled for safety, the competitors themselves have an uncontrollable drive to win. In Racer Mansion and on the track, anything can happen; so buckle up and prepare for the race of your life.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?609404</url></doc>
