<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="612325">
  <docid>612325</docid>
  <title>Tonight in That Building</title>
  <year>1991</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Italian</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Italy">T</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Italy">5 February 1991</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Italy">80</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <writers>
    <writer>Ninchi, Arnaldo</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Elia, Antonella</actor>
      <role>Alex</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grado, Alessandra</actor>
      <role>Roby</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>These are the story's main characters: Alex and Robi, two young students bound by a rather particular friendship; Stefano, their friend the actor; Guidobaldo Foglia, a somewhat Mephistophelean landlord; Matilde, a nineteenth century noblewoman magically reincarnated that evening; an eccentric violinist; two old women with a joyful past; a crazy psychoanalyst. These are the various personalities that, in an old apartment in the center of Rome, alternate and overlap in an exhilarating web of situations in the classic style of Italian comedy. Will Stefano/ Arnaldo succeed in playing the boyfriend of both Robi and Alex at the same time? And how will he deal with the unexpected arrival of the girls' parents? Will he save Matilde, the victim of the insane psychoanalyst? Will he be able to save himself from the ferocious temper of Foglia, who threatens to kill them all with an axe? This all happens during a single night at year's end, a theater for surprise and revelation, in that building governed by an ancient spell. But a happy ending will crown the episode in which love will triumph.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?612325</url></doc>
