<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="613694">
  <docid>613694</docid>
  <title>Torture Dungeon</title>
  <year>1970</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Milligan, Andy (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>pitchfork</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Canada">R</certificate>
    <certificate country="USA">R</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">23 January 1970</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">80</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Milligan, Andy (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Mishkin, William</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Borske, John</writer>
    <writer>Milligan, Andy (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Adams, Helen (III)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Baylor, Matt</actor>
      <role>Torture dungeon victim</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Borske, Hal</actor>
      <role>Alfred, Duke of Aberthy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Box, George</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cassidy, Susan (I)</actor>
      <role>Heather MacGregor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dillon, Patricia (I)</actor>
      <role>Lady Jane</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Flanagan, Neil</actor>
      <role>Peter the Eye</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fricelle, Robert</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Garvey, Patricia</actor>
      <role>Rosemary</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jacuzzo, Gerald</actor>
      <role>Norman, Duke of Norwich</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lyra, Dan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mason, Richard (XII)</actor>
      <role>Ivan the Hunchback</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The sudden decapitation of Lord Harkin has the Kingdom, as well it should, in a state of fear. For it is well known to one and all of the citizens around and about that Norman, the evil Duke of Norwich (played by who cares) and his buddies, bimbos and cohorts over at---Drum Roll---The Torture Dungeon are responsible. Norman has plans to marry off his dimwit half-brother Albert of Aberthy to Heather McGregor of No Title, the most beautiful and sensual girl in the Kingdom. But first he has to arrange for the pitchforking of her current squeeze, William the Nobody. Heather has no idea of what she is getting into but, following the spectacular Royal Wedding followed by the erotic ceremony of the spectacular consumation of the Royal Marriage, she begins to suspect that all that is rotten does not lie entirely in Denmark, especially if Andy Milligan is around. Norman'S half sisters---this guy has no full siblings---Lady Agatha and Lady Jane, in a very good effort to warn Heather of Norman's methods, take her down to roll--The Torture Dungeon. She is terrified at what she sees, which is somewhat surprising for one who has just been exposed to Albert, as it is basically gory sights of mutilated victims. Norman, a man with a plan, has his henchmen, Ivan the Terrible Dwarf and Maudlin the Execeutioner, do away with Albert, Lady Jane and Lady Agatha and is attempting to kill Heather, who is but doesn't know it, the true heir to the throne recently vacated by the late, decapitated Lord Harkin. But, Norman is foiled by Margaret the Hag, a disfigured member of the Court, who spears him to death just before she is trampled to death by a horse, or audience members stampeding for the exits.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?613694</url></doc>
