<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="615490">
  <docid>615490</docid>
  <title>Trailblazing: The Women of Nepal's Trekking Industry</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Hoffe, Lisa</editor>
    <editor>Reid, Cyril</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>nepal</keyword>
    <keyword>trekking</keyword>
    <keyword>women</keyword>
    <keyword>gender</keyword>
    <keyword>tourism</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Nepali</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Canada">13+</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">9 December 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">24</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Hoffe, Lisa J.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Hoffe, Lisa J.</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chhetri, Lucky</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chhetri, Nickey</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Clark, Lisa (VIII)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dahlborg, Karin</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Shot in the beautiful Annapurna region of the Himalayas, Trailblazing documents the pioneering spirit of the few women working as guides in the lucrative yet male-dominated adventure tourism sector in Nepal. Their niche are the many female tourists who come to Nepal every year to "trek" the mountainous routes from village to village. 'Trailblazing' profiles the remarkable story of the three determined sisters of the Chhetri family and how they came to operate the first and only female-owned trekking agency in a highly competitive industry. The sisters saw a niche in the market when some women tourists returning from treks told of incidents of inappropriate behaviour from their male guides. To meet the high demand for female guides, the sisters developed a training program to expand capacity for women in the industry, training over 500 women since 1998. This is also a first. 3 Sisters Adventure Trekking is a 'social enterprise', diverting a percentage of the annual income to building capacity for more women in the industry. The film also profiles several young trainees in the program and provides a sense of the social conditions and limited expectations for young Nepali women within Nepali culture.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?615490</url></doc>
