<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="615900">
  <docid>615900</docid>
  <title>Trans</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Ruiz, Claudia (II)</editor>
    <editor>Verkoulen, Gijs</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>trans-siberia-express</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Russian</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Netherlands">AL</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Netherlands">30 September 2005</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Hungary">1 May 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Netherlands">25</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Ruiz, Claudia (II)</director>
    <director>Verkoulen, Gijs</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Ruiz, Claudia (II)</writer>
    <writer>Verkoulen, Gijs</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Goldewijk, Yorick</composer>
    <composer>Hendrikx, Tuur</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>'Trans' is a 25-minute documentary about a journey by train from Moscow to Beijing. On board of the famous Trans Siberian express the film passes by the fascinating visuals of extreme differences in countryside, traveler's and natives. During this 7 day journey we experience how the eye and the mind change the perspective as the hours go by. From an alert objective view from start we leap over to a subjective view on the end. When in the beginning traditional views come to the screen, on the end the viewer sees what the time-frame of this journey changes in the alertness of the eye. As time goes by shifting of railway tracks and power lines get fascinating, you will get delirious as the Gobi dessert passes by and by, and you will see the beauty of light as it passes like a stroboscope through the compartments. 'Trans' is a visual poem that shows a new view on a journey everybody has heard of. Finally the viewer can really experience how it is to make a journey on the longest railway track on earth, from start to finish.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?615900</url></doc>
