<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="616093">
  <docid>616093</docid>
  <title>Translucitum</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Asanger, Sabine</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>star</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">4</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Asanger, Sabine</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Asanger, Sabine</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Asanger, Sabine</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Asanger, Sabine</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>The creatures from Translucitum want their planet to be the brightest star in the universe. This planet is completely made out of glass and relies on the sunlight reflecting off of its surface. In order for the planet to keep its shininess, any kind of dirt that might collect on its surface must be washed away. Transluscitum heavily depends on the rain showers of the massive gray clouds that cover the entire planet everyday. The volcanoes of Glomar help contain some of the precious water, so that the fragile Whalms can absorb it with their silk-like tentacles. This daily moisture helps protect the Whalms against bright light coming from the neighboring forest of Maloops, who are known for their unintended ability to concentrate sunlight into harsh light beams. Norf, one of the planet's most influential inhabitants, makes sure he is the shiniest and brightest individual. One day as he is showing of his new shiny fro, the gray clouds hinder the sun from making him radiant. Despite Brolli's warnings, the enraged Norf sends the clouds away from the planet. Soon the sun dries up every last bit of water. The Whalms are no longer able to protect themselves against the stinging rays of the Maloops, so the Whalms silk-like tentacles catch fire leaving the entire planet in flames. Once the flames die down, the ashes settle, leaving the once crystal clear planet dull and unable to shine like a star.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?616093</url></doc>
