<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="619660">
  <docid>619660</docid>
  <title>Truly Unusual</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Ramirez, Travis</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Ramirez, Travis</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Stoddard, Josh</producer>
    <producer>Meier, Deborah Lynn</producer>
    <producer>Murray, Matthew (III)</producer>
    <producer>Ramirez, Travis</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Ramirez, Travis</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chenoweth, Brian</actor>
      <role>Vince Taylor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cordileone, Nick</actor>
      <role>Craig Bellows</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Damian, Scott</actor>
      <role>Jim Caldoon</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Davis, Susan Carol</actor>
      <role>Underwear Thrower</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Emmett, Bert</actor>
      <role>Sterling</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Guider, Forest Freedom</actor>
      <role>John Debato</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Irwin, Rick</actor>
      <role>Casino Employee</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Karsell, Elizabeth</actor>
      <role>Dana</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kosta, Carissa</actor>
      <role>Concierge</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Meier, David Robert</actor>
      <role>Driver in muscle car</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Meier, Deborah Lynn</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Meier, Roberta May</actor>
      <role>Susan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Murray, Matthew (III)</actor>
      <role>Glen Ferguson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ramirez, Travis</actor>
      <role>Offscreen Filmmaker</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Reed, Gary Lee</actor>
      <role>Director</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stoddard, Josh</actor>
      <role>Mason Humbert</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Walker, Jeremy</actor>
      <role>Gary</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>For more than thirty years, Tom Jones has captured the hearts (and panties) of followers around the world. His vocal styling and sexy on-stage magnetism still captivate women - and men - both young and old. Our story follows a faithful and zealous band of devotees whose unquenchable thirst for everything "Tom" is embodied in their notorious and eccentric organization: The Society for the Preservation and Proliferation of the Music and Artistry of Tom Jones. Their mission: to honor and defend the renowned entertainer. Your window to this fanatical world is opened by an anonymous and ever-present documentary film crew. Through their lens we are witness to the unusual activities of the Society's four founding members: Craig, K, Mason and Glen. It's quickly obvious - this is no ordinary fan club. In fact, they reject the very notion of the common fan. In their minds, they are equals with Tom - at one with his place in the spotlight. The focus of the film is the Society's preparation for the annual Las Vegas Concert Trip - their yearly pilgrimage to see Tom perform. This year, the group plots to steal a few precious moments with Jones after the show, but for these cohorts, it's not about shaking hands and getting autographs. No, they are preparing for a meeting of equals. The trip committee quickly gets down to business. With only two months of preparation, there are tickets to buy, rooms to reserve and transportation to arrange. Despite a serious cash shortage and growing dissatisfaction among their members, the Society's leaders are convinced that this time they will succeed in meeting their hero, a dream that has eluded them for five years. Although a Tom Jones insider has agreed to set up the meeting, pitfalls and ill-planning threaten to wreak havoc on the group's mission once more. Will the four shake the hand of their adored icon? Do they possess the courage to withstand the intensity of his presence? For the answers to these and other questions, we can only wait.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?619660</url></doc>
