<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="620808">
  <docid>620808</docid>
  <title>Tum Se Achcha Kaun Hai</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">26 April 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Anand, Deepak</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Rathod, Shravan</composer>
    <composer>Saifi, Nadeem</composer>
    <composer>Sodhi, Surendra Singh</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Agnihotri, Rati</actor>
      <role>Prof. Dixit</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Asghar, Ali</actor>
      <role>Ali</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bafna, Ruchi</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chhabria, Aarti</actor>
      <role>Naina Dixit</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Irani, Adi</actor>
      <role>Amar Deep</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Nakul</actor>
      <role>Arjun Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khote, Viju</actor>
      <role>Inspector Vijay Chander</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kiran, Shashi (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mahadevan, Anant</actor>
      <role>Sunil Mahadevan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pendse, Neha</actor>
      <role>Urmilla Singh)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shankar, Girja</actor>
      <role>Arjun's brother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tahil, Dalip</actor>
      <role>Gujral</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vora, Neeraj</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Yadav, Raghuvir</actor>
      <role>Manto</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Yadav, Rajpal</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Working as a Guide and bus driver in Jaisalmer, Arjun had always dreamed of being a famous singer. When he meets beautiful tourist, Naina Dixit, he impresser her with his singing, she encourages him to come to Bombay and try his luck there, and leaves her address with him. Shortly thereafter, Arjun bids farewell to his brother, his Bhabi, and nephew and sets forth to Bombay. Upon arrival he does meet with Naina's friend, Monto, who takes him to several places to try his luck, but no one even bothers to even listen to him, leave alone hear him sing. He lives with Naina, her sisters, Anu and Tuktuk, and their college professor mom, who empathize with him. Then Naina hits upon an idea to have a open song and dance show in a public park. The show does take place, and a wealthy young woman, Bobby Gujral, does notice Arjun and invites him to sing for a firm run by her dad's partner, Sunil Mahadevan. When Sunil refuses to get involved, Bobby talks to her dad and opens her very own recording company featuring Arjun as the main artist. Soon Arjun becomes famous overnight, but has not forgotten Naina and her family. This does not auger well with Bobby, who is very possessive and wants Arjun all to himself - and she makes up her mind that she will never permit anyone to come close to Arjun - for she has a gun, and knows how to use it.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?620808</url></doc>
