<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="621239">
  <docid>621239</docid>
  <title>Turn It Loose</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Carlin, Paul (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Sport</genre>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>deep</keyword>
    <keyword>dance</keyword>
    <keyword>hip-hop</keyword>
    <keyword>eyes</keyword>
    <keyword>breakdance</keyword>
    <keyword>battle</keyword>
    <keyword>pressure</keyword>
    <keyword>discipline</keyword>
    <keyword>africa</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>French</language>
    <language>Wolof</language>
    <language>Arabic</language>
    <language>Japanese</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Turkey">12 February 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="UK">19 June 2009</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Ireland">20 February 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">96</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Siddons, Alastair</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Nikolsky, Grisha</producer>
    <producer>Bodie, Grace</producer>
    <producer>Holzmann, Oliver</producer>
    <producer>Nixon, Sasha</producer>
    <producer>Bermann, Georges</producer>
    <producer>Manderla, Philipp</producer>
    <producer>Sanderson, Madeleine</producer>
    <producer>Pitt, Josh (V)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Jones, Dan (III)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Abaldonado, Ronnie</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hong10</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lilou (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>RoxRite</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Taisuke</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In September 2007, 16 of the world's best b-boys battle one on one in a disused power station in the heart of Soweto, South Africa, to determine who will be the next world champion. TURN IT LOOSE is a film about this competition. Through the eyes of six competitors we leave behind any preconceived notions of what breakdance used to represent, and as the film digs deeper into their lives, we discover an extraordinary form of non-contact combat that has evolved over 30 years to become a truly 21st century global phenomenon, stretching the limits of physical capability and pushing dance itself to astonishing new heights. From very different corners of the planet, the six characters that lead us through the competition all have their own stories to tell. From the professional to the rookie, we travel from Senegal to Japan, and discover a generation united in a physical language that crosses cultures. Drawn together by a dream to be the best, what quickly becomes clear is that these b-boys are a unique breed of athletes exceptionally skilled in a craft with no formal training that combines martial arts, gymnastics and dance. For this is still a street culture, born out of poverty and hardship and as we begin to understand the drive and determination that has pushed our characters to the very top of their game, we become absorbed and involved in their journey through the competition.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?621239</url></doc>
