<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="621844">
  <docid>621844</docid>
  <title>Twenty One</title>
  <year>2000</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
    <genre>Game-Show</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>non-fiction</keyword>
    <keyword>isolation-booth</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Canada">E</certificate>
    <certificate country="USA">TV-G</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">9 January 2000</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>McKinnon, Bob (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Loto, Jennifer</producer>
    <producer>Silver, Phil (I)</producer>
    <producer>Gurin, Philip</producer>
    <producer>Silverman, Fred (I)</producer>
    <producer>Winnik, Javier</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Deutsch, Ruth</writer>
    <writer>Solomon, Aaron (I)</writer>
    <writer>Tschorn, Adam</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Pietsch, Scooter</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cramer, John (I)</actor>
      <role>Announcer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Povich, Maury</actor>
      <role>Host</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The 2000 remake of "Twenty-One" was an attempt to re-create the success of the game show that precipitated the infamous quiz show scandal. The rules of the remake were similar to the classic version, with several new rules. As before, two contestants, one a returning champion, were placed in separate isolation booths, and could hear nothing except when host Pauvich spoke directly to them. A category was announced, with the multiple-questions rated in difficulty from 1 to 11 points (1 being easiest, 11 being the most difficult). Each contestant alternated in answering the questions, choosing how many points they wanted to play for. Correct answers were worth the value of the question; incorrect answers were worth a strike. A new rule allowed a contestant to use a "Second Chance," meaning they could enlist the aid of a friend or relative to help answer a question; however, an incorrect answer earned the contestant two strikes. After two rounds, the game is stopped and either contestant may choose to end the game if they believe they have enough points to win. The game ended and a champion crowned in one of three ways: 1, Reaching 21 before his/her opponent (however, if both contestants reached 21, a sudden-death question was asked); 2, By having more points than the opponent if either player wants to stop the game; or 3. If one contestant earns three strikes, his/her opponent automatically wins. First-time winners won $25,000, a second win earned the player an additional $50,000, the third $100,000 and so on up to the seventh win, which rewarded the lucky contestant with $1 million. The champion, who kept his frontgame winnings, played a newly-added bonus round called "Perfect 21," which consisted of six true-false questions, worth (in order) 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 and 6 points. Each point is worth $10,000, with a maximum payout of $210,000 possible. A contestant could stop at any time and keep what he/she had accumulated in the bonus round; however, an incorrect answer at any time stopped the game and lost all bonus round winnings. Contestants continued until they were defeated.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?621844</url></doc>
