<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="622563">
  <docid>622563</docid>
  <title>Two Impossible Films</title>
  <year>1995</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">28</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Lewis, Mark (IV)</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bird, Alastair</actor>
      <role>Second Chessplayer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cum, Paul</actor>
      <role>First Chessplayer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jocelyn, Michael</actor>
      <role>Phillip Sturgess</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Moojabber, Lucy</actor>
      <role>Ann</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pan, David</actor>
      <role>First Bricklayer</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Two Impossible Films is an art gallery "conceptual" film, consisting in two feature films but whose opening &amp; closing credits only are actually shown. The first film is an adaptation of Marx's "The Capital" such as Eisenstein was planning to do it until he got the interdiction by Stalin. It starts a bit like "Zabriskie Point" (by Michaelangelo Antonioni), in a college classroom with a debate held between students. The second film, humbly called "A History of Psychoanalysis" is meant to talk about the missed encounter, in 1932, between Sigmund Freund and Samuel Goldwyn, who was planning to ask the Austrian physician to write a film about psychoanalysis. For both films, opening credits are displayed while the film starts (35 mm film, with a cast &amp; extras &amp; shootings on location), but once the name of the director has been displayed, the screen turns black and for a few seconds, white lines read "story development", "emotional apex", "plot resolution" until full end credits (with mostly imaginary names I guess) start to roll down for over 5 minutes, with all the legal mentions, logos and thanks at the end. By creating a frustration over two legendary projects that were never put to completion, Mark Lewis first pretends to watch cinema as an art form tightly tied to our recent history. An art form also subject to reinterpretations according to the links it has precisely developed with the philosophical pillars of our society (psychoanalysis, politics). The result is a strange, ironic, beautiful (even plastically speaking) experience for movie lovers who will understand the meaning of this high profile hoax, started in 1995 and that Lewis has kept on working on, titling the whole project "cinema in parts"</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?622563</url></doc>
