<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="622853">
  <docid>622853</docid>
  <title>Two Tigers</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>number-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Singapore">M18</certificate>
    <certificate country="USA">R</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Italy">14 February 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Cecca, Sandro</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Pelone, Sergio</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Biglione, Luca</writer>
    <writer>Caico, Giovanna</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khoo, Selena</actor>
      <role>Lin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Natelle, Jay</actor>
      <role>Colin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pagès, Olivier</actor>
      <role>Michel</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Patresi, Matt</actor>
      <role>Detective McWilliam</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This action story takes place in Shanghai, China where Gilda, a stunning blonde 'femme Nikita' is commissioned to take out an important Lebanese official. As a professional killer, her real identity is kept secret. Her boss has arranged a new name and profession for her in Shanghai as the new manager of an information technology company. She takes up residence in a beautiful condo where she gets to know her neighbor, Lin, a beautiful Chinese girl who turns out to be a high-class call girl. Their friendship develops as they help one another along the way as they are betrayed by their hearts for men who turn out to be scoundrels. The drama propels into a highly emotional and sensitive story about two women who are independent and ferocious in guarding affairs of their heart, even though their individual jobs lead many to believe that they are only cold-blooded and materialistic. Experts in martial arts and in art of lovemaking, both women's lives are woven together in a fatal collision in the fight for true love in the face of betrayal. The two tigers must surmount their individual mountains in the key to finding true happiness.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?622853</url></doc>
