<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="625337">
  <docid>625337</docid>
  <title>Ultraviolent</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Redic, Rashad</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Animation</genre>
  </genres>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">20 March 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Redic, Rashad</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Domina, Mario</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Redic, Rashad</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>This exciting science fiction animation and action-adventure story is based on one man's journey of personal redemption. The year is 2032. Remarkable advances in science have conquered all diseases. Everything is good in the world, but a perfectly preserved human body found in space is a harbinger of things to come. 32 years later - the world is gripped in the throes of a spiritual disease known as ULTRAVIOLENT. ULTRAVIOLENT becomes a physical manifestation of unpredictable violence by rotting a victim's soul and spreading through moments of mental weakness. It spreads with frightening rapidity but the scientific community is unable to stop it. Simeon Rockwell is a loner who hunts down people infected with ULTRAVIOLENT. When he meets the mysterious and sultry jazz singer Satia Niall, he is drawn into a conflict between religion and science. As the story unfolds, relationships become complicated, and even Simeon's friends are drawn into the danger of a simmering war between armies of the Church and a brutal paramilitary force known as Rhinoceros. While attempting to research a cure, Dr. Ram Code triggers a monstrous mutation in the disease, causing it to become even more deadly and contagious than before. Simeon holds the key to stopping the disease, if only he can deal with his own personal demons. As the Church makes a dangerous power play to steal important scientific data for devious means, time is running out as Simeon attempts to confront the source of the disease while surrounded by a fever pitched battle for life and death itself</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?625337</url></doc>
