<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="625712">
  <docid>625712</docid>
  <title>Umar</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Verma, Sanjay (I)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Musical</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="UK">12A</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">17 March 2006</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="UK">17 March 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">135</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Razdan, Karan</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Gupta, P.D.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Razdan, Karan</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Tandon, Shamir</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chopra, Prem</actor>
      <role>Chandrakant 'Chander' Mehta</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Clark, Emily (I)</actor>
      <role>Victoria</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Shakti (I)</actor>
      <role>Prem Lakha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kaushik, Satish</actor>
      <role>Rajpal Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kempton, Rez</actor>
      <role>Girish</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Kader (I)</actor>
      <role>Iqbal Khan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kher, Anupam</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shergill, Jimmy</actor>
      <role>Shashank Dutt</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tahil, Dalip</actor>
      <role>Banwari 'Ben' Chibber</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Beautiful Sapna Lakha lives a very wealthy lifestyle with her businessman dad, Prem, and housewife mom in the United Kingdom. One day while eating out at a restaurant, she falls in love with a singer-cum-waiter, Shashank Dutt, who is also attracted to her. She introduces him to her dad, who disapproves of him, and would like Sapna to get married to Vikram 'Vick', the son of a local politician, Banwari Chibber. Prem, however, agrees to let Sapna marry Shashank after his assurances that he will do his best to make her comfortable, backed by three elderly men, Chandrakant Mehta - who is abused by his son and daughter-in-law; Rajpal Singh who is treated as a servant and babysitter by his son and daughter-in-law; and Iqbal Khan, who is discriminated against by London's Social Security merely because he is a Muslim. Shortly thereafter the owner, Victoria, of the restaurant where Shashank is employed is brutally murdered, and the police find evidence linking Shashank to her death, as a result he is arrested and held in a cell, then subsequently brought before the Court, where it is revealed that he was having an affair with Victoria, his fingerprints are found on the murder weapon, a knife, and he is ordered to be placed in Police custody pending his trial. If convicted, Shashank may well spend the rest of his life in jail and incur the hate of Sapna. The question remains: why did Shashank kill Victoria?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?625712</url></doc>
