<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="625740">
  <docid>625740</docid>
  <title>Umbrage</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>one-word-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">18 December 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Cullingham, Drew</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Duru, Spencer</producer>
    <producer>Halberstam, Yoram</producer>
    <producer>Wallinger, Francis</producer>
    <producer>Cullingham, Drew</producer>
    <producer>Phillips, Simon (IV)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Cullingham, Drew</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bradley, Doug (I)</actor>
      <role>Jacob</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Celino, Natalie</actor>
      <role>Lilith</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Croot, Jason</actor>
      <role>Adam</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fisher, James (IV)</actor>
      <role>Stanley</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Halberstam, Yoram</actor>
      <role>Adam</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hurn, Jonnie</actor>
      <role>Phelan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Thomas, Scott (XVI)</actor>
      <role>Travis</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>In the Old West, the assassination of an ageing cowboy is thwarted by a sultry vampiress, the would-be killer left for dead in the dust.  A hundred years later an ancient obsidian mirror, long unearthed from the Mesopotamian desert, is liberated from an American collector's vault and illegally transported to Europe. Jacob, an unscrupulous antiques dealer, moves to a remote farmhouse with his pregnant young wife, Lauren, and his difficult ward, Rachel. His goals are clear: to pass this near-priceless mirror to the highest bidder, and to prevent these two women from ripping each other apart. Nearby, a beautiful ornithologist, in nocturnal pursuit of the Screech Owl, is disturbed in her hide by a couple of noisy hikers. Her efforts ruined, she joins them by their campfire, but when one of them is mysteriously mutilated in the woods, she and the other are forced to flee and seek refuge at Jacob's farm. Something has been unleashed into the dark of that night.... Shadows take on a life of their own, and the blood begins to flow. Maybe it's all down to the ominous cowboy hiding in the barn who doesn't seem to cast any reflection in the dark mirror. Maybe it's because the shiny black artifact is the enchanted talisman and portal of Lilith, the willful first wife of Adam, exiled from Eden to spawn her demonic offspring. The family find themselves in the middle of a century old grudge between a vengeful undead cowboy and the re-awakened Lilith, mother to the Succubi, ruler of shadows, slaughterer of children, and consort to the devil himself. Sometimes the only weapon against evil is evil itself.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?625740</url></doc>
