<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="627464">
  <docid>627464</docid>
  <title>Un pogrom en Buenos Aires</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Almirón, Alejandra</editor>
  </editors>
  <languages>
    <language>Yiddish</language>
    <language>Spanish</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Argentina</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Argentina">Atp</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Argentina">6 December 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">75</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Szwarcbart, Herman</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Kameniecki, Gabriel</producer>
    <producer>Kameniecki, Gabriel</producer>
    <producer>Szwarcbart, Herman</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Szwarcbart, Herman</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Telechanski, Martin</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Pogrom means persecution, "hunting" of Jews. In the beginning of the last century, a lot of Jews arrived in Argentina, running away from the attacks they suffered in Europe. In 1919, during a workers conflict known as The Tragic Week, a pogrom was held in Buenos Aires, in the Once neighbourhood. Of that event, it's been said that "it was done by some well-to-do boys who went out to hunt the kikes". The film starts with the questions that the director himself, whose grandfather arrived in Buenos Aires in early Twentieth Century, asks himself about that event and its implications. And about the causes and consequences of its scarce spreading, about the distorted facts on the number of people who died and about the internal ideological disputes inside the Jewish Community. The director finds a few stories, allusions in a song, or in a film. But he knows, that in view of the little which is known and remembered, one has to listen, reconstruct, ask, even fictionalize. And thus bring together a film-research that one follows as a tale of painful, controversial and unfair mysteries.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?627464</url></doc>
