<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="629672">
  <docid>629672</docid>
  <title>Undercover Distress</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>blown-cover</keyword>
    <keyword>naked-woman</keyword>
    <keyword>undercover-cop</keyword>
    <keyword>exotic-dancer</keyword>
    <keyword>native-american</keyword>
    <keyword>vignette</keyword>
    <keyword>softcore</keyword>
    <keyword>bondage</keyword>
    <keyword>evil-clown</keyword>
    <keyword>police-detective</keyword>
    <keyword>policewoman</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">26 May 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Blair, Goldie</actor>
      <role>Undercover Police Officer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Leigh, Shannan</actor>
      <role>Policewoman</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Policewomen discover the occupational perils of their profession in separate story lines. In the first a buxom brunette policewoman sneaks into the bad guy's hideout seeking evidence to crack an important case. Her efforts go for naught when the villain grabs her before she can escape, then gags her and ties her to a chair. After each escape attempt, the plucky policewoman's bondage becomes tighter and more intricate until finally the crook exits the building leaving the heroine bound, gagged and exposed, in order for her to be humiliated when discovered by her colleagues. In the second story, two undercover cops dress as Indian maiden and an exotic dancer to infiltrate the bad guy's hideout. Before they can find the needed evidence the detectives are captured, stripped and left bound and gagged to struggle helplessly while their quarry escapes. In the final vignette a bosomy blonde is nabbed by a sinister clown, hogtied, bandanna gagged and left to ineffectually struggle against her bonds.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?629672</url></doc>
