<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="629814">
  <docid>629814</docid>
  <title>Undertrial</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Makrani, Ashfaq</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>prison</keyword>
    <keyword>rape-accusation</keyword>
    <keyword>trial</keyword>
    <keyword>child-rape</keyword>
    <keyword>false-accusation</keyword>
    <keyword>prisoner</keyword>
    <keyword>forced-prostitution</keyword>
    <keyword>incest</keyword>
    <keyword>wrongful-imprisonment</keyword>
    <keyword>court</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">A</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">9 February 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Khan, Aziz (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Rizvi, Nazim Hassan</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Amrohi, Khaleeq</writer>
    <writer>Arjun, Aadesh K.</writer>
    <writer>Rizvi, Nazim Hassan</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Malik, Anu</composer>
    <composer>Tandon, Shamir</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Castelino, Monica</actor>
      <role>Sameena S. Hussain</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chopra, Prem</actor>
      <role>Public Prosecutor Anand Verma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kazmi, Pratima</actor>
      <role>Justice Jaya Reddy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Kader (I)</actor>
      <role>Advocate Ravi Vishnoi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Puri, Rajesh</actor>
      <role>Advoate Apte</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rege, Sunil</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tiwari, Mukesh</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Yadav, Rajpal</actor>
      <role>Sagar Hussain</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Sagar Hussain lives a poor lifestyle in India. He relocates to Mumbai in order to better his prospects and finds work at a factory that only hires male employees. On his first day at work he observes all the workers leave their respective workplaces, go to an adjoining room to spy throw on a hole on a woman next door who is taking a bath. The next day he approaches the woman, Sabina, tells her of the intrusion to her privacy, but she mocks him. She does cover the hole, and then subsequently both Sagar and she fall in love and get married. Soon they become parents of three girls. Several years later Sameena approaches a Social Worker, Ambare, and tells him that Sagar has been sexually molesting her daughters for the last eight years. Appalled at this, Ambare informs the Police, Sagar is arrested, held in Central Jail as an Undertrial, and is to be produced before Justice Jaya Reddy, a Judge who has been known to sentence a man to jail for six months for merely throwing a peanut on a woman. Sagar hires a lawyer, Ravi Vishnoi, and his Assistant, Apte, and enters a plea of not guilty even though he has been found guilty not only by the Public Prosecutor, the Police, his neighbors, the media as well as his fellow inmates. What are Sagar's chances of a fair trial - especially when his very own wife and daughters will be coming forward to testify against him, and his fellow inmates, who have already contracted someone in the 'safe yard' to kill him.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?629814</url></doc>
