<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="630676">
  <docid>630676</docid>
  <title>Unfinished Spaces</title>
  <year>2010</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Minnick, Alex</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>arts</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>architecture</keyword>
    <keyword>cuba</keyword>
    <keyword>cuban-revolution</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Spanish</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">85</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Nahmias, Alysa</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Garatti, Vittorio (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gottardi, Roberto</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Porro, Ricardo</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Unfinished Spaces tells the turbulent story of the Cuban Revolution through its most significant architectural achievement - the Cuban National Art Schools - and the architects Ricardo Porro, Vittorio Garatti, and Roberto Gottardi, who designed them. Their story acts as a touchstone to explore Cuba's past, present, and future, also inviting discussions about art and politics. In 1961, these three young, visionary architects were commissioned by Fidel Castro and Che Guevara to create "the world's most beautiful art school" on the grounds of a former golf course in Havana, Cuba. Construction of their radical designs began immediately and the school's first classes soon followed; but as the euphoria of the Revolution faded, Castro abruptly halted the construction and the architects and their designs were deemed counter-revolutionary. Fifty years later the schools are in use, but remain unfinished and decaying. Castro, in an unprecedented change-of-mind, has invited the exiled architects back to finish their unrealized dream. The architects, like Cuba's aging leaders, are "not the same boys" they once were. At 80 years old they re-consider the relevance of Utopian ideals for a 21st century Cuba.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?630676</url></doc>
