<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="630657">
  <docid>630657</docid>
  <title>Unfiltered</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kubera, Paul</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>world-champion</keyword>
    <keyword>swimming</keyword>
    <keyword>olympics</keyword>
    <keyword>one-word-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">21 October 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">120</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Edelman, Brian</director>
    <director>Keegan, Sean (III)</director>
    <director>Korver, Luke</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Keegan, Sean (III)</producer>
    <producer>Korver, Luke</producer>
    <producer>Carlisle, Peter</producer>
    <producer>Edelman, Brian</producer>
    <producer>Foley, Sean (VIII)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Keegan, Sean (III)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bowman, Bob (III)</actor>
      <role>Bob Bowman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Crocker, Ian (I)</actor>
      <role>Ian Crocker</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Phelps, Michael</actor>
      <role>Michael Phelps</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Reese, Eddie</actor>
      <role>Eddie Reese</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>"Unfiltered" is an unprecedented look into the lives and competitive rivalry of two of America's greatest swimmers: Michael Phelps and Ian Crocker. Phelps, 20, is already considered the best swimmer of all time and has been virtually uncontested in all of his races; expect one. In 2003 Ian Crocker stormed the swimming world and took home the world title and World Record in the 100 Butterfly beating Michael Phelps in the process. After Ian lowered his World Record at the Olympic Trials, Michael took the one that counts - Olympic Gold in Athens in 2004. While growing up in Baltimore, Michael had one stable home: the swimming pool. After 8 Gold medals in Athens, Michael is acclimating to his new life as a worldwide celebrity as he balances a demanding schedule both in and out of the water. From commercials and photo shoots to award shows and celebrity appearances, Michael is embracing his new life as the world's most recognized swimmer, all while continuing to train every day. Despite it all, when he heads back to his new home in Ann Arbor he still is just another freshman at the University of Michigan. For Crocker, things couldn't be more different. Ian has settled back into his life in Austin, Texas. The mild-mannered and soft-spoken "Austinite" trains with little distraction except when he his playing his guitar or restoring his 1971 Buick Riviera. Distinctly different, yet revealingly similar in their desire to win, these two premiere competitors and friends gear up to meet again at this year's World Championships this summer in Montreal.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?630657</url></doc>
