<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="631070">
  <docid>631070</docid>
  <title>Universal Remote</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Brown, Matthew (XIII)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>marriage</keyword>
    <keyword>remote</keyword>
    <keyword>universal</keyword>
    <keyword>magical</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">20</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Mork, Sebastian</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>McDaniels, Kevin</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Christopherson, Stefanianna</actor>
      <role>Indira</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cronin-Shneidre, Riley</actor>
      <role>Teenage boy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Daniels, Gregory (III)</actor>
      <role>Norm</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lane, Briana</actor>
      <role>Teenage girl</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Liffey, Anya</actor>
      <role>Evelyn Ormstead</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Naggar, Alan</actor>
      <role>Ned Ormstead</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stellate, Nick</actor>
      <role>Derek</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Ned is just trying to please his wife, but she hates that. As far as she's concerned, there's nothing wrong with him that a complete transformation wouldn't fix. She tells him this. And tells him. And tells him. It's one of an infinite numbers of things she won't shut up about. At dinnertime the doorbell rings, and a strange repairman with pointy ears announces that he's there to pick up the couple's television remote. Which is strange; they haven't called a repairman. The man takes the device, and gives them a replacement unit which he says is a "universal" remote. After the man leaves, Ned tries the new remote. He presses a button and Evelyn pauses, her fork halfway to her mouth. Not only does she stop eating, but for the first time in a long marriage, she is quiet. Ned pushes Pause again, and Evelyn resumes her abusive heckling. After a little further experimentation, Ned puts Evelyn on pause for the night and goes upstairs to consider the possibilities. Next day, Ned is ready for some excitement in the form of his comely but desperate neighbor. She ignores him until until he turns the remote on her, at which point she takes him by the hand and into her bedroom. Everything Ned points the remote at makes a wish come true - but only his wishes, not anyone else's. After a life of being beaten down, is there any guarantee that he will know what to wish for?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?631070</url></doc>
