<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="631255">
  <docid>631255</docid>
  <title>Unlimited Nordic Skiing</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>McMahon, David (IV)</editor>
    <editor>McMahon, David (XI)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Sport</genre>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>nordic</keyword>
    <keyword>fitness</keyword>
    <keyword>cross-country</keyword>
    <keyword>skiing</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby Digital</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Canada">G</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">1 October 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">300</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>McMahon, David (IV)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>McMahon, David (IV)</producer>
    <producer>Meloche, Lise</producer>
    <producer>McMahon, David (XI)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Batstone, Dean</composer>
    <composer>Sum 41</composer>
    <composer>Voisine, Roch</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Meloche, Lise</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The movie "UNLIMITED" engages some of the best outdoor athletes in the New World, breath taking cinematography and an exhilarating sound track to craft "a New Kind of Action" constituted from "Clean Oxygen Fed Sport." Featuring music by Sum41, Roch Voisine, Dean Batstone and Drastik, and the talent of 57 Olympic and World-Class athletes in a variety of outdoor and adventure sports including Nordic skiing, trail running, triathlon, inline, mountain biking, rowing, telemark skiing, para-gliding, roller skiing, cycling, paddling, climbing and adventure racing. Elite athletes and aficionados together share their love and spiritual attachment to outdoor activity and the land. The producers have sought to define this sub-culture from behind the lens of a camera. Filmed across North America in Digital Video and 16mm, trekking where few have gone before. The central thread is bound around cross-country skiing and a lifestyle that transcends the seasons. Nordic skiing coaches, instructors and aficionados, from beginner to expert alike, will be thrilled with the instructional content provided on the second disk. Olympic skiers and coaches provide the most comprehensive contemporary guide to nordic ski technique (skating, classic, norpine), training and equipment. The Unlimited Technique DVD is delivered as part of the National Coaching Certification Programme Technical curriculum for Cross-Country Skiing and Biathlon.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?631255</url></doc>
