<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="631201">
  <docid>631201</docid>
  <title>Unknown Passage: The Dead Moon Story</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Fix, Kate</editor>
    <editor>Summers, Jason (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>musician</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>rockumentary</keyword>
    <keyword>singing</keyword>
    <keyword>diy</keyword>
    <keyword>band</keyword>
    <keyword>singer</keyword>
    <keyword>punk</keyword>
    <keyword>song</keyword>
    <keyword>punk-rock</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Norway">17 November 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Fix, Kate</director>
    <director>Summers, Jason (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Fix, Kate</producer>
    <producer>Summers, Jason (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cole, Fred (I)</actor>
      <role>Guitar, Vocals</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cole, Toody</actor>
      <role>Bass, Vocals</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Loomis, Andrew</actor>
      <role>Drums</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Undisputedly written into the annals of rock history and dedicated to the most sincere methods of the DIY ethos, Northwest musicians Dead Moon (Andrew Loomis and Fred &amp; Toody Cole) have intentionally cut out the bullshit, and left the major labels and "commercial success" behind. Unknown Passage: The Dead Mood Story follows the band on the road and at home, chronicling lifestyle rock and rollers who happen to also be small business owners and grandparents. Beginning with footage of a 14 year-old Deep Soul Cole ("the white Stevie Wonder"), Unknown Passage tells the history of one of the most reclusive bands through their various garage, psych, folk, and punk rock incarnations. Today, pressing their records at home, in a house they built from the ground up, Dead Moon run their own "frontier mini-mall," record label and music store, while in their spare time "keep one gig ahead of a day job" by touring through the US and Europe-with the occasional 15-hour penny-slots casino pitstop. Here stands the triumph of a family of "old-west homesteaders" against corporate control and gracelessly growing old. Unknown Passage: The Dead Moon Story is Fred, Toody &amp; Andrew's Dead Moon experience, a culmination of their 40-year life in music and love.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?631201</url></doc>
