<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="633125">
  <docid>633125</docid>
  <title>Uphaar</title>
  <year>1971</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Family</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Roy, Sudhendu</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Barjatya, Tarachand</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Kudalkar, Laxmikant Shantaram</composer>
    <composer>Sharma, Pyarelal Ramprasad</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Aarti</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arora, Lata</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bhaduri, Jaya</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chaturvedi, Shail</actor>
      <role>Shankarlal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chatwal, Suresh</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dutt, Swarup</actor>
      <role>Anoop</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kaushal, Kamini</actor>
      <role>Anoop's mom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mehtab, Minoo</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mishra, Leela</actor>
      <role>Kaki</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Palsikar, Nana</actor>
      <role>Ramchandra Awasthi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Parvez, Yunus</actor>
      <role>Banwari</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Anoop studies law in Calcutta, while his widowed mom in a small town in West Bengal. He has a sister, Sudha, who is married to Anil and lives in Calcutta. Since Anoop is of marriageable age, his mom has seen a girl for him, whose name is Vidya, and is the daughter of Shankarlal. When Anoop returns home, she asks him for his approval, but he says he wants to see the girl first. He goes to see Vidya, and also gets to meet another belle by the name of Minoo. He returns home, tells his mom that he cannot marry Vidya, but will marry only Minoo. His mother reluctantly agrees and the marriage takes place. It is then that they find out that Minoo has no household skills, neither is she educated, nor mature enough to understand her relationship with Anoop. Her only interests appear to be stealing mangoes and other fruit, and playing with children much younger than her. Anoop's mom is quite exasperate with her and is compelled to keep her under lock and key. When the time comes for Anoop to return to Calcutta, he asks Minoo to come with him, but she refuses. His mother cannot handle her childishness and refuses to let her stay with her. Anoop accordingly leaves her with her mom, Sharda Awasthi. The question remains will Minoo returns to her childish ways, and forget having married Anoop?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?633125</url></doc>
