<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="633889">
  <docid>633889</docid>
  <title>Usne Kaha Tha</title>
  <year>1960</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Bhattacharjee, Moni</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Roy, Bimal (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Choudhury, Salil</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Baby Farida</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bose, Tarun</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Devi, Sarita</actor>
      <role>Kamli's mom</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dutt, Sunil</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khan, Rashid (I)</actor>
      <role>Khairathi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Khote, Durga</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mishra, Leela</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nath, Rajendra</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sen, Asit (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Nandu lives in a small town with his widowed mom, Paro. He is friendly with two young girls, Farida and Kamli. He is depressed when Kamli's dad becomes ill and she and her mom re-locate to Ambala. Years later, Farida and Nandu have grown up and continue to be friends. Then they get the news that Kamli's dad has passed away, and they are to return back. Initially they do not recognize each other, but when they do, both fall in love and want to marry. When Paro goes to meet with Kamli's maternal uncle, she is shunned, humiliated because they are poor and Nandu is unemployed, &amp; considered a trouble-maker. When Nandu is told the bitter truth, he leaves the town, joins the army, with the hope that her uncle will consider him suitable enough to get Kamli married to him. After training, he gets 21 days leave and returns home triumphantly - only to find that Kamli has been married. Dejected, he returns back to the army to try and forget Kamli - only to find that his superior officer, Hav. Ram Singh is Kamli's husband. Now Nandu has to decide whether to quit the army and re-locate elsewhere in order to forget Kamli.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?633889</url></doc>
