<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="634019">
  <docid>634019</docid>
  <title>Ute Indian Snake Dance</title>
  <year>1903</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">February 1903</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
<plot>Never before have the Utes permitted a photographer around their teepees when they gave their snake dance. This weird rite is performed every fall after the harvest has been good and its meaning is a tribute to the snakes who are supposed to bring plenty of rain next season. To omit paying homage to the reptiles is to invite a season of shortage of water and crop failures and famine for the Utes. Our photographer in Colorado has known Quin-Chuck-A-Chaw, Sub-Chief of the Southern Utes, for many years. Buckskin Charlie, the main chief, never permitted the photographing of any of the Ute dances so when "Quin" was alone with the dancers at the last dance he gave permission for just two minutes of picture work. The camera was placed where the entire dance could be seen. The light was perfect and the film is one of the clearest and brightest ever made anywhere. It is a most wonderful specimen of photography aside from its interesting subject. When the dance opened the Indians had their snakes in their hands, waving them aloft and turning them with certain dexterity that always enabled them to dodge the fangs of the enraged reptiles. After dancing around once or twice the chief put his snake in his mouth. Just as the slimy head darted to sink the fangs into cheek the Indian reached up and grabbed the snake behind the head and avoided danger. Some of the Indians dropped their reptiles on the ground and teased them with feathers to get them to strike. Others twisted them up in the air and in other ways tried to annoy the reptiles. Every movement of snakes and Indians can plainly be seen and all the horrible details of the dance are shown in full and wonderful precision. From an ethnological standpoint alone the film is one that will pass into scientific circles immediately and last there for many years. As long as researches are made into Indian lore and customs, this film will stand as an authority on its subject. Its accuracy can never be questioned. To-day it forms a great addition to a motion picture show that will create more comment than any other of its class ever made.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?634019</url></doc>
