<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="635480">
  <docid>635480</docid>
  <title>Vallamai Thaaraayo</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Venkataramanan, Vijay</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Tamil</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="India">U</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">28 June 2008</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">April 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="India">126</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Sundararaman, Madhumita</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Raman, Sundar</producer>
    <producer>Srinivasan (VIII)</producer>
    <producer>Sundar Raman, Nalini</producer>
    <producer>Sundar Raman, Trisakti</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Sundararaman, Madhumita</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Bharadwaj (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Parthiban</actor>
      <role>Anand</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shrikanth</actor>
      <role>Sekar</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Vallamai Thaaraayo is a sensitive portrayal of a woman torn between a relationship, her own feelings and her desires. The movie deals with the story of a rebellious young woman who wishes to divorce her husband just because he is a good man. Are relationships really made in heaven? Do we have to compromise in our married life just to please the society? Is it always important to be politically correct? Vallamai Thaaraayo deals with the change that takes place in a married woman's psyche. Nandita and Anand are newly wed. But even after marriage, Nandita is unable to forget her lover Sekar and longs to go back to him. As a consequence, she feels distanced from her husband. The film explores the perspective that life doesn't need to be accepted as it is. That it is alright to question society, to be politically incorrect, to be selfish, to make mistakes and regret them. But the process of personal fulfillment must not stop at regret and acceptance of the status quo. It is also important to be proactive, and make a change for the better.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?635480</url></doc>
