<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="637023">
  <docid>637023</docid>
  <title>Veerabhadra</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Raju, Gautham</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>physically-handicapped</keyword>
    <keyword>brother-sister-relationship</keyword>
    <keyword>assassination</keyword>
    <keyword>bad-parents</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Telugu</language>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">29 April 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Chowdary, A.S. Ravi Kumar</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Krishna, Ambika</producer>
    <producer>Ramanjaneyulu, Ambika</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Pushpanand, A.</writer>
    <writer>Raja, Marudhuri</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Sharma, Mani</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ajay (IX)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Balakrishna (I)</actor>
      <role>Shamsher Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brahmanandam</actor>
      <role>Hero friend</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dev, Rajan P.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dutta, Tanushree</actor>
      <role>Malti</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Raj, Prakash</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shinde, Sayaji</actor>
      <role>Panduranga</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Shamsher Singh is smuggler for many years, has a good heart, is known to the police, and lives with his grandmother, an alcoholic father; a photographer brother and his wife; and a sister. The family, expect for his grandmother, is generally cruel and abusive towards him even though he runs the household. One day his brother brings a photograph of a lovely girl and Shamsher is told that she is the girl he is going to get married to. Shamsher meets her, finds out her name is Malti, and eventually both fall in love with each other. It is then that Malti's brother, Panduranga, a dreaded and influential gangster, who the local police on his pay-roll, opposes this alliance. Things spiral out of control for Shamsher as his family disowns him. He is then taken in by a wealthy Thakur, who claims that Shamsher is his illegitimate son, and lives with a wheel-chair bound daughter, Manisha, who was a daughter, but became crippled after being assaulted by Panduranga. An altercation ensues between Panduranga and Shamsher, the police step in to prevent Shamsher from getting to Panduranga, fisticuffs break out, and a senior police officer is gravely injured and believed to be dead, with the police being ordered to bring in Shamsher dead or alive. Shamsher will now find out that he has no one to call his own, as Manisha disowns him; his original family, including his grandmother, will have nothing to do with him; and Malti, his one true love, believes he is having an affair with Chandramukhi, and will not only have nothing to do with him, but is also getting married to a man who has been chosen for her by Panduranga.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?637023</url></doc>
