<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="639110">
  <docid>639110</docid>
  <title>Via Vanoudenhoven</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>meeting</keyword>
    <keyword>celebrity</keyword>
    <keyword>idol</keyword>
    <keyword>traveling</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Dutch</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Belgium</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Belgium">KT</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Belgium">24 February 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">55</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Van Looy, Erik</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cambré, Marc</actor>
      <role>Several (2002)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vanoudenhoven, Rob</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>There were these two Belgian comedians, who are supposedly semi-well known in Belgiumk, who wanted to meet JC Van Damme. They started by training at Van Damme's former school in Belgium under his sensei, Claude Goetz. It was pretty funny, 'cause these guys are the most non-athletic people you've ever seen! It was a very beautiful gym; (JC still trains there regularly when he's in Belgium). They then went to Knokke, where JC used to live, and met his parents, who seemed very nice. His parents called JC and he talked to them for a while. One of the comedians (Herr Seele), who's an artist, made a painting of JC's parents. Next, they went to LA to meet JC. JC arrived at the hotel and was very friendly, as always. They talked about all kinds of stuff like spirituality, movies, martial arts and his parents'. JC also impersonated Sly Stallone, which was really funny! Seele showed JC the painting and painted JC in it .JC then signed it. He said he could see the painter had lots of respect for his parents and it showed in the painting. He seemed pretty moved someone would make a painting and come all the way from Belgium to show him. They goofed around a bit, JC threw some cool kicks and then he said goodbye to them (he said he really loves Belgium and that people from Belgium should be proud of him). The two guys were very impressed with JC's combination of physical strength and intelligence's well as spirituality. JC seemed to have a great time and treated them like friends. It was a great show!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?639110</url></doc>
