<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="639434">
  <docid>639434</docid>
  <title>Vicious Circle</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
    <genre>Crime</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>betrayal</keyword>
    <keyword>nightclub</keyword>
    <keyword>gangster</keyword>
    <keyword>doomed-romance</keyword>
    <keyword>loyalty</keyword>
    <keyword>hi-def</keyword>
    <keyword>manipulation</keyword>
    <keyword>carole</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">95</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Guest, David T.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Guest, David T.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Guest, David T.</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cameron, Luke (I)</actor>
      <role>Easy</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Set in the grim underworld of Manchester, the nightclub Dante's stands independent of the malicious influence of crime boss Mr Clarke. Its owners Billy Bickers and Michael 'Mack' Gaines, minor crooks themselves have struggled long and hard to keep the club under their control. Mack, released from prison after four years, comes back to the club to find things subtly different. On the surface Dante's is prosperous and popular, Mr Clarke is keeping his distance and Billy rules with an iron fist. Yet underneath the glitzy veneer lurk dangerous power games. Mack's closest friend Easy has apparently stolen 100,000 pounds from Billy and Billy sends Mack to retrieve the money. Easy refuses to confirm or deny that he took the money and in a fit of rage Mack kills him. Wracked by guilt Mack convinces himself that Easy didn't take the money and seeks to find out what happened to the money and why Billy is so nonchalant about the matter once Easy has died. Then Billy is found dead, murdered in cold blood. The circle of suspects includes Billy's girlfriend Carole; head bouncer Slim, father figure to both Mack and Billy; the flashy new DJ Jez and the conscience stricken Mack. Locked in the nightclub after hours, with enemies circling, and a briefcase containing 200,000 pounds Mack has till morning to discover who killed Billy and to learn an inescapable truth, what goes around, comes around.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?639434</url></doc>
