<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="639901">
  <docid>639901</docid>
  <title>Video X: The Dwayne and Darla-Jean Story</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Connelly, Kevin (I)</editor>
    <editor>Gregoline, Jim</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Thriller</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>video-x</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1 March 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">150</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Mortellaro, James D.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Benjamin, J. Kevin</producer>
    <producer>Longmuir, Steve</producer>
    <producer>Mortellaro, James D.</producer>
    <producer>Schonfeld, Stuart</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Longmuir, Steve</writer>
    <writer>Mortellaro, James D.</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gibson, Joey</actor>
      <role>Dwayne Foote</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kyle, Jack</actor>
      <role>Billy Epp</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>VIDEO X: THE DWAYNE AND DARLA-JEAN STORY, this shocking video presents the actual home video footage shot by Kentucky killers Dwayne Foote and Darla-Jean Stanton as they embark on a deadly rampage. Watch in awe as the heartless lovers stumble into a situation that triggers one of the most violent crime sprees America has ever seen. Recently discovered by the authorities, this footage is haunting in its immediacy. Also included in the double disc set is, MURDER IN THE HEARTLAND: THE SEARCH FOR VIDEO X, 17 robberies; 11 murders; 6 states; 2 lovers; 1 camera; A film crew sets out to find answers to the worst crime spree in years, and uncovers a secret they never dreamed - the criminals, Dwayne Foote and Darla-Jean Stanton, actually videotaped their robberies and brutal murders. Now the search begins to find this unimaginable tape called "VIDEO X". But where is the tape? Who is hiding it and why? Despite arrests and risks to their lives, the film crew travels through the Deep South to interview family, friends and corrupt police officials to find out why "VIDEO X" is missing and why authorities are lying about it. Only one question remains, as the mystery unfolds, one bloody crime scene after another - what is "VIDEO X" and why must it be kept out of the public eye? Only the tape itself can answer that. ...bleak, startling and ultimately believable look at the dark side and comes highly recommended to those who have grown tired of the usual slasher fare and Hollywood moneymakers. ~Jonny Metro</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?639901</url></doc>
