<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="641074">
  <docid>641074</docid>
  <title>Viola fondente</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Freddi, Paola</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>food</keyword>
    <keyword>chocolate</keyword>
    <keyword>love</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Italian</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby SR</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="Italy">T</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Italy">20 April 2005</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">February 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Italy">13</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Simonelli, Fabio</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bellini, Chiara</producer>
    <producer>Scura, Francesco</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bellini, Chiara</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Vivaldi, Paolo</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cassola, Carla</actor>
      <role>Maria</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Giorgino, Ilaria</actor>
      <role>Viola</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hroz, Inna</actor>
      <role>Swedish girl</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lai, Vania</actor>
      <role>Check-out clerk</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Romano, Sergio (I)</actor>
      <role>Viola's husband</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Viola, an overweight 35-year-old beautiful woman, works in her husband's clothing boutique as sales assistant. Her everyday life is pivoted on a monotonous routine spent between her job and her household life. No one around her seems to ever notice her presence, or rather they only do so as regards her size: the sour colleague in the boutique where she works, her husband, even the supermarket cashier where she goes shopping every day who always comments malignantly on the enormous bulk of sweets she buys. She devotes herself to cooking them every night to forget life's futility. One day Viola is compelled to a turning point in her existence. When she gets back from the supermarket, she cannot enter her home because her husband has changed the lock of the door. He is fed up with her, with her multi-coloured bowls scattered around their apartment, and with their sheets dirty with chocolate. With her neighbour's help, she decides to leave everything behind and fill her life with something that has always been present in her daily life: food, candies, and chocolate especially. Chocolate will be the key to her new future: she opens a deli kiosk right in front of her husband's boutique. He will be obliged to change the name of the shop from "Fashion II" into "Fashion IV". Her newly-found freedom and self-reliance in her own beauty will be an ideal retribution with respect to those who had always made fun of her.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?641074</url></doc>
