<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="641390">
  <docid>641390</docid>
  <title>Virginal Young Blondes</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Feinsod, Mark L.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">16</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Feinsod, Mark L.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Beckett, Lee</producer>
    <producer>Feinsod, Mark L.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Feinsod, Mark L.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Wolff, Roland</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brinen, Joshua D.</actor>
      <role>John's Father/Bar Patron #2</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carney, Bradley</actor>
      <role>Bar Patron #3</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Clift, Valerie</actor>
      <role>The Bartender</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grinda, Marie-Line</actor>
      <role>Sofia's Voice</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hanks, Jennifer Vilas</actor>
      <role>The Chocolatier's Voice</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mallozzi, Luciana</actor>
      <role>New York State Unemployment Insurance Tel-Service Line/Bar Patron #1</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Waldschmidt, Andy</actor>
      <role>John O'Hara</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>During another New York City weekday as people rush about their business, unemployed twenty-something John O'Hara spends the afternoon alone in his apartment. The State-of-the-Union address plays on television, and newspapers litter the room. The New York State Unemployment Insurance phone line can be heard. John gets a letter from a potential employer, informing him that there are no job openings. He has a telephone conversation with his Father, who ambivalently offers to send him a check. Depressed, John decides to go out for a bit. Arriving at a bar / cafe, John reads his newspaper. He notices a beautiful blonde named Sofia and, at first, glances shyly at her. Each time he looks, Sofia is boldly staring back at him. Finally, she strikes up a conversation; indicating his newspaper, she asks about the stock market. John realizes that, because he's sitting around during the middle of the day instead of working, Sofia's mistaken him for a trust-fund brat and is trying to pick him up. He's shocked when she hands him her card, and informs him that she does private stripteases. She informs him that she doesn't do anything illegal, "but for a little extra, anything can be arranged." Stunned but intrigued, John doesn't bother to dispel Sofia's misconceptions about him. When she mentions that she can give him a nude full body-to-body massage with lotions and fruit, John, in a weird mood from being cooped up at home, peppers Sofia with questions about the fruit. Despite the oddness of the exchange, Sofia laughs and invites him to get stoned with her. John accepts and, paying for both of their drinks, realizes that he's almost at the end of his money. As John and Sofia pass "the most expensive chocolate shop in the world", both are captivated by the cakes in the windows. John, trying to be charming, offers to buy them each a sweet. Sofia tells him to pick something out for her, as she needs to check her messages. John goes in and selects two desserts. In a perfectly orchestrated routine bordering on the fetishistic, a Chocolatier takes the confections and prepares them for purchase, tape is secured to the bottom of each cake, they're placed in a box, and a ribbon is tied around it. John is stunned when the amount comes to $42.50. As his remaining cash dwindles further, he pays what he owes and returns outside. Sofia brusquely says that she has an appointment at eight and needs to be sober by then. By the water, Sofia and John smoke a joint. The drug causes Sofia to open up and she shares a traumatic incident with a shocked John. This time last year, she was living with her boyfriend, a drug dealer. They lived together for eight years, doing drugs and having sex. One day, two men came over and, after arguing with Sofia's boyfriend, killed him. They stabbed Sofia, and raped her repeatedly. John can't believe what he's hearing. Sofia tells him that she had no idea who the killers were, and that she pretended to be "the dumb girlfriend" when the cops questioned her at the hospital. Embarrassed, she tells John that everything's fine now. Sofia sits beside him and embraces him as John, uncomfortable at Sofia's closeness, looks around. Recomposing herself, Sofia tells him that she has to get ready for her "meeting". John is disappointed, and Sofia tells him to call her. After watching her leave, John spots the unopened box. He opens it and, in his drugged state, devours the cakes.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?641390</url></doc>
