<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="642779">
  <docid>642779</docid>
  <title>Voci fuori campo</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Corrieri, Filippo</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Italian</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Italy">5 October 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Italy">14</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Cigliano, Alessio</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Pezza, Ivan</producer>
    <producer>Ricciardi, Giulia (II)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Cigliano, Alessio</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Calò, Daniela</actor>
      <role>Paola</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cigliano, Patrizio</actor>
      <role>La portiera</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Duranti, Sabrina</actor>
      <role>La signora</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Genolini, Claudia</actor>
      <role>Giulia</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Majano, Paola</actor>
      <role>Rossana</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Scalera, Ciro</actor>
      <role>Lorenzo</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Lorenzo is a fifty-something family man stuck in an ordinary life, dividing his time between home and office. His small, tidy universe gravitates around the numerous female universes which encircle him and which prove to be more polarizing than his own. At home, his wife Rosana and his teenage daughter Giulia systematically put him down. The former with her one-sided view of marriage in which he is a worthless satellite; the other taking advantage of his shortcomings to challenge him even on everyday opinions. At work Lorenzo has no allies, only individuals, always women, ready to take advantage of his diligence and to attack him, finding in him an easy target on which to unload blame and responsibility. Lorenzo may be spineless but he's not stupid. He endures with perseverance: this is his life as he wanted it and arranged it. And when the center of gravity of his universe tends to go askew, disrupted by the strong universes surrounding him, he gets into his car and goes for a drive to wind down, comforted by a soft voice which gently guides him along a familiar and reassuring route.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?642779</url></doc>
