<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="645969">
  <docid>645969</docid>
  <title>Waiting for Tomorrow</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Gomez, George (IV)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>urban</keyword>
    <keyword>homelessness</keyword>
    <keyword>gen-y</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Gomez, George (IV)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Davis, Terry (IX)</producer>
    <producer>Gomez, George (IV)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Gomez, George (IV)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Allen, Victoria</actor>
      <role>Ray's Girlfriend</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Alvarez, Ronnie</actor>
      <role>Hector</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Burnham, Jason</actor>
      <role>Rob</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Charroux, Carl</actor>
      <role>Officer Johnson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Coulter, Jay</actor>
      <role>Travis</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dorn, Aaron (II)</actor>
      <role>Bobby</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Eliot, Elisa</actor>
      <role>Tracy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Evans, Najashi</actor>
      <role>Bert</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Garcia, Gabriela (I)</actor>
      <role>Susana</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gomez, George (IV)</actor>
      <role>Pedro Joaquin</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harding, Lance</actor>
      <role>Norman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Huntsman, Dwight</actor>
      <role>Philip</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mathews III, James</actor>
      <role>Raymond Jackson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McDuffie, Janora</actor>
      <role>Naomi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rhodes, Ramjasha</actor>
      <role>Sammy</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rodriguez, Rick</actor>
      <role>Havoc</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Behind the glitz and glamor of Hollywood, lies an underworld of sex and drugs, where young people looking for money and fame easily fall victim to life on the streets of Los Angeles. Waiting For Tomorrow, takes a glimpse into this dark world as it follows a young couple living on the streets of Hollywood who are desperate for a way out. During what is to be the couple's last 24 hours in Los Angeles, we find seventeen-year-old Lori staying at a shelter for runaway teens while her twenty-one-year old boyfriend PJ wakes up on the shores of Venice beach. Once they meet for breakfast, PJ confirms with Lori his plan to sell marijuana to come up with the money for their trip north. But after departing to make the deal he instead chooses to visit old acquaintances from his days of street walking to deal with something more profitable - heroin. Meanwhile, Lori ties loose ends with her caretakers at the shelter. Afraid that they will stop her from leaving, she runs back and forth between the shelter and getting high with friends to avoid her exit interview. Friends turn to sexual predators and as a result, she's sexually assaulted. If that was not enough, her choice to ignore her caretakers is hampering her chances of ever return to the shelter. In the end, life's harsh reality is destined to catch up with both of them. Moral choices become the fault line in an endless day. But as time runs out, one can't help feel the necessity of Lori and PJ being together. It is the only thing that they can look forward to in contrast to dying on the streets. To Lori, PJ is proof that love exists. For PJ, Lori is purpose. It is something that he has never found. In his mind, purpose is the reason why they will always be together. By next morning, the couple has to face reality and decide whether being together is all that matters.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?645969</url></doc>
