<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="646797">
  <docid>646797</docid>
  <title>Wamkelekile</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Morcos, Daniel</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Xhosa</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>South Africa</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="South Africa">30 November 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="South Africa">24</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Vucic, Dorotea (I)</director>
    <director>Vucic, Dorotea (II)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Morcos, Daniel</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Morcos, Daniel</writer>
    <writer>Vucic, Dorotea (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cola, Sililami</actor>
      <role>Mandisi</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Holloway, Ashleigh</actor>
      <role>Receptionist</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mauritz, Allen</actor>
      <role>Herman</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mdidimba, Mzwakhe</actor>
      <role>Simpiwe Bala</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ngcingwana, Vuks</actor>
      <role>Lukhanyo Bala</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Lukhanyo (25) hasn't seen his strange father in many years. But today is different because he must travel back home in order to bring his father to the city, where someone else will take care of him. The little house on a farm where he grew up brings many memories, awakens questions of belonging, of times past and of the ever present sense of being out of place. But almost the first second spent with his father, Simpiwe (56), Lukhanyo is reminded of the reasons he left. Simpiwe is weird, eccentric, difficult, interested in only a few things: watching the Oprah Winfrey show, his midnight cooking and in that matter, coordinating food by its color. If either any of these interests fall out of place and time, Simpiwe turns into a stubborn child. Lukhanyo is determined to finish his task of bringing Simpiwe back to the city- and being on time for his job (which he knows he will loose if he is late again). But everything is against him - he looses his phone, his car gets stolen and his father is impossible to communicate with. Despite that, on the way to the city, in the beautiful wide landscapes of the Cape West Coast, Lukhanyo embarks on a strange journey of patience and tolerance. He learns to notice the humor in his situation as well as discovering that he has a very wise father. Most importantly, Lukhanyo is able, for the first time, to identify his father's special way of expressing his love for him. He accepts his father's gift of time and accepts his place in it. "Welcome back" is a simple, human and light hearted story about how a young man finds his place in time and his place in a fathers heart.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?646797</url></doc>
