<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="647168">
  <docid>647168</docid>
  <title>Waqt Ka Shahenshah</title>
  <year>1987</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Mohan, A.</editor>
    <editor>Satishkumar, C.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">1987</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Bapaiah, K.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Ahuja, Ajay Kumar</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Amburi, Ali Akbar</writer>
    <writer>Paruchuri, Gopalakrishna</writer>
    <writer>Paruchuri, Venkateswara Rao</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Khanna, Usha</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Annapoorna (I)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kanchana</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Krishna (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Prabhakar Reddy</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Raogopalrao</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Kanchan Mahalakshmi, known as Lakshmi (Sridevi) goes on cycle door to door and sells sarees on instalment basis. She has the responsibility of looking after her family as her father Raghunath is a drunkard, and her mother Savitri is a disabled woman. Lakshmi loves an educated youngman Manoj (Krishna). Manoj is respected and liked by his fellow farmers. He comes to their rescue whenever they are exploited and cheated by Bishambarnath, the owner of a sugar factory, in connection with the supply of sugar-cane. Bishambar decides to separate Lakshmi and Manoj by revealing that Manoj's mother Rajeshwari is in jail on charge of a murder. After having released from the jail, Rajeshwari straightly goes to attack Bishambar, but she is caught by the police and brought to the court. In the court, it is revealed that Lakshmi is the legal heir of the sugar mill and the only daughter of Shrikant, the real owner of the sugar mill whom Bishambar had killed to grab all his properties. It is also revealed that Lakshmi is the adopted daughter of Savitri.After hearing, the judge entrusts the court-commissioner to look after the property affair until further investigation by the C.B.I. in this regard.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?647168</url></doc>
