<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="647394">
  <docid>647394</docid>
  <title>War on Their Minds: Voices of American Kids</title>
  <year>2005</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Dwyer, Alicia</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">12 March 2005</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">26</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Glos, Jennifer W.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Glos, Jennifer W.</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Cutler, Miriam</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Meet the children of America: smart, funny, patriotic, passionate, scared. They wrestle with these unsettling times, trying to understand what is right and wrong, what is necessary, what they should believe in, and what they can do. We talk to sons and daughters of soldiers in Iraq, a high school political cheerleading team that protests war, children of activist parents, and cadets at a military boarding school. From ages 4 to 18, they are Caucasian, African-American, Latino, East Asian, East Indian - a portrait of the diversity of America. They speak out passionately on 9-11, the Iraq War, and their hopes and fears for their future. They demand answers: When is war justified? Does protest work? What is worth dying for? Is world peace possible? They express themselves through words, drawings, and play-acting. War in the 21st century will be determined by the children of today. At a time when we are debating the merits and justifications of war, this is a timely and important film, one that reflects on what we're teaching the next generation, and on what they have learned.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?647394</url></doc>
