<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="647587">
  <docid>647587</docid>
  <title>Warning Signs</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Engeran, Dave</editor>
    <editor>Torpy, Kathleen</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>News</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">20 January 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">22</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>DeWitt, Stacey</producer>
    <producer>Siedor, Collin</producer>
    <producer>Halevy, Emily</producer>
    <producer>Wilkenfeld, Adam</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Wilkenfeld, Adam</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>Each year in America more than half a million teenagers drop out of high school. One point five million run away from home. Two million are diagnosed with depression. And one million kids attempt suicide. Experts say, all of these behaviors that are red flags in high schools across America, that are so easy to spot because they are hitting us over the head, in reality, most of them started a long time ago. Robert J. Aloia is the Superintendent of Bergen County Technical Schools and Special Services. He says: "Had we done a better job of early intervention in pre-K, first grade, second grade, had we identified the warning signs back then, obviously I would be dealing with a lot less of it at the high school level." These true stories are profiled in the TV special, "Warning Signs." Bianca and Naomi Mendez are sisters, ages five and four respectively. Last year, at about the same time, they both started throwing temper tantrums much more often than before. It wasn't until a counselor in a unique program at the girls' school helped out, that the problems were finally understood and addressed. Kyle Copija was 16 when he tragically decided to take his own life. Were their warning signs? In retrospect, his mother says there were, but she missed them. Sixteen-year-old K.C. Holt has been picked on and teased ever since she was seven. She became sad, angry and depressed. But then a new program at her high school organized a support group of students to give her a hand, and this program has not cost the school a cent. Connect with Kids programs feature real kids, true stories, experts and educators; a way to help parents and kids start a conversation about the tough topics kids face every day.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?647587</url></doc>
