<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="648199">
  <docid>648199</docid>
  <title>Watch Horror Films, Keep America Strong!</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Cava, Anthony</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">15 May 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">75</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Napton, Robert</producer>
    <producer>Wyrsch, Tom</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Monahan, Michael (I)</writer>
    <writer>Napton, Robert</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fosselius, Ernie</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shaw, Bob (VIII)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Stanley, John (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wilkins, Bob (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>For 14 years, from January 1971 through September 1984, CREATURE FEATURES ranked in the Nielsen ratings as one of the most popular TV shows in San Francisco Bay Area television history. Broadcasted from KTVU Channel 2 in Oakland, California, the Saturday night series was hosted by former TV advertising writer Bob Wilkins for eight years, followed by San Francisco Chronicle entertainment writer John Stanley who kept the series alive for another six. To those who grew up watching with family members and friends, the mixture of host commentary and classic and not-so-classic horror movies remains a nostalgic memory. Wilkins' wit and unusually droll personality and Stanley's celebrity interviews and satiric short subjects are all part of WATCH HORROR FILMS, KEEP AMERICA STRONG, a full-length documentary journeying back through those years. Featuring interviews with Wilkins, Stanley and other key figures close to the show, as well as classic clips, this historic journey illuminates an era of television that should never be forgotten.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?648199</url></doc>
