<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="648273">
  <docid>648273</docid>
  <title>Watch the Stars!</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Roberts, Charlie (III)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>stars</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">5 May 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">10</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Butterfly, Elisabeth Joelle</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Butterfly, Elisabeth Joelle</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Butterfly, Elisabeth Joelle</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Cotton, Richard</actor>
      <role>Howard</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harvey, Terence</actor>
      <role>Banister</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Homewood, Ben</actor>
      <role>Harvey</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Plante, Julien</actor>
      <role>Photographer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Renfrew-Knight, Maximilian</actor>
      <role>Max</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sibony, Clément</actor>
      <role>Tortu</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A little English boy, Max, insists that his Dad tells him his favourite bedtime story about his French grandfather, Jean Tortu... Tortu, who has survived cultivating vegetables in France, dreams of sending a tourist rocket to the moon. He arrives at the London Atlantis Travel Agency, which specialises in trips to the south of France, to pitch his project. The boss, Banister, has little interest in Tortu's foolish dream but pretends to the contrary, intending to take advantage of him for his ad campaign. Tortu begins to work on his rocket in his loft office while his real rocket is being brought through the Swiss mountains. Banister's ill-intentions are revealed when Tortu wakes up one morning to discover a huge poster advertising the trip to the moon. Expressing his discontent to Banister, Tortu is coldly fired but Kelly, the boss' daughter and associate, expresses enthusiasm for his quest. Two generations later, little Max might make the dream come true. A story about foolish projects, dreams and dreamers, and their place in a rational society.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?648273</url></doc>
