<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="648861">
  <docid>648861</docid>
  <title>We Are Still Here</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Mulvihill, Ron</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>reenactment</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">20 April 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">57</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Podgorski, Leigh</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Podgorski, Leigh</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Estrada, Josh</actor>
      <role>Mukat</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Lucaj, Princess</actor>
      <role>Moon Maiden - Storyteller</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wescott, Brian</actor>
      <role>Palmitchkwit - Storyteller</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Wise, Michael (I)</actor>
      <role>Temayuwat - Coyote</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>We Are Still Here is the incredible story of Dr. Katherine Siva Saubel, Cahuilla Indian Elder, raised in poverty, who became an educator, historian, tribal leader, and world-renowned scholar and her efforts to preserve the history, language, and culture of her people. We Are Still Here documents the tenacious struggle of elder Dr. Katherine Siva Saubel and her efforts to preserve the culture, history, and traditions of the Cahuilla people. Presented through in-depth interviews with Dr. Saubel and her brother, traditional Cahuilla Bird Singer, Alvino Siva, the film also portrays the powerful Creation Mythology of the Cahuilla performed by a stellar all Native American cast. Footage also includes Cahuilla festivals and traditional artists basket weaver Donna Largo, potter David Largo, and the bird songs of Alvino and Paul Siva. Dr. Saubel also introduces the viewer to the ethno botany of the Cahuilla people. The culture and history of the Cahuilla people is kept alive through the personages of Katherine Siva Saubel and her brothers, Alvino and Paul Siva. The Cahuilla people have lived in the tradition of their ancestors, and are teachers of their language and the songs that maintain their culture. Dr. Katherine Siva Saubel is acknowledged nationally and internationally as one of California's most respected Native American leaders. Dr. Saubel has received a PhD in Philosophy from Los Sierra University, Riverside, California.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?648861</url></doc>
