<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="648926">
  <docid>648926</docid>
  <title>We Enjoy Yourself</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Pepino, Chris</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>coventry</keyword>
    <keyword>fans</keyword>
    <keyword>phish</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Pepino, Chris</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Pepino, Chris</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Anastasio, Trey</composer>
    <composer>Fishman, Jon</composer>
    <composer>Gordon, Mike (I)</composer>
    <composer>McConnell, Page</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>This documentary takes you on a journey with the band Phish on their farewell tour through New England in August, 2004. Some 70,000 fans came out from all corners of the country, determined to witness the band's closing shows in Northern Vermont, and they would get there at any cost. Phish's followers are some of the most dedicated, passionate and relentlessly die hard music fans in the world. "We Enjoy Yourself" provides a rare window into what it was like for these fans to come together, for what could have been one last time, to celebrate their favorite musicians, and to express their overwhelming gratitude for years of unforgettable experiences on the road. Concertgoers are traced hiking into the Coventry, Vermont site on foot from as far as 20 miles away after having been forbidden entrance by state troopers due to overwhelming weather conditions. Faced with the decision to turn back after sitting in up to 50 hours of traffic, thousands of fans rather chose to abandon their cars on the interstate and proudly walked toward the concert. Filled with emotionally candid interviews, "We Enjoy Yourself" is a testament to Phish fans' unwavering dedication to and absolute love for the band and their music. The film's soundtrack was drafted from the last five shows the band played on their farewell tour, capturing the raw excitement and musical expression of these momentous final days.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?648926</url></doc>
