<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="650134">
  <docid>650134</docid>
  <title>Welcome to Los Angeles: Quintessential LA</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">15 January 2002</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">105</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>McGregor, W. Courtney</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>McGregor, W. Courtney</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>McGregor, W. Courtney</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hunting, Fred</actor>
      <role>Host</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The first and only interactive motion picture DVD of Los Angeles and its world-famous landmarks. Feature length (105 minutes) presentation of digital film clips that capture the essence of a highly diverse city. Includes aerial shots and behind-the-scenes footage never before seen. Hotels, restaurants, and attractions that are unique to LA. Be the director of your own tinseltown tour with interactive DVD. Signature tour includes moving image sequences of Beverly Hills, Celebrity Homes from the Air, Century City, Griffith Observatory, Hollywood, Venice Beach, LAX Pylons, Santa Monica Pier, Sunset Strip, The Getty Center, The Hollywood Sign, Universal City, Watts Towers and more. Moving image sequences from inside the top 10 Quintessential LA restaurants: Belvedere, Campanile, Chinois on Main, Crustacean, Hotel Bel-Air, Lucques, Michael's, Patina, Rockenwagner, Spago Beverly Hills. Other tourist favorites are included. Additional moving image sequences of "Quintessential LA things to do" include: Beach activities, Hollywood celebrity sightings at the Walk of Fame, at Movie Premiers and at The Oscars, Frank O. Gehry architectural highlights, LaBrea Tar Pits, Museum Row, Museum of Neon Art, and much more. Two bonus features: "Angles on Angels in the City of Angels" features moving image sequences of an extraordinarily diverse range of angels from the sublime to the whimsical and unexpected - typifying LA. 'Glamour and Image' features the name and image of LA icon Marilyn Monroe, found throughout the city. Also an interview with a Beverly Hills plastic surgeon.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?650134</url></doc>
