<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="651063">
  <docid>651063</docid>
  <title>Westinghouse</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bussler, Mark</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>History</genre>
    <genre>Biography</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>inventor</keyword>
    <keyword>robot</keyword>
    <keyword>civil-war</keyword>
    <keyword>ed-reis</keyword>
    <keyword>world's-fair</keyword>
    <keyword>shock-absorbers</keyword>
    <keyword>england</keyword>
    <keyword>battle-of-the-currents</keyword>
    <keyword>train</keyword>
    <keyword>automobile</keyword>
    <keyword>battle-of-the-centuries</keyword>
    <keyword>electricity</keyword>
    <keyword>industrialist</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">Not Rated</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">8 April 2008</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">112</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Bussler, Mark</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Bussler, Mark</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Bussler, Mark</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Espy, Carol Lee</actor>
      <role>Narrator</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Reis, Edward J.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Westinghouse is a feature-length documentary about the life and times of George Westinghouse, his companies, legacy, personality, partnership with Nikola Telsa and conflict with Thomas Edison. George Westinghouse is considered America's greatest industrialist and the only man who would go up against Thomas Edison, and win. His victory over Edison during the Battle of the Currents set the stage for the entire future of electric power. The Westinghouse air brake is considered one of the most important inventions in history. Automobile shock absorbers, railroad signaling and the modern day weekend all owe their existence to the man who Andrew Carnegie called "A genius who can't be downed." Westinghouse may be most famous for the massive companies that he created, but the man called "Uncle George" was a reserved, creative giant who went out of his way to treat his workforce with dignity and respect. He was an honest millionaire in the days of robber barons, an optimist in the days of skeptics and a generous CEO from whom today's executives can learn. Westinghouse was filmed in cooperation with the George Westinghouse Museum and features rare and never before seen footage, industrial films and photos previously buried deep within the Westinghouse archives. The film includes interviews with the following: - Edward J. Reis, executive director, George Westinghouse Museum (1998-2007) - William H. Terbo, grandnephew of visionary genius Nikola Tesla - Quentin R. Skrabec, Jr., PhD, author, "George Westinghouse: Gentle Genius"</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?651063</url></doc>
