<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="651459">
  <docid>651459</docid>
  <title>What America Needs: From Sea to Shining Sea</title>
  <year>2003</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Nichols, Nick (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">8 November 2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">93</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="USA">93</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Wojahn, Mark</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Wojahn, Mark</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Wojahn, Mark</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>That is the question asked to more than 500 Americans in the documentary What America Needs - From Sea to Shining Sea. Filmmaker Mark Wojahn traveled, post 9/11, from New York City to Los Angeles by train, bus and motor home, visiting 9 states to ask Americans from all walks of life one simple question. The responses were sometimes simple, sometimes complex, sometimes funny, and as varied as the individuals and characters he met. By the end of the journey, however, it appears that several themes do emerge as Americans reflect on the events of the last several years and anticipate the upcoming election year. The sincerity and thoughtfulness with which people responded makes this film more than a travelogue or slice-of-life documentary, rather it is a thought-provoking look at who Americans are and what they instinctively know. Wojahn's personal journey is woven throughout the film, yet he resists influencing the responses of the interviewees, including their interpretation of the question, "What does America need?" It is a journey worth taking with him.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?651459</url></doc>
