<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="652046">
  <docid>652046</docid>
  <title>What a Difference a Day Made: Doris Day Superstar</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>German</language>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Germany">2 April 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">90</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Davies, Andrew (VI)</director>
    <director>Schäfer, André</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Davies, Andrew (VI)</writer>
    <writer>Schäfer, André</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brown, Philip (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Day, Doris (I)</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Graves, Peter (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Joseph, Jackie</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Keen, Noah</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>LeVett, Denny</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Patrick, Pierre</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Santopietro, Tom</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>If you ask most people in the street today about the Hollywood legend Doris Day, they will probably say "Is she still alive?" Yes, she is! And she will be celebrating her 85th birthday this year. Doris Day is living in Carmel-by-the-sea, a Californian resort with the charm of San Francisco and the glamor of Hollywood. Although she has not appeared in public for over thirty years, Doris Day is considered to be a cultural icon of the 20th and 21st century: Her films are shown regularly on TV worldwide, she still gets around 200 fan letters a week and she is selling more records than ever before. All over the world her songs are still known. This star has not come down from heaven but from the kitchen sink. Doris Day has written cinema history by simply playing the girl next door. So, who is the Doris Day of today? We are unveiling answers from the past, when we get to meet her actor and singer colleagues and friends: In Cincinnati, New York, Los Angeles and the German province. And the whole world is listening when radio station Magic 63 AM broadcasts a Doris Day Tribute programme on her birthday each year, which includes live telephone calls with her and friends throughout the day. We were there last year too, for her 84th birthday celebrations, living in Hotel Day, together with her most notorious fans - even if she cannot be there herself. The documentary will reflect the turbulent and successful life of Doris Day with footage of events in the USA in addition to extracts and trailers from some of her many feature films and stage and TV appearances, photos and material from private archives in order to reveal and contrast the foibles and characteristics of her real life against the background of her screen and music life.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?652046</url></doc>
