<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="652358">
  <docid>652358</docid>
  <title>What's Your Dream?</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Johnson, Carl (VII)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Reality-TV</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">21 July 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Hustus, Hank</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Persson, Penny</producer>
    <producer>Hustus, Hank</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>What's Your Dream? is a TV reality show that highlights someone's dream and helps make that dream come true. Think for a moment; Pretend you are just an average person who works everyday 9-5. You are a good provider and your family always comes first. Maybe your kids are all in sports, you drive them all over town several times a week or maybe you take care of all the typical duties around the house and you have nothing to look forward to except your personal time with the TV or maybe a night out once in a while. While sitting at home watching TV one night, you flip through the channels; suddenly! A new reality show called; What's Your Dream? is advertised giving you a chance to send in your personal dream to be considered to make come true on National TV would you send in your personal dream? This could be any dream at all like a Nashville Dream; where you always wanted to perform at the Grand 'ole Opry so the show would take you to Nashville, Tennessee and get you into a studio, you would work with professional musicians and in 5 days you would be ready to perform on stage then, just when your ready to walk on the stage, your favorite singer comes out and meets you and sings a song with you in front of millions of people! It does not make any difference if they are no good at it or not, it just allows the person who is selected to have a chance to make their dream a reality. The series will take the selected person from a "Zero to a Hero" and each 1 hour show would span over a 5 day period.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?652358</url></doc>
