<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="653881">
  <docid>653881</docid>
  <title>Where Were We...</title>
  <year>2002</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>UK</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="UK">2003</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="UK">3</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="default">3</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Golding, Matt (III)</director>
    <director>Smith, Matt (XXIX)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Davies, Abigail (I)</producer>
    <producer>Meredith, Sarah-Jane</producer>
    <producer>Frederick, Christopher (II)</producer>
    <producer>Parkhouse, Andrew</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Golding, Matt (III)</writer>
    <writer>Smith, Matt (XXIX)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Smith, Matt (XXIX)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Harnett, Shareena</actor>
      <role>The Couple</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hillier, James (II)</actor>
      <role>The Couple</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Llewellyn, Christopher</actor>
      <role>Logan</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A couple sit on a log in front of sand dunes facing a small but clear beach. They are in the midst of a contemplative conversation. It isn't life changing, but it isn't an everyday chat, and they are engrossed. Suddenly, from behind a dune, a man comes hurtling into view. He accosts the couple, imploring them to help him. Despite their initial reluctance the man persists and the couple are persuaded to follow him down the beach, where they find his car stuck in the wet sand. It is wedged fast and in the path of the in-coming tide. The couple grab some driftwood and work hard to release the vehicle whilst the man helplessly stands by. After some struggle they manage to ram wood under the front wheels and the man jumps into the car. He revs as the couple push and finally the car is released. Overjoyed, the man waves excitedly to the couple, shouting thanks as he speeds off. But instead of driving away from further trouble, to the couple's amazement, the man heads straight for the sea. As the car plunges into the waves, the couple stare in disbelief. Then, unsure of what else to do, they continue their conversation.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?653881</url></doc>
