<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="654751">
  <docid>654751</docid>
  <title>White Screen</title>
  <year>2008</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Di Giambattista, Alessio</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Di Giambattista, Alessio</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Costabile, Fabio</producer>
    <producer>Malygin, Konstantin</producer>
    <producer>Di Giambattista, Alessio</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Di Giambattista, Alessio</writer>
    <writer>Iozzia, Alberto</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bellomo, Bryan</actor>
      <role>Will</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Brewster, Paul (I)</actor>
      <role>Producer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Church, John (VII)</actor>
      <role>Ben Bradford</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Demir, Alex</actor>
      <role>Jack Jhonson</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Herr, Warren</actor>
      <role>Bob Brown</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Landa, Edgar</actor>
      <role>Eddy Oliver</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Long, Samantha</actor>
      <role>Kate</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>The young, attractive film producer Kate is sent by her boss to a meeting with a particular screenwriter, who has a new script ready to pitch. Will is a novel writer who decided to gave a twist to his life becoming a screenwriter for feature films. As soon as he faces Hollywood, he discovers that his style is not really blockbuster-friendly: in fact, in each and every story he writes, the protagonist dies in the end. When Kate shows up to the meeting she quickly finds out that her 'professional meeting' looks more like a romantic dinner. She decides to stay because the pressure from the studio for this pitch is big. Towards the end of the night, she convinces Will to pitch her the script. The story is about a writer who struggles to get his work produced by studios. Every executive he meets has different suggestions for the ending of his screenplays. After several meetings the writer decides to rewrite the story but he is stuck in a 'writers' block'. He can't manage the suggestions that the executives gave him. So far, Kate is very impressed by the story. The block of the writer drives him nuts until he has an epiphany.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?654751</url></doc>
