<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="654791">
  <docid>654791</docid>
  <title>White Trash</title>
  <year>1977</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Adult</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>masturbation</keyword>
    <keyword>robbery</keyword>
    <keyword>fellatio</keyword>
    <keyword>independent-film</keyword>
    <keyword>bathroom</keyword>
    <keyword>sex</keyword>
    <keyword>homosexual</keyword>
    <keyword>hardcore</keyword>
    <keyword>hustler</keyword>
    <keyword>gay-interest</keyword>
    <keyword>rock-concert</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <certificates>
    <certificate country="USA">X</certificate>
  </certificates>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1977</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">58</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Ross, Toby</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Anthony, St.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Carmichael, Wren</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Crespon, Karl</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Duke, St.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Filoni, Sam</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Frank, Speedfreak</actor>
      <role>Stoned Hippie</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McDonald, Kevin (X)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vincent, Gerald</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This early Toby Ross film is broken up into four segments. The film opens to a stoned hippie with dreadlocks stumbling around while creepy music plays on the soundtrack, it then goes into the first segment (which is untitled), as we watch two guys fool around with each other in the bathroom of an apartment as the action then moves to the main bedroom. The second segment is titled "Ripoffs" in which two young men get together an apparently plan a robbery, they break into a house and start piling everything they want to take on the floor, before they leave with their stolen goods they start having sex. The third segment is called "Underground" as we are brought into the world of the male hustler. A car pulls up and calls over a young man who is waiting by a white picket fence, the two then make a deal and the hustler gets into the car. They then go to the tricks house and have sex. The forth and last segment (as well as the film's main tile) is called "White Trash" as two guys go into a movie house that is playing concert footage of Led Zepplin. They start to mess around and then go to the theatre's restroom and finally finish up in a bedroom. The film ends with the same dread-locked hippie walking on a bridge as a police truck passes him, he then walks toward the camera as it cuts to "The End" written on a brick wall (like the rest of the credits in the film).</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?654791</url></doc>
