<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="655414">
  <docid>655414</docid>
  <title>Who's Who of World Giving</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Antonik, Michael</editor>
    <editor>Merrill, Chris (II)</editor>
    <editor>O'Brian, Danny (II)</editor>
    <editor>Reese, Taran</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>giving</keyword>
    <keyword>punctuation-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>apostrophe-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>charity</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">22 November 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <producers>
    <producer>Goldman, Dan (II)</producer>
    <producer>Ross, John (VI)</producer>
    <producer>Thomas, Brad (VII)</producer>
    <producer>McKenzie, David (III)</producer>
    <producer>Sharratt, Paul</producer>
    <producer>McKenzie, David (III)</producer>
    <producer>Aguilar, Carlos (VIII)</producer>
    <producer>Jarczak, Steve</producer>
    <producer>Montavano, Danielle</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gumbel, Bryant</actor>
      <role>Himself - Host</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>America's favorite journalist Bryant Gumbel hosts this in-depth one hour look at the phenomenon of charitable giving. Emphasizing the people behind the donations; from everyday donors, to celebrity givers and the super-philanthropists; we'll see what it takes to become a world class giver and why even people who don't make a lot of money still find ways to make a difference. You'll be surprised at who the biggest donors are and who are the most famous. The program features exclusive interviews with a wide range of celebrities who are all world class philanthropists: André Agassi, Della Reese, Ed Begley Jr., Etan Thomas, Eva LaRrue, Jewel, Joan Collins, John Densmore, Kareem Abdul Jabar, Kobe Bryant, Maurice Evans, Montel Williams, Paul Mitchell, Prince Albert "Prince of Monaco", Prince Radu of Hohenzollern-Veringen, Princess Margarita of Romania, Sir Roger Moore, Ron Artest, Theo Ratliff and Tony Hawk. Inspiring, informative, and surprising, Who's Who of World Giving brings unique perspective and insight to a subject that grows more important every day. This fascinating one-hour special, shot in dazzling high-definition, will become an event that no one will want to miss.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?655414</url></doc>
