<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="655611">
  <docid>655611</docid>
  <title>Whose Children Are These?</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Talukdar, Shashwati</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>immigration</keyword>
    <keyword>youth</keyword>
    <keyword>post-september-11-2001</keyword>
    <keyword>special-registration</keyword>
    <keyword>muslim-american</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">11 October 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">28</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Thanjan, Theresa</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Thanjan, Theresa</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Rastegar, Kamran</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ali, Navila</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Finn, Marianne</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hussain, Mohammad Sarfaraz</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Whose Children Are These? provides a gripping view into the lives of three Muslim teenagers impacted by domestic national security measures. One such program, "Special Registration," required male non-citizens, as young as 16 from 25 countries, to register with the Department of Justice. Of those who registered, nearly 14,000 men were deported. The film introduces Navila, an honors student who fought to have her father released from detention; Sarfaraz, a popular basketball player who confronts pending deportation; and Hager, a young woman who faces bias and is spurred into activism as a result. Each young person comes from one of the twenty five countries profiled by the Special Registration program (Bangladesh, Pakistan and Egypt). From the period of November 2002-December 2003, over 83,000 Muslim men complied with the program and nearly 14,000 were put into deportation proceedings due to immigration status violations. Although the program claimed to be a tool to increase national security, none of these men were actually charged with terrorism related offenses. Through the eyes of three courageous teens, Whose Children Are These? brings to light the harsh realities faced by Muslim communities in post 9/11 America- including family separation, round ups, bias crimes, detentions, and deportations.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?655611</url></doc>
