<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="655771">
  <docid>655771</docid>
  <title>Why Is God...</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Miglio, Paul</editor>
    <editor>Shastri, Seema</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>question-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>ellipsis-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">17 March 2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">15.00</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Shastri, Seema</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Shastri, Seema</producer>
    <producer>Kosinski, Katherine</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Shastri, Seema</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Hiltscher, Jared</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gavankar, Janina</actor>
      <role>Mina</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jethmalani, Anish</actor>
      <role>Husband</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sheppard, Lorado</actor>
      <role>Reverend</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Why is God... is a dramatic narrative about Mina, a young Indian American woman. When Mina's newborn baby dies in her arms, she suddenly begins to question her identity, and the reality of God in her life. If she is not a mother than who is she? Why is God doing this? Does such a God belong in her life? Why is God so cruel? Mina witnesses her devout Hindu mother reacting to this death with superstition that seem only to heighten Mina's loss. As Mina conflicts with what Hinduism and God has to offer, she encounters a Reverend of a nearby church. He is someone with unquestionable faith. The Reverend pushes her out of the way of a moving car, and is himself hit by the car. In a beautiful, dark, dream sequence, Mina is forced to face the anxiety surrounding her faith. She is awakened by sudden rainfall and quickly struggles to perform CPR on the Reverend. Mina saves his life and realizes a new avenue of "giving life." This realization brings her some measure of peace, and allows Mina to begin the journey of recovering both her faith and identity. Why is God... is a combination of beautiful surreal visuals, set within a family drama. In this film we get first hand look into the Indian American subculture, told from the point of view of a young Indian American woman.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?655771</url></doc>
