<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="655787">
  <docid>655787</docid>
  <title>Why Krausemeyer Couldn't Sleep</title>
  <year>1899</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>question-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>character-name-in-title</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Silent</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">August 1899</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <producers>
    <producer>Lubin, Siegmund</producer>
  </producers>
<plot>"One of the funniest life-motion pictures ever seen is this one showing the trouble Hans Krausemeyer met with when he engaged a room in the country hotel. Krauemeyer is first seen entering the room, led by the porter, who charges him for the room and also for his services. Hans places his roll of bank notes under the pillow, but is seen doing so by the porter, who extracts it while Krausemeyer disrobes. He then leaves the room and our Teuton friend divests himself of all his clothing and tumbles into bed, cuddling up for a good snooze. The famous Jersey mosquitoes now get in their work, assisted by a number of residents usually found in the beds of a country inn. The occupant of the bed twists and squirms until, utterly disgusted, he leaps to the floor and grasping a towel proceeds to kill a few of the 'skeeters' on the wall. He finally pulls the bedding out on the floor and tries to sleep again, but the mosquitoes seem to know a good thing when they bite it, and they will not let him rest. Hans puts his boots on to protect his feet, but an unusually large 'skeeter' attacks his face. After driving him away he settles down and thinks himself safe, when a rate deliberately runs across the floor and steals his sheet, the only covering he has. Exasperated beyond endurance, Krausemeyer arises and throws the chairs about the room in his anger and awakens the porter, who fires him from the room, caressing him occasionally with his boot by way of emphasis. This film is not only funny but very interesting and full of life and action."</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?655787</url></doc>
