<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="659700">
  <docid>659700</docid>
  <title>Wolf-Hunt</title>
  <year>1993</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>French</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>France</country>
    <country>Belgium</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Belgium">16 March 1993</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Bulgaria">65</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Rousseva, Zlatina</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Gueorguiev, Lubomir</producer>
    <producer>Perrin, Jacques</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Rousseva, Zlatina</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Minkin, Tzenko</composer>
    <composer>Vysotsky, Vladimir (I)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mars (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shashurin, Sergey</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Toumanov, Vadim</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>This is a film about freedom. It opens to the songs of Vysotsky, about the journey across Siberia he planned with his friend Vadim Tumanov, to the most horrible death camps of the Gulag, fenced in by walls of steel. This film is a reflection on what it actually was that we were looking for, what we expected, what freedom meant to us when we listened to Vysotsky, and what it turned out to be in reality. On this journey we follow the path of three exceptional individuals. Vadim Tumanov was sentenced to 125 years imprisonment in the death camps, but he managed to get out and found the first independent gold mining company, long before Perestroika. Our second traveling companion is Sergei Shashurin, a man who has endured prison and psychiatric institutionalization, a former Mafia member and one of the wealthiest men in Russia, who set up a trust that employs 200,000 people. The third is Mars, a descendant of Ghengis Khan, a hereditary thief, and former Mafia boss of the thieves of Tatarstan. Through the fates and thoughts of these three very contradictory and different personalities, we embark on an epic journey envisioned by Vysotsky, in search of the measure and meaning of freedom.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?659700</url></doc>
