<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="661028">
  <docid>661028</docid>
  <title>World War II: Breadlines to Boomtimes</title>
  <year>1994</year>
  <type>TelevisionMovie</type>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
  </genres>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">180</runningtime>
    <runningtime country="USA">170</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Emerson, Wesley</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Brimmer, Martin</producer>
    <producer>Rae-Mansfield, Jere</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Brimmer, Martin</writer>
    <writer>Jacobs, Rodger (II)</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Sterling, Lianne</composer>
    <composer>Swanson, Eric (VI)</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sikking, James</actor>
      <role>Host and Narrator</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>A rare look at how a nation of men and women mobilized to convert our economy into a war machine, emerging as the most powerful country in the world. Hosted by James B. Sikking. Includes: Vol. 1 - "Changing the Face of America" Politics make war, and men and women do the fighting. And a war such as World War II is as much a war of economy as of armies. For each soldier, each sailor, each airman had alongside him the factory worker, the shipbuilder, the "Rosie the Riveter" that so epitomized a time of unity that may never be repeated again.. Vol. 2 - "A World in Flames" They shared the look of broken promises. But this is America, land of opportunity, land of promise. Yet there was no work. There was no hope. In a land built on hope, on promise, on dreams, there were breadlines, there were bank closures, and there were so many frightened faces. Vol. 3 - "The Problems of Peace" GI Joe was home. An incredible industrial war machine had been assembled and had emerged victorious. The face of the world would be forever changed. The face of American also. The economy of war success would now have to adapt to peace. Prosperity had a new enemy.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?661028</url></doc>
