<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="661021">
  <docid>661021</docid>
  <title>World War 1: American Legacy</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>War</genre>
    <genre>History</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>number-in-title</keyword>
    <keyword>red-cross</keyword>
    <keyword>african-american</keyword>
    <keyword>europe</keyword>
    <keyword>wwi</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">October 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">116</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Bussler, Mark</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Connelly, Brian (I)</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>THE GREAT WAR THAT CHANGED AMERICA World War 1 - American Legacy vividly shows many forgotten stories of the men and women who served in the Great War, reminding Americans of their impact on our country that can still be felt today. Writers like E. E. Cummings, Ernest Hemingway, Joyce Kilmer and Alan Seeger turned tragedy into literary masterpieces. African-American soldiers like James Reese Europe and the Harlem Hell Fighters made history. Female volunteers like the "Hello Girls" and Red Cross nurses risked their lives supporting the troops and started a new era for women. Individuals like Charles Whittlesey of the Lost Battalion and Father Duffy of the Fighting 69th became famous for surviving against impossible odds. Pilots like Victor Chapman and Quentin Roosevelt and ambulance drivers like Richard Hall made the supreme sacrifice. Monuments and dedications to World War 1 veterans surround Americans today as a tribute to their service and sacrifice. From the summer of 1914 to November 1918, the Great War cost over 14 million lives, devastated millions of acres of land and destroyed countless architectural landmarks. The war also led to important developments in literature, technology, music and social equality that have shaped the culture of 21st century America. Filmed in High-Definition and full of period music, photographs and monuments, World War 1 - American Legacy includes rare images that have never been seen before on DVD, bringing the extreme detail of the Great War to the screen.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?661021</url></doc>
