<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="661357">
  <docid>661357</docid>
  <title>Wounded Knee</title>
  <year>2009</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Benson, Lillian</editor>
    <editor>Lerew, Lawrence</editor>
    <editor>Tunsil, Aljernon</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Documentary</genre>
    <genre>History</genre>
  </genres>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">16 January 2009</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">74</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Nelson, Stanley (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Brannum, Julianna</producer>
    <producer>Grimberg, Sharon</producer>
    <producer>Samels, Mark (I)</producer>
    <producer>Nelson, Stanley (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Smith, Marcia (II)</writer>
  </writers>
<plot>On the night of February 27, 1973, a caravan of cars carrying 200 armed Oglala Lakota-led by American Indian Movement (AIM) activists-entered Wounded Knee on the Pine Ridge Reservation and quickly occupied buildings, cut off access, and took up defensive positions. When federal agents arrived, they declared, "The Indians are in charge of the town," and a 71-day standoff ensued. Compiling an astonishing amount of archival film footage (notable for the key moments it captures) and firsthand accounts from participants, Stanley Nelson creates an immersive, comprehensive account of the occupation and its fascinating complexity. The Oglala Lakota sought redress of old grievances and broken treaties (just miles from the massacre of 1890) but also demanded the ouster of Pine Ridge tribal leader Dick Wilson, who governed through corruption and intimidation as he pursued deeply divisive policies of assimilation. Nelson also explores the climate of racism in border towns; the broad political context that shaped the AIM-its tactics, organization and ability to exploit the national media; and ultimately the role armed protest played in Native American self-conception. With its iconic images of Indians holding the government at bay, Wounded Knee not only brought national attention to an invisible community and its desperate conditions but contributed to the tribe's awakened sense of dignity and connection with their proud heritage.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?661357</url></doc>
