<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="661310">
  <docid>661310</docid>
  <title>Worthy to Stand</title>
  <year>1969</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Bickerton, Richard (II)</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>missionary</keyword>
    <keyword>prayer</keyword>
    <keyword>bishop</keyword>
    <keyword>elders-quorum</keyword>
    <keyword>mormon</keyword>
    <keyword>marriage-counseling</keyword>
    <keyword>home-schooling</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Mono</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">1969</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">25</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Whitaker, Judge</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Whitaker, Judge</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Whitaker, Scott (I)</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Clinger, Morris</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Farrell, Judy</actor>
      <role>Brenda (Jim Slater's Secretary)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Farrell, Mike (I)</actor>
      <role>Fred Washburn</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fletcher, Marian</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Thompkins</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Frederickson, Ron</actor>
      <role>Jim Slater</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Maag, Cliff</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Marin, Richard (II)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Nygren, Bradley M.</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rockwood, La Var</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Williams, Hal</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Starting his day in prayer, Rick Thompkins, a Mormon missionary in Europe, pleads for his parent's troubled marriage to heal when his father Jack starts consulting a lawyer about divorce. Back in Utah, Jim Slater, Home Teacher for the Thompkins Family, asks his Elder's Quorum president, Fred Washburn, for release due to failure with the inactive families for which he has responsibility. Fred says he will comply, but only if Jim gives it one last try. Not knowing of the discord, Jim and his partner, Ronny, find Rick's sister alone at home and she tearfully explains that "nothing is right." Even more convinced of his failure, Jim asks for release again. Rick writes, asking Jim to help and enclosing part of a letter from his mother where she explains that she had wanted to confide in Jim as her Home Teacher, but he seemed aloof, with other things on his mind. Jim has his secretary, Brenda, arrange a fishing trip with Fred and Bishop Weston. Over the campfire they all admit failure in not helping the Thompkins and resolve to do better. Bishop Weston cites The Doctrine &amp; Covenants, Sec. 107 verse 100 "...he that learns not his duty and shows himself not approved shall not be counted worthy to stand." Rick returns to his flat with his companion one evening to find a letter from his mother telling how the three men have been counselling his parents together.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?661310</url></doc>
