<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="661444">
  <docid>661444</docid>
  <title>Wreck Beach Butoh</title>
  <year>2006</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Provost, Pascal Jean</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>butoh-dance</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Dolby</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="Canada">4 November 2006</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Canada">24</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Provost, Pascal Jean</director>
  </directors>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arvidson, Heather</actor>
      <role>Dancer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chan, Carolyn</actor>
      <role>Dancer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chu, Mary Ann</actor>
      <role>Dancer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hirabayashi, Jay</actor>
      <role>Dancer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Holt, Holly</actor>
      <role>Dancer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>McKinley, Jennifer</actor>
      <role>Dancer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rosenberg, George (IV)</actor>
      <role>Dancer</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Seaton, Robert (I)</actor>
      <role>Dancer</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Between the impenetrable blackness of the endowment lands rain forest and the primordial Pacific Ocean lies Wreck Beach Butoh, Pascal Provost's transcendent art film of a collaboration of Butoh by Kokoro Dance. Intentionally employing the nature of 16mm Kodak Double X, this cross-cultural film is a provocation of black and white with the specter of light continually emerging from the shadows to introduce the possibility of speaking about the unspeakable. The grain is used to push the audience away from the constraints of the physical realm, collapsing the air, the water, the sand and the naked body into one. The soundtrack is an extension beyond the pictures, seducing the viewer into a vicarious, hypnotic dance. That which is formless becomes seen and that which is soundless, heard. Wreck Beach Butoh successfully translates the precepts of Ankoku Butoh from one form into another, with each leading parallel existential lives. Both the dance and the film become an exceptional and universalizing transitory moment for these artists' shared sensibilities.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?661444</url></doc>
