<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="661802">
  <docid>661802</docid>
  <title>Wu ren he cai</title>
  <year>1993</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>based-on-novel</keyword>
    <keyword>romanic</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Mandarin</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Xia, Gang</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Chen, Zhi Gu</producer>
    <producer>Song, Vivian</producer>
    <producer>Wu, Jimmy (I)</producer>
    <producer>Cai, Rubin</producer>
    <producer>Song, Xiao Jun</producer>
    <producer>Wu, Cynthia (I)</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Wang, Shuo</writer>
    <writer>Zhu, Meng</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ding, Jiali</actor>
      <role>Han Li Ting</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fang, Zi Ge</actor>
      <role>Qian Kang</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gai, Xiaoling</actor>
      <role>Xiao Ke Ping</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Xie, Yuan</actor>
      <role>Li Mian Ning</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>No More Applause aka Wu Ren He Cai Synopsis Xiao Ke Ping is a flautist in a philharmonic orchestra, but it is popular music, not classical, that floods the music market. Xiao and her colleagues are often reduced to playing little-appreciated chamber music in hotel bars and cafés. Her Husband, Li Mian Ning, was once an advanced technology engineer. When he returns to Beijing be with Xiao, Li had to abandon his specialty and become a security guard in the Forbidden City. It is only when he is playing electronic games after work that Li's energy shows through. Life is getting drier and drier. After many career setbacks, Xiao becomes short-temper. Husband and wife quarrel repeatedly. Finally they divorce. Due to the lack of housing, Li and Xiao have to go on living, specially, in the same apartment. Later, each takes a "new lover" home, mostly to provoke the other. Han Li Ting, a woman in her thirties, tries to go out of her way to please Li because he has a room to live in. Qian Kang, an old classmate of Xiao who had been in a one-side love affair with her during their high school-days, now has given up teaching to make money as a businessman. He still loves Xiao as much as ever. Using jocular and humorous tone, "No More Applause" fallows these two coupes sorrows and joys.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?661802</url></doc>
