<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="663943">
  <docid>663943</docid>
  <title>Yang men hu jiang</title>
  <year>2004</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>History</genre>
    <genre>Romance</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Mandarin</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="China">24 December 2004</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="China">42</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <producers>
    <producer>Li, Mi</producer>
    <producer>Zhao, Yi Fang</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bao, Jianfeng</actor>
      <role>Yang Wu Lan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chae, Rim</actor>
      <role>Pan Yu Yan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chiu, Angie</actor>
      <role>Shu Sai Hua</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Fang, Zhou Bo</actor>
      <role>Emperor</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hu, Jing</actor>
      <role>Liao Princess Ming Ji</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kou, Zhenghai</actor>
      <role>Pan Ren Mei</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Su, Alec</actor>
      <role>Yang Si Lan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Su, Alec</actor>
      <role>Yang Si Lang</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Su, Alec</actor>
      <role>Yang Si Lang</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ti, Lung</actor>
      <role>Yang Ye</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Yan, Kun</actor>
      <role>Yang Qi Lang</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Yu, Xiao Wei</actor>
      <role>Yang San Lang</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Based on the historical exploits of the Yang military family during the Song Dynasty, this drama begins as war between China and the neighboring Liao kingdom is about to begin. The Song emperor is counseled by Pan Ren Mei, an ill-scheming prime minister whose political ambitions fuel a dangerous rivalry with the Yang family, leading to disastrous military decisions and treachery. As head of the Yang family, General Yang Ye is extremely loyal to the Songs, to the extent of being an overbearing authoritarian to his seven sons, dealing out stricter punishments to them than he would to ordinary soldiers in order to demonstrate impartiality. His harshness is especially evident in his treatment of his fourth son, Si Lang. Being equally stubborn, each of them fights persistently for his own beliefs even when both sides of the argument are valid. Although each of the Yang sons has a defined character and a personal story line within the drama, the main focus is on Si Lang. He falls in love with the enemy's daughter, Pan Yu Yan, when they meet in the Yang family compound, Tian Bo, accidentally. However, when Si Lang kills Yu Yan's brother, Pan Bao, in self-defense, the two lovers have to flee. After eloping, the pair have more obstacles ahead of them, such as the Laio Princess Ming Ji, whose determination to be with Si Lang comes in conflict with her role as a military leader for the invaders. While the Yang generals lead their armies into battle, Pan Ren Mei's enmity with the Yangs, fueled further by his son's death and daughter's desertion, leads him into a treasonous alliance with the Liao kingdom. As the war progresses, bravery, intrigue, passion and tragedy combine to bring the story to a dramatic climax.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?663943</url></doc>
