<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="664078">
  <docid>664078</docid>
  <title>Yapayalniz</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>TelevisionSeries</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>tv-mini-series</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Turkish</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Turkey">220</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Gök, Sahin</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Inanoglu, Türker</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Önal, Safa</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Barlas, Taner</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bosnali, Cem</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Erdem, Bora</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ernak, Serhan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gölge, Gül</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Olgaç, Atilla</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Otag, Yalçin</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Peker, Faruk</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ural, Hakan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Yaylali, Mürsel</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Yildiz, Nebi</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Yilmaz, Tarkan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Everything that is holding you on life, everything that you never think will end or finish up may one day finish suddenly. And you may find yourself "all alone". Funda, a young girl full of life, is a high school student living in a seaside town in Anatolia. With her family and friends, she lives in a world getting contented with the minor things of life. In this small town she lives all her "first" encounters in life. Funda met her first love here, too. She falls in love with the law student who works as a lifeguard at the beach. Alluring and charming Funda is always bothered by the town's loafers Erhan and his men. Thus, it even ends up in a rape. The young girl's whole world breaks down. The rumor about Funda's rape goes around the town. Funda can't look into her darling's, family's and friends' face anymore. This psychological breakdown offers her two alternatives. Either she has to commit suicide or she has to go away, to a place where nobody knows her. She takes the second option and decides to go to Istanbul. A young girl living all alone whose future dreams become unrealized due to her rape. The problems of the big city and the situations she finds herself in, people and places. On one side a drugs milieu and poverty, on the other side a life of allure, glitter and wealth. This is Istanbul, a big city, a place of sweet dreams and bitter disappointment. Funda has to come to terms with her "loneliness" in this spellbinding city!</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?664078</url></doc>
