<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="664611">
  <docid>664611</docid>
  <title>Yeh To Kamaal Ho Gaya</title>
  <year>1982</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Tatineni, Rama Rao</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Rao, P. Mallikharjuna</producer>
  </producers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Burman, Rahul Dev</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Arora, Vijay</actor>
      <role>Advocate Mahesh Chander</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ashalata</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Laxmi Saxena</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Bole, Kumud</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Shanta Chander</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chatwal, Suresh</actor>
      <role>Auditorium Manager</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dhillon, Poonam</actor>
      <role>Priya Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Hassan, Kamal</actor>
      <role>Ratan Chander/Ajay Saxena</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Satyendra</actor>
      <role>Shankar Chander</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mehra, Raj</actor>
      <role>Mohan Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mitchell, Hannah</actor>
      <role>Mrs. Kathryn Saxena</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ranjeet</actor>
      <role>Chandru Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shivpuri, Om</actor>
      <role>Advocate Rashik Bihari Saxena</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Shady and corrupt lawyer, Rashik Bihari Saxena, frames an innocent child, Mahesh Chander, the son of a convicted thief, for murder. Mahesh is sent to juvenile jail for several years. His father, Shankar, swears vengeance against Advocate Saxena, and abducts one his children, a boy, and names him Ratan. He and his wife, Shanta, nurture him and let him grow with them. Shankar teaches him all the tricks that would make him a master cat burglar. Years later, Ratan has grown up to be a master cat burglar while his lookalike brother, Ajay Saxena, is studying in London. Ajay returns home with a Caucasian wife, Kathryn, who is not welcomed by Advocate Saxena, as a result Ajay too leaves the house. Then a woman named Ruby Gupta is killed, and the evidence links this crime to Saxena. The police arrest him, and a trial is conducted. In the meantime, Shankar asks Ratan to take Ajay's place in the Saxena household, which Ratan does so. As a result, Ajay is framed for a robbery, is arrested and held in jail. With both father and son awaiting respective trials, it looks like Shankar is going to have his vengeance after all.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?664611</url></doc>
