<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="664603">
  <docid>664603</docid>
  <title>Yeh Raaste Hain Pyaar Ke</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Kunder, Shirish</editor>
  </editors>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="India">10 August 2001</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="USA">10 August 2001</releasedate>
    <releasedate country="Kuwait">12 September 2001</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <directors>
    <director>Shivdasani, Deepak S.</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Sadarangani, Pradeep</producer>
    <producer>Shivdasani, Deepak S.</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Shivdasani, Deepak S.</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Rathod, Darshan</composer>
    <composer>Rathod, Sanjeev</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Deol, Sunny (I)</actor>
      <role>Sagar (Special Appearance)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Devgan, Ajay</actor>
      <role>Vicky/Rohit Verma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dhillon, Deep</actor>
      <role>Bhanwarlal</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Dixit, Madhuri</actor>
      <role>Neha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Gokhale, Vikram</actor>
      <role>Rohit's father</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jain, Madan</actor>
      <role>Madhuri's brother in law</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jaykar, Smita</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kumar, Kiran (I)</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mayur</actor>
      <role>Bhanwarlal's brother</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Talsania, Tiku</actor>
      <role>Kishanchand Bhagwandas Chellaramani</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Tiwari, Lalit (I)</actor>
      <role>Ashok Sharma</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Verma, Rajeev</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Two con artistes and car thieves, Vicky (Devgan) and Sakshi (Zinta), are faced with death when they accidentally kill Bhanwarlal's (Deep Dhillon) brother. Bhanwarlal and his other brother (Mayur) both swear to avenge the death of their brother and mistakenly kill Rohit Verma (also Devgan), who is a look-alike of Vicky. The mistaken identity causes Sakshi to think that her Vicky is dead and is she is devastated. Meanwhile unknown to Sakshi and Bhanwarlal, Vicky is still alive and reaches Manali where he finds out about Rohit. On discovering Rohit's wealth Vicky realizes he has hit the jackpot and decides to play along, fooling Rohit's dad, Pratap Verma (Vikram Gokhale). On the other hand Pratap Verma already knows that Rohit is dead, but Rohit's dad convinces Vicky to pose as Rohit for the sake of his daughter-in-law, Neha (Dixit) who is oblivious to the fact that her husband is dead. He agrees to do the job in return for payment. However, half way through the job he decides to grab the money and return to Sakshi. They are about to forget all about Rohit and start a life of their own, when Vicky discovers that he is responsible for Rohit's death. Because Bhanwarlal meant to kill him not Rohit. He realizes the debt he owes to Rohit and decides to return, leaving Sakshi once again. Meanwhile Sakhi's parents try to get her married off to Bhanwarlal's son and so she runs away to Manali to be with Vicky. Vicky at this point can't tell Neha the truth and so tells Sakshi that he can't be with her. Soon with the arrival of Bhanwarlal and Sakshi's parents the truth unravels. Will Vicky remain with Neha or will he return to his true love Sakshi?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?664603</url></doc>
