<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="665793">
  <docid>665793</docid>
  <title>Yoga Total Body Makeover</title>
  <year>2007</year>
  <type>DirectToVideo</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <editors>
    <editor>Rena, Becky W.</editor>
  </editors>
  <genres>
    <genre>Sport</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>yoga</keyword>
    <keyword>alanna-zabel</keyword>
    <keyword>makeover</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>English</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>USA</country>
  </countries>
  <releasedates>
    <releasedate country="USA">7 October 2007</releasedate>
  </releasedates>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="USA">60</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Levitus, Chris</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Farwell, Victoria</producer>
    <producer>Rena, James</producer>
    <producer>Kisner, Kim</producer>
  </producers>
  <writers>
    <writer>Zabel, Alanna</writer>
  </writers>
  <composers>
    <composer>Chassen, Brett</composer>
    <composer>Kulick, Bob</composer>
  </composers>
<plot>Yoga Total Body Makeover with Alanna Zabel Use traditional, flowing yoga to totally transform your body. Yoga Total Body Makeover moves you through sequences that are targeted on specific body parts and muscle groups for the ultimate body makeover. It begins with a simple warm-up and moves to lower body to lift and tighten buns, thighs and hips. Next is a middle-whittling core segment, followed by a sculpting arm and upper body sequence. You'll finish with a total body stretch to lengthen and sooth all your muscles. Get lean, balanced and buff with Yoga Total Body Makeover. Alanna Zabel is a certified Yoga instructor and personal trainer. She currently lives and works in the Southern Calirornia area, providing yoga instruction to some of Hollywood's elite, as well as organizing retreats in locals such as Desert hot Springs, California and the coast of Costa Rica. Alanna teaches weekly classes at Carlsbad's famous La Costa Resort &amp; Spa. She is also passionate about child development and early education. She has written several children's books and teaches a yoga class just for kids.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?665793</url></doc>
