<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="668994">
  <docid>668994</docid>
  <title>Zakhmi Zameen</title>
  <year>1990</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Musical</genre>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>Hindi</language>
  </languages>
  <soundmixes>
    <soundmix>Stereo</soundmix>
  </soundmixes>
  <countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Shah, Mahendra (I)</director>
  </directors>
  <composers>
    <composer>Chitragupth, Anand</composer>
    <composer>Chitragupth, Milind</composer>
  </composers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ali, Ishrat</actor>
      <role>Lala Milavatram</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ambegaonkar, Mona</actor>
      <role>Mona Singh (Thakur's daughter)</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Chandrashekhar</actor>
      <role>Mouni Baba</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jamuna (III)</actor>
      <role>Courtesan</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Jayapradha</actor>
      <role>Radha</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Kapoor, Annu</actor>
      <role>Madhav</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Karia, Raju</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mohan, Ram (I)</actor>
      <role>Radha's dad</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Pancholi, Aditya</actor>
      <role>Mangal/Raju/Inspector Vijay</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Ranjeet</actor>
      <role>Bhairav</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rawal, Paresh (I)</actor>
      <role>Thakur Pratap Singh</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Shah, Mahavir</actor>
      <role>Chotey Thakur</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Wealthy and aristocratic Thakur Pratap Singh lives in a palatial mansion, and has a dream of building a dream house, similar to the Taj Mahal, with the help of his Architect brother. In order to do this, he must first get rid of the villagers, and take possession of their respective lands. He runs into problems when Mangal and a few handful of villagers refuse to part with their lands. Pratap Singh, his brother, and some of his goons get together and convive a deadly plan that will result in the death of Mangal and the villagers who are opposed to selling their lands. The plans is carried out, and Mangal is at first crippled, and finally brutally killed. Then Mangal's infant son is killed in his cradle, leaving his mother, Radha, alone and devastated to face life at the mercy of the cruel Thakur and his men. Pratap Singh dreams materialize when his brother finally arranges the construction of their dream house. But their dreams will soon turn to nightmares when they find out that Radha has joined a gang of dacoits, and is out to kill them - one by one. The Thakur, together with his wife and infant daughter, Mona, must now decide to re-locate or else face certain death.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?668994</url></doc>
