<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="669853">
  <docid>669853</docid>
  <title>Zeit Raum</title>
  <year>1998</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Short</genre>
  </genres>
  <languages>
    <language>None</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Austria</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="default">8</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Renoldner, Thomas</director>
  </directors>
<plot>A clear concept ­ time is made visible through changes in the place and place through the layering of time. A day ­ A place (a market) is divided vertically into four time zones. In the second time zone is the busy market. To the left of this, the market stands are being set up, to the right they are being dismantled and the street washed clean. The sound wanders from the morning (left) through conversations about buying and selling to (right) the sound of water at the end of market day. People repeat the gestures of work. It's true, time passes and slips away simultaneously. Where do the people at the edges of the time zones? A year ­ Four times a piece of beach on the Adriatic coast. Without a point of reference, size becomes indeterminable. Sea and sand change constantly but nevertheless remain unchanged. One has the impression of duration. When the summer use with its colorful sunshades has come to an end again, all that remains for the sea and sand is, perhaps a ship. In Thomas Renoldner's work time and place are able to be experienced best right on their margins ­ here in the simultaneity of the long dissolves. Day and year ­ Traces of time and place are washed away one after the other but not erased. For the "A Year" part of the film I went four times to the Italian Adriatic coast at different times of the year to shoot this take. I wanted to fuse these four different seasons on film so that real experiences with place and time would be transposed into a new cinematographic place/time experience. Because of the image of the mass of people who take over this tiny piece of beach, it is also a film about the threat to the ecological balance. In the last scene, where the fishing boat slowly floats into the middle of the picture I have tried, at least on film, to restore an optical harmony.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?669853</url></doc>
