<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="670091">
  <docid>670091</docid>
  <title>Zengin mutfagi</title>
  <year>1988</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Color</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <genres>
    <genre>Drama</genre>
    <genre>Comedy</genre>
  </genres>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>cook</keyword>
    <keyword>based-on-play</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <languages>
    <language>Turkish</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </countries>
  <directors>
    <director>Sabuncu, Basar</director>
  </directors>
  <writers>
    <writer>Ongören, Vasif</writer>
    <writer>Sabuncu, Basar</writer>
  </writers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Acikalin, Nilufer</actor>
      <role>Herself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Görgen, Osman</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Korunan, Oktay</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Mete, Gökhan</actor>
      <role>Himself</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Sen, Sener</actor>
      <role>Lütfi Usta</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Lutfu is a cook in the mansion of the wealthy Kerim. One morning he sees that there is nobody at home. The maid is to get engaged on that day but her fiancée does not show up either. From the brother of their driver, he learns that workers are on strike and their boss Kerim has gone to Europe. Things get back to normal. The maid is engaged and Kerim is back to the house. Lutfu is angry as he has to cook special menus for the dog Kerim has brought with. The maid's fiancée Selim is in trouble and Lutfu helps him and sends him to a special camp. Whe he returns, Selim has become a different person: cool and aggressive. Lutfu poisons the constantly problem causing dog. Selim thinks that only an anarchist would do such a thing and starts investigating the matter. He is suspicious of his fiancée. Kerim brings two new dogs. The maid learns about Selim's doubt and leaves him. Lutfu sees a picture in the newspaper of Selim and his former fiancée. He thinks that he couldn't act as courageously as this young woman. Will he stay at the mansion or will he leave?</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?670091</url></doc>
