<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="672742">
  <docid>672742</docid>
  <title>Zwanzig Minuten mit einem Engel</title>
  <year>2001</year>
  <type>movie</type>
  <colorinfos>
    <colorinfo>Black and White</colorinfo>
  </colorinfos>
  <languages>
    <language>German</language>
  </languages>
  <countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </countries>
  <runningtimes>
    <runningtime country="Germany">50</runningtime>
  </runningtimes>
  <directors>
    <director>Golovkov, Radik</director>
  </directors>
  <producers>
    <producer>Wegelein, Saskia</producer>
  </producers>
  <cast>
    <credit>
      <actor>Book, Hermann</actor>
      <role>Dienstreisender 1</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Golovkov, Radik</actor>
      <role>Der Unbekannte</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Grüsser, Wolfram</actor>
      <role>Der Geiger</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Rakovskij, Michael</actor>
      <role>Der Ehemann</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <actor>Vermeer, Benedikt</actor>
      <role>Dienstreisender 2</role>
    </credit>
  </cast>
<plot>Two travelling salesmen in a hotel room. A new day begins and the mood is still cheery - although they are out of both alcohol and money. Fond memories of the last few days seem to account for this. Up to a certain point these men seem to be close acquaintances, and to like each other. The celebration, they concur, must continue and the games must go on. Do they really need money or can they manage without it? The chance of securing funds appears to them very slight, and this makes the game of looking for it all the more exciting; but where should they start to look? that is the question. Ccommon sense tells them that their situation is hopeless, and to prove this to themselves, they devise a test. One of them opens a window and calls out a sum of money that he considers the minimum required. "look at the people. they just laugh." but then they hear a knock at their door. "you need money? here, take this," a stranger says. Anything that so blatantly contradicts common sense must be investigated and that is precisely what our travellers decide to do.</plot><url>http://localhost:8983/solr/movie.html?672742</url></doc>
